<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='2'>Chapter 1 GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>1-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Amendments to Code; effect of new ordinances; amendatory language.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000062</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 1-4. Amendments to Code; effect of new ordinances; amendatory language.<section>All ordinances passed subsequent to this Code of Ordinances which amend, repeal or in any way affect this Code of Ordinances, may be numbered in accordance with the numbering system of this Code and printed for inclusion therein. When subsequent ordinances repeal any chapter, section or subsection or any portion thereof, such repealed portions may be excluded from said Code by omission from reprinted pages.</section><section>Amendments to any of the provisions of this Code should be made by amending such provisions by specific reference to the section number of this Code in substantially the following language: "That section of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida is hereby amended to read as follows: (Set out new provisions in full) ."</section><section>When the County Commission desires to enact an ordinance of a general and permanent nature on a subject not heretofore existing in the Code, which the Commission desires to incorporate into the Code, a section in substantially the following language shall be made a part of the ordinance:</section><section>"Section . It is the intention of the County Commission, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance shall become and be made a part of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, and the sections of this ordinance may be re-numbered to accomplish such intention."</section><section>All sections, articles, chapters or provisions of this Code desired to be repealed should be specifically repealed by section or chapter number, as the case may be.</section></section></text></law>