<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='2'>Chapter 1 GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>1-4.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Reorganization of County Administrative Departments.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000065</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 1-4.3. Reorganization of County Administrative Departments.<section prefix='(a)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Enterprise Technology Services Department provided in all enactments of this Board including, but not limited to, ordinances, resolutions, implementing orders, regulations, rules, and provisions in the Code of Miami-Dade County ("Legislative Enactments") are hereby transferred to the Information Technology Department. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Enterprise Technology Services Department shall be deemed to be references to the Information Technology Department. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Enterprise Technology Services Department shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Information Technology Department or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Government Information Center provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Community Information and Outreach. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Government Information Center shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Community Information and Outreach. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Government Information Center shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Community Information and Outreach or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement and Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. Commencing October 1, 2012, the powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the stormwater utility functions, including, but not limited to, the administration of the County's Floodplain Management Program, are hereby transferred from the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement and Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. Commencing October 1, 2012, the references to the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement, Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, and Regulatory and Economic Resources that set forth, define or otherwise affect the stormwater utility functions, including, but not limited to, the administration of the County's Floodplain Management Program, shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Departments of Building and Neighborhood Compliance, Planning and Zoning (except those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Office of Countywide Healthcare and Planning), Environmental Resources Management, Economic Development and International Trade, Small Business Development, Film and Entertainment, Sustainability, Consumer Services, Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement and Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee, except, commencing October 1, 2012, for those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect the stormwater utility functions, including, but not limited to, the administration of the County's Floodplain Management Program, which shall be deemed a delegation to the Director of the Department of Public Works and Waste Management, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Community Action Agency and the Department of Human Services provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Community Action and Human Services. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Community Action Agency and the Department of Human Services shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Community Action and Human Services. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Community Action Agency and Department of Human Services shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Community Action and Human Services or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Department of Emergency Management provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Fire Rescue. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Department of Emergency Management shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Fire Rescue. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Department of Emergency Management shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Fire Rescue or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Office of Americans with Disabilities Act Coordination and the Departments of General Services Administration (except for those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), Procurement Management, Capital Improvement (except for those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs), and Human Resources provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Internal Services. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Office of Americans with Disabilities Act Coordination and the Departments of General Services Administration (except for those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), Procurement Management, Capital Improvement (except for those references which set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs), and Human Resources shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Internal Services. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Office of Americans with Disabilities Act Coordination and the Departments of General Services Administration (except for those delegations which set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), Procurement Management, Capital Improvement (except for those delegations which set forth, define or otherwise relate to bond programs), and Human Resources shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Internal Services or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Director of the Department of Internal Services shall hold the powers and responsibilities of the personnel director as set forth in Section 5.05 of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Strategic Budget Management, Grants Coordination, Planning and Zoning (only those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning functions), and Capital Improvements (only insofar those powers, functions and responsibilities set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs) provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Management and Budget. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Strategic Budget Management, Grants Coordination, Planning and Zoning (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning functions) and Capital Improvements (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs) shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Management and Budget. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Director of the Departments of Strategic Budget Management, Grants Coordination, Planning and Zoning (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning functions) and Capital Improvements (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect bond programs) shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Management and Budget, or at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing) and Department of Housing and Community development provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development. Commencing October 1, 2012, the powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Enterprise Zone Program, are hereby transferred from the Department of Public Housing and Community Development to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing) and Department of Housing and Community Development shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development. Commencing October 1, 2012, the references relating to the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing), the Department of Housing and Community Development and the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development that set forth, define or otherwise affect the Enterprise Zone Program, shall be deemed to be a reference to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Miami-Dade Public Housing Agency, General Services Administration (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect infill housing) and Department of Housing and Community Development shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee, except, commencing October 1, 2012, for those delegations which set forth, define or otherwise affect the Enterprise Zone Program, which shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Park and Recreation and Public Works (only those powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect Right-of-Way Aesthetic and Assets Management functions) provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Park, Recreation and Open Spaces. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Park and Recreation and Public Works (only those references that set forth, define or otherwise affect Right-of-Way Aesthetic and Assets Management functions) shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Park, Recreation and Open Spaces. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Departments of Park and Recreation and Public Works (only those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect Right-of-Way Aesthetic and Assets Management functions) shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Park, Recreation and Open Spaces or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The powers, functions and responsibilities of the Departments of Public Works and Solid Waste Management provided in Legislative Enactments are hereby transferred to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. Commencing October 1, 2012, the powers, functions and responsibilities that set forth, define or otherwise affect platting, roadway concurrency management, land development and permitting functions, are hereby transferred from the Department of Public Works and Waste Management to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All references in Legislative Enactments relating to the Departments of Public Works and Solid Waste Management shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management. Commencing October 1, 2012, those references to the Departments of Public Works, Solid Waste Management and Public Works and Waste Management that set forth, define or otherwise affect platting, roadway concurrency management, land development and permitting functions, shall be deemed to be references to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. All delegations of Commission authority, power and responsibility to the Directors of the Departments of Public Works and Solid Waste Management shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Public Works and Waste Management, or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee, except, commencing October 1, 2012, for those delegations that set forth, define or otherwise affect platting, roadway concurrency management, land development and permitting functions, which shall be deemed to be a delegation to the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or, at the County Mayor's discretion, to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Any delegation made by the County Mayor pursuant to this section shall be made in writing and shall become effective upon the filing of the delegation, or any amendment or modification thereto, with the Clerk of the Board, with a copy to the County Attorney and each Commissioner. The Clerk of the Board shall list such delegations on the agenda of the next available Commission meeting and such delegations shall be subject to disapproval by majority vote of those Commissioners present upon a motion made at such meeting.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Notwithstanding any provision of a Legislative Enactment to the contrary, the qualification and requirements of any Department Director set forth in any Legislative Enactment may be satisfied by a designee of the County Mayor who shall (a) report directly to the Department Director and (b) have primary responsibility for overseeing the functions of the Department related to such qualifications. The County Mayor shall report to the Board of County Commissioners in writing which qualifications of a Department Director, if any, will be satisfied by a designee of the Mayor at the time the Mayor presents the appointment of the Department Director to the Board pursuant to Section 2.02(D) of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter and Part 8.1 of the Rules of Procedure of the County Commission.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-70, § 12, 9-23-11; Ord. No. 11-72, § 11, 11-23-11; Ord. No. 11-74, § 6, 11-23-11; Ord. No. 12-38, § 4, 5-15-12; Ord. No. 12-70, § 11, 9-20-12; Ord. No. 12-72, § 11, 9-20-12; Ord. No. 12-74, § 6, 9-20-12)</history></law>