<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='2'>Chapter 1 GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>1-6</section_number>
<catch_line>[Laws of Florida, chapter 2000-312, section 10 nullified within the county.]</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000068</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 1-6. [Laws of Florida, chapter 2000-312, section 10 nullified within the county.]<section prefix='(a)'>This Board [of County Commissioners] finds that Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312 of the Laws of Florida is a special law applying to Miami-Dade County (or a general law applying only in Miami-Dade County) that is inconsistent with the common interest of the people of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>This Board in the exercise of the home rule powers vested in Miami-Dade County by Article VIII, Section 6 of the Florida Constitution of 1968 and the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter hereby supersedes and nullifies Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312 of the Laws of Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>This Board finds that the "governing board, agency, or authority that is wholly independent from the public health trust" created or required to be created by Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312 of the Laws of Florida is a board whose jurisdiction lies wholly within Miami-Dade County that is inconsistent with the common interest of the people of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(d)'>This Board in the exercise of the home rule powers vested in Miami-Dade County by Article VIII, Section 6 of the Florida Constitution of 1968 and the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter hereby abolishes the board, offices, and functions of the "governing board, agency, or authority" created or required to be created by Section 10 of Chapter 2000-312.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The County Attorney is authorized to prosecute or defend any lawsuits to ensure that the purpose and intent of this ordinance are fulfilled.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-111, §§ 2—6, 9-19-00)</history></law>