<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>ARTICLE 1. BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>1.02</section_number>
<catch_line>RESOLUTIONS AND ORDINANCES.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000007</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 1.02. RESOLUTIONS AND ORDINANCES.<section prefix='A.'>The Board shall adopt its own rules of procedure and shall decide which actions of the Board shall be by ordinance or resolution, except as otherwise provided in this Charter and except that any action of the Board which provides for raising revenue, appropriating funds, or incurring indebtedness (other than refunding indebtedness), or which provides a penalty or establishes a rule or regulation for the violation of which a penalty is imposed shall be by ordinance.</section><section prefix='B.'>Every ordinance shall be introduced in writing and shall contain a brief title. The enacting clause shall be "Be it Ordained by the Board." After passage on first reading, a short summary of the ordinance shall be published in a daily newspaper of general circulation at least once together with a notice of the time when and place where it will be given a public hearing and be considered for final passage. The first such publication shall be at least one week prior to the time advertised for hearing. No ordinance shall be declared invalid by reason of any defect in publication or title if the published summary gives reasonable notice of its intent.</section><section prefix='C.'>At the time and place so advertised, or at any time and place to which such public hearing may from time to time be adjourned, the ordinance shall be read by title and a public hearing shall be held. After the hearing, the Board may pass the ordinance with or without amendment. No provision herein shall prohibit a committee of the commission from conducting such public hearing, as provided by Section 1.08</section><section prefix='D.'>The Board may adopt in whole or in part any published code by reference as an ordinance in the manner provided by law.</section><section prefix='E.'>The effective date of any ordinance shall be prescribed therein, but the effective date shall not be earlier than ten days after its enactment.</section><section prefix='F.'>To meet a public emergency affecting life, health, property, or public safety the Board by two-thirds vote of the members of the Board may adopt an emergency ordinance at the meeting at which it is introduced, and may make it effective immediately, except that no such ordinance may be used to levy taxes, grant or extend a franchise, or authorize the borrowing of money. After the adoption of an emergency ordinance, the Board shall have it published in full within ten days in a daily newspaper of general circulation.</section><section prefix='G.'>Each ordinance and resolution after adoption shall be given a serial number and shall be entered by the clerk in a properly indexed record kept for that purpose.</section><section prefix='H.'>Within two years after adoption of this Charter the Board shall have prepared a general codification of all county ordinances and resolutions having the effect of law. The general codification thus prepared shall be adopted by the Board in a single ordinance. After adoption the Board shall have the codification printed immediately in an appropriate manner together with the Charter and such rules and regulations as the Board may direct. Additions or amendments to the code shall be prepared, adopted, and printed at least every two years.</section></section></text></law>