<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>ARTICLE 1. BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>1.07</section_number>
<catch_line>VACANCIES IN THE OFFICE OF MAYOR OR COUNTY COMMISSIONER.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000012</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 1.07. VACANCIES IN THE OFFICE OF MAYOR OR COUNTY COMMISSIONER.<section>Any vacancy in the office of Mayor or the members of the Board shall be filled by majority vote of the remaining members of the Board within 30 days, or the Board shall call an election to be held not more than 90 days thereafter to fill the vacancy. The qualification period for such election shall be the first 10 days after the call of the election and any runoff election shall be held within 30 days of the certification of election results requiring a runoff. The person chosen to fill the office vacated must at the time of appointment meet the residence requirements for the office to which such person is appointed. A person appointed shall serve only until the next county-wide election. A person elected shall serve for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. If a majority of the members of the Board should become appointed rather than elected to office, then the Board shall call an election to be held not more than 90 days thereafter to permit the registered electors to elect commissioners to succeed the appointed commissioners; appointed commissioners may succeed themselves unless otherwise prohibited by the Charter. The qualification period for such election shall be the first 10 days after the call of the election and any runoff election shall be held within 30 days of the certification of election results requiring a runoff. If a county-wide election is scheduled to be held within 180 days from the date on which the majority of the members of the Board become appointive, the Board may elect to defer the required election until the scheduled county-wide election.</section></section></text></law>