<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Grounds for discipline; penalties and enforcement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002074</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-14. Grounds for discipline; penalties and enforcement.<section prefix='(a)'>Either division of the Board or a disciplinary action panel appointed pursuant to this chapter may discipline the holder of any certificate of competency issued to a contractor, journeyman, master, maintenanceman, installer, or technician as well as the holder of any certificate of eligibility to act as a qualifying agent by suspending, revoking or denying renewal of the certificate, by issuing a fine or a reprimand; or, by placing the contractor on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as either division of the Board or disciplinary action panel may specify, including, but not limited to, requiring the contractor to work under the supervision of another contractor after notice and reasonable opportunity to be heard, if it is found that:<section prefix='(1)'>The certificate was fraudulently obtained or erroneously issued.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The holder of the certificate or any member or employee of the firm, or any officer or director, if a corporation, has violated any of the provisions of this chapter or the rules adopted pursuant thereto.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The holder of the certificate of competency has failed to maintain the insurance required by Section 10-19. The Board may reinstate any certificate revoked for failure to maintain insurance at such times as the holder of the certificate furnishes proof satisfactory that the insurance requirements have been complied with. Moreover, permits may be denied to those contractors without the required insurance.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The holder of the certificate or any member or employee of the firm, or any officer or director, if a corporation, has been convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of contracting or the ability to practice contracting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Either division of the Board, or disciplinary action panel may discipline any person, firm or corporation not possessing a certificate issued by the Board, or by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board or by the Florida Electrical Contractors' Licensing Board, engaging in contracting or in a trade, to the same extent as a certified person. Moreover, any uncertified person who is found guilty by either division of the Board or a disciplinary action panel, a criminal court judge or a hearing officer under Chapter 8CC of this Code of contracting may be denied certification by the Board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-41, 11-3-59; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 71-15, § 2, 1-26-71; Ord. No. 93-70, § 2, 7-15-93; Ord. No. 93-109, § 1, 10-19-93; Ord. No. 95-46, § 1, 4-4-95; Ord. No. 99-10, § 1, 1-21-99)</history></law>