<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-13.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Continuing education.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002073</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-13.1. Continuing education.<section prefix='(a)'>Requirements for certificate holders. Each person who is certified by the Board as a maintenanceman, journeyman, a master who is not also a qualifying agent, holders of a certificate of eligibility, or a qualifying agent not registered under F.S. 489, Part I or II in active status, must, as a condition of each renewal of the certificate after January 1, 1996, maintain proof of completion of continuing education hours in one (1) or more courses approved by the Board in accordance with the rules adopted by the Board. The Board shall also accept continuing education credits earned by attending courses approved by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board and the Florida Electrical Contractors' Licensing Board, provided the course is also Miami-Dade County approved.<section prefix='(1)'>For the purposes of continuing education, each certificate of eligibility is to be effective for one (1) term, which begins on the date of the Board's approval of certification and ends on the certificate's date of expiration. In no event shall a certificate be valid for more than twenty-four (24) months.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A certificate-holder who holds more than one (1) certificate issued by the Board is required to complete the continuing education requirements only once during each term. Proof of completion by any such person must be filed with the department prior to the submittal of each renewal application.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A certificate-holder is not required to complete any continuing education requirements for the term in which a certificate is initially issued.</section><section prefix='(4)'>An individual holding a personal certificate of competency or a personal certificate of eligibility in inactive status may defer the continuing education requirement of this chapter for one (1) or more renewal periods until such time as the individual applies to the Board for active status. Deferral of the continuing education requirement shall not prevent the personal certificate holder from renewing his or her certificate. Any individual with a personal certificate in inactive status who applies to the Board to place the certificate in active status must provide proof of having satisfied any deferred continuing education. The Board may not waive any deferred continuing education.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Board members who are qualifying agents of contractors licensed pursuant to this chapter shall earn one (1) credit hour of continuing education for each meeting of the Board attended up to a maximum of five (5) credit hours each year. Certificate holders who are not members of the Board shall earn three (3) credit hours of continuing education for each meeting of the Board attended in which disciplinary cases are considered up to a maximum of three (3) credit hours each term. Proof of attendance must be recorded at the beginning and end of each meeting by the Clerk of the Board.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Registration of course sponsors.<section prefix='(1)'>Any person or legal entity who seeks to conduct a course, seminar or other program of instruction intended to be offered for the purpose of enabling participants to earn continuing education hours under this chapter shall apply to the Board for registration as a course sponsor.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In order to register as a course sponsor, the person or legal entity must submit an application for approval on a form and in a manner approved by the Board with payment of the registration fee established by separate administrative order.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The course sponsor registration is valid for two (2) years from the date of issue.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Approval of continuing education courses.<section prefix='(1)'>Any registered course sponsor may submit an application for approval of a continuing education course.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The application for approval of a continuing education course shall be submitted on a form approved by the Board with payment of the fee established by separate administrative order.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The continuing education course approval is valid for two (2) years from the date of approval.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Discipline of course sponsors.<section prefix='(1)'>If, at any time, a partner, owner, director, officer or duly-appointed representative of a course sponsor falsifies or fraudulently misrepresents any information which is provided to the Board or, in the alternative, violates any of the provisions of Chapter 10 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (or the Board's rules and regulations promulgated thereunder) it shall be deemed a violation of Section 10-14 of this Code, punishable in the manners provided in that Section, with penalties to include revocation or suspension of the course sponsor registration.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-173, ยง 1, 10-7-97; Ord. No. 99-10, ยง 1, 1-21-99)</history></law>