<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-19</section_number>
<catch_line>Insurance requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002081</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-19. Insurance requirements.<section>All contractors holding certificates of competency issued pursuant to this chapter shall maintain at all times with an insurance company authorized to do business in the State of Florida public liability insurance with limits of liability not less than three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per accident or occurrence for bodily injury and fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per accident for property damage. It shall be the responsibility of all persons holding certificates of competency issued pursuant to this chapter or the Florida Statutes and doing business within Miami-Dade County, Florida, to ensure that the originals of certificates, signed by a qualified agent of the insurer, shall be filed with the Secretary of the Board showing the name of the insurer, the type of policy issued, the policy number, the inception and expiration dates of the policy, and the limits of liability, and that the Secretary of the Board or his designee will be notified by registered or certified mail of any material change in the policy or its cancellation. The insurance shall provide by endorsement of the policy that the insurer shall notify the Secretary of the Board by certified or registered mail of the intent to cancel the policy for any reason, at least thirty (30) days prior to such cancellation. When a contractor holding a certificate of competency issued pursuant to this chapter cancels the insurance required by this section or is notified by his insurer that such insurance is being canceled, the contractor will immediately submit to the Secretary of the Board or his designee a list of outstanding permits which he has been issued but for which the work thereunder has not yet been completed. Such list will include the permit number, address of the work under permit and the name of the agency issuing the permit, together with an estimate of the percentage of the work that has been completed under the outstanding permits; provided, however, that no such list will be required if the contractor whose insurance has been canceled has already obtained the required insurance from an alternate insurer and has filed the above required certificate from the insurer. By affixing his signature to any application for a permit, the qualifying agent for a contractor will be considered to have thereby certified that the insurance required by this section has been obtained by the contractor he qualifies and that such insurance is in full force and effect. A binder signed by a qualified agent of the insurer, indicating compliance with the foregoing requirements may be accepted in lieu of a certificate for a period not to exceed thirty (30) days.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-41, 11-3-59; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 76-41, § 1, 5-4-76; Ord. No. 82-32, § 1, 4-20-82; Ord. No. 91-116, § 1, 10-1-91; Ord. No. 99-10, § 1, 1-21-99)</history></law>