<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-15.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Administrative suspension.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002077</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-15.2. Administrative suspension.<section prefix='(a)'>The Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources shall suspend the certificate of competency or the certificate of eligibility of any person or firm who has accumulated points as provided in the following schedule:<section prefix='(1)'>For ten (10) points earned within a consecutive twelve-month period, the suspension shall be for a period of three (3) months.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For sixteen (16) points earned within a consecutive eighteenth-month period inclusive of points earned under paragraph 10-15.2(a)(1), the suspension shall be for a period of six (6) months.</section><section prefix='(3)'>For twenty (20) points earned within a consecutive twenty-four-month period, inclusive of points earned under paragraph 10-15.2(a)(2), the suspension shall be for a period of nine (9) months.</section><section prefix='(4)'>For twenty-six (26) points earned within a consecutive thirty-six-month period, inclusive of points earned under paragraph 10-15.2(a)(3), the suspension shall be for a period of twelve (12) months.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Points shall be assessed as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Convictions of violation of Section 10-22(d) or Section 10-22.1(b)—Six (6) points.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Conviction of violation of Section 10-2—Eight (8) points.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Conviction of violation of Section 10-4—Two (2) points.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Conviction of violation of Section 301, Florida Building Code—Ten (10) points.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Conviction of violation of Section 201.1(e), Florida Building Code—Ten (10) points.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Conviction of violation of Section 8-14, Code of Miami-Dade County—Six (6) points.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Conviction of violation of Section 8-16, Code of Miami-Dade County—Six (6) points.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Conviction of Section 109.6, Florida Building Code—Six (6) points.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Suspension or revocation of certificate by Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board or Florida Electrical Contractors' Licensing Board—Ten (10) points.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>For the purposes of this Section 10-15.2, conviction shall be deemed to mean (i) conviction by County Court or Circuit Judge or jury; or (ii) the entry of a guilty plea to a County Court or Circuit Court proceeding; or (iii) payment of a civil penalty for any violation of this chapter pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 8CC, Code of Miami-Dade County; or (iv) a finding of violation by a hearing officer in a proceeding conducted pursuant to Chapter 8CC, Code of Miami-Dade County; or (v) entry of a guilty plea to such a proceeding. For the purposes of this Section 10-15.2, conviction shall be deemed to have occurred when the time for filing direct appeals shall have expired and no appeal has been filed or when the last appropriate court with jurisdiction to hear direct appeals shall have issued its ruling.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources shall notify the holder of each certificate administratively suspended pursuant to this Section 10-15.2</section><section prefix='(e)'>The holder of any certificate suspended pursuant to this Section 10-15.2 may request in writing that the appropriate division of the Board reinstate the certificate at its first available meeting. The Division may reinstate the certificate upon a finding that the certificate was suspended due to clerical error.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-71, § 1, 10-20-87; Ord. No. 93-70, § 3, 7-15-93; Ord. No. 93-109, § 1, 10-19-93; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 6, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-13, § 2, 2-8-00; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>