<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure for imposition of discipline; review of adverse decision; payment of fines; recovery of unpaid fines; unpaid fines to constitute a lien; foreclosure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002075</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-15. Procedure for imposition of discipline; review of adverse decision; payment of fines; recovery of unpaid fines; unpaid fines to constitute a lien; foreclosure.<section prefix='(a)'>The Secretary of the Board or his designee, for good cause, may, upon his own motion, or upon a complaint in writing of any person, investigate or cause to be investigated the complaints against any person, firm, corporation, joint venture, contractor, or employee, officer or director of a contractor, or any holder of a certificate of competency or certificate of eligibility to act as qualifying agent or tradesman within the meaning of this chapter and submit a written or oral report to a probable cause panel; however, no such investigation or report shall be required. Upon the Secretary discovering that a contractor holding a certificate of competency has been adjudicated bankrupt or such contractor has filed a voluntary petition under State or federal bankruptcy or insolvency statutes or has made assignment for the benefit of creditors, or upon the Secretary discovering that such contractor has failed to keep in force the insurance policy required in Section 10-19, the Secretary of the Board or his designee shall immediately report the matter to the Board.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The probable cause panel shall decide whether the report or complaint establishes that probable cause exists to support a finding that a violation of this chapter or the rules promulgated thereunder has been committed and if so, shall take one (1) or more of the following actions:<section prefix='(1)'>Instruct the Secretary of the Board or his designee to send a letter of guidance by registered or certified mail to the contractor or employee, partner, director, officer and/or qualifying agent at their last known address.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Instruct the Secretary or his designee to send a letter to the certificate of competency holder or holders and the qualifying agent or agents or to the certificate of eligibility holder or holders, setting out the name of the complainant; the alleged offense and the approximate time of the commission; the Section(s) of this chapter alleged to be violated; notifying them to appear before either division of the Board or disciplinary action panel of the Board at a time and place fixed, not sooner than twenty (20) days from the date of service of the letter; to show cause why their certificate should not be suspended or revoked, a letter of reprimand issued, or why a fine and costs should not be imposed; advising that they may be represented by an attorney, that they should bring all original documents and other data that may be pertinent to the case and that they will be given an opportunity to present such witnesses and evidence they deem appropriate. Service shall be made by certified mail, return receipt requested, and regular mail to the last known business address as shown by the Board's records or by posting of the letter on these same premises.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Refer the matter to the State Attorney or County Attorney for appropriate action.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The administrative hearing provided for above shall be open to the public.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The proceedings at the hearing shall be recorded and may be transcribed at the expense of the party requesting the transcript.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The hearing need not be conducted according to technical rules relating to evidence and witnesses. Any relevant evidence shall be admitted if a division or disciplinary action panel as determined by Board rule finds it competent and reliable, regardless of the existence of any common law or statutory rule which might make improper the admission of such evidence. Hearsay evidence may be used for the purpose of supplementing or explaining any direct evidence but shall not be sufficient in itself to support a finding unless it would be admissible in civil actions. Irrelevant and unduly repetitious evidence shall be excluded.</section><section prefix='(f)'>(1)Each party may have the following rights: To call and examine witnesses; to introduce exhibits; to cross-examine opposing witnesses on any matter relevant to the issues even though that matter was not covered in the direct examination; to im peach any witness regardless of which party first called him to testify; and to rebut the evidence against him.<section prefix='(2)'>In order to make a decision of guilt, a division or disciplinary action panel must find that the weight of substantial competent evidence indicates that the person charged has violated the Sections of this Code as charged. Before imposing a penalty, the division or disciplinary action panel may consider mitigating circumstances presented through testimony and evidence. A sincere offer to make full restitution to the injured property owner may be considered as a mitigating circumstance.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>A decision shall be made at the close of the hearing. The division or disciplinary action panel shall make a finding of guilty or not guilty as to each charge. The division or disciplinary action panel shall impose one (1) or more of the following penalties on each charge for which a finding of guilty is made:<section prefix='(1)'>Suspension of the certificate, stating time.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Revocation of the certificate, naming the effective date. After revocation, the certificate may only be renewed or reissued after a period of at least one (1) year and upon a showing of rehabilitation of the former certificate holder.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Official letter of reprimand to become a part of the certificate holder's permanent file.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Imposition of an administrative fine up to, but not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) on each of the charges upon which a certificate holder has been found guilty by the division or disciplinary action panel. The penalty of suspension, revocation and reprimand authorized in Sections 10-15(g)(1), (2) and (3) above.<section prefix='a.'>Fines assessed by a division or disciplinary action panel pursuant to this chapter and any administrative costs are due and payable to the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources on the last day of the period allowed for the filing of an appeal from the division's or disciplinary action panel's decision, unless a specific time for payment is stated in the order, or, if proper appeal has been made, when the appeal has been finally decided adversely to the named violator.</section><section prefix='b.'>If a certificate holders fails to pay the fines and administrative costs as assessed by the division or disciplinary action panel, the certificate of such a person or firm shall be administratively suspended until the fine and costs have been paid, and the certificate holder and all municipalities will be so notified. Failure to pay a fine or administrative costs within the time specified in this section or the division's or the disciplinary action panel's order shall result in the assessment of an interest payment at an annual percentage rate of eighteen (18) percent. The interest payment shall begin to accrue from the date immediately succeeding the due date of the fine and administrative costs.</section><section prefix='c.'>The Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or Public Works and Waste Management Department may institute proceedings in a court of competent jurisdiction to compel payment of fines or administrative costs imposed by the division or disciplinary action panel.</section><section prefix='d.'>A certified copy of the division's or disciplinary action panel's decision imposing a fine or administrative costs may be recorded in the public records and thereafter shall constitute a lien against any real or personal property owned by the individual or entity fined by the division or disciplinary action panel; and, it may be enforced in the same manner as a court judgment by the sheriffs of this State, including levy against the personal property, but shall not be deemed to be a court judgment except for enforcement purposes. After one (1) year from the filing of any such lien which remains unpaid, Miami-Dade County may foreclose or otherwise execute on the lien.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Restitution to complaining parties. In cases where restitution is ordered, the restitution shall be paid on or before the last day of the period allowed for the filing of an appeal from the division's or disciplinary action panel's decision unless a specific time for payment is stated in the order, or if proper appeal has been made, when the appeal has been finally decided adversely to the named violator.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a violation of Section 105 of the Florida Building Code shall result in an administrative fine of five hundred dollars ($500.00).</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Notice of guilty decisions shall be mailed to all municipalities within Miami-Dade County and to the certificate holder at his last known address.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Any party aggrieved by a division's or disciplinary action panel's decision may have such decision reviewed by the filing of a direct appeal in the Circuit Court of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, for a review of the record upon which the decision is based, in accordance with the procedure and within time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for the review of the rulings of any commission or Board, which rules of practice and procedure are hereby adopted. For such purposes, the secretary of the Board shall make a available for public inspection and copying the record of each such decision to be reviewed; provided, such secretary may make a reasonable charge commensurate with the cost, in the event he is able to and does furnish copies of all or a portion of such Board's record. Prior to certifying a copy of any record or portion thereof, the secretary or his designee shall make all necessary corrections in order that the copy is a true and correct copy of the record, or those portions thereof requested, and shall make a charge of not more than actual copying costs per page, instrument or exhibit; provided the charges here authorized are not intended to repeal or amend any fee or schedule of fees otherwise established.</section><section prefix='(j)'>In addition to any fines imposed under Section 10-15(g), the Department may recover any administrative costs associated with investigating and resolving complaints which give rise to any disciplinary proceeding resulting in a finding of guilty or any settlement agreement pursuant to Section 10-15.1 of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-41, 11-3-59; Ord. No. 61-25, § 1, 6-13-61; Ord. No. 64-59, §§ 18, 19, 11-24-64; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 71-15, § 3, 1-26-71; Ord. No. 71-84, § 1, 10-5-71; Ord. No. 76-38, § 1, 5-4-76; Ord. No. 82-15, § 1, 3-2-82; Ord. No. 84-6, § 1, 1-17-84; Ord. No. 87-71, § 1, 10-20-87; Ord. No. 91-115, § 1, 10-1-91; Ord. No. 91-116, § 1, 10-1-91; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 6, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-10, § 1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 00-13, § 1, 2-8-00; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>