<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-23</section_number>
<catch_line>Refund of examination fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002087</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-23. Refund of examination fees.<section>An application fee paid for the purpose of taking an examination as required by this chapter may be refunded to the applicant only under the following circumstances:<section prefix='(a)'>If a refund is requested prior to the application being presented to the Board for screening to determine if the applicant is eligible to take the examination, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>If upon screening the application, the Board determines that the applicant is ineligible to take any examination which the particular Board is authorized to give, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the applicant is found eligible to take an examination but prior to the examination order date thereof he notifies the Secretary of the Board in writing that he is unable to take the examination, the full fee may be refunded or applied as the fee for the next examination only which is given for the particular trade, except that if prior to the examination, but after the examination order date thereof he notifies the Secretary of the Board in writing that he is unable to take the examination, the fee will not be refunded but will be applied as the fee for the next examination only which is given for the particular trade, or</section><section prefix='(d)'>If an applicant for an examination has fulfilled the requirements set forth elsewhere in this section for a refund of an examination fee, that applicant must make written request for such refund, within six (6) months after the date of the examination for which he applied and a failure to do so will automatically forfeit all of the rights of the applicant to such refund of an examination fee.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 62-21, ยง 1, 5-15-62; Ord. No. 67-82, ยง 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 69-11, ยง 13, 2-4-69; Ord. No. 76-39, ยง 1, 5-4-76)</history></law>