<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Certificate of competency and license required, classification and scope of work.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002059</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-2. Certificate of competency and license required, classification and scope of work.<section>I. IN GENERAL</section><section>Before any person, firm, or corporation may work at a trade, engage in business, or contract for work as a contractor or tradesman in one (1) or more of the classifications as set forth herein, or into such other classifications as may be from time to time established as provided in, be shall first be classified and certified as provided herein, a certificate of competency be approved and issued and a license, where required, be applied for and issued.</section><section>II. SCOPE OF WORK</section><section>The scope of work for each person, partnership, firm or corporation holding a certificate of competency shall be limited to work as described in the classification for which a certificate of competency is held, and the standards established, including examination, for the obtaining of any particular certificate of competency shall cover the entire scope of the work involved in the particular classification concerned. The possessing of a current valid certificate of competency and a current occupational license pursuant thereto as a contractor or sub-contractor in any classification shall include the right to contract and to obtain permits for all work included in the scope of the work described in the classification and such contractor or sub-contractor shall be issued permits for such work by the administrative agency concerned. Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit the work included under one (1) classification from also being included under another classification, if so set forth hereinafter in the scope of the work of the classification concerned and whether on private or public property, shall have no bearing unless specified otherwise.</section><section>III. BUILDING CONTRACTOR</section><section>The scope of work of a building contractor shall be as defined in the various building contractor classifications listed herein:<section prefix='(A)'>General building contractor is a building contractor qualified and certified on or before the effective date of this ordinance. Such license holders will be issued a general contractor's license and additional certificates authorized by the scope of the general building contractor license. No further certificates shall be issued for the general building contractor category after the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Sub-general building contractor is a building contractor qualified and certified on or before the effective date of this ordinance. Such license holders will be issued a building contractor's license and additional certificates authorized by the scope of the sub-general building contractor license. No further certificates shall be issued for the sub-general building contractor category after the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Sub-building contractor is a building contractor qualified and certified on or before the effective date of this ordinance. Such license holders will be issued a residential contractor's license and additional certificates authorized by the scope of the sub-building contractor license. No further certificates shall be issued for the sub-building contractor category after the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(D)'>General contractor is a contractor whose services are unlimited as to the type of work, height, area or complexity of construction, and has a qualifying agent with the experience, knowledge and skill gained by not less than four (4) years' experience for a State of Florida certified or registered general contractor with at least one (1) year as either a superintendent or foreman or four (4) years' experience as a State of Florida certified or registered building contractor or sub-general contractor or has an accredited college-level education in a construction-related field equivalent thereto, or any combination thereof, with at least one year of proven experience as a superintendent or foreman and who has satisfactorily passed a general contractors' examination. A general contractor may do, contract for, and take out permits for the work of any specialty building contractor subject to the limitations contained herein.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Building contractor is a contractor whose services are limited to construction of commercial buildings and single dwelling or multiple dwelling residential buildings, which commercial or residential buildings do not exceed three (3) stories in height, and accessory use structures in connection therewith, or a contractor whose services are limited to remodeling, repair, or improvement of any size building if the services do not affect the structural members of the building and has a qualifying agent with the experience, knowledge and skill gained by not less than four (4) years' experience for a State of Florida certified or registered general, general building, building or sub-general contractor with at least one (1) year as either a superintendent or foreman or has an accredited college-level education in a construction related field equivalent thereto, or any combination thereof, with at least one year of proven experience as a superintendent or foreman and who has satisfactorily passed a building contractors' examination. A building contractor may construct, contract for, and take out permits for the work of any specialty building contractor subject to the limitations contained herein.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Residential contractor is a contractor whose services are limited to construction, remodeling, repair, or improvement of one-family, two-family, or three-family residences not exceeding two habitable stories above no more than one uninhabitable story and accessory use structures in connection therewith and has a qualifying agent with the experience, knowledge and skill gained by not less than four (4) years' experience for a State of Florida certified or registered general, general building, building, sub-general, residential or sub-building contractor with at least one (1) year as either a superintendent or foreman or has an accredited college-level education in a construction-related field equivalent thereto, or any combination thereof, with at least one year of proven experience as a superintendent or foreman and who has satisfactorily passed a residential contractors' examination. A residential building contractor may do, contract for, and take out permits for the work of any specialty contractor subject to the limitations contained herein.</section><section prefix='(G)'>A general, building, or residential contractor shall subcontract all electrical, mechanical, plumbing, liquefied petroleum gas, roofing, sheet metal, swimming pool, and air-conditioning work, including specialties and categories thereunder, unless such contractor holds a state certificate or registration in the respective trade category; however:<section prefix='(1)'>A general, building, or residential contractor, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, shall be responsible for any construction or alteration of a structural component of a building or structure, and any general contractor may perform clearing and grubbing, grading, excavation, and other site work for any construction project. Any building contractor or residential contractor may perform clearing and grubbing, grading, excavation, and other site work for any construction project in this state, limited to the lot on which any specific building is located.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A general contractor shall not be required to subcontract structural swimming pool work. All other swimming pool work shall be subcontracted to an appropriately licensed swimming pool contractor.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A general, building, or residential contractor shall not be required to subcontract the installation, or repair made under warranty, of wood shingles, wood shakes, or asphalt or fiberglass shingle roofing materials on a new building of his or her own construction.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A general contractor, on new site development work, site redevelopment work, mobile home parks, and commercial properties, shall not be required to subcontract the construction of the main sanitary sewer collection system, the storm collection system, and the water distribution system, not including the continuation of utility lines from the mains to the buildings.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A general contractor shall not be required to subcontract the continuation of utility lines from the mains in mobile home parks, and such continuations are to be considered a part of the main sewer collection and main water distribution systems.</section></section><section prefix='(H)'>Specialty building contractor is a building contractor who specializes in one (1) or more of the following building crafts and whose scope of work is so limited under the certificate of competency held, and whose principal contracting business is the execution of contracts, usually subcontracts, in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable, and has satisfactorily passed an examination for the specialty concerned, and who has the financial means and has a qualifying agent with the experience, knowledge and skill as evidenced by three (3) years' experience as a mechanic, or supervisory or managerial experience or education equivalent thereto, or any combination thereof, in the particular building specialty concerned, except as such three (3) year period may be modified in the particular categories listed hereinafter. Such contractor shall subcontract with a qualified contractor any work which is incidental to the work of the specialty but which is specified herein as being the work of other than that of the building specialty for which certified. The following are the various crafts of specialty building contractors.<section prefix='(1)'>A reinforcing steel placing contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to fabricate, place, tie and weld steel reinforcing bars (rods) that are or may be used to reinforce concrete buildings or structures.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A concrete forming and placing contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to proportion, batch and mix aggregates, cement and water to agreed specifications; to construct forms and framework for the casting and shaping of concrete, including, but not limited to, columns, beams, decks and window frames; to place and erect reinforcing steel and miscellaneous embedded steel; and to pour, place and finish concrete, including terrazzo.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A structural steel erection contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to erect structural steel shapes and plates including such minor field fabrication as may be necessary, of any profile, perimeter or cross-section, that are or may be used as structural members for buildings and structures, including steel joists, steel decking and siding, and communication towers, and including riveting, welding and rigging only in connection therewith. The experience requirement for the qualifying agent for the structural steel erection contractor shall be five (5) years.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A metal decking and siding contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to erect metal decking and siding or other material incidental thereto that may be used for enclosing buildings or other structures including welding, bolting or other attachments in connection therewith and including such minor field fabrication as may be necessary and also the installation of industrial doors and windows in connection therewith.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A communications tower contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to fabricate and erect steel communications towers and do the welding, bolting and riveting in connection therewith.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A unit masonry, marble and exterior veneer contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to select, cut and lay brick and concrete block or any other unit masonry products, or clay products, rough cut and dress stone, artificial stone and precast blocks, structural glass brick or block, decor block and veneer, laid at random or in course, with or without mortar, or to do any part, or any combination thereof and shall include the application of tile to floors and exterior wall surfaces; provided, however, that the scope of work shall not include the pouring, placing or finishing of cast-in-place concrete except for masonry or precast concrete fences.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A prestressed precast concrete erection contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to erect structural precast concrete units such as decks, beams, girders, walls, columns and stairs that are or may be used as structural members for buildings and structures, including welding and rigging in connection therewith and to erect precast concrete units for guard rails and decorative panels above the ground floor, including such minor field fabrication as may be necessary.</section><section prefix='(7.1)'>A miscellaneous metals contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to fabricate, apply, erect and install miscellaneous appurtenances, appendages, parts or equipment of metal, including other materials incidental thereto, in or on buildings or other structures and shall also include all work involving: metal awnings and storm shutters, canvas awnings, metal cabinets and store fixtures, screen enclosures and all work incidental thereto, metal partitions, flagpoles, ornamental metals including structural railings, and metal sunshades. The work of a miscellaneous metals contractor shall not include the work of a metal decking and siding contractor, reinforcing steel placing contractor, or structural steel contractor. (Ord. No. 73-75, § 1, 9-18-73)</section><section prefix='(8)'>A roof deck contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to erect, construct, fabricate and install roof decks of Portland cement or gypsum concrete, using lightweight aggregate, on joists or other supporting members erected by others, and shall include the placing of forms and welding of supporting members for forms and miscellaneous reinforcing of the deck and the proportioning, mixing and placing of cement, aggregate and water, provided, however, that roof decks of wood, metal, heavy aggregate concrete, glass or plastic and the application of roofing felts or other water resistant membranes shall not be a part of the scope of such work. The experience requirement for the qualifying agent for a roof deck contractor shall be one (1) year.</section><section prefix='(9)'>A roofing contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to install, repair and replace roof systems, as defined in the Florida Building Code, and the waterproofing thereof. Work may include, but shall not be limited to, roof deck insulation, roof coating, painting and covering, including use of sheet metal and installation of other sheet metal products incidental to roofing work, including gutters and downspouts, and other material in connection therewith or any combination thereof and including installation of nonstructural decking and siding. During the repair or replacement process of a roof system, a roofing contractor shall be allowed to repair and/or replace damaged decking and/or damaged wood structural or nonstructural members of the roof framing, provided that such replacement and/or repair conforms to the requirements of the Florida Building Code and the repair or replacement of damaged decking and wood structural or nonstructural members of the roof framing constitutes less than fifty (50) percent of the value of the total work performed.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A glass and glazing contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to fabricate, install and attach windows of any type, fixed or movable, and swinging or sliding glass doors to building walls or columns erected by others including installation of glass-holding or supporting mullions or horizontal bars which in turn are attached to building walls or columns erected by others, including the cutting and installation of glass, and shall also include metal accessories and prefabricated glass, metal or plastic curtain walls or panels. The scope of work shall include the caulking incidental to all such work and shall include the fabrication and installation of garage and industrial doors and shower and tub enclosure doors and metal facias, store front awnings or canopies.</section><section prefix='(11)'>A lathing and plastering contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to apply and affix wood, gypsum or metal lath or any other product prepared or manufactured, including the placing of metal studs and runners to which lath is to be applied, to provide key or suction bases for the support of plaster coatings, to provide hangers, channels and other mechanical suspension work for the support of lath or acoustical tile or other prefabricated ceiling materials, including the channel iron work for the support of metal or other fire resistive lath on walls, ceilings or soffits, or for solid plaster partitions; and to coat surfaces with a mixture of sand or other aggregate, gypsum, plaster, Portland cement or quick lime and water or any combination of such materials as to create a permanent surface coating and which coatings are usually applied with a plasterer's trowel or by pneumatic pressure on any surface which offers a mechanical key for the support of such coatings or to which the coating will adhere by suction. The scope of work shall not include the erection of wood stud or masonry walls. Such contractor may perform the work of a drywall contractor.</section><section prefix='(12)'>A drywall contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to install gypsum drywall products to studs, joists and suspended ceiling channels and to fabricate and install accessories and all necessary trim in connection therewith including metal and wood studs, runners, hangers, channels, drywall metal suspension accessories and prefabricated ceiling materials, provided that any plaster work or trowelled material, application of block or wood partitions shall not be a part of the scope of such work. The experience requirement for the qualifying agent for a drywall contractor shall be one (1) year and six (6) months.</section><section prefix='(13)'>A pneumatic concreting and pressure grouting contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to proportion and apply concrete to surfaces by pneumatic methods, chip loose concrete, sandblast and clean reinforcing, batch and proportion cement, sand and water, to erect forms and framework to which concrete is to be applied pneumatically and place miscellaneous reinforcing for repair of concrete and to proportion and place cement and intergrout by pneumatic pumping methods that under an agreed specifications subsurface load bearing capacities can be stabilized or previously settled structures raised or restored to plumb, grade or alignment.</section><section prefix='(14)'>A nonelectric sign contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to paint or otherwise apply or erect any outside display of characters, letters, illustrations or ornamentations which do not include the incorporation of any electrical work in their manufacture, fabrication or erection. The work of a nonelectric sign contractor shall include the installation of panels, facing, frame, structure, movable or fixed, free standing or attached to a building or other structure which is to be used for sign purposes and which do not include any electrical work in their manufacture, fabrication or erection.</section><section prefix='(15)'>A swimming pool contractor is a contractor whose scope of work involves two (2) or more building trades or crafts and is qualified and certified to excavate, construct, fabricate, install and equip swimming pools and such contractor shall subcontract to a qualified contractor, in the field concerned, all other work set forth in this chapter as being the exclusive work of a plumbing, electrical, mechanical or liquefied petroleum gas contractor.</section><section prefix='(16)'>A demolition contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to demolish, wreck or disassemble buildings or other structures or parts thereof and remove the debris therefrom in such a manner that adjoining structures and properties and parts thereof and workmen and other persons may be kept safe.</section><section prefix='(17)'>A concrete slab sawing and core drilling contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to cut and/or core concrete, asphalt or any masonry combination thereof. Where cutting or coring is done on any structural member of any building or structure, it shall be under the direct supervision of the general or prime contractor and professional engineer who is responsible for that building or structure. All cutting or coring is to be approved by and coordinated between the general or prime contractor and the specialty or subcontractor as to the layout of the work to be performed. Such contractor shall have a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by at least one (1) year's practical work in this field and who has passed a designated examination.</section><section prefix='(18)'>A fence contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to fabricate, assemble, erect and install fences of masonry, wire, concrete, wood and other fence materials, in such manner that an acceptable fence can be erected complying with applicable regulations including zoning regulations. Such contractor shall have a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by at least one (1) year's practical working this field and who has passed a designated examination.</section><section prefix='(19)'>A metal awning and storm shutter contractor is qualified and certified to fabricate, erect and install awnings or canopies of metal including other materials, incidental thereto, in or on buildings or other structures, and which may be, in whole or part, supported from a building wall erected and provided by others, or may be self-supporting, and including footings or slabs on grade in connection therewith. Such contractor shall have a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by at least one (1) year's practical work in this field and who has passed a designated examination.</section><section prefix='(20)'>A screen enclosure contractor is qualified and certified to fabricate, erect and install on grade only, screen enclosures with metal-supporting members, in whole or in part self-supporting, having walls and roof of screen except that the roof may be of metal or plastic where the area of solid wind resistant material does not exceed forty (40) percent of the area of screen roof. The scope of work shall include footings or slab on grade in connection therewith. Such contractor shall have a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by at least one (1) year's practical work in this field and who has passed a designated examination.</section><section prefix='(21)'>A window frame contractor is qualified and certified to construct forms and formwork for window frames into which concrete is to be placed. Such contractor shall have a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by at least one (1) year's practical work in this field and who has passed a designated examination.</section><section prefix='(22)'>A utility building contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to erect and install prefabricated buildings made of metal, wood or other approved material on an approved foundation or base. The forming, mixing, constructing and/or placing of the concrete slab, base, anchor or foundation is a part of the scope of work of such contractor. Such contractor shall have a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by at least three (3) years of practical work in this field and who has passed a designated examination.</section></section><section prefix='(I)'>Building maintenanceman is a person qualified and certified by examination to maintain buildings and structures owned or occupied by the person, firm or corporation by which the building maintenanceman is regularly employed. The work of a building maintenanceman shall be confined to the erection, repair or relocation of nonbearing interior partitions, painting, the patching of stucco and plaster, the repair of floors of all types, the repair of cabinets and counters of wood, metal or plastic, the repair of awnings and canopies, the repair of wall and floor tile. A building maintenanceman may make only repairs to bearing walls, both interior and exterior, and roofing work shall be limited to stoppage of leaks. A building maintenanceman shall not make addition to or change the outline of any building or structure, and the work of a building maintenanceman shall not include plumbing, electrical, mechanical or liquefied petroleum gas work of any kind. A certified sub-building, sub-general or general qualifying agent shall automatically qualify as a building maintenanceman. (Ord. No. 69-64, § 2, 9-17-69; Ord. No. 75-62, § 1, 7-16-75)</section></section><section>IV. ENGINEERING CONTRACTOR</section><section>The scope of work of an engineering contractor shall be as defined in the various engineering contractor classifications listed herein.<section prefix='(A)'>General engineering contractor is an engineering contractor whose contracting business consists of the execution of contracts involving two (2) or more trades and who has the financial means, and who has a qualifying agent with the art, ability, experience, knowledge, science and skill gained by not less than ten (10) years experience either as a superintendent for a general engineering contractor or as a licensed building or engineering contractor for such period (or has had an education equivalent thereto) or any combination thereof, to construct and properly supervise, direct and coordinate work in the engineering trade in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable, and who has satisfactorily passed a general engineering contractor's examination. The scope of work of the general engineering contractor shall be unlimited in the engineering trade field, except that his work in connection with utilities shall be considered to stop at a point five (5) feet from a building not specifically constructed for the purpose of pumping or processing pipeline products. Such contractor shall subcontract to a qualified contractor in the field concerned, all other work specified herein as being the exclusive work of a plumbing, electrical, mechanical or liquefied petroleum gas contractor, including the specialties and categories thereunder. A general engineering contractor, qualified and certified before the effective date of this ordinance may do, contract for, and take out permits for the work of a general building contractor. Such license holders will be issued additional certificates authorized by the scope of the general engineering contractor license. After the effective date of this ordinance a general engineering contractor may do, contract for, and take out permits for the work authorized by the scope of the general contractor license. (Ord. No. 69-11, § 5, 2-4-69; Ord. No. 08-26, § 1, 3-4-08)</section><section prefix='(B)'>Specialty engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who specializes in one (1) or more of the following engineering crafts and whose scope of work is so limited under the certificate of competency held. Such contractor's principal contracting business is the execution of contracts, in some instances subcontracts, and possibly involving two (2) or more trades and who has the financial means, and has a qualifying agent with the experience, knowledge and skill as herein set forth, to engage in the business of the particular engineering specialty concerned, in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable, and who has satisfactorily passed an examination in the engineering specialty concerned. Such contractor shall subcontract with a qualified contractor any work which is incidental to the specialty but which is specified herein as being the work of other than that of the engineering specialty for which certified. The following are the various crafts of specialty engineering contractors.<section prefix='(1)'>A plant construction engineer contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained but not less than three (3) years as a general superintendent for a general building or general engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and certified to construct and properly supervise, direct and coordinate the construction of buildings, plants and other structures which are incidental to water treatment plants, sewage treatment plants, pumping and lift stations, power generating plants and sub-station, including the equipment and piping installation (except the exclusive work of an electrical contractor) and placing therein in connection with the purpose for which the structure is being erected. A plant construction engineering contractor may perform the work of a pile driving and foundation engineering contractor.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A pipeline engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent who is qualified by the experience and skill gained by not less than three (3) years as a general superintendent for a general engineering contractor or pipeline engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof and certified to excavate, construct, install, repair or alter pipelines, such as water and gas transmission and distribution lines, storm and sanitary sewerage lines, force mains, outfalls, and pumping facilities incidental to the collection or installation of pipeline products including the equipment and piping installation and placing within a structure which is constructed for the purpose of pumping or processing such pipeline products. A pipeline engineering contractor may construct or install junction boxes, manholes, inlets, valves and similar components, in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable. The work of the pipeline engineering contractor shall be considered to stop at a point five (5) feet from a building not specifically constructed for the purpose of pumping or processing pipeline products. The scope of work of such a contractor does not include the installation of chilled water lines or related work incidental thereto. (Ord. No. 71-69, § 1, 8-31-71)</section><section prefix='(3)'>A structural engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than three (3) years as a general superintendent for a general building or a general engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified and certified to construct and properly supervise and direct the construction of bridges, tunnels, overpasses, harbor facilities, docks, shipyards, bulkheads, retaining walls, seawalls, dams, locks and similar structures. A structural engineering contractor may perform the work of a seawall and small dock engineering contractor, a pile driving and foundation engineering contractor, and a concrete work engineering contractor.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A seawall and small dock engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than two (2) years as a general superintendent for an engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified and certified to construct seawalls and small docks. A seawall and small dock engineering contractor may drive piling for one (1) story building construction.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A pile driving and foundation engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than two (2) years as a general superintendent for a general building or general engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified and certified to drive piling including sheet piling and construct foundations including the excavating, forming and placing of reinforcing steel and concrete and perform other work incidental thereto.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A paving engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than three (3) years as a general superintendent for an engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified and certified to construct roads, airport runways, and aprons, parking lots, sidewalks, curbs and gutters, property line walls, storm drainage facilities and to perform the excavating, clearing and grading incidental thereto. A paving engineering contractor may not excavate for canals and lakes.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A concrete-work engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than one (1) year as a general superintendent for a building or engineering contractor, or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified and certified to construct concrete driveways, sidewalks, curbs and gutters and related nonstructural concrete components.</section><section prefix='(8)'>An excavating and grading engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than two (2) years as a general superintendent for an engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and certified to make excavations, to obtain or remove materials such as rock, gravel or sand, to construct or excavate canals, lakes, levees, roadways, including land clearing, filling and grading. An excavating and grading engineering contractor may do the work of a land clearing and grubbing engineering contractor.</section><section prefix='(9)'>A land clearing and grubbing engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than one (1) year as a general superintendent for an engineering contractor or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified and certified to clear land of surface debris and vegetation growth, including the grubbing of roots, the removal of the debris therefrom and the general leveling of the surface thereinafter and work incidental thereto.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A soil compaction and tamping engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than six (6) months as a general superintendent for a building or engineering contractor, or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified and certified to compact fill in or surrounding buildings, bridges and trenches.</section><section prefix='(11)'>A railroad construction engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than two (2) years in railroad construction, or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, and qualified to construct railroads, including spur lines and sidings and all incidental work such as grading, placing ballast, track laying and installation of switch equipment.</section><section prefix='(12)'>An underground electrical and communications conduits engineering contractor is an engineering contractor who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than three (3) years in this field, or education equivalent thereto, or combination thereof, and qualified and certified to trench, backfill and restore paving and concrete block and cement work incidental to or a part of the work in the construction of manholes and splice pits, laying of rigid conduit for electrical communication lines. The scope of work of this classification shall be limited to that work directly involved in performing contract work for the construction of underground electrical and communication facilities.</section><section prefix='(13)'>A fuel transmission and distribution line engineering contractor is an engineering contractor, who has a qualifying agent with the experience and skill gained by not less than three (3) years' experience in this field or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, qualified and certified to excavate for and construct, alter, repair and maintain transmission and distribution lines for liquid or gaseous fuels under pressure in welded pipes, including pumping and booster stations, valves, meters and similar components incidental thereto and restoration of pavement. The scope of work of a fuel transmission and distribution line engineering contractor shall be considered to stop at the metering device.</section><section prefix='(14)'>A direct burial cable television (CATV) contractor is an engineering contractor certified by this Board to trench, backfill and restore paving and concrete block and cement work either incidental to or as a part of the work of installing, repairing, altering or adding to any system of underground cable in the public rights-of-way for the commercial transmission of television signals. Such contractor shall have a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by at least two (2) years' practical work in this field and who has passed an examination approved by this Board. The scope of work of this classification shall be limited to that work directly involved in performing contract work underground for direct burial of cable for receiving and transmitting community antenna television signals. (Ord. No. 81-43, § 1, 4-21-81)</section></section></section><section>V. PLUMBING CONTRACTOR</section><section>The scope of work of a plumbing contractor is as defined in the various contractor classifications listed herein.<section prefix='(A)'>A plumbing contractor is a contractor whose contracting business consists of the execution of contracts requiring the experience, financial means, knowledge and skill to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend plumbing, septic tanks, drainage and supply wells, swimming pool and piping or solar heating systems and all appurtenances, apparatus or equipment used in connection therewith, including boilers and pressure and process piping and including the installation of water, gas, storm and sanitary sewer lines, and for the mechanical installation of gas, water and sewage plants and substations. The scope of work of the plumbing contractors shall also include the installation, maintenance, repair, alteration or extension of airpiping, vacuum line piping, oxygen line piping, nitrous oxide piping, fire line standpipes and fire sprinklers, ink and chemical lines, gasoline piping and tank and pump installation (excepting bulk storage plants) and pneumatic control piping systems, all in such a manner as to comply with all plants, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable. Such contractor shall have as qualifying agent a master plumber. The scope of work of the plumbing contractor shall apply to private and public property, shall include any excavation work incidental thereto and shall include the work of the specialty plumbing contractor. Such contractor shall subcontract, with a qualified contractor in the field concerned, all other work incidental to the work, but which is specified herein as being the work of a trade other than that of a plumbing contractor. The scope of work of such a contractor does not include the installation of chilled water lines or related work incidental thereto. (Ord. No. 71-69, § 2, 8-31-71)</section><section prefix='(B)'>A specialty plumbing contractor is a contractor who specializes in one (1) or more of the following crafts and whose scope of work is so limited under the certificate of competency held. The specialty plumbing contractor's principal contracting business is the execution of contracts requiring the experience, financial means, knowledge and skill to engage in the business of the particular plumbing specialty concerned in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable and the qualifying for the specialty concerned. Such contractor shall sub-contract with a qualified contractor in the field concerned all other work incidental to the work, but which is specified herein as being the work of a grade other than that of the plumbing specialty for which such specialty plumbing contractor is certified. The following are the various crafts of specialty plumbing contractors.<section prefix='(1)'>A septic tank contractor is a contractor having the financial means, and who has a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by not less than one (1) year as a general superintendent for a plumbing or septic tank contractor or education equivalent thereto, or combination thereof, and qualified and certified to install, clean, repair, alter, extend and excavate for septic tanks, drainfields, interceptor tanks, dry wells, gas and oil interceptors, soakage pits and catch basins and shall not include any other plumbing work or connecting pipes or pumps except the nonferrous pipes between the catch basin and soakage pit. The septic tank contractor shall maintain in proper and sanitary condition for use, subject to inspection at any time, the following minimum equipment:<section prefix='(a)'>A vehicle equipped with a sewage-tight tank of not less than one thousand (1,000) gallons capacity, equipped with suitable pump and at least eighty (80) feet of three-inch minimum diameter suction hose.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A ten thousand (10,000) gallon-per-hour centrifugal pump equipped with two-inch hose.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>A well drilling contractor is a contractor having the financial means, and who has a qualifying agent with experience and skill gained by not less than one (1) year as a general superintendent for a plumbing or well drilling contractor, or education equivalent thereto, or combination thereof, and qualified to drill water supply or drainage wells. A well drilling contractor may install lawn sprinkler systems, and make connection of such lawn sprinkler systems to potable water supply piping but he shall not make a connection to sanitary or storm sewers. A well drilling contractor shall, when engaged in the well drilling business, provide and maintain the necessary equipment in proper and sanitary condition. Well drilling contractors who obtained their certificates prior to August 1, 1991, are qualified to install, maintain and repair pumps, filters, chlorinators and piping incidental to a private swimming pool; provided, that the work is not subject to the regulation of the State Board of Health.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A swimming pool piping contractor is a contractor having the required financial means and having a qualifying agent as provided herein. Such qualifying agent shall have experience and skill gained by not less than one (1) year of experience, or its educational equivalent, or a combination of such experience and education, in installing swimming pool piping under the supervision of a plumbing contractor or a contractor making swimming pool piping installations. Such qualifying agent shall be qualified, examined, and certified to perform the functions within the scope of work of a swimming pool piping contractor as hereinafter provided. The scope of work of a swimming pool piping contractor shall permit such a contractor to install, maintain, repair, alter, or extend swimming pool piping systems including the pumps, filters, pool heaters and chlorinators incidental to swimming pools and involving the means of disposing of pool water. The scope of work in this classification shall not include the making of connections to any water supply to be used for human consumption or to sanitary or storm sewers nor shall the scope of work include the installation of any lawn sprinkler system. The swimming pool piping contractor shall have a qualifying agent at all times. A contractor holding a current, valid certificate of competency as a swimming pool piping contractor on the effective date of this section shall continue to be entitled to such certificate and to do, contract for, and take out any permits which might be required for the work of a swimming pool piping contractor.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A gas fitting contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend fuel gas piping or appliances, including wall and central heating units, in any building or structure or on any premises, public or private, including liquefied petroleum gas piping and appliances, if such contractor qualified, in addition, under State law. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a master gas-fitter.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Swimming pool maintenance contractor (limited) is a contractor qualified and certified to do any or all of the following, including, but not limited to, maintaining and treating the water in existing swimming pools, both public and private, making minor repairs to existing pool masonry such as patching cracks in pool bottoms and walls, repainting or resurfacing the walls and bottoms of pools, performing preventive maintenance and replacing existing equipment and appurtenances thereof of swimming pools, such as pumps, valves, filters and chlorinators; provided, such a contractor may only replace existing equipment and appurtenances in private pools of single-family residences.<section>As an additional prerequisite to qualifying as a swimming pool maintenance contractor, the qualifying agent of the contractor must possess a current swimming pool operators certificate issued by the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health, and must furnish proof satisfactory that he has been actively engaged as a trainee for a licensed swimming pool maintenance contractor in swimming pool maintenance work for a period of two (2) years. All persons or firms holding a current certificate of competency as a swimming pool maintenance contractor as of November 1, 1965, shall be automatically classified as a swimming pool maintenance contractor (limited) for renewal purposes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Swimming pool maintenance contractor (unlimited) is a contractor qualified and certified to do the work of a swimming pool maintenance contractor (limited) and is covered by the same definition except that the swimming pool maintenance contractor (unlimited) shall be able to carry on all such work in connection with both private and public pools.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A pool maintenance contractor is not permitted to do any other plumbing, electrical, or mechanical work as covered by the Florida Building Code, or to do any of the original construction on installation in a new pool.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All employees of Swimming Pool Maintenance Contractors both limited and unlimited who are engaged in the cleaning and treatment of water in existing swimming pools shall possess a current swimming pool operator's certificate.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Certification under this Chapter is not required for individuals who are solely engaged in the cleaning and treatment of water in existing swimming pools. All such individuals shall be required to register with the Department on a form adopted by the Department. As a precondition for registration, individuals engaged in the cleaning and treatment of water in swimming pools shall:<section prefix='1.'>Maintain at all times with an insurance company authorized to do business in the State of Florida public liability insurance with limits of liability not less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per accident or occurrence for bodily injury and twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) per accident for property damage. The insurance shall provide by endorsement of the policy that the Insurer shall notify the Department by certified or registered mail of the intent to cancel the policy for any reason, at least thirty (30) days prior to such cancellation.</section><section prefix='2.'>Possess a current swimming pool operator's certificate.</section><section prefix='3.'>Identify all trucks used in the furtherance of their business by use in the transporting of materials, equipment or employees to a job site, excepting a truck owned by an employee which truck is only used for private transportation or in carrying employees' personal tools and personal equipment necessary to fulfill their job tasks, by placing on the sides thereof, in a permanent manner, identification, by name or symbol, and their registration number, in letters and numerals not less than three (3) inches in height, excepting those trucks rented or leased by a contractor from a commercial vehicle rental agency for a period of less than one (1) month and such trucks are plainly marked with the name of the lessor in letters and numerals not less than three (3) inches in height.</section><section>All registrations shall be valid for one year and shall expire on the last day of September. Annual renewal shall include verification of continued qualification for certification exemption. A registration fee of sixty dollars ($60.00) shall be assessed at initial registration and renewal.</section></section></section><section prefix='(6)'>A lawn sprinkler contractor is a contractor, having the financial means and who has a qualifying agent with one (1) year experience in the lawn sprinkler trade, and qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend a lawn sprinkling system and appliances and devices used in connection with such systems, except that such systems shall not include the drilling of wells or the connecting of such systems to potable water. Sprinkler and irrigation systems used for agricultural purposes shall not be included within the scope of this subsection.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Maintenance plumber is a person qualified and certified by examination to maintain plumbing installations. The work of the maintenance plumber shall be confined to maintenance repairs involving only the working parts of a faucet or valve, the clearance of stoppages, repairing of leaks and the replacement of defective faucets or valves contained and used upon the premises or building owned, occupied or otherwise controlled by the person, firm or corporation by whom the maintenance plumber is regularly employed. Maintenance plumbers' work shall not include the cutting into, connecting to or extension of potable water lines, or drain waste and vent systems. A certified master or journeyman plumber shall automatically qualify as a maintenance plumber.</section></section><section>VI. ELECTRICAL CONTRACTOR</section><section>The scope of work of an electrical contractor shall be as defined in the various contractor classifications listed herein.<section prefix='(A)'>An electrical contractor is a contractor whose principal contracting business consists of the execution of contracts requiring the experience, financial means, knowledge and skill to install, repair, alter, add to or change any electrical wires, fixtures, appliances, apparatus, raceways, conduit or any part thereof, which generates, transmits, transforms or utilizes electrical energy in any form for light, heat, power or communications including the electrical installations and systems within plants and substations, all in such manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable and his scope of work shall include that of a room air-conditioning contractor, installation only. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a master electrician. The scope of such contractor's work shall apply to private and public property and shall include any excavation and paving work incidental thereto, and shall include the work of all specialty electrical contractors. Such contractors shall subcontract with a qualified contractor in the field concerned, all other work incidental to the work, but which is specified herein as being the work of a trade other than that of an electrical contractor.</section><section prefix='(B)'>A specialty electrical contractor is a contractor who specializes in one (1) or more of the following crafts and whose scope of work is so limited under his certificate of competency. Such contractor's principal contracting business is the execution of contracts requiring the financial means to engage in the business of the particular electrical specialty concerned, in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a specialty electrical master in the specialty field concerned and shall subcontract with a qualified contractor in the field concerned, all other work incidental thereto, but which is specified herein as being the work of a trade other than that of the electrical specialty for which he is certified. The following are the various crafts of specialty electrical contractors.<section prefix='(1)'>An electrical sign contractor is a contractor, qualified and certified to install, repair, alter, add to or change any electrical wires, apparatus, raceways, conduit or any part thereof, on electrical signs. Such contractor may connect to an existing sign circuit, beyond the last overcurrent device, and may contract for and take out building permits for the erection of signs.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A utility electrical contractor is a contractor, qualified and certified to install, repair, alter, add to or change any electrical wires, apparatus, raceways, conduit, or any part thereof, on underground or overhead electric utilities transmission and distribution lines or distribution systems including such distribution work within power plants and sub-stations. The scope of work in this classification shall be limited to the work directly involved in performing contract work for the construction of electric utility distribution systems and shall include any excavation and paving work incidental thereto. All other personnel employed by a utility electrical contractor shall be exempt from the requirements of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A burglar alarm specialty electrical contractor is a contractor qualified to install, repair, alter, add to or change any system electrically energized, in whole or in part, for the detection, prevention or control of burglary. The scope of these systems shall include conductors and raceways, radio frequency carriers, laser beams, light beams, sonic beams, and any other means of signal transmissions, as well as all apparatus pertaining to burglar alarm systems. A burglar alarm specialty electrical contractor may connect to an existing separate circuit of approved capacity, which is terminated in an approved outlet, junction box, or fused disconnect switch within six (6) feet of the equipment to be energized. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a burglar alarm master. Also burglar alarm journeymen are required in this trade.<section>Prior to the issuance of a certificate of competency to such a master or journeyman, the issuing authority will have obtained from the Miami-Dade Police Department the following: (1) a clearance based upon a check of the files of that department to the effect those files reflect that the applicant has never been convicted of a felony and has not within the preceding five (5) years been convicted of any criminal offense involving dishonesty or a breach of trust; and (2) confirmation that the Department has fingerprinted the applicant. Such a master or journeyman shall carry at all times during which he is engaged in the contractor's business an identification card issued by the contractor which card will contain the date of issue, a recent photograph of applicant, the applicant's name and title, physical description, signature and right thumbprint. Such identification card will also bear the name, address, and telephone number of the employing contractor together with the signature and title of the appropriate supervisor representing the contractor.</section><section prefix='(a)'>A contractor holding a current, valid certificate of competency as a burglar alarm specialty electrical contractor on the effective date of this section shall continue to be entitled to do, contract for, and take out any permits which might be required, for the work of a burglar alarm specialty contractor.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any master burglar alarm technician holding a current, valid certificate of competency on the effective date of this section shall be considered a burglar alarm master without requirement for further examination and when such certificate as a master burglar alarm technician expires and requires renewal, the new certificate, upon receipt of a proper renewal application, and fee, will bear the grade designation of "burglar alarm master."</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any burglar alarm installer holding a current, valid certificate of competency on the effective date of this section shall be considered a burglar alarm journeyman without requirement for any further examination and when such certificate as a burglar alarm, installer expires and requires renewal, the new certificate, upon the receipt of a proper renewal application and fee, will indicate the holder to be a "burglar alarm journeyman."</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>A fire alarm contractor is a specialty electrical contractor qualified and certified to install, repair, alter, add to or change any system, electrically energized, in whole or in part, for the detection, prevention or control of fire, noxious gases, liquids or atomic radiation. The scope of these systems shall include conductors and raceways, radio frequency carriers, laser beams, light beams, sonic beams, and any other means of signal transmissions as well as all apparatus pertaining to fire alarm systems. A fire alarm specialty electrical contractor may connect to an existing separate circuit, of approved capacity, which is terminated in an approved outlet, junction box, or fused disconnect switch within six (6) feet of the equipment to be energized. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a fire alarm master. Also fire alarm journeymen are required in this trade.<section prefix='(a)'>A contractor holding a current, valid certificate of competency as a fire alarm specialty electrical contractor on the effective date of this section shall continue to be entitled to do, contract for, and take out any permits which might be required, for the work of a fire alarm specialty contractor.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A master fire alarm technician holding a current, valid certificate of competency on the effective date of this section shall be considered a fire alarm master without requirement for further examination and when such certificates as a master fire alarm technician expire and require renewal, the new certificate, upon the receipt of the proper renewal application and fee, will bear the trade designation of a "fire alarm master."</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any fire alarm installer holding a current, valid certificate of competency on the effective date of this section shall be considered a fire alarm journeyman without requirement for further examination and when such certificates as a fire alarm installer expire and require renewal, the certificate, upon the receipt of a proper renewal application and fee, will indicate the holder to be a "fire alarm journeyman."</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any County ordinance, rule or regulation which conflicts with this subsection (B)(4) is hereby repealed.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>A low voltage specialty electrical contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to install, fabricate, erect, repair, alter, add to or change any electrical wiring, fixtures, appliances, thermostats, apparatus, raceways and conduit, or any part thereof, not to exceed seventy-seven (77) volts, which generates, transmits, transforms or utilizes electrical energy, when those items are for the purpose of transmitting any form of light, heat or communications, including, but not limited to, telephone, radio, computer and data. A low voltage specialty electrical contractor may connect to an existing separate circuit of approved capacity, which is terminated in an approved outlet, junction box or fused disconnect within six (6) feet of the equipment to be energized. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a master low voltage technician as defined below. The scope of the work of such a contractor shall not include the work of burglar alarm and fire alarm specialty electrical contractors.<section prefix='(a)'>Master low voltage technician shall mean any person who possesses the required skill, knowledge and experience as evidenced by two (2) years as a mechanic, supervisor or manager, or educational equivalent thereto, in the low voltage specialty electrical contractor trade. He shall possess a valid certificate of competency as a master technician.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any sound and intercom specialty electrical contractor or master sound and intercom technician who holds a valid certificate of competency as of the date of adoption of this ordinance shall be issued a certificate of competency as a low voltage specialty electrical contractor or master low voltage technician respectively without requirement for further qualifications under this category provided an application requesting such contractor or technician certification or license renewal form is filed with the department by December 31, 1997.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any person who applies for certification as a low voltage specialty electrical contractor prior to and including December 31, 1997, shall be entitled to take the certification examination if he or she has been engaged in the business of installating communications wiring or systems during any part of the twelve-month period preceding the date of adoption of this ordinance and obtains a temporary certificate as a low voltage specialty electrical contractor by June 30, 1997. Evidence that the applicant for a temporary certificate has been engaged in the business of installing communications wiring or systems shall be demonstrated by submittal of an affidavit documenting the applicant's work history and experience, letters of reference, copies of occupational and other government issued licenses and a representative list of contracts completed in the last twelve-month period. The list shall include the description of each job, location, owner and general contractor, if applicable. After obtaining the temporary certificate, the applicant must receive his initial certification as a low voltage specialty electrical contractor by December 31, 1998.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any person or business entity that was engaged in the business of installing communications wiring or systems on or before January 1, 1984 shall be issued a certificate of competency as a master low voltage technician or low voltage specialty electrical contractor respectively without requirement for further qualifications under this category provided an application requesting such technician or contractor certification is filed with the department by December 31, 1997. Evidence that the applicant was engaged in the business of installing communications wiring or systems shall be demonstrated by submittal of an affidavit documenting the applicant's work history and experience, copies of occupational and other government issued licenses and a representative list of contracts, if available. The list shall include the description of each job, location, owner and general contractor, if applicable.</section></section></section><section prefix='(6)'>A master TV antenna specialty electrical contractor is a contractor qualified and certified to install, repair, alter, add to or change any privately owned TV antenna systems on and in multiple occupancy, residential or commercial buildings of three (3) or more tenants, rooms or apartments all connected to a central master system, as well as in theaters, schools and like public occupancies. Such systems may be electrically energized in whole or in part for the reception, amplification and distribution of TV signals. The scope of these systems shall include conductors and raceways, radio frequency carriers, laser beams and any other means of signal transmission as well as all apparatus pertaining to master TV antenna systems, including, but not limited to, amplifiers, splitters, cables and outlets for connecting individual TV sets. A master TV antenna specialty electrical contractor may connect to an existing separate circuit of approved capacity, which is terminated to an approved outlet, junction box, or fused disconnect switch within six (6) feet of the equipment to be energized. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a master TV antenna master technician as defined below.<section prefix='(a)'>A master TV antenna technician shall mean any person who possesses the required skill, knowledge and experience as evidenced by one (1) year's experience as a mechanic, or supervisory or managerial experience or education equivalent thereto in the master TV antenna specialty electrical field as defined for master TV antenna specialty electrical contractor and who has passed a designated examination. He shall possess a valid certificate of competency as a master technician.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Maintenance electrician is a person qualified and certified by examination to maintain electrical installations. A maintenance electrician can perform or supervise the work of other personnel under a premise permit providing that such work shall be confined to the repair of existing branch circuits, fixtures, apparatus or equipment connected thereto, and shall include the relocation of existing branch circuits and the switching and de-energizing of existing facilities for safety purposes, contained and used upon the premises or building, owned, occupied or otherwise controlled by the person, firm or corporation by whom the maintenance electrician is regularly employed. The maintenance electrician's work shall not include the installation, alteration or replacement of service equipment or any feeder to any center or centers of service equipment. A certified master or journeyman electrician shall automatically qualify as maintenance electrician.</section></section><section>VII. MECHANICAL CONTRACTOR</section><section>The scope of work of a mechanical contractor is as defined in the various contractor classification listed hereinafter.<section prefix='(A)'>A general mechanical contractor is a contractor whose contracting business consists of the execution of contracts requiring the experience, financial means, knowledge and skill to perform the following: install, maintain, repair, alter or extend air conditioning, refrigeration, heating, ventilating, boiler and unfired pressure vessel systems, and all appurtenances, apparatus or equipment used in connection therewith; also, piping, duct work, insulation of pipes, vessels and ducts, pressure and process piping, installation of chilled water lines and related work incidental thereto, pneumatic control piping, gasoline tank and pump installations, piping for gasoline tank and pump installations, fire sprinkler systems and standpipes, air piping, vacuum line piping, oxygen lines, nitrous oxide piping, ink and chemical lines, fuel transmission lines, mechanical sections of sewage disposal and water treatment plants and installing a condensate drain from an air conditioning unit to an existing safe waste or other approved disposal other than a direct connection to a sanitary system, all in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable. Such contractor shall have as qualifying agent a general mechanical master. The scope of work of such contractor shall also include any excavation work incidental thereto, but shall not include any work specified in this chapter as being the work of any other trade or contractor, such as but not limited to liquefied petroleum or natural gas fuel lines within buildings, potable water lines, or connections thereto, sanitary sewer lines, swimming pool piping and filters and electrical work. The scope of the work of such a contractor shall also include the work of a specialty mechanical contractor, except for elevator and transporting assembly installations; and if there is work incidental to such contractor's authorized scope of work to be performed pursuant to contract for which such contractor does not hold a certificate of competency, such work shall be subcontracted to a qualified contractor in the trade concerned.</section><section prefix='(B)'>A specialty mechanical contractor is a contractor who specializes in one (1) or more of the following crafts and whose scope of work is so limited under his certificate of competency. Such a contractor shall have as a qualifying agent a specialty mechanical master in the field concerned. Such contractor's business is to consist of the execution of contracts requiring the experience, financial means, knowledge and skill to engage in the business of the particular mechanical specialty concerned, in such a manner as to comply with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable. The scope of work of any specialty mechanical contractor shall also include any excavation work incidental thereto but shall not include any work specified in this chapter as being work of any other trade or contractor, such as, but not limited to, electrical work, liquefied petroleum, or natural gas fuel lines within buildings, or potable water lines, or connections thereto, and sanitary sewer lines and swimming pool piping and filters. If there is work incidental to such contractor's authorized scope of work to be performed pursuant to contract for which such contractor does not hold a certificate of competency, such work shall be subcontracted to a qualified contractor in the trade concerned. The following are the various crafts of specialty mechanical contractors.<section prefix='(1)'>A refrigeration and air conditioning contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, repair, alter, add to or change any system of refrigeration, air conditioning, heating and ventilating, unlimited in horsepower or tons, including any or all duct systems necessary to make complete a refrigeration or air conditioning system and including the installation of a condensate drain from an air conditioning unit to an existing safe waste or other approved disposal other than a direct connection to a sanitary disposal system; provided, however, ammonia refrigeration, boilers or unfired vessels shall not be a part of the scope of such work.</section><section prefix='(2)'>An air conditioning contractor (unlimited) is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, repair, alter, add to or change any system of air conditioning, heating and ventilating, unlimited in horsepower or tons, including any or all duct systems necessary to make complete an air conditioning system and including the installation of a condensate drain from an air conditioning unit to an existing safe waste or other approved disposal other than a direct connection to a sanitary disposal system; provided that boilers or unfired pressure vessels shall not be a part of the scope of work.</section><section prefix='(3)'>An air conditioning contractor (limited) is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, repair, alter, or extend any system of air conditioning and warm air heating and ventilation in connection therewith, of a size not exceeding fifteen (15) tons in any type of building providing the total conditioning load in any common area does not exceed fifteen (15) tons, including any or all duct systems necessary to make complete an air conditioning system, and including the installation of a condensate drain from such an air conditioning unit to an existing safe waste or other approved disposal other than a direct connection to a sanitary disposal system; provided that boiler and unfired pressure vessels shall not be part of the scope of work. (Ord. No. 69-11, § 8, 2-4-69)</section><section prefix='(4)'>A room air conditioning contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, service and repair any air conditioning unit consisting of and limited to a package unit, completely self-contained, air-cooled, usually called a room unit and not to exceed three (3) tons and attached to electric power only by the method of a plug-in receptacle. This unit, factory wired and supported only by window or wall supports, shall not have any duct work attached or any method of air distribution other than the unit's factory installed grill; provided that installation of any condensate drain or drains to the outside of the unit is not included in this work. (Ord. No. 69-11, § 9, 2-4-69)</section><section prefix='(5)'>A refrigeration contractor (limited) is a mechanical contractor, qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair or alter any system of refrigeration not exceeding five (5) horsepower, self-contained or with remote compressor, where such refrigeration system is for the purpose of food preservation and/or processing, other than human-comfort refrigeration systems. The scope of work of a refrigeration contractor (limited) shall be limited to refrigeration systems using Group I refrigerants only.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A refrigeration contractor (unlimited) is a mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair or alter any system of refrigeration unlimited to tons or horsepower, provided, however, that such refrigeration is intended to be used for the purpose of food and product preservation and/or processing and is not to be used for comfort systems; and further provided that this scope of work does not include ammonia refrigeration systems.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A heating contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor, qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter, add to or change systems of heating, whether by water, steam or hot air furnaces and all appurtenances and duct work used in conjunction therewith.</section><section prefix='(8)'>A warm air heating contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair or alter a system of warm air furnace heating and all appliances and appurtenances in connection therewith, including duct work, vents and flue connections.</section><section prefix='(9)'>A steam generating boiler and boiler piping contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified to install, maintain, repair and service steam boilers and boiler piping, including the boiler auxiliary equipment, controls and steam actuated machinery such as, but not limited to, engines, pumps, prime movers, pressing machinery, and dryer rolls, but excluding comfort heating systems.</section><section prefix='(10)'>An ammonia refrigeration contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor, qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend any system of refrigeration using ammonia as a refrigerant including all appliances and appurtenances thereto.</section><section prefix='(11)'>A sheet metal contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to manufacture, assemble, cast, cut, shape, stamp, forge, fabricate, weld, repair, recondition, adjust and install sheet and rolled metal of any kind or combination and all other materials used in lieu thereof, and including all air-veyor systems and air handling systems regardless of materials used including all equipment and all reinforcements in connection therewith.</section><section prefix='(12)'>A pressure and process piping contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend any systems of piping, tubing, vessels, containers, pumps, apparatus, and appurtenances, in connection with such pressure piping used for circulation, transporting, holding or processing of any gas, vapor, fluid, liquid, semi-liquid or any combination thereof; provided, however, that boilers, boiler piping, as defined by the International Boiler and Pressure Vessel Code of the current edition of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, piping used to convey potable water, sanitary sewage, liquefied petroleum, manufactured or natural gas or refrigeration, air conditioning, and comfort heating piping shall not be a part of the scope of such work.</section><section prefix='(13)'>A pneumatic control piping contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend any system used for the purpose of controlling various instruments, valves, damper motors, controllers, and similar paraphernalia through pneumatic lines of size and strength required for the duty performed.</section><section prefix='(14)'>A gasoline tank and pump contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend any system used for storing and dispensing of gasoline, kerosene, diesel oils and similar liquid hydrocarbon fuels or mixtures to be used solely in connection with gasoline filling stations dispensing fuel to mobile vehicles or marine equipment; provided, however, bulk plants shall not be a part of the scope of such work.</section><section prefix='(15)'>A gas control installation contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair or extend gas metering, odorizing and gas pressure reduction stations.</section><section prefix='(16)'>An insulation contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend any insulation primarily installed to prevent loss or gain of heat from internal or external sources in pipes, vessels, ducts or in built-up refrigerated boxes or rooms, and such installations to include any protective coating thereof involved with insulation. (Ord. No. 69-11, § 10, 2-4-69)</section><section prefix='(17)'>A mechanical service and maintenance contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified on or before May 14, 1976, to repair and maintain, without alteration or addition, any system of air conditioning, heating, ventilating, boiler and unfired pressure vessels and apparatus and equipment in connection therewith. Such a contractor shall have as a qualifying agent one (1) who is qualified as a mechanical service and maintenance master in the field or fields of work enumerated herein and can only hold a certificate of competency as such a contractor in such field or fields for which such qualifying agent is approved. Only those contractors holding current, valid certificates of competency as mechanical service and maintenance contractors on or before May 14, 1976, shall be entitled to such certificates. No further mechanical service and maintenance contractor's certificates shall be issued, and mechanical service and maintenance work shall be done, other than as indicated above, by contractors certified and qualified as general mechanical contractors or by specialty mechanical contractors in the field or fields concerned. (Ord. No. 76-40, § 1, 5-4-76)</section><section prefix='(18)'>An elevator installation contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, repair, alter or extend any elevator, dumbwaiter or escalator; provided, however, transporting assemblies, as defined herein, shall not be a part of the scope of such work.</section><section prefix='(19)'>An elevator maintenance and service contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to maintain and service any elevator, dumbwaiter or escalator; provided, however, transporting assemblies, as defined herein, shall not be a part of the scope of such work.</section><section prefix='(20)'>A transporting assembly installation contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified and certified to install, maintain, alter and extend any Transporting Assemblies, as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(21)'>A transporting assembly maintenance and service contractor is a specialty mechanical contractor qualified to maintain and service Transporting Assemblies as defined herein.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Mechanical maintenance man is a person qualified and certified by examination to maintain mechanical installations. The work of a mechanical maintenance man shall be confined to repairing, maintaining, servicing of existing systems involving air conditioning, refrigeration, heating, ventilation and pressure and process piping contained and used upon the premises or building owned, occupied or otherwise controlled by the person, firm or corporation by whom the mechanical maintenance man is regularly employed. A certified mechanical master or journeyman shall automatically qualify as a mechanical maintenance man. (Ord. No. 69-64, § 5, 9-17-69; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</section></section><section>VIII. LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS INSTALLATION CONTRACTOR</section><section>The scope of work of a liquefied petroleum gas installation contractor is as defined in the various classifications listed hereinafter.<section prefix='(A)'>A liquefied petroleum gas installation contractor is a contractor whose contracting business consists of the execution of contracts requiring the experience, financial means, knowledge and skill to install, maintain, repair, alter, or extend liquefied petroleum gas piping appliances, gas mains, lines, laterals, tanks, regulators, meters and other appurtenances and paraphernalia in connection therewith, including wall and central heating units in any building or structure or on any premises, public or private; or who furnishes, delivers and sells the liquefied petroleum gas to the consumer for heat, light and power. Such contractor shall have as a qualifying agent an installer as defined in subsection (B) hereof. If there is work incidental to such contractor's scope of work to be performed pursuant to contractor for which such contractor does not hold a certificate of competency, such contractor shall sub-contract the same to a qualified contractor in the trade concerned.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Installer shall mean any person who possesses the required skill and knowledge gained by two (2) years' experience, and who has passed an examination, to perform the scope of work set forth hereinabove for a liquefied petroleum gas installation contractor. He shall possess a valid certificate of competency as an installer. (Ord. No. 69-11, § 11, 2-4-69)</section></section><section>IX. MASTER</section><section>The term shall mean any person to whom this Board has issued a current valid certificate of competency as a master in a trade after having passed a designated examination and having otherwise demonstrated to this Board that he or she possesses the required skill, knowledge and experience to plan, lay out, supervise and do the work in the trade. As a prerequisite to taking the examination, an applicant shall have held for not less than two (2) years this Board's certificate of competency as a journeyman and shall have at least two (2) years of prior field work experience. However, this Board may, in its discretion, accept in lieu of the journeyman certificate, satisfactory proof of (i) at least six (6) years of comprehensive, specialized training, education and field experience associated with the trade or (ii) registration as a professional engineer in the discipline concerned. "Field experience" is defined as experience gained at actual construction sites where the full spectrum of practical situations and problems arising in the trade are found; drafting, estimating, designing, other office work or maintenance or service installations do not satisfy the requirement.</section><section>In the plumbing, electrical and mechanical trades a contractor must be qualified by a master.</section><section>Masters are required to earn continuing education credit during each term the personal certificate of competency is valid as established in this chapter and as required by the Board through written rules or regulations commencing October 1, 1995. (Ord. No. 69-11,, 2-4-69; Ord. No. 80-77, § 1, 7-15-80; Ord. No. 95-46, § 1, 4-4-95)</section><section>X. JOURNEYMAN</section><section>The term shall mean any person who possesses the required skill, knowledge and experience, as evidenced by three (3) years' proven experience in the trade or craft, or education equivalent thereto, or a combination thereof, but not more than one-half (½) of such experience may be education equivalent, and who has passed an examination in his or her particular trade or craft and possesses a valid certificate of competency as a journeyman in such trade or craft. There shall be at least one (1) journeyman for every three (3) trainees on each construction or installation job site for which a permit is required, and which involves a trade in which journeyman are required and certified. It shall be the responsibility of the employing contractor, and the qualifying agent, to provide journeymen on each job site in accordance with this section, and failure to do so shall be a violation of this chapter, subject to the penalties provided herein, and provided under of this Code. In addition, any work in the trade concerned on any such job site wherein journeymen are not provided in accordance with this section shall be stopped by the enforcing agency or administrative agency concerned until journeymen are so provided. Further, any person working at a trade which requires journeymen on the job site where no journeyman or master in the trade concerned is present shall be in violation of this chapter and subject to the penalties provided herein, and provided under of this Code. A journeyman may only work in the employ of a contractor holding a certificate of competency in the field in which the journeyman is certified. Journeymen shall be required in the electrical, plumbing and mechanical trades.</section><section>Journeymen are required to earn continuing education credit during each term the personal certificate of competency is valid as established in this chapter and as required by the board through written rules or regulations commencing October 1, 1995. (Ord. No. 73-75, § 2, 9-18-73; Ord. No. 95-46, § 1, 4-4-95)</section><section>XI. TRAINEE</section><section>The term shall mean any person working on the job in the capacity of a learner, apprentice, helper, or improver who does not possess the skill, knowledge, experience or ability of a journeyman and does not possess a certificate of competency, but he can work at the grade on a job for which a permit is required only when a journeyman or a master is present at the particular job site concerned.</section><section>XII. MAINTENANCE PERSONNEL</section><section prefix='(a)'>The term maintenance personnel, other than as defined elsewhere in this section, shall mean all maintenance personnel who are regularly employed to maintain and make minor repairs to systems, apparatus, equipment or structures within the scope of work of any of the contractors defined in this section, where such systems, apparatus, equipment or structures are owned, occupied or controlled by the person, firm or corporation by whom such personnel are employed. Such maintenance personnel, when employed by the owner of a building or plant, must hold a certificate or certificates or competency for the particular maintenance work involved, or a certificate as a master or a journeyman in the grade in which they are engaged, except that such maintenance personnel regularly employed by a State, County or municipal franchised gas, electrical, water or communications utility firm shall be exempt from the requirement of being qualified and holding a certificate of competency for the doing of maintenance work in connection with the utility including the service of systems, apparatus, equipment, lines or meters in connection therewith owned or controlled by such utility company whether on public or private property. The word maintenance as used in the paragraph, is not intended to include operators of appliances, apparatus or equipment. The application of this paragraph shall not apply to employees of a State, County or municipal franchised public utility doing maintenance on the utility equipment or within the utility plant.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On certification that an individual has been regularly employed for a period of five (5) years prior to July 1, 1970, and submission of evidence of that five (5) years or more of experience and work as a building maintenanceman, maintenance plumber, maintenance electrician or mechanical maintenanceman by the employer or employers of the individual so employed and upon certification that he is employed by the holder of a premise permit, he shall, upon payment of the fee for the particular certificate or certificates of competency concerned, be issued the necessary maintenanceman certificate in the applicable trade or grades; provided application and certification shall be submitted prior to sixty (60) days from the effective date of this subsection; thereafter, maintenanceman certificates shall be issued only upon providing evidence of one (1) year of proven experience and passing a written examination.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Maintenancemen are required to earn continuing education credit during each term the personal certificate of competency is valid as established in this chapter and as required by the board through written rules or regulations commencing October 1, 1995. (Ord. No. 95-46, § 1, 4-4-95; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</section><section>XIII. AUTHORIZED EMPLOYEE CERTIFICATE OF COMPETENCY</section><section>Means the certificate issued by the Construction Trades Qualifying Board to any person who holds a current certificate of competency issued by the Construction Trades Qualifying Board or a State of Florida Certified Contractor and who does not hold himself or herself out for hire and who is an employee of a Miami-Dade County Department or Municipal Department while acting in accordance with the terms of their employment and as qualifying agent. The scope of work for the Authorized Employee Certificate of Competency shall be determined by the Construction Trades Qualifying Board or State of Florida Contractor license category(ies) held. All valid categories shall be reflected on the Authorized Employee Certificate of Competency. No additional examination shall be required.</section><section>Exception: Journeymen and Maintenancemen are ineligible.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-26, § 1, 3-4-08; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>