<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-20</section_number>
<catch_line>Construction Trades Qualifying Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002083</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-20. Construction Trades Qualifying Board.<section prefix='(A)'>Membership, appointment, qualifications, Secretary, compensation. There is hereby established a Construction Trades Qualifying Board consisting of twenty-seven (27) members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The membership shall be comprised of one (1) architect, one (1) registered engineer, and the qualifying agents of each of the following types of contractors holding a certificate of competency pursuant to this chapter issued by Division A or Division B of the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board: Four (4) general contractors, two (2) engineering contractors, three (3) electrical contractors, three (3) plumbing contractors, two (2) mechanical contractors, two (2) roofing contractors, one (1) contractor certified in both swimming pool piping and swimming pool maintenance (commercial) categories, one (1) liquefied petroleum installation contractor, one (1) swimming pool contractor, two (2) Building Specialty Contractors and four (4) members from the general public with each member to have one (1) vote. Those individuals appointed as alternate members of the Board and currently serving in that capacity on the effective date of Ordinance No. 75-75 shall automatically be appointed as regular members for the duration of the terms for which they were appointed as alternates. If a contractor having a Miami-Dade County certificate of competency at the time of his appointment fails to renew or maintain that certification, he will be disqualified from membership on the Board and a replacement appointed by the Board of County Commissioners. Any member of the Board on the effective date of Ordinance No. 83-105 who does not have a Miami-Dade County certificate of competency shall be permitted to remain on the Board until the expiration of his or her current term.</section><section>All members shall reside in and have principal places of business in Miami-Dade County. All members shall have been active in their respective professions or trades in the County for a minimum of ten (10) years but not necessarily a qualifying agent during all of said ten-year period.</section><section>The Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources shall serve as Secretary to the Board but shall have no vote. The Director shall be permitted to designate a staff member to serve in his stead and there shall be a Clerk to the Board appointed by the Secretary, but the Clerk shall have no vote.</section><section>Members of the Board shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties upon approval of the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Terms of office; vacancies.<section prefix='(1)'>The Board members shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years, or until their successors are appointed and qualified, except that the terms of the members of the first Board appointed and their alternates shall be staggered as provided in the County Commission resolution of appointment.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any member of the Board may be removed from office by a majority vote of the entire County Commission.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any vacancy occurring during the unexpired term of office of any Board member shall be filled by the County Commission for the unexpired term within thirty (30) days after such vacancy occurs.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Organization of Board.<section prefix='(1)'>The Board shall elect a Chairman and Vice-Chairman and such other officers as may be necessary from among its members. Terms of all offices shall be for one (1) year.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Board shall be divided into Division A and Division B, as follows, for the purposes hereinafter provided:<section prefix='(a)'>Division A to consist of the three (3) general contractors, two (2) engineering contractors, one (1) architect, and two (2) roofing contractors, one (1) registered engineer, one (1) swimming pool contractor, two (2) Building Specialty Contractors and two (2) members from the general public.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Division B to consist of the three (3) electrical contractors, three (3) plumbing contractors, two (2) mechanical contractors, one (1) liquefied petroleum installation contractor, one (1) swimming pool piping and maintenance (commercial) contractor, one (1) general contractor and two (2) members from the general public.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each division shall elect a Chairman and Vice-Chairman and such other officers as may be necessary from among its members. Terms of all officers shall be for one (1) year. The Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources shall serve as Secretary for each division but shall have no vote. The Director shall be permitted to designate a staff member to serve in his stead.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Probable cause panels. The Chairman of each division shall appoint probable cause panels consisting of two (2) members of the division plus one (1) alternate, each of whom represents a different trade or profession than the others. Probable cause panels shall hold meetings open to the public to determine, as to each complaint which comes before the divisions, whether probable cause exists for the division or disciplinary action panel to hold a disciplinary hearing under Section 10-15. Probable cause shall be determined by an affirmative decision of both panel members. The terms of all panel members shall be one (1) year. Panel members may be reappointed.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Disciplinary action panels. The Chairman of the Board shall appoint disciplinary action panels consisting of three (3) members of one (1) or both divisions plus one (1) alternate, each of whom represents a different trade or profession than the others. Members who served in the probable cause panel shall not be eligible for service in the disciplinary action panel for the same case. One (1) member of the panel must possess a certificate of competency in the same trade as the contractor that is the subject of the disciplinary hearing before the panel. If the contractor that is the subject of the disciplinary hearing possesses more than one (1) certificate of competency then at least one (1) panel member must possess a certificate in one (1) of the trades in which the contractor was engaged in on one (1) or more of the jobs on which contractor committed violation(s) which are the subject of the disciplinary hearing.<section>Disciplinary action panels are empowered to conduct disciplinary hearings under on behalf of the divisions. A majority vote of the panel members present and voting shall be required to make a decision of guilty in any disciplinary hearing. The terms of all panel members shall be one (1) year. Panel members may be reappointed.</section><section>The Board by rule shall determine when a disciplinary hearing should be presented to a Disciplinary Action Panel or a division of the Board. The determination should be made based in part on the following criteria:</section><section prefix='a.'>The number and severity of the alleged complaint.</section><section prefix='b.'>The number of cases pending resolution before the division of the Board.</section><section prefix='c.'>The complexity of the case.</section></section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Meetings.<section prefix='(1)'>The Board shall hold not less than one (1) regular meeting each year and the divisions shall hold not less than four (4) regular meetings each fiscal year, one (1) in July, one (1) in October, one (1) in January, and one (1) in April. Probable cause panels shall meet as necessary. Disciplinary action panels shall meet as required by the Board upon a majority vote of the members present.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Meetings shall be called by the Chairman of the Board and in his absence by the Vice-Chairman of the Board or may be called by the Secretary.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All minutes of Board meetings shall be public records, except those portions which are of a confidential nature, such as, but not limited to, credit reports, financial statements, and communications received by the Board in respect to the applicant's qualifications. Examination questions and answers shall not constitute public records and are declared to be of a confidential nature, but any applicant may upon written request be permitted to examine his examination answers in the presence of the Board's Secretary, but shall not be entitled to remove or copy the same, except upon written consent of the Secretary. All minutes and records shall be kept in the office of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources, or in such other location as the Director of that Department may designate.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A majority of the appointed members of the Board shall constitute a quorum at any meeting. A majority vote of those present and voting shall be required to make any decision.</section></section><section prefix='(E)'>Additional employees in enforcement. For the purpose of administering this chapter, the Board may call upon the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources and Public Works and Waste Management Department to furnish such employees as may be necessary to assist the Board in performing its duties. It shall be the duty of such employees to enforce the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Promulgating rules; examining witnesses. The Board may make such rules and regulations consistent with the general policies of this chapter as it may deem necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter, such rules and regulations altering provisions contained in this chapter shall be subject to the approval of the Board of County Commissioners, and may administer oaths and subpoena witnesses in the manner provided for in the County Court. Any person, firm or corporation that fails to appear in answer to a subpoena issued by the Construction Trades Qualifying Board, one (1) of the divisions thereof or a disciplinary action panel and issued over the signature of the Secretary of the Board and the Clerk of the Board, or their designee(s), shall be guilty of a violation of this section, punishable by a fine of up to five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment for not more than sixty (60) days, or both.</section><section prefix='(G)'>Authority concerning applicants, etc. The Construction Trades Qualifying Board, in addition to the other authority granted to it by this chapter, shall determine if an applicant for any type of certificate meets the qualifications provided by this chapter for the particular type of certificate applied for, save and except it shall not have authority to prepare, give or grade examinations. In addition, the Board shall be empowered to decide questions of definition and interpretation of the scope of work of the various contractors, masters and journeymen, and other tradesmen covered by this chapter, and the Board shall, from time to time, make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners for amendment or modification of this chapter as may be deemed necessary. The Board shall, at the request of the Director of Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources, or the Director of the Public Works and Waste Management Department, act in an advisory capacity in the formulation and updating of examinations.</section><section prefix='(H)'>Powers, duties, quorum and vote of the divisions and disciplinary action panels. The Board may interpret the provisions of this chapter to cover a special case if it appears that the provisions do not definitely cover the point raised, or that the intent of the provision is not clear, or that ambiguity exists in the wording; but it shall have no authority to grant variances where this chapter is clear and specific. The Board shall act through its divisions except as otherwise provided in exercising all of the powers, duties and authority herein granted to it in regard to the review and denial or approval of applicants for examination, certificates of competency and eligibility, and in regard to disciplinary action, and in the exercise of such powers, duties and authority, the divisions, shall be subject to all of the provisions, prerequisites, standards and procedures applicable thereto as established herein. In exercising such powers, duties and authority, Division A shall have jurisdiction over all building and engineering categories except in conducting disciplinary hearings and Division B shall have jurisdiction over all plumbing, electrical, mechanical and liquefied petroleum gas categories except in conducting disciplinary hearings. A simple majority of the membership of each Division in office shall be necessary to constitute a quorum. All actions shall require the affirmative vote of a majority of the members present and voting.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-25, § 17.11(H)(7), 11-12-57; Ord. No. 58-44, § 1, 12-9-58; Ord. No. 59-41, 11-3-59; Ord. No. 64-52, §§ 1, 2, 10-6-64; Ord. No. 64-59, §§ 22—30, 11-24-64; Ord. No. 67-34, § 3, 5-16-67; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 71-69, §§ 4, 5, 8-31-71; Ord. No. 75-75, § 1, 9-17-75; Ord. No. 83-105, § 1, 11-15-83; Ord. No. 84-20, § 1, 3-6-84; Ord. No. 87-28, § 1, 5-19-87; Ord. No. 87-71, § 1, 10-20-87; Ord. No. 94-05, § 1, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-188, § 1, 10-17-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 6, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-10, § 1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 07-44, § 1, 3-6-07; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13; Ord. No. 13-86, § 1, 9-17-13)</history></law>