<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-32</section_number>
<catch_line>Exemptions for motion picture, television producers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002097</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-32. Exemptions for motion picture, television producers.<section>This chapter does not apply to any fabrication, construction, maintenance, operation, improvement, assembly, disassembly or repair of props, temporary structures, sets, portable or temporary lighting and recording equipment and other portable or temporary devices and equipment used in motion picture or television production, or in connection therewith; provided the same are for the use of the producer only and the work is performed by the producer's employees; and provided further, that such temporary structures or sets will be disassembled and removed when the same are no longer required by the producer as a production set, or within six (6) months after their assembly or construction, whichever occurs first, provided such six-month period may be extended for a reasonable time by the Building Official of the jurisdiction and Regulation upon the showing that the same are still needed for further production and it is determined by such Building Official, after inspection, that the same have not become a nuisance, or detrimental to the public health, welfare, safety and morals; provided further, however, that in the event of a hurricane alert such structures and sets which are not erected within a permanent building shall be immediately disassembled and removed or adequately secured to prevent injury or damage to life and property.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 66-22, ยง 1, 5-17-66; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 6, 9-3-98)</history></law>