<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BIDDING ON PUBLIC PROJECTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-35</section_number>
<catch_line>Releases of claim by subcontractors required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002104</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-35. Releases of claim by subcontractors required.<section>Before any prime contractor can receive any draw, except the first draw, for moneys due it as a result of a percentage of the work completed, it must pay all first-tier subcontractors and all direct suppliers of the prime contractor who have performed any work or supplied any materials directly to the prime contractor for the project as of that date their proportionate share of all previous draws and must provide the County's Project Manager with duly executed affidavits (subcontractor's statement of satisfaction) or releases of claim from all first-tier subcontractors and direct suppliers to the prime contractor who have performed any work or supplied any materials for the project as of that date, stating that said subcontractors and suppliers have been paid their proportionate share of all previous draws. In the event such affidavits cannot be furnished, the contractor may submit an executed consent of surety to requisition payment, identifying the subcontractors and suppliers, and the amounts for which the statement of satisfaction cannot be furnished. The contractor's failure to provide a consent of surety to requisition payment will result in the amount in dispute being withheld until (1) the statement of satisfaction is furnished, or (2) consent of surety to requisition payment is furnished.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-23, ยง 2, 4-4-78; Ord. No. 84-11, ยง 1, 2-7-84; Ord. No. 86-6, ยง 1, 2-4-86; Ord. No. 88-13, ยง 1, 3-1-88)</history></law>