<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-33.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Required provisions and disclosures in contracts for residential repair, alteration, addition or remodeling of a residential structure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002099</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-33.1. Required provisions and disclosures in contracts for residential repair, alteration, addition or remodeling of a residential structure.<section prefix='(a)'>In all contracts for the repair, alteration, addition or remodeling of a residential structure of Group R occupancy within Miami-Dade County, which contracts exceed the sum of $5,000.00 and which involve work for which permits must be obtained, the contractor shall include in the contract in bold capitalized letters of at least 12-point type the following provisions and disclosures in substantially the form described below:<section prefix='(i)'>YOU ARE ADVISED THAT THE COUNTY CONSTRUCTION TRADES QUALIFYING BOARD AND THE BUILDING AND ZONING DEPARTMENT OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, AND THE STATE OF FLORIDA DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS AND PROFESSIONAL REGULATION MAY HAVE INFORMATION ON FILE CONCERNING THE FINANCIAL RESPONSIBILITY AND ANY COMPLAINTS AND INVESTIGATIONS PERTAINING TO THE WORK OF THIS CONTRACTOR. THE PUBLIC RECORDS OF THE COUNTY ARE AVAILABLE FOR INSPECTION AND COPYING.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>YOU ARE ALSO ADVISED THAT THIS CONTRACTOR HAS PUBLIC LIABILITY INSURANCE AND WORKERS COMPENSATION INSURANCE THROUGH [NAME OF INSURERS] UNDER POLICY NUMBERS [NUMBERS], WITH EXPIRATION DATES OF [DATES] AND LIMITS OF LIABILITY IN THE AMOUNTS OF [NUMBERS].</section><section prefix='(iii)'>YOU ARE ADVISED THAT IN ORDER TO PROTECT YOURSELF, YOU MAY REQUEST THAT THIS CONTRACT ALLOW FOR PAYMENTS TO THE CONTRACTOR TO BE CONDITIONED UPON THE CONTRACTOR OBTAINING AND PASSING MANDATORY INSPECTIONS.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>YOU ARE ADVISED THAT YOU MAY PAY THE COST OF PURCHASING A CONTRACTOR'S PAYMENT BOND OR OTHER SECURITY, TO COVER PAYMENTS TO SUBCONTRACTORS AND MATERIAL SUPPLIERS, IN THE EVENT THIS CONTRACTOR FAILS TO DO SO, A COPY OF THOSE DOCUMENTS WHICH PROTECT YOU WILL BE FURNISHED UPON REQUEST, IF YOU SO WISH TO PURCHASE SUCH PROTECTION.</section><section prefix='(v)'>YOU ARE ADVISED THAT IN ORDER TO PROTECT YOURSELF, YOU MAY REQUEST THAT THIS CONTRACT CONTAIN A WORK COMPLETION DATE, IN THE ABSENCE OF A COMPLETION DATE, YOU MAY REQUEST THAT INTERIM MILESTONES OR TIME PERIODS BE ESTABLISHED FOR COMPLETION OF PORTIONS OF THE WORK.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>WITH LIMITED EXCEPTIONS PROVIDED BY LAW, THE WORK YOU ARE CONTRACTING FOR MUST BE PERFORMED BY A STATE OF FLORIDA CERTIFIED CONTRACTOR OR A MIAMI COUNTY CERTIFIED CONTRACTOR WHO IS ALSO REGISTERED WITH THE STATE.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>YOU ARE FURTHER ADVISED THAT IF, AFTER OBTAINING A PERMIT FOR THE WORK, YOUR CONTRACTOR TERMINATES THIS PROJECT WITHOUT JUST CAUSE OR FAILS TO PERFORM WORK WITHOUT JUST CAUSE FOR 30 CONSECUTIVE DAYS, THE PROJECT MAY BE CONSIDERED ABANDONED. ABANDONMENT CONSTITUTES A PENALTY FOR WHICH A CONTRACTOR MAY BE DISCIPLINED BY THE STATE OR BY THE COUNTY.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-188, ยง 3, 10-17-95; Ord. No. 13-08, ยง 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>