<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Persons without certificates representing selves as contractors; identification of vehicles.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002061</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-4. Persons without certificates representing selves as contractors; identification of vehicles.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person, firm or corporation not possessing a current certificate of competency and advertising in any newspaper, airwave transmission, phone directory or other advertising media or who issues any card, advertising or device indicating to the public that he is a contractor, or is qualified to engage in the business as a contractor, or who holds himself out as a contractor as plaintiff or defendant in any court of this State, is in violation of, and shall be subject to the provisions and penalties of, this chapter; and a certified copy of such court record or a copy of such newspaper, telephone directory, or other advertising making such assertion shall be prima facie evidence in court, or in any other proceeding authorized by this chapter, that the person is purported to have the capacity to act as a contractor.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Contractors conducting their contracting business within Miami-Dade County shall identify all trucks used in the furtherance of their business by use in the transporting of materials, equipment or employees to a job site, excepting a truck owned by an employee which truck is only used for private transportation or in carrying employees' personal tools and personal equipment necessary to fulfill their job tasks, by placing on the sides thereof, in a permanent manner, identification of contractor, by name or symbol, and their certificate number, in letters and numerals not less than three (3) inches in height, excepting those trucks rented or leased by a contractor from a commercial vehicle rental agency for a period of less than one (1) month and such trucks are plainly marked with the name of the lessor in letters and numerals not less than three (3) inches in height.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Anyone who advertises in any newspaper, airwave transmission, telephone directory, handbill, or other advertising medium for contracting to do any work covered by the provisions of this chapter shall include in all such advertising the permanent certificate of competency number from the certificate of competency required as a prerequisite under the provisions of this chapter. Failure to include this permanent certificate of competency number in all such advertising as evidenced by a copy or transcript of the subject advertisement shall constitute a violation of the chapter subject to the penalties provided herein and under Section 1-5 of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-41, 11-3-59; Ord. No. 64-59, § 4, 11-24-64; Ord. No. 65-79, § 3, 12-22-65; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 73-75, § 3, 9-18-73; Ord. No. 75-74, § 1, 9-17-75; Ord. No. 76-2, § 1, 1-6-76; Ord. No. 80-78, § 1, 7-15-80; Ord. No. 87-71, § 1, 10-20-87; Ord. No. 95-186, § 2, 10-17-95)</history></law>