<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Qualifications for obtaining permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002063</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-5. Qualifications for obtaining permits.<section prefix='(a)'>Applications for permits will be accepted only from contractors holding a current certificate of competency and license in their respective fields and against whom no revocation or suspension is pending; or fines and fees imposed by the Board or a division thereof, a hearing officer under Chapter 8CC of this Code, or a Civil or Criminal Court Judge relating to his work as a contractor remain unpaid, except as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>The owner or lessee or tenant of a property may make application for permit and supervise and do the work in connection with the erection of a new one-story building, other than a single-family or duplex residence, not exceeding five hundred (500) square feet in area, or a first-story addition not exceeding five hundred (500) square feet in area, or make maintenance repairs and nonstructural alterations to any building owned, leased or occupied by the applicant, provided the cost of repairs does not exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00). He shall obtain all required permits for such work, and as a prerequisite to obtaining permits, he shall satisfy the Building Official that he has the ability and knowledge of the Florida Building Code to do such work in the trades involved.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A sole owner may make application for permit, supervise and do the work in connection with the construction, maintenance, repair, alteration and addition to a single-family or duplex residence for his own use and occupancy and not intended for sale. He shall obtain all required permits for such work, and as a prerequisite to obtaining permits, he shall satisfy the Building Official that he has the ability and knowledge of the Florida Building Code to do such work in the trades involved.<section>A sole owner, may in addition, personally install, repair, alter, or add to the plumbing, electrical, mechanical and gas systems in his own single-family or duplex residence for his own use and occupancy and not intended for sale. He shall obtain all required permits for such work, and as a prerequisite to the obtaining of permits, he shall satisfy the Building Official that he has the ability and knowledge of the Florida Building Code to do such work in that trade. Such installation shall be made by the owner for himself and on his own premises, without compensation from others, and he shall not employ anyone to assist with such installations.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>In connection with paragraph (2) above, no more than one (1) permit shall be issued to an owner for the construction of a new single-family or duplex residence in any twenty-four-month period, and permits for alterations and additions, or plumbing, electrical, mechanical or gas installations shall be issued only in connection with one (1) single-family or duplex residence in any twenty-four-month period, although more than one (1) permit may be issued for such work on the same single-family or duplex residence during that period.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Building Officials, as defined in the Florida Building Code, may require proof that the applicant is the owner of the property upon or in which construction or installation is to take place, and nothing herein is to be construed to invalidate the requirement for applying for and obtaining permits, paying fees, calling for required inspections, and complying with all plans, specifications, codes, laws and regulations applicable.</section><section prefix='(5)'>When the building permit is held by an owner, lessee or tenant as set forth in subsections (1) and (2) and any work thereunder is by contract and separate permits are required for the work, the contractor shall separately and in addition to such owner, lessee or tenant, permit, make application for, and obtain permits to include all work done by him under contract.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The United States, federal agencies and their contractors, in the execution of federal projects authorized by Congress, are exempted from the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A sole owner may make application for permit in connection with the maintenance or repair to a single family or duplex residence for his own use and occupancy and not intended for sale at the time of application for said permit without satisfying the Building Official that he has the ability and knowledge of the Florida Building Code to do such work in the trades involved provided:<section prefix='(a)'>A non-profit corporation, fund or foundation that is organized and existing exclusively for religious, charitable or education purposes is providing construction services to the owner free of any remuneration or consideration; and,</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The work to be performed is supervised by a contractor having a current valid certificate of competency from either the State of Florida or the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board in the trade concerned and against whom no disciplinary action is pending. As a condition of obtaining a building permit, an affidavit, reasonably satisfactory to the Building Official, shall be submitted to the Building Official with the permit application, and executed by the non-profit corporation, fund or foundation, the supervising contractor and the owner of the structure to be repaired which identifies the structure and location of the property and which states that the services are being performed without remuneration or consideration.</section><section>The Building Official may limit the number of permits issued to property owners under paragraph 7 to insure that the work being performed through any non-profit corporation, fund or foundation is completed on a timely basis. In addition, a Building Official may deny a permit to any owner due to a sponsoring non-profit corporation, fund or foundation having failed in the past to provide continuous supervision by a contractor, correct violations of the Florida Building Code or obtain mandatory inspections.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-41, 11-3-59; Ord. No. 64-59, § 5, 11-24-64; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 68-23, § 2, 4-16-68; Ord. No. 91-116, § 1, 10-1-91; Ord. No. 99-07, § 1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>