<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Masters, journeymen and maintenance personnel certificates.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002066</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-7. Masters, journeymen and maintenance personnel certificates.<section>A certificate of competency for masters, journeymen and maintenancepersonnel shall be obtained in the following manner:<section prefix='(a)'>Application. All applicants shall make application on a form which includes the information described in Section 10-6(B)(1)—(8) above and as prescribed by the Board. The application shall be retained by the County together with all supporting papers.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Fee. A fee established by separate administrative order shall be paid for the examination for journeymen and maintenance personnel, and for masters.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notice of next examination. The applicant shall be notified of the time and place of the next examination. This notice shall be in addition to the notice provided for in Section 10-12</section><section prefix='(d)'>Examination. He shall pass the examination in the particular category and trade concerned.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Denial of application.
                         Section 10-6(D) applies as though fully set forth herein.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Temporary certificates. Any person who has in his possession a current license or certificate as a master or journeyman issued by any state, County, or municipality in the United States certifying that the holder has been examined and found competent to perform the work of a master or journeyman, shall, after making application for the next examination, be issued a temporary certificate by the Secretary of the Board, authorizing such master or journeyman to work in the capacity of a journeyman. Such certificate shall be issued only upon written request of the employing contractor. Failure to take or pass the examination applied for shall automatically terminate such certificate and the employing contractor shall return the certificate to the Board. No further certificate will be issued to the applicant unless he shall take and pass an examination.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-25, § 17.07, 11-12-57; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 76-70, § 3, 7-20-76; Ord. No. 91-114, § 1, 10-1-91; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>