<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='2'>Chapter 10 CONTRACTORS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>10-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Examination—Conduct of and general standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002067</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 10-8. Examination—Conduct of and general standards.<section>Examinations shall be prepared, conducted and graded by the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or his designee in the building, plumbing, electrical, mechanical and liquefied petroleum gas categories, and by the Director of Public Works and Waste Management in the engineering category. There shall be at least two (2) examinations given each year in all categories requiring the same. Each director may designate staff standards members to assist in these examination duties as he may deem necessary. In addition, the directors may employ consultants to advise and assist in the preparation and grading of examinations, and, upon approval of the County Commission, may contract for the preparation and grading of examinations with recognized and approved agencies qualified in the preparation and grading of such examinations, all within budgetary limitations. Upon completion of the grading, the directors shall certify to the Board the names of the applicants passing the examination. The directors shall submit quarterly reports to the Board of County Commissioners, such reports to list the number of applicants passing and failing the examinations given during the quarter concerned.</section><section>The directors shall be responsible for the annual review and improvement of all examinations, in order that such examinations are fair and comprehensive and indicative of current practices and codes.</section><section>The general standards of examination for certificates of competency shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Each applicant shall be examined by an objective written test, except for cases of language difficulty, or other impediments, for which special provision is made pursuant to Section 10-11 of this Code, as to his fitness to be granted the type of certificate applied for.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The passing grade for journeyman examinations shall be seventy-five (75) percent. The passing grade shall be seventy (70) percent for all other examinations unless a different passing grade is established by the directors in advance of the examination, and if a passing grade other than seventy (70) percent is so established, the notice of examination posted pursuant to Section 10-12 of this Code shall specify such passing grade.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The examination shall be made with reference to knowledge of such portions of the Florida Building Code or other rules, laws or principles as may be relevant to the trade or specialty involved.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The written examination shall be of a multiple choice, fill-in or true-false character or may include or consist of diagrams, plans or sketches upon or in connection with which the applicant is required to demonstrate his knowledge of circuits, installations or the like by answering true-false, multiple-choice or one (1) word fill-in questions keyed to such diagrams, plans or sketches.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-41, 11-3-59; Ord. No. 64-59, § 13, 11-24-64; Ord. No. 67-82, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 6, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-10, § 1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 13-08, § 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>