<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='2'>Chapter 11 COURTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Group classification for Official Court Reporters; supplemental annual compensation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002108</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11-1. Group classification for Official Court Reporters; supplemental annual compensation.<section prefix='(a)'>Official Circuit Court Reporters for the Eleventh Judicial Circuit of Florida, in and for Miami-Dade County, shall be classified into four (4) groups, according to the number of judges served by each Court Reporter. Such classification shall be:<section>shall include all Official Reporters serving one or more, but not exceeding four (4), Circuit Court Judges.</section><section>shall include all Official Reporters serving five (5) or more, but not exceeding eight (8), Circuit Court Judges.</section><section>shall include all Official Reporters serving nine (9) or more, but not exceeding twelve (12), Circuit Court Judges.</section><section>shall include all Official Reporters serving thirteen (13) or more Circuit Judges.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Each Official Court Reporter of the Circuit Court of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit, in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, duly appointed pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 29, Florida Statutes, shall receive a supplemental salary payable by Miami-Dade County in equal monthly installments. Such salary shall be paid according to the following schedule:<section>shall receive $16,100.00 per annum.</section><section>shall receive $19,800.00 per annum.</section><section>shall receive $23,500.00 per annum.</section><section>shall receive $27,200.00 per annum.</section></section><section>Such supplemental salary shall be in addition to the annual salary paid by the State, but shall not be in lieu of the appearance fees and transcript fees, as established by court rule from time to time. Such salary shall be in lieu of all other compensation or benefits heretofore received from the County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The supplemental annual compensation shall be excluded from annual cost of living increase and any other general increase, as from time to time may be promulgated by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The supplemental annual compensation may be increased only by specific act of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-81, §§ 2—4, 9-18-73; Ord. No. 90-38, § 1, 4-17-90)</history></law>