<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='2'>Chapter 11 COURTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional court costs in criminal proceedings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002120</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11-11. Additional court costs in criminal proceedings.<section>In addition to any other fine, penalty, or cost imposed by any other provision of law, a sixty-five dollar ($65.00) court cost is hereby imposed upon any conviction, plea of nolo contendere or finding of guilt, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld, for each felony, misdemeanor, or criminal traffic offense. The court shall not waive this court cost. The Clerk of the Court shall collect the sixty-five dollar ($65.00) assessments for court costs established in this section and shall remit it to Miami-Dade County. All proceeds collected shall be allocated as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Twenty-five percent (25%) of the amount collected shall be allocated to fund innovations to supplement state funding for the elements of the state court system identified in Section 29.004, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, and county funding for local requirements under Section 29.008(2)(a)2, as amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Twenty-five percent (25%) of the amount collected shall be allocated to assist legal aid programs.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Twenty-five percent (25%) of the amount collected shall be allocated to fund personnel and legal materials for the law library.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Twenty-five percent (25%) of the amount collected shall be allocated to support teen court programs, the Juvenile Assessment Center or other juvenile alternative programs.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-116, ยง 1, 6-8-04)</history></law>