<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='2'>Chapter 11 COURTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Increase in certain filing charges in the Circuit and County Courts; use.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002110</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11-3. Increase in certain filing charges in the Circuit and County Courts; use.<section prefix='(a)'>Except as provided hereafter for the institution of a petition for modification of a final judgment of dissolution and petitions for dissolution of marriage, in all cases in which there are five (5) or fewer defendants, a party instituting any civil action, suit or proceeding in the Circuit Court of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit of Florida shall pay to the Clerk of said Court a service charge of one hundred fifty-eight dollars and fifty cents ($158.50), which amount shall include a fee of ten dollars ($10.00) to be allocated to the Miami-Dade County Public Guardianship Program and matched by Miami-Dade County from general revenue, for payment of costs associated with public guardianships, in addition to the service charge payable to the clerk of said court pursuant to general law, including Section 28.241, Florida Statutes, provided that the additional service charges for each defendant in excess of five (5) and additional service charges for any party seeking a severance shall remain unchanged from that provided in Section 28.241, Florida Statutes.</section><section>Upon the institution of a petition for dissolution of marriage in the Circuit Court, the petitioner shall pay to the Clerk of the Court a service charge of one hundred fifty-nine dollars and fifty cents ($159.50) which amount shall include a fee of ten dollars ($10.00) to be allocated to the Miami-Dade County Public Guardianship program and matched by Miami-Dade County from general revenue, for payment of costs associated with public guardianships; and upon the institution of a petition for modification of a final judgment of dissolution in the Circuit Court, the petitioner shall pay to the Clerk of the Court a service charge of forty-five dollars ($45.00). All such service charges shall be in addition to the service charges and fees payable pursuant to general law, including Section 28.241, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Upon the institution of any civil action or proceeding in County Court, the plaintiff, when filing the action or proceeding, shall pay to the clerk of the Court the following service charges in addition to the service charges payable pursuant to general law, including Sections 28.241 and 34.041, Florida Statutes:<section prefix='(1)'>For all claims less than $100.00$ 3.50</section><section prefix='(2)'>For all claims of $100.00 or more but not more than $1,500.0018.50</section><section prefix='(3)'>For all claims of more than $1,500.00 but not more than $2,500.0061.50</section><section prefix='(4)'>For all claims of more than $2,500.00 but not more than $5,000.00100.50</section><section prefix='(5)'>All claims of more than $5,000.00148.50</section><section prefix='(6)'>For removal of tenant action90.50</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Any party instituting a probate matter, except probate cases which involve disposition of personal property with a value of less than two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) and which also require no administration, shall pay to the Clerk of the Court a service charge in addition to the service charge payable to the Clerk of said Court pursuant to general law, including Section 28.2401, Florida Statutes, as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For the opening of any estate of one (1) document or more, including, but not limited to, petitions and orders to approve settlement of minor's claims; to open a safe deposit box; to enter rooms and places; for the determination of heirs, if not formal administration; and for a foreign guardian to manage property of a nonresident; but not to include issuance of letters or order of summary and family administration$56.00</section><section prefix='(2)'>Caveat60.00</section><section prefix='(3)'>Petition and order to admit foreign wills, authenticated copies, exemplified copies, or transcript to record59.00</section><section prefix='(4)'>For disposition of personal property with a value of two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) or more, without administration79.50</section><section prefix='(5)'>Summary administration116.50</section><section prefix='(6)'>Family administration84.50</section><section prefix='(7)'>Formal administration, guardianship, ancillary, curatorship, or conservatorship proceedings122.50</section><section prefix='(8)'>Guardianship proceedings of person only58.50</section><section prefix='(9)'>Determination of incompetency (incapacity)58.00</section><section prefix='(10)'>Foreign guardianships77.50</section><section prefix='(11)'>Adversary proceedings, probate related trusts148.50</section><section prefix='(12)'>Re-opening of formal administration, probate related trusts50.00</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>The additional service charges herein provided for shall, together with other available funds, be expended for the operation of the Miami-Dade County Law Library and its branches; the Miami-Dade County Legal Aid Program; and to acquire by lease, purchase or otherwise; to construct, reconstruct, enlarge, or modify; to operate, maintain, and repair court facilities in Miami-Dade County, including court information systems, case management systems, and court technology, together with ancillary improvements and services related to any of the foregoing. Said charges may be pledged by the county as security for servicing the principal and interest on revenue bonds to accomplish one or more of the foregoing purposes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-45, § 1, 6-4-75; Ord. No. 81-117, § 1, 10-26-81; Ord. No. 81-128, § 1, 11-17-81; Ord. No. 89-62, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-71, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 93-55, § 1, 5-20-93; Ord. No. 93-91, § 11, 9-20-93; Ord. No. 96-42, § 1, 3-5-96; Ord. No. 00-173, § 1, 12-7-00)</history></law>