<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='2'>Chapter 11 COURTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional court costs for Teen Court.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002117</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11-8. Additional court costs for Teen Court.<section>Pursuant to Section 938.19, Florida Statutes, and, in addition to any other fine, penalty, or cost imposed by any other provision of law, the court shall impose a three dollar ($3.00) court cost upon every person who pleads guilty or nolo contendere to, or is convicted of, regardless of adjudication, a violation of a state criminal statute or a municipal ordinance or county ordinance or who pays a fine or civil penalty for any violation of Chapter 316, Florida Statutes. Any person whose adjudication is withheld pursuant to the provisions of Section 318.14(9) or (10), Florida Statutes, shall also be assessed such cost.</section><section>The three dollar ($3.00) assessment shall specifically be added to any civil penalty paid for a violation of Chapter 316, Florida Statutes, whether such penalty is paid by mail, paid in person without request for a hearing, or paid after hearing and determination by the court. However, the three-dollar ($3.00) assessment shall not be made against a person for a violation of any state statute, county ordinance, or municipal ordinance relating to the parking of vehicles, with the exception of a violation of the handicapped parking laws.</section><section>The Clerk of the Circuit Court shall collect the respective three dollar ($3.00) assessments for court costs established in this section and shall remit the same to the teen court monthly, less five (5) percent, which is to be retained as fee income of the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-185, ยง 1, 12-15-98)</history></law>