<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='2'>Chapter 11 COURTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional Mediation and Arbitration Service Charges.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002118</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11-9. Additional Mediation and Arbitration Service Charges.<section prefix='(a)'>Circuit Court Service Charge. Upon the institution of any civil action, suit or proceeding in the Circuit Court in and for the Eleventh Judicial Circuit of Florida, the party or parties instituting, such action, suit or proceeding shall pay a service charge of five dollars ($5.00), in addition to any other service charges which may heretofore or hereafter be levied. This service charge shall be collected by the clerk of the court at the time of filing such action, suit or proceeding and shall be deposited in the court's mediation-arbitration account fund under the supervision of the chief judge of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit of Florida.</section><section prefix='(b)'>County Court Service Charge. Upon the institution of any civil action, suit or proceeding in the County Court in and for the Eleventh Judicial Circuit of Florida, the party or parties instituting such action, suit or proceeding shall pay a service charge of five dollars ($5.00), in addition to any other service charges which may heretofore or hereafter be levied. This service charge shall be collected by the clerk of the court at the time of filing such action, suit or proceeding and shall be deposited in the court's mediation-arbitration account under the supervision of the chief judge of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit of Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Distribution of Funds. As required by Section 44.108(4), Florida Statutes, the clerk of the court shall forward one dollar ($1.00) of each service charge collected to the Office of the State Courts Administrator to be used by the Supreme Court of Florida to carry out its responsibilities set forth in Section 44.106, Florida Statutes. The remainder of the service charges collected shall be utilized to support the arbitration and mediation services provided by the Eleventh Judicial Circuit of Florida under the supervision of the chief judge.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Posting and Report by the Clerk. On a monthly basis, the clerk of the court shall post the amount of funds that were deposited into the mediation/arbitration account. Upon request of the chief judge or his designee and/or the Board of County Commissioners, the clerk of the court shall provide a financial report on the mediation/arbitration account outlining the revenues, disbursements and investment earnings (if any), for the period of time as specified by said request.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-141, ยง 1, 9-13-01)</history></law>