<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. DOMESTIC PARTNERS AND FAMILY HEALTH COVERAGE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-75</section_number>
<catch_line>Extension of benefits to domestic partners of County employees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002212</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-75. Extension of benefits to domestic partners of County employees.<section prefix='(a)'>Any County employee who is a party to a registered domestic partnership relationship under this ordinance shall be entitled to elect insurance coverage for his or her domestic partner or the children of such domestic partner on the same basis in which any County employee may elect insurance coverage for his or her spouse or children. A County employee's right to elect insurance coverage for his or her domestic partner, or the partner's children, shall extend to all forms of insurance provided by the County to the spouses and children of County employees, unless such coverage is prohibited by state or federal law or the terms of a collective bargaining agreement. All elections of coverage shall be made in accordance with the requirements of applicable county ordinances, administrative rules, county policies and applicable collective bargaining agreements. However, in no event shall an employee make an election for coverage of a domestic partner more than two (2) times in a plan year.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any County employee who is a party to a registered domestic partnership relationship under this ordinance shall be entitled to use all forms of leave provided by the County including, but not limited to, sick leave, annual leave, funeral leave and family leave to care for his or her domestic partner or the children or parents of the domestic partner as applicable. The use of leave authorized in this section shall be consistent with the applicable requirements in county ordinances, administrative rules, and collective bargaining agreements.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Unless prohibited by state or federal law or the terms of a collective bargaining agreement, all other benefits available to the spouses and children of County employees shall be made available on the same basis to the domestic partner, or child of such domestic partner, of a County employee who is a party to a registered domestic partnership relationship pursuant to this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any County employee who obtains or attempts to obtain benefits under this provision fraudulently shall be subject to discipline, up to and including termination.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Mayor is authorized and directed to take all actions necessary to implement the provisions of this section within ninety (90) days after this ordinance is enacted.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-61, ยง 1, 5-20-08)</history></law>