<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. OFFICE OF FAIR EMPLOYMENT PRACTICES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-37</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002180</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-37. Duties and powers.<section>The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Office and its Director shall include the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Pursuant to Section 11A-28, jurisdiction over complaints of employment discrimination by county employees and applicants arising under Article IV of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Enforcement of the provisions of this article and rules and regulations promulgated hereunder.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Overall jurisdiction in the development implementation and monitoring of fair employment guidelines as they relate internally to Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Subject to the approval of the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee and the County Attorney, review and approve department affirmative action plans which address underutilization of minorities, women and the disabled.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Monitor County hiring and employment practices to ensure compliance with federal and state employment discrimination legislation. Reports of noncompliance shall be forwarded to the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee and the County Commission for review and determination.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Establish rules and procedures for processing and resolving complaints of employment discrimination by County employees.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Promulgation of rules and regulations to ensure fair employment practices within the County's employment system.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Assure that information and technical assistance is provided to all County administrators, County employees, and applicants for employment, concerning fair employment practices.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Publish and disseminate public information and materials relating to equal employment opportunities and fair employment practices, including serving as a fair employment resource to the community at large.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Make annual reports to the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee and the County Commission concerning the status of Miami-Dade County employment system as it relates to fair employment practices, the enforcement of the provisions of this article and recommendations concerning methods by which to improve the County's fair employment practices.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Perform such other administrative duties as may be assigned by the County Mayor.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 13-39, ยง 3, 5-7-13)</history></law>