<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. DOMESTIC PARTNERS AND FAMILY HEALTH COVERAGE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-73</section_number>
<catch_line>Termination of registered domestic partnership relationship.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002210</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-73. Termination of registered domestic partnership relationship.<section prefix='(a)'>Either partner to a registered domestic partnership relationship may terminate such relationship by filing a notarized declaration of termination of domestic partnership relationship with the Consumer Services Department. Upon the payment of the required fee, the Consumer Services Department shall file the declaration and issue a certificate of termination of domestic partnership relationship to each partner of the former relationship. The termination shall become effective 30 days from the date the certificate of termination is issued.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If any partner to a domestic partnership relationship enters into a legal marriage, the domestic partnership relationship shall terminate automatically, and all rights, benefits, and entitlements thereunder shall cease as of the effective date of the marriage. The marrying domestic partner shall file a declaration terminating the domestic partnership relationship within 10 days after entering into a legal marriage.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The death of either domestic partner shall automatically terminate the domestic partner relationship.</section><section prefix='(d)'>If either member of the domestic partnership ceases to be responsible for the other's basic food and shelter, the domestic partnership shall be considered terminated.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-61, ยง 1, 5-20-08)</history></law>