<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. FAMILY LEAVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-29</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative findings and purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002172</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-29. Legislative findings and purpose.<section prefix='(1)'>The County Commission finds that the number of families within the County in which both parents or a single parent is employed outside the home has increased significantly within recent years. Due to a lack of employment policies designed to accommodate working parents, many individuals are forced to choose between job security and parenting or providing care for ill family members. The Commission further finds that it is necessary to promote the economic security of families by guaranteeing jobs to wage earners who choose to take a period of leave upon the birth or placement for adoption of a child or serious health condition of a family member. The Commission also recognizes that unrestricted leave by an employee may interfere with an employer's legitimate business needs. The Commission, therefore, declares that it is the policy of the County to balance the demands of the workplace with the needs of families, to promote stability and economic security in families and to entitle employees to take reasonable leave for medical reasons, for the birth or adoption of a child, and for the care of a child, spouse or other close relative who has a serious health condition. The County further declares that employees should be entitled to take such leave without risk of termination of employment or retaliation by employers.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The County Commission finds that the enactment of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, Public Law No. 103-3 (29 U.S.C. ยง 2611 et seq.) fulfills many of the purposes for which this chapter was originally intended. In order to avoid imposing possibly conflicting burdens on employers and unduly confusing employees about their family leave rights, the Commission believes it appropriate to make the County ordinance consistent with the federal act and intends that the ordinance be so interpreted. In enacting this revised chapter, the County Commission intends to provide employees in the County with an efficient alternative means of enforcing their rights to family medical leave through the Commission on Human Rights.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 17, 6-30-09)</history></law>