<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. DOMESTIC LEAVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-61</section_number>
<catch_line>Entitlement to domestic leave.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002199</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-61. Entitlement to domestic leave.<section prefix='(1)'>Employees, as defined in this article, shall be entitled to a total of thirty (30) work days of unpaid domestic leave during any twelve (12) month period for one (1) or more of the following:<section prefix='(a)'>To obtain and receive medical and/or dental assistance for a medical and/or dental problem resulting from domestic or repeat violence, including obtaining such services for the employee's dependent children;</section><section prefix='(b)'>To obtain and receive legal assistance relating to domestic or repeat violence, including but not limited to criminal prosecution, a protective order, divorce, custody of children, and child support;</section><section prefix='(c)'>To attend court appearances relating to domestic or repeat violence, including but not limited to criminal prosecution, protective order, divorce, custody of children and child support;</section><section prefix='(d)'>To attend counseling or support services, including counseling or support services for dependent children;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any other arrangements necessary to provide for the safety and well-being of an employee subject to domestic or repeat violence.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Domestic leave under this section may be taken by an employee intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule. However, if an employee requests intermittent leave or reduced leave that is foreseeable based on a planned schedule, the employer may require such employee to transfer temporarily to an available alternative position for which the employee is qualified and that has equivalent pay and benefits, and better accommodates recurring periods of leave.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Domestic leave may be taken in addition to the family leave allowed under Article V of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Prior to requesting domestic leave, an employee must exhaust all paid vacation leave and/or personal leave.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-05, ยง1, 1-21-99)</history></law>