<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PUBLIC ACCOMMODATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-24</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement by private persons.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002166</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-24. Enforcement by private persons.<section prefix='(1)'>If within one hundred eighty (180) days after a complaint is filed alleging discrimination, the Director has been unable to obtain voluntary compliance with the provisions of this chapter, the complainant may demand a notice of right-to-sue from the Director, the issuance of which shall terminate the jurisdiction of the Director and the Board over such complaint. Not later than ninety (90) days following receipt of the notice of right-to-sue, the complainant may commence a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction against the respondent named in the complaint.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If, in a private enforcement proceeding under this chapter, the court finds that a discriminatory practice has occurred or is about to occur it may issue an order prohibiting the practice and providing affirmative relief from the effects of the practice, including temporary or permanent injunctive and other equitable relief, temporary restraining order, actual and punitive damages, reasonable Attorney's fees, interest, costs or other order.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Upon request of the Board, the County Attorney may intervene on behalf of the County in an action brought under the provisions of this article, if the Board certifies that the case is of public importance to the citizens of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 16, 12-5-06)</history></law>