<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PUBLIC ACCOMMODATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-20.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Accessibility Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002161</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-20.1. Accessibility Requirements.<section prefix='(1)'>Within ninety (90) days of enactment of this Ordinance, all gas station retailers shall be required to prominently display a sign, decal or sticker, no smaller than fifteen (15) square inches, on the front of all gasoline pumps clearly stating the telephone number for that gas station retailer, the international symbol of accessibility ("ISA), and wording such as "Call for Assistance" or "Assistance Available upon Request," in substantially the form pictured below. The sign, decal or sticker must also be on a blue background. The telephone number indicated on the sign decal or sticker shall be operational and answered directly by an employee of the gas station retailer is open for business to the public.</section><section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The gas station retailer shall require an attendant to provide refueling assistance to any motor vehicle properly displaying an exemption parking permit as provided in Section 316.1958 or 320.0848, Florida Statutes, as may be amended, or a license plate issued pursuant to Sections 320.084, 320.0842, 320.0843, or 320.0845, Florida Statutes, as may be amended, when the person to whom such permit has been issued is the operator of the vehicle and such service is requested during the hours the gas station retailer is open for business to the public.</section><section prefix='(3)'>However, should such assistance be requested during times when a second attendant is not present at a self-service gasoline station, the gas station retailer is not required to provide the requested assistance. In such case, if a remote or electronic means of communication with the requester exists, the one attendant on duty shall inform the person that he or she is unable to provide such assistance as a result of having only one attendant on duty.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-48, ยง 3, 7-3-12)</history></law>