<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. CONTRACTING, PROCUREMENT BONDING AND FINANCIAL SERVICES ACTIVITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-38</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002182</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-38. Definitions.<section>The definitions set out in shall apply to this article in addition to the definitions set forth below. As used in this article:</section><section>means a quotation, proposal, letter of interest or offer by any bidder in response to any kind of invitation, request or public announcement to submit such quotation, proposal, letters of interest or offer to perform the contract.</section><section>means any person, partnership, corporation or other business entity that submits a bid.</section><section>shall mean any written charge alleging an unlawful practice prohibited by this article.</section><section>shall mean any person, persons or business entities alleging an unlawful practice prohibited by this article.</section><section>or shall mean a written agreement resolving or otherwise disposing of a complaint and which is entered into by the parties and the Director prior to final resolution of the complaint.</section><section>means the building, maintaining, painting, altering, or repairing of a public or private improvement.</section><section>means an agreement that may include, but is not limited to those proposed by the County or Public Health Trust staffs or approved by the County Commission or Public Health Trust in any of the following classes:<section prefix='(1)'>Procurement of goods and services not included in the subsections (2), (3), and (4) below;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Construction of a public or private improvement;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Professionals subject to Section 287.055, Florida Statutes and Section 2-10.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Other professional services including but not limited to accounting, legal, health care, consulting and management services.</section></section><section>shall mean a final investigative report issued by the Director of DBD or his or her designee.</section><section>as used in this article, shall mean the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Business Development (hereinafter known as DBD) or his or her designee.</section><section>shall mean any difference, distinction or preference in treatment, access or impact because of race, color, religion, ancestry, national origin, gender, pregnancy, age, or disability which is prohibited by this article. Discrimination also includes sexual harassment of any sort.<section prefix='(1)'>Disparate treatment means intentional treatment of a person or business in a discriminatory manner which is prohibited by this article or by State or Federal law.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Disparate impact means intentional or unintentional activities or practices which have a discriminatory impact on a group protected under this article.</section></section><section>shall include any bank, insurance company, bonding company, savings and loan association, credit union, mortgage company or any other person or organization engaged in the business of lending money, guaranteeing loans, or extending credit.</section><section>means any tangible product, material or supply that is not a service.</section><section>is the person designated to hold hearings on complaints of discriminatory activities.</section><section>shall include any union, association, joint committee, board or other combination, or any agent thereof which bargains or deals with employers concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rates of pay, hours or other terms or conditions of employment.</section><section>shall mean person, persons or business entities alleged to have engaged in an unlawful practice prohibited by this article or by State or Federal law.</section><section>"Right to sue letter" is a letter that would allow the charging party to initiate a civil action in a court of appropriate jurisdiction.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-67, ยง 1, 6-3-97)</history></law>