<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. HOUSING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement by private persons.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002155</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-15. Enforcement by private persons.<section prefix='(1)'>A complainant may file a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction no later than two (2) years after the alleged discriminatory housing practice has occurred or terminated or after a breach of a conciliation agreement. A person aggrieved by an alleged housing discrimination practice or breach may file a civil action regardless of whether he or she has filed a complaint under this article and regardless of the status of any complaint filed under this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any sale, encumbrance or rental consummated prior to the filing of a complaint of discrimination pursuant to this chapter, and involving a bona fide purchaser, encumbrance or tenant without actual notice of the existence of the filing of a complaint or civil action under the provisions of this chapter shall not be affected.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If, in a private enforcement proceeding under this chapter, the court finds that a discriminatory practice has occurred or is about to occur it may issue an order prohibiting the practice and providing affirmative relief from the effects of the practice, including temporary or permanent injunctive and other equitable relief, temporary restraining order, actual and punitive damages, reasonable Attorney's fees, interest, costs or other order.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Upon request of the Commission, the County Attorney may intervene on behalf of the County in an action brought under the provisions of this article, if the Commission certifies that the case is of public importance to the citizens of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 12, 12-5-06; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 13, 6-30-09)</history></law>