<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. EMPLOYMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-25</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002168</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-25. Definitions.<section>The definitions set out in shall apply to this article in addition to the definitions set forth below. As used in this article:<section prefix='(1)'>Employee shall mean an individual employed by an employer.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Employer shall mean any person who in the regular course of business has five (5) or more employees in Miami-Dade County in each of four (4) or more calendar weeks in the current calendar year and any agent, acting manager, contractor or subcontractor of such person, but such term does not include:<section prefix='(a)'>The United States or a corporation wholly owned by the government of the United States;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The State of Florida;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(d)'>An Indian Tribe; or</section><section prefix='(e)'>A bona fide private membership club.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Employment agency shall mean any person or agent thereof, regularly undertaking, with or without compensation, to recruit for prospective employees, opportunities to work for an employer on any basis, including, full-time, part-time, temporary, permanent or any combination thereof.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Labor organization shall include any union, association, joint committee, board or other combination, or any agent thereof, which bargains or deals with employers concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rates of pay, hours or other terms or conditions of employment.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97)</history></law>