<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. CONTRACTING, PROCUREMENT BONDING AND FINANCIAL SERVICES ACTIVITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-40</section_number>
<catch_line>Qualifications of Hearing Officers and removal; organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002184</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-40. Qualifications of Hearing Officers and removal; organization.<section prefix='(1)'>Hearing Officers shall be residents of Miami-Dade County who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, interest, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability. Appointments shall be made by the County Manager or his or her designee. Qualifications for Hearing Officers should include retired judges who are licensed and admitted to practice law in the State of Florida, or arbitrators or mediators certified by the Circuit Court or State Bar Associations. Additional qualifications include but not limited to experience in equal opportunity, anti-discrimination, contracting, procurement, bonding or financial services activities. Such appointments shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners for ratification by the Clerk. The Clerk shall submit an annual report to the Board on the number of women who have served as hearing examiners.<section prefix='(2)'>The County Manager or his or her designee shall appoint as many Hearing Officers as are deemed necessary. Appointments shall be made for a term of one (1) year. Any Hearing Officer may be reappointed at the discretion of the County Manager, subject to ratification by the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. There shall be no limit on the number of reappointments that may be given to any individual Hearing Officer; provided, however, that a determination as to reappointment must be made for each Hearing Officer at the end of each of his one-year terms. The County Manager shall have authority to remove Hearing Officers at any time. Appointments to fill a vacancy shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Hearing Officers shall not be County employees but shall be compensated at a rate to be determined by administrative order.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Miami-Dade County Attorney's Office shall serve as general counsel to the Hearing Officers.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-67, ยง 1, 6-3-97)</history></law>