<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. HOUSING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-17</section_number>
<catch_line>Civil fines.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002157</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-17. Civil fines.<section prefix='(1)'>At the conclusion of a hearing and upon a finding of housing discrimination in violation of Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 as amended, the Board may recommend that the County Attorney commence a civil action for fines without cost to the complainant. Such civil action shall be commenced within ninety (90) days of the issuance of the final order by the Board. If such civil action is brought the court may impose the following fines:<section prefix='(a)'>Up to ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) if the respondent has not previously been found guilty of a violation of this article;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Up to twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) if the respondent has been found guilty of one (1) prior violation of this article within the preceding five (5) years prior to filing of a complaint;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Up to fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) if the respondent has been found guilty of two (2) or more violations of this article within the preceding seven (7) years prior to filing of a complaint.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>In imposing a fine under this section, the court shall consider the nature and circumstances of the violation, the degree of culpability, the history of prior violations of this article, the financial circumstances of the respondent and the goal of deterring future violations of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All fines imposed pursuant to this article shall be paid to the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97)</history></law>