<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PUBLIC ACCOMMODATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-20</section_number>
<catch_line>Places of public accommodation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002160</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-20. Places of public accommodation.<section>shall mean any establishment, service, place or building which offers, sells or otherwise makes available to the public any good, service, facility, privilege or advantage. Each of the following establishments which services the public is a place of public accommodation within the meaning of this article:<section prefix='(a)'>An inn, hotel, motel or other place of lodging, except for an establishment located within a building that contains not more than five (5) rooms for rent or hire and that is actually occupied by the proprietor of such establishment as the residence of such proprietor;</section><section prefix='(b)'>A restaurant, bar or other establishment serving food or drink;</section><section prefix='(c)'>A motion picture house, theater, concert hall, stadium, or other place of exhibition or entertainment;</section><section prefix='(d)'>An auditorium, convention center, lecture hall or other place of public gathering.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A bakery, grocery store, clothing store, hardware store, shopping center, or other sales or rental establishment;</section><section prefix='(f)'>A laundromat, dry-cleaner, bank, barber shop, beauty shop, travel service, shoe repair service, funeral parlor, gas station, office of an accountant or lawyer, pharmacy, insurance office, professional office of a health care provider, hospital or other service establishment;</section><section prefix='(g)'>A terminal, depot or other station used for specified public transportation including but not limited to taxis, limousines and buses.</section><section prefix='(h)'>A museum, library, gallery or other place of public display or collection;</section><section prefix='(i)'>A park, zoo, amusement park or other place of recreation;</section><section prefix='(j)'>A nursery, elementary, secondary, undergraduate or postgraduate private school, or other place of education;</section><section prefix='(k)'>A day care center, senior citizen center, homeless shelter, food bank, adoption agency or other social service center establishment; and</section><section prefix='(l)'>A gymnasium, health spa, bowling alley, golf course, or other place of exercise or recreation.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Any area or structure provided for the purpose of storing personal property.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Gas station retailers. For purposes of this article, "gas station retailer" shall mean any full service gasoline station; or any self-service gasoline station that has two or more attendants on duty at any given time during the hours the station is open for business to the public.</section><section prefix='(o)'>A gasoline station. For purposes of this article, "gas station" shall mean that portion of property where flammable and combustible liquids used as motor fuels are stored and subsequently dispensed from fixed, approved dispensing equipment into fuel tanks of motor vehicles by any person.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 13, 12-5-06; Ord. No. 12-48, ยง 2, 7-3-12)</history></law>