<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. HOUSING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002151</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-11. Definitions.<section>The definitions set out in shall apply to this article in addition to the definition set forth below. As used in this article:<section prefix='(1)'>Dwelling or dwelling unit shall mean any building, mobile home, trailer, structure or portion thereof which is occupied, designed, arranged or intended for occupancy as a home, residence or sleeping place of one (1) or more persons, or vacant land which is offered for sale or lease for the construction or location of any building, mobile home, trailer or structure or portion thereof.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Financial institution shall include any bank, insurance company, savings and loan association, credit union, mortgage company or any other person or organization engaged in the business of lending money, guaranteeing loans, or extending credit.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Mortgage broker shall mean an individual who is engaged in or performs the business or services of a mortgage broker as defined in Chapter 494, Florida Statutes, as amended.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Owner shall include a lessor, lessee, sublessee, co-tenant, assignee, managing agent, manager or other person having the right to sell, rent, lease or control any housing or office accommodation.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Premises shall mean the interior or exterior spaces, parts, components or elements of a building including individual dwelling units and the public and common use areas of a building.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Real estate broker or real estate salesperson shall include any individual or agent thereof who is engaged in or performs the business or the services of a real estate broker or salesperson as defined in Chapter 475, Florida Statutes, as amended.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Real property includes buildings, portions of buildings, structures, lands, tenements, leaseholds, cooperatives, condominiums or any interest therein.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Single-family dwelling shall include a single-family home, mobile home, apartment, townhouse unit, cooperative unit or condominium unit.</section><section prefix='(9)'>To rent shall mean to lease, sublease, let or otherwise grant for consideration the right to occupy premises not owned by the occupant.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Conciliation shall mean the attempted resolution of issues raised by a complaint or by the investigation of such complaint, through informal negotiations involving the complainant, the respondent, and the Director.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Person shall mean one or more individuals, corporations, partnerships, associations, labor organizations, legal representatives, mutual companies, joint-stock companies, trusts, unincorporated organizations, trustees, trustees in cases under Title 11 [of the United States Code], receivers, and fiduciaries.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Source of income shall mean the lawful, verifiable income paid directly to a tenant or paid to a representative of a tenant, including, but not limited to, Section 8 Housing Choice Vouchers, Supplemental Security Income, Social Security, pensions and other retirement benefits.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 9, 12-5-06; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 10, 6-30-09)</history></law>