<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. DOMESTIC PARTNERS AND FAMILY HEALTH COVERAGE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-72</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration of domestic partnerships.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002209</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-72. Registration of domestic partnerships.<section prefix='(a)'>A valid domestic partnership relationship may be registered by any two (2) persons by filing a declaration of domestic partnership with the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department, which declaration shall comply with all requirements set forth in this ordinance for establishing such domestic partnership. Upon payment of any required fees, the Consumer Services Department shall file the declaration of domestic partnership and issue a certificate reflecting the registration of the domestic partnership relationship in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A declaration of domestic partnership shall contain the name and address of each domestic partner, the signature of each partner, and each partner shall swear or affirm under penalty of perjury that:<section prefix='(1)'>Each person is at least eighteen (18) years old and competent to contract;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Neither person is married under Florida law, a partner to another domestic partnership relationship or a member of another civil union;</section><section prefix='(3)'>They are not related by blood;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Each person considers himself or herself to be a member of the immediate family of the other partner and to be jointly responsible for maintaining and supporting the registered domestic partnership.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Each person agrees to immediately notify the Consumer Services Department, in writing, if the terms of the Registered Domestic Partnership are no longer applicable or one (1) of the domestic partners wishes to terminate the domestic partnership.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The partners reside in the same primary residence.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Any partner to a domestic partnership may file an amendment to the domestic partnership certificate issued by the Consumer Services Department to reflect a change in his or her legal name or address, or to add or delete children.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-61, ยง 1, 5-20-08)</history></law>