<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002142</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-2. Definitions.<section>The definitions set out herein shall apply to articles II, III, IV and V:<section prefix='(1)'>Age shall mean the chronological age of any individual who is eighteen (18) years or older.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Commission shall mean the Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights or its successor.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Complaint shall mean any written allegation of a discriminatory act or practice prohibited by this chapter.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Complainant shall mean any person or persons alleging a discriminatory act or practice prohibited by this chapter that has occurred or is about to occur and who has filed a written complaint.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Conciliation Agreement shall mean a written agreement resolving or otherwise disposing of a complaint and which is entered into by the parties and the Director prior to a hearing in front of the board.</section><section prefix='(6)'>County shall mean Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Director shall mean the Director of the Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights or his or her designee.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Discrimination shall mean any difference, distinction or preference in treatment, access or impact because of race, color, religion, ancestry, national origin, sex, pregnancy, age, disability, marital status, familial status, sexual orientation, or source of income.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Familial status is established when:<section prefix='(a)'>An individual who has not attained the age of eighteen (18) years is domiciled with a parent or other person having legal custody of such individual; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>An individual who has not attained the age of eighteen (18) years is domiciled with a designee of a parent or other person having legal custody of such individual with the written permission of such parent or other person; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>An individual becomes pregnant or is in the process of securing legal custody of any individual who has not attained the age of eighteen (18) years.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Family shall include a single individual.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Finding related to probable cause shall mean the conclusion reached by the Director after completion of an investigation as to whether or not the discriminatory act or practice alleged in the complaint occurred and shall consist of the final investigative report and recommended order.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Marital status shall mean the state of being married, unmarried, single, divorced, separated or widowed, and the conditions that may be associated therewith, including pregnancy or parenthood.</section><section prefix='(13)'>National origin shall include citizenship status, ancestry, place of birth, and language characteristics thereof.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Person shall mean one (1) or more natural persons, individuals, employees, employers, employment agencies, owners, businesses, government, government agencies, government departments, unions, joint apprenticeship committees, firms, associations, joint ventures, partnerships, estates, trusts, trustees, trustees in bankruptcy, legal representative, mutual companies, joint-stock companies, receivers, syndicates, fiduciaries, corporations, unincorporated organizations, and all other groups or combinations.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Person with a disability<section prefix='(a)'>"Person with a disability" shall mean:<section prefix='(i)'>An individual with a physical or mental impairment which substantially limits one (1) or more of that individual's major life activities;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>An individual who has a record of such impairment; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>An individual who is perceived or regarded as having such an impairment.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>"Physical or mental impairment" shall include:<section prefix='(i)'>Any physiological disorder or condition, cosmetic disfigurement, or anatomical loss affecting one (1) or more of the following body systems: neurological, musculo-skeletal, special sense organs, cardiovascular, reproductive, digestive, genitourinary, hemic or lymphatic, skin, and endocrine;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Any mental or psychological disorder, such as intellectual disability, organic brain syndrome, emotional or mental illness, and specific learning disabilities; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Any degree of paralysis, epilepsy, lack of physical coordination, blindness or visual impairment, deafness or hearing impairment, muteness, speech impediment or persons who rely upon a seeing eye dog, wheelchair or other remedial method, appliance or device.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>"Major life activities" shall include functions such as caring for one's self, performing manual tasks, walking, seeing, hearing, speaking, learning and working.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A "record of such impairment" shall include having a history of, or having been misclassified as having a history of, physical or mental impairment which substantially limits one (1) or more major life activities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>"Individual who is perceived as or regarded as having a disability" shall mean any individual who:<section prefix='(i)'>Has a physical or mental impairment that does not substantially limit one (1) or more major life activities but such impairment is treated by others as constituting such a limitation;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Has a physical or mental disability that substantially limits one (1) or more major life activities only as a result of the attitude of others toward such impairment; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Has no impairment defined in this subsection but is treated by another as having such an impairment.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>"Disability" does not include current, illegal use of or addiction to a controlled substance as defined in Chapter 893, Florida Statutes, as amended.</section></section><section prefix='(16)'>Religion shall mean any belief protected by the free exercise clause of the First Amendment of the United States Constitution.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Respondent shall mean person or persons alleged to have engaged in a discriminatory act or practice prohibited by this chapter.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Sexual orientation shall mean heterosexuality, homosexuality or bisexuality whether such orientation is real or perceived.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Mediation shall mean an informal conference held with a neutral third party to help the parties resolve their disputes prior to the investigation of the complaint, or at any time during the investigation of the complaint.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Hearing officer shall mean an employee of the Division of Administrative Hearings within the State of Florida, Department of Administration, employed to conduct hearings pursuant to F.S. chapter 120, or other person selected by the Chairperson of the Commission on Human Rights, or his or her designee, to conduct a hearing pursuant to this chapter from a pool of hearing officers, who are members of the Florida Bar in good standing. The hearing officers shall serve for a term of two (2) years and shall not be entitled to compensation; however, they shall receive reimbursement for parking in county garages and for mileage for any hearing-related business. Such reimbursement shall be consistent with County policy.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Prevailing party shall have the same meaning as such term has in section 722 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (42 U.S.C. 1988).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, § 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 98-170, § 1, 12-1-98; Ord. No. 06-179, § 2, 12-5-06; Ord. No. 09-53, § 2, 6-30-09; Ord. No. 13-83, § 5, 9-17-13)</history></law>