<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PUBLIC ACCOMMODATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-22</section_number>
<catch_line>Exceptions to unlawful public accommodations practices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002164</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-22. Exceptions to unlawful public accommodations practices.<section prefix='(1)'>The provisions of this article shall not apply to a club or other establishment not in fact open to the public which proves it is in its nature distinctly private except as provided below.</section><section prefix='(2)'>An institution, club facility or place of accommodation shall not be considered in its nature distinctly private if it has more than four hundred (400) members, provides regular meal service and regularly receives payment for dues, fees, use of space, facilities, services, meals or beverages directly or indirectly from or on behalf of nonmembers for the furtherance of trade or business.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any place of accommodation which is required as a result of this section to construct or reconstruct locker room, shower, or other facilities shall be allowed until October 1, 1990 to complete such work, and prior to such date shall not be found guilty of sex discrimination. The board, for good cause shown, may grant an extension not to exceed an additional ninety (90) days after the date allowed such place of accommodation to complete such work.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The foregoing provisions notwithstanding, this article shall not apply, with respect to sex, to places of public accommodation where the Board of County Commissioners grants an exemption based on bona fide considerations of public policy.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Nothing in this article shall apply with respect to a religious organization, association, society or any non-profit institution or organization operated, supervised or controlled by or in conjunction with any such group, from limiting its goods, facilities, services, privileges or advantages to persons of the same religion or from giving preference to any such person, however, that religious organization, association or society shall not restrict membership based on race, color, national origin, ancestry, sex, pregnancy, age, marital status, familial status or disability. Furthermore, nothing in this article relating to unlawful public accommodation practices based on sexual orientation shall pertain to any religious organization, association, society or any non-profit institution or organization operated, supervised or controlled by or in conjunction with a religious organization, association or society.</section><section prefix='(6)'>It is not the policy of Miami-Dade County to prohibit bona fide discount programs based on age classification so long as such programs are not designed, intended or used to deny an individual or group either access to the premises, the right to reside on the premises, or the right to patronize the premises.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 98-170, ยง 1, 12-1-98; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 15, 12-5-06)</history></law>