<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. DOMESTIC LEAVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-60</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002198</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-60. Definitions.<section>As used in this article:<section prefix='(1)'>Commission shall mean the Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Director shall mean the Director of Miami-Dade County Commission on Human Rights.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Domestic violence shall mean a pattern of coercive behavior used by one (1) person to control another such as but not limited to: physical, sexual, emotional and psychological violence and abuse; threats; intimidation; verbal abuse; economic control; and stalking; and as defined in Sections 741.28, 784.046 and 784.048 of Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Employee shall mean a person who has been employed by the employer in Miami-Dade County for at least ninety (90) days and for at least three hundred and eight (308) hours of service with such employer during the previous ninety (90) days.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Employer shall mean a person defined in 11A-29 of this Chapter which has in the regular course of business fifty (50) or more employees working in Miami-Dade County for each working day during each of twenty (20) or more calendar work weeks in the current or preceding calendar year.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Perpetrator shall mean a person who engages in domestic or repeat violence against another person(s).</section><section prefix='(7)'>Victim of domestic or repeat violence shall mean a person who is subjected to domestic or repeat violence by a perpetrator.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-05, ยง1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 19, 6-30-09)</history></law>