<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. HOUSING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Unlawful housing practices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002152</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-12. Unlawful housing practices.<section prefix='(1)'>Discrimination in sale or rental of housing and other prohibited practices. It shall be unlawful for any person, owner, financial institution, real estate broker, real estate agent or any representative of the above to engage in any of the following acts because of race, color, religion, ancestry, national origin, age, sex, pregnancy, disability, marital status, familial status or sexual orientation of a prospective buyer, renter, lessee or any person associated with a prospective buyer, renter or lessee:<section prefix='(a)'>To refuse to sell, purchase, rent, lease, finance, negotiate or otherwise deny to or withhold any dwelling or to evict a person; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>To discriminate against a person in the terms, conditions, or privileges of the sale, purchase, rental or lease or any dwelling, or in the furnishing of facilities or services in connection therewith; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>To refuse to receive or transmit a bona fide offer to sell, purchase, rent or lease any dwelling; or</section><section prefix='(d)'>To represent to a person that any dwelling is not available for inspection, sale, purchase, rental or lease when in fact it is so available, or to refuse to permit a person to inspect any dwelling; or</section><section prefix='(e)'>To refuse to lend money, whether or not secured by mortgage, or otherwise refuse to make funds available for the purchase, acquisition, construction, alteration, improvement, repair or maintenance of any dwelling, to impose different terms or conditions of such financing or refuse to provide title or insurance relating to the ownership or use of any interest in any dwelling, or to refuse to provide appraisal or brokerage services; or</section><section prefix='(f)'>To refuse to purchase loans, debts, or securities which support the purchase, construction, improvement, repair or maintenance of a dwelling or which are secured by residential real estate or to impose different terms or conditions for such purchases; or</section><section prefix='(g)'>To make, publish, print, circulate, post, mail, or cause to be made, published, printed, circulated, posted or mailed, any notice, statement or advertisement, or to announce a policy, or to sign or to use a form of application for the sale, purchase, rental, lease or financing of any dwelling, or to make a record of inquiry in connection with the prospective sale, purchase, rental, lease or financing of any housing accommodation which indicates any discrimination, any discriminatory preference, any intent to discriminate or any intent to make a discriminatory preference; or</section><section prefix='(h)'>To discriminate in any financial transaction involving real property because of its location, or to "red-line"; or</section><section prefix='(i)'>To offer, solicit, accept or use a listing of any dwelling for sale, purchase, rental or lease with the understanding that a person may be subjected to discrimination in connection with such sale, purchase, rental, lease, or the furnishing of facilities or services in connection therewith; or</section><section prefix='(j)'>To directly or indirectly induce or attempt to induce for profit, the sale, purchase, rental, lease or the listing for any of the above, of any dwelling by representing that the presence or anticipated presence of a person of a particular race, color, religion, national origin, age, sex, disability, familial status, marital status or sexual orientation will or may result in blockbusting, such as but not limited to:<section prefix='(i)'>The lowering of property values in the area;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>An increase in criminal or anti-social behavior in the area; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>A decline in the quality of the schools or other services or facilities in the area; or</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>To make any representations concerning the listing for sale, purchase, rental, or lease, or the anticipated listing of any sale, purchase, rental, or lease of any dwelling for the purpose of inducing or attempting to induce any such listing for any of the above transactions; or</section><section prefix='(l)'>To engage in or hire to be done, or to conspire with others to commit acts or activities of any nature, the purpose of which is to coerce, cause panic, incite unrest, or create or play upon fear with the purpose of either discouraging or inducing, or attempting to induce, the sale, purchase, rental, lease or listing of any dwelling on any basis prohibited by this chapter; or</section><section prefix='(m)'>To aid, abet, incite, compel or coerce any person to engage in any of the practices prohibited by this chapter, or to obstruct or prevent any person from complying with the provisions of this chapter or any other issued thereunder; or</section><section prefix='(n)'>To resist, prevent, impede or interfere with the Commission on Human Rights, its members and/or representatives in the lawful performance of their duties under this chapter; or</section><section prefix='(o)'>To canvas to commit any unlawful practice prohibited by this chapter; or</section><section prefix='(p)'>To deny or withhold any dwelling from a person on any basis prohibited by this chapter, or</section><section prefix='(q)'>To deny any qualified person access to or membership in or participation in any multiple-listing service, real estate brokers' organization, or other service, organization, or facility relating to the business of selling or renting dwellings, or to discriminate against such person in the terms or conditions of such access, membership, or participation on any basis prohibited by this chapter; or</section><section prefix='(r)'>To coerce, intimidate, make threats, or harass people who have aided or encouraged any other person in the exercise or enjoyment of any right granted or protected by this article.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Reasonable modification and reasonable accommodation for disabled. It shall be a discriminatory housing practice to:<section prefix='(a)'>Refuse to permit, at the expense of a disabled person, reasonable modifications of existing premises occupied or to be occupied by such disabled person if such modifications may be necessary to afford such persons full enjoyment of the premises; except that in the case of a rental a landlord may, where it is reasonable to do so, condition permission for a modification on the renter agreeing to restore the interior of the premises to the condition that existed before the modification, reasonable wear and tear excepted;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Refuse to make a reasonable accommodation in rules, policies, practices or services, when such an accommodation may be necessary to afford a disabled person equal opportunity to use and enjoy the dwelling unit;</section><section prefix='(c)'>In connection with the design and construction of covered multifamily dwellings submitted for building permit on or after January 13, 1990 to fail to design and construct those housing accommodations in such a manner, that:<section prefix='(i)'>The public use and common use portions of such dwellings are readily accessible to and usable by disabled persons;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>All the doors designed to allow passage into and within all premises within such housing accommodations are sufficiently wide to allow passage by persons in wheelchairs; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>All premises within such accommodations contain the following features of an adaptive design:<section prefix='(I)'>An accessible route into and throughout the dwelling, unless it is impracticable to do so because of the terrain or unusual characteristics of the site;</section><section prefix='(II)'>Light switches, electrical outlets, thermostats and other environmental controls in accessible locations;</section><section prefix='(III)'>Reinforcements in the bathroom walls to allow later installation of grab bars; and</section><section prefix='(IV)'>Usable kitchens and bathrooms such that an individual in a wheelchair can maneuver about the space.</section></section><section prefix='(iv)'>As used in this section, "covered multifamily dwelling" means a building which consists of four (4) or more dwelling units and has one (1) or more elevators; or the ground floor dwelling units of a building which consists of four (4) or more dwelling units and does not have an elevator.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Compliance with the appropriate requirements of the American National Standards Institute for buildings and facilities providing accessibility and usability for physically handicapped persons, commonly cited as "ANSI A117.1 (1986)" suffices to satisfy the requirements of this Subsection (c). Public areas shall also comply with the standards set forth in the Americans with Disabilities Act Accessibility Guidelines.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Nothing in this subsection requires that a dwelling be made available to an individual whose tenancy would constitute a direct threat to the health or safety of other individuals or whose tenancy would result in substantial physical damage to the property of others.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Parking accessibility for disabled.<section prefix='(a)'>If parking is provided at the dwelling site then designated accessible parking at the dwelling unit or parking most convenient to the entrance served, shall be provided on request of residents with disabilities on the same terms and with the full range of choices (for example surface parking or garage) that are provided for other residents of the dwelling site. Accessible parking on a route accessible to wheelchairs shall be in a number at least equal to one (1) and not less than two (2) percent of the total number of covered dwelling units. Accessible visitor parking shall be provided sufficient to provide access to grade level entrances of covered multifamily dwellings and accessible parking at facilities (for example, swimming pools) that serve accessible buildings shall also be provided.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To meet the requirements of this chapter, those accessible resident spaces required in new construction must meet the width requirements specified for accessible spaces under Section 316.1955, Florida Statutes, as amended, or its successor and be adjacent to a five-foot access aisle on the same level. The slope of the spaces, and the portion of the access aisles adjacent to the spaces, shall not exceed two (2) percent in any direction. It shall not be required that the spaces be outlined in blue nor is it required to have a sign stating "parking by disabled permit only," unless such signs and striping are necessary to effectively reserve those spaces for the individuals to whom they are assigned. The spaces may be temporarily assigned to persons who do not have disabilities. A written policy must be provided to all residents who purchase or rent dwelling units stating that those spaces will be assigned or reassigned as a reasonable accommodation to residents with disabilities on the basis of need.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When the space is assigned to a resident with a disability the space must be marked in a manner that will effectively reserve that space for the individual to whom it is assigned. Where visitor or guest parking is provided at a residential building, parking for persons with disabilities shall be provided in the same numbers and with the same configuration and specifications as required in Section 316.1955, Florida Statutes, with the following exceptions. Where all of the spaces provided for visitors provide relatively equal convenience to the building served, are level, meet the width requirements specified for accessible spaces under Section 316.1955, Florida Statutes, are on an accessible route to the building, and have an adjacent access aisle at least five (5) feet wide on the same level, then no visitor spaces need to be marked or signed or otherwise reserved for visitors with disabilities.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 98-170, ยง 1, 12-1-98; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 10, 12-5-06; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 11, 6-30-09)</history></law>