<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and powers of the Commisssion.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002145</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-5. Duties and powers of the Commisssion.<section>The Commission on Human Rights shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:<section prefix='(1)'>To apply to the appropriate court on behalf of the County for such temporary or permanent injunctive relief as the Commission, or a Hearing Panel thereof, believe is necessary to preserve the status quo or to prevent irreparable harm and to carry out the purposes of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(2)'>To adopt, promulgate, amend and rescind rules and regulations necessary to effectuate the purposes and provisions of this chapter following a public hearing and subject to approval by the County Commission;</section><section prefix='(3)'>To issue an adjudicative final order upon the authority of the Chairperson following approval by the appropriate Hearing Panel. Such an adjudicative final order may review and uphold, modify or reverse recommended final orders issued by the Director or his or her designated representative in accordance with the provisions of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(4)'>To administer oaths;</section><section prefix='(5)'>To compel, by subpoena issued by the Chairperson of the Commission, the attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence for discovery, investigation, hearing or deposition for the preservation of testimony;</section><section prefix='(6)'>To issue remedial orders requiring cessation of violations of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(7)'>To issue such other final orders as, in the judgment of the Hearing Panel, will carry out the purposes of this chapter, including but not limited to:<section prefix='(a)'>Hiring, reinstatement or promotion of employees with accrued seniority, with accrued benefits and with back pay;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Taking affirmative action and making corrections; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Requiring reasonable accommodation;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Awarding of front pay, to the extent that the calculation of any such front pay is quantifiable and reasonably definite.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>To issue final orders dismissing the complaint;</section><section prefix='(9)'>To award quantifiable relief to a prevailing complainant for injuries incurred as a proximate result of an act prohibited by this chapter or to apply to the appropriate court for such an award, provided that such damages are not prohibited by state or federal law;</section><section prefix='(10)'>To award costs and Attorney's fees to a prevailing party or to apply to the appropriate court for such an award; provided, however, that such an award is not contrary to the purposes of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(11)'>To award prejudgment interest to a prevailing party upon a finding of employment discrimination and post judgment interest to a prevailing party upon a finding of any type of discrimination, or to apply to the appropriate court for such an award;</section><section prefix='(12)'>At the conclusion of a hearing and upon a finding of housing discrimination in violation of Article II of this chapter, to recommend that the County Attorney commence a civil action on behalf of the County for fines pursuant to Section 11A-17</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 5, 12-5-06; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 5, 6-30-09)</history></law>