<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Discretionary review; request for rehearing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002146</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-6. Discretionary review; request for rehearing.<section prefix='(1)'>Within fifteen (15) days following the issuance of the final adjudicative order, a party may file a written request for rehearing of a case or amendment of a final order by the Commission on Human Rights. A request for rehearing shall state with particularity the factors overlooked or misapprehended by the original hearing panel, and shall not reargue the merits of the case. The nonmoving party may file a written response within ten (10) days of receipt of the written request for rehearing.</section><section prefix='(2)'>At the first regularly scheduled meeting following the receipt of such a request, the members of the original Hearing Panel shall vote on whether to grant the request for rehearing.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If the request for rehearing is granted, the Commission shall expeditiously schedule a hearing. At least five (5) members shall constitute a Hearing Panel for the purpose of such rehearing.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Upon the conclusion of rehearing, the rehearing panel shall issue a new adjudicative final order which may affirm, modify, rescind or reverse the final adjudicative order issued by the original Hearing Panel.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The filing of a request for rehearing shall toll the time for commencing an appeal pursuant to Section 11A-8</section><section prefix='(6)'>No appeal to the Commission shall be had from a denial of a request for rehearing.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 06-179, ยง 6, 12-5-06; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 6, 6-30-09)</history></law>