<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. DOMESTIC PARTNERS AND FAMILY HEALTH COVERAGE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-70</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative findings and purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002207</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-70. Legislative findings and purpose.<section prefix='(a)'>The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners finds that a significant number of Miami-Dade residents establish and maintain important personal, emotional, and economic relationships with persons to whom they are not married. Individuals forming such domestic partnerships often live in a committed family relationship. Domestic partners may be denied the right to visit each other or their children or parents when hospitalized or incarcerated for lack of a system that establishes rights of visitation in such circumstances. Also, partners in domestic relationships may be denied public and private sector benefits because there is no established system for such relationships to be registered or recognized. In addition, because of the status of their relationship, domestic partners in many cases are not extended certain employment benefits that are otherwise made available to other employees.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners finds that employment benefits form an essential portion of the compensation provided to County employees.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners acknowledges that in 1994 over three million (3,000,000) Americans identified themselves as living in a domestic partnership. As a result, employers have begun to provide domestic partner benefits in greater numbers.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners finds that the provision of domestic partner benefits promotes employee recruitment, employee retention, and employee loyalty. Furthermore, the provision of such benefits promotes fairness and serves to address the discriminatory effect of practices which deny such benefits solely upon the basis of an employee's familial or marital status.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The rules developed to implement the provisions of this ordinance shall be liberally construed to accomplish the policies and purposes of the ordinance. However, this ordinance shall not be construed to supersede any federal, state, or county laws or regulations, nor shall this ordinance be interpreted in a manner as to bring it into conflict with federal, state, or other county laws. Nothing in this ordinance shall be construed as recognizing or treating a domestic partnership as a marriage.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-61, ยง 1, 5-20-08)</history></law>