<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. HOUSING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Election of judicial determination.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002156</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11A-16. Election of judicial determination.<section prefix='(1)'>This section shall pertain only to those housing discrimination complaints filed under Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968, as amended that result in the Director issuing a finding that probable cause exists to believe that a discriminatory act has occurred or is about to occur.</section><section prefix='(2)'>When the Director issues a finding that probable cause exists to believe that a discriminatory act has occurred or is about to occur under Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968, as amended, the complainant may elect to have the discrimination findings decided in a civil action by a court of competent jurisdiction in lieu of a hearing by the Commission as prescribed in Section 11A-14(9).</section><section prefix='(3)'>The decision to elect a civil action in lieu of a hearing by the Commission or a Hearing Officer must be made not later than twenty (20) days after the receipt of the Director's finding related to probable cause. The person who elects to pursue a civil action shall give notice of this election to the Commission, and to all other complainants and respondents to whom the complaint relates.</section><section prefix='(4)'>If the decision to elect a civil action is made, then the Commission shall authorize the election, and the Director shall provide complainant with an Attorney without cost to the complainant. Such Attorney shall commence a civil action on behalf of the complainant not later than thirty (30) days after election for civil action is made.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Any person aggrieved by the alleged discriminatory housing practices to be determined in the civil action may intervene as of right in that civil action.</section><section prefix='(6)'>If the court finds that a discriminatory housing practice has occurred or is about to occur, the court may award to the complainant actual and punitive damages, court costs and reasonable Attorney fees and may grant any relief such as permanent or temporary injunction, temporary restraining order, or other order as may be appropriate.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-17, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 09-53, ยง 14, 6-30-09)</history></law>