<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='2'>Chapter 11B DUMPS AND LANDFILL SITES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11B-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Bond required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002225</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11B-9. Bond required.<section prefix='(a)'>No permit herein required shall be issued unless there is filed at the time of application therefor a cash bond or a bond with a corporate surety in the amount of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) to assure that: (1) the permittee will operate the dump or landfill site in accordance with the conditions and requirements of this chapter and will comply with all of the conditions and requirements of this chapter; and (2) the permittee shall reimburse Dade County, in accordance with Section 11B-14 of this chapter, for any and all expenses and costs which Dade County may incur as a result of extinguishing any fire in the dump or landfill site which the permittee has either failed to extinguish or is unable to extinguish within the time specified in Section 11B-10(b) of this chapter, or which Dade County is requested to extinguish by the permittee; provided, however, that no municipality shall be required to secure and file the bond herein required.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Before a corporate bond is accepted by the County Manager as being in compliance with this section, the bond shall be reviewed and approved by the Dade County Insurance and Safety Division, and shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. A corporate bond shall be executed by a corporation authorized to do business in the State of Florida as a surety. A cash bond shall be deposited with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, who shall give receipt therefor.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-81, ยง 5, 11-19-69)</history></law>