<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='2'>Chapter 11B DUMPS AND LANDFILL SITES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11B-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Application for permit; issuance of permit; fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002224</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11B-8. Application for permit; issuance of permit; fees.<section prefix='(a)'>All applications for permits for a dump or landfill site shall be filed with the County Manager and shall contain the full name and address of the applicant; a description and survey of the land to be used as a dump or landfill site; a description of the sequence and plan of operation; the location of a working, nonpay telephone which satisfies the requirement of Section 11B-12(1) of this chapter; the size and type of fencing which satisfies the requirement of Section 11B-12(2) of this chapter; the availability, size and type of equipment for fire control purposes which satisfies the requirement of Sections 11B-12(3) and (4) of this chapter; plans for fire, nuisance and vermin control; existing and proposed roadways and easements; existing topography and watercourses, together with a diagram and written statement explaining proposed location and extent of earthwork and fill operations; and the proposed estimated daily or weekly volume of waste materials to be deposited thereon. The application shall contain an agreement to hold Dade County harmless from any and all claims, liabilities, costs or damages arising out of the issuance of the permit and the operation of the dump or landfill site. The application shall be signed by the applicant and acknowledged in the manner prescribed by law.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Manager shall examine the application and shall be permitted access to the land on which the dump or landfill site is to be operated for purposes of his examination of such land. Upon determining that no violation of zoning, health, or other applicable State laws or County ordinances would be involved and upon determining that the requirement of Section 11B-9 of this chapter is satisfied and that the requirements of Section 11B-12 of this chapter are satisfied or can be satisfied, the County Manager shall issue the permit.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A schedule of filing fees to cover the cost of investigating and processing applications for permits shall be established by the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners and no application shall be issued until the appropriate filing fee for such permit is paid.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-81, ยง 4, 11-19-69)</history></law>