<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='2'>Chapter 11B DUMPS AND LANDFILL SITES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11B-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002218</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11B-2. Definitions.<section>As used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section:<section prefix='(1)'>Person shall include any individual, corporation, partnership, association, or municipality, and shall include any agent or employee thereof and shall include both singular and plural.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Permittee shall mean any person who has obtained a permit in the manner herein provided, and shall include any agent or employee of the permittee.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Combustible waste shall mean all waste substances capable of incineration or burning.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Refuse shall mean all waste substances including garbage as well as combustible and noncombustible wastes.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Dump or landfill site shall mean any land used for the purpose of permitting any person to deposit or make disposal thereon of any combustible waste or refuse, or any combination thereof, whether the land is used in such manner for profit or not; provided, however, "dump or landfill site" shall not include land upon which is deposited only rock, dirt, sand or any combination thereof.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Board shall mean the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board.</section><section prefix='(7)'>County Manager shall mean the County Manager of Dade County and shall include whatever person or department is designated by the County Manager to administer the provisions of this chapter.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-81, ยง 2, 11-19-69)</history></law>