<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='2'>Chapter 11B DUMPS AND LANDFILL SITES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11B-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum standards for operation of dump or landfill site.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002228</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11B-12. Minimum standards for operation of dump or landfill site.<section>In the operation of any dump or landfill site, the following requirements shall apply:<section prefix='(1)'>A working, nonpay telephone shall be located on the land to be used for the dump or landfill site, and shall be easily accessible. This requirement may be waived by the County Manager if the applicant demonstrates that a two-way radio in good working operation is installed in a vehicle which is used to patrol the premises on a twenty-four-hour basis, or if the applicant shall provide adequate transportation to carry the operator or watchman of the dump or landfill site to a working, nonpay telephone located in close proximity to the dump or landfill site.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Fencing, of a size and type adequate to restrict ingress or egress to the dump or landfill site by use of any access road, shall be installed; this requirement may be waived upon satisfactory showing that a watchman shall be on duty twenty-four hours a day to guard against unauthorized use of the dump or landfill site.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A water pump, in good working condition and of a capacity of at least five hundred (500) gallons per minute, shall be located on the land to be used as a dump or land fill site, and there shall be available sufficient hoses to be connected thereto by proper fittings to reach all portions of the land to be used as a dump or land fill site. A well, lake, stream or other source of water shall be available to supply water in sufficient quantity for the capacity of the water pump.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A bulldozer or other heavy earth-moving equipment shall be supplied and shall be of a size and weight capable of moving without difficulty the type of refuse deposited on the land to be used as a dump or land fill site. A person able to operate such equipment shall be on duty at all times, or shall be on call and able to respond to any call within one (1) hour of the call.</section><section prefix='(5)'>On no less than a monthly basis, the operators of all Class I disposal facilities permitted by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Regulation and not owned by Metropolitan Dade County shall submit to the County a report indicating the amount of solid waste disposed of by each user of the facility, which report must be delivered to the Department on a schedule and format to be prescribed by the Department.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-81, ยง 6, 11-19-69; Ord. No. 91-123, ยง 1, 10-15-91)</history></law>