<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='2'>Chapter 11C DEVELOPMENT WITHIN FLOOD HAZARD DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11C-17</section_number>
<catch_line>Required disclosure in contracts for sale of real estate.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002247</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11C-17. Required disclosure in contracts for sale of real estate.<section prefix='(a)'>In any contract for the sale of improved real estate located in unincorporated Metropolitan Miami-Dade County which is in a Coastal High Hazard Area, the seller shall include in the contract or a rider to the contract the following disclosure in not less than ten-point bold-faced type:<section>THIS HOME OR STRUCTURE IS LOCATED IN A COASTAL HIGH HAZARD AREA. IF THIS HOME OR STRUCTURE IS BELOW THE APPLICABLE FLOOD ELEVATION LEVEL AND IS SUBSTANTIALLY DAMAGED OR SUBSTANTIALLY IMPROVED, AS DEFINED IN CHAPTER 11C OF THE METROPOLITAN Miami-Dade COUNTY CODE, IT MAY, AMONG OTHER THINGS, BE REQUIRED TO BE RAISED TO THE APPLICABLE FLOOD ELEVATION LEVEL.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>In any contract for the sale of improved real estate located in unincorporated Metropolitan Miami-Dade County which is in a Special Flood Hazard Area, the seller shall include in the contract or a rider to the contract the following disclosure in not less than ten-point bold faced type:<section>THIS HOME OR STRUCTURE IS LOCATED IN A SPECIAL FLOOD HAZARD AREA. IF THIS HOME OR STRUCTURE IS BELOW THE APPLICABLE FLOOD ELEVATION LEVEL AND IS SUBSTANTIALLY DAMAGED OR SUBSTANTIALLY IMPROVED, AS DEFINED IN CHAPTER 11C OF THE METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY CODE, IT MAY, AMONG OTHER THINGS, BE REQUIRED TO BE RAISED TO THE APPLICABLE FLOOD ELEVATION LEVEL.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 93-21, ยง 1, 3-30-93)</history></law>