<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='2'>Chapter 11C DEVELOPMENT WITHIN FLOOD HAZARD DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11C-16</section_number>
<catch_line>When chapter provisions effective.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002246</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11C-16. When chapter provisions effective.<section>The provisions of this chapter shall become effective on January 20, 1993. However:<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to those buildings for which a building permit has been issued and is in effect or for which proper and complete applications and plans have been submitted for building permits on or before the effective date of this chapter provided that the construction under the permit shall be commenced and progressively carried to a conclusion within the time limitations for permits established in Section 304.3 of the South Florida Building Code. Furthermore, the provisions of this chapter shall not apply to buildings for which:<section prefix='(1)'>Plans and specifications as required by Section 302.2, South Florida Building Code, were in actual preparation prior to December 20, 1992; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Said plans and specifications were substantially completed by December 31, 1992; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Applications for building permits, accompanied by said plans and specifications, as completed, have been submitted for building permits prior to January 10, 1993; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Construction under said building permits is commenced and progressively carried to a conclusion within the time limitations for permits established in Section 304.3 of the South Florida Building Code.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>For the purpose of this section, the burden shall be on the applicant to submit to the Department of Environmental Resources Management, competent, substantial evidence establishing compliance with these provisions. Such evidence may include affidavits sworn to under oath by registered professional Florida architects or engineers; dated work sheets of such architects or engineers; invoices; contracts and other tangible documentary evidence establishing compliance herewith. The term "substantially completed" shall mean that the plans and specifications referred to hereinabove are fifty (50) percent or more completed as of December 20, 1992.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Determinations by the director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management, pursuant to this section, may be appealed to the Environmental Quality Control Board in accordance with the provisions of Section 24-6 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-75, ยง 1, 11-3-87; Ord. No. 92-150, ยง 1, 12-1-92)</history></law>