<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='2'>Chapter 11C DEVELOPMENT WITHIN FLOOD HAZARD DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11C-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Statement of legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002231</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11C-1. Statement of legislative intent.<section>The coastal areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida, are subject to flooding resulting in danger to life, loss of property, health and safety hazards, disruption of commerce and governmental services, extraordinary public expenditures for flood protection and relief, and impairment of the tax base, all of which adversely affect the public health, safety and general welfare. The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, by Resolution No. R-671-69, adopted on May 28, 1969, expressed willingness to take action necessary to meet the objectives of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 within Miami-Dade County, Florida; and by Resolution No. R-912-70, adopted on July 24, 1970, reaffirmed its interest in securing flood insurance coverage under said act, and agreed to establish by December 31, 1971, measures required under the Federal Insurance Program. In August of 1970, the Federal Insurance Administration declared the entire area of Miami-Dade County eligible for federally assisted flood insurance, which insurance will mitigate the effects of damages from such natural disasters as hurricanes and severe storms and their attendant flooding. This chapter is adopted to insure the continued availability of said flood insurance; to comply with federally imposed requirements; and to protect the public health, safety and general welfare, by minimizing flood losses in the coastal areas of Miami-Dade County, and to require that uses vulnerable to floods, including facilities which serve such uses, be protected against flood damage at the time of initial construction; control the alteration of natural floodplains, stream channels, and natural protective barriers which are involved in the accommodation of floodwaters; control filling, grading, dredging and other development which may increase erosion or flood damage; and to insure that potential home buyers are notified that property is in a flood area.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-75, ยง 1, 11-3-87; Ord. No. 92-150, ยง 1, 12-1-92; Ord. No. 09-66, ยง 1, 7-21-09)</history></law>