<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='2'>Chapter 11C DEVELOPMENT WITHIN FLOOD HAZARD DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11C-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Development within Coastal High Hazard Areas (CHH).</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002234</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11C-4. Development within Coastal High Hazard Areas (CHH).<section prefix='(a)'>Existing uses located on land in a CHH Area which is below the elevation of the regulatory flood shall not be expanded and no building permit referred to in Section 11C-3 of this chapter may be issued therefor unless the provisions of subsection (b) hereof are complied with.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No new construction or substantial improvement shall be undertaken and no building permit referred to in Section 11C-3 may be issued therefor upon any lands within CHH Areas which are below the level of the regulatory flood unless said new construction or substantial improvement:<section prefix='(1)'>Is located landward of the reach of the mean high tide; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Is elevated on adequately anchored pilings or columns, and securely anchored to such piles or columns so that the lowest portion of the structural members of the lowest floor (excluding the pilings or columns) is elevated at or above the regulatory flood level.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>There shall be no fill used as structural support. Noncompacted fill may be used around the perimeter of a building for landscaping/aesthetic purposes provided the fill will wash out from storm surge (thereby rendering the building free of obstruction) prior to generating excessive loading forces, ramping effects, or wave deflection. The County shall approve design plans for landscaping/aesthetic fill only after the applicant has provided an analysis by an engineer, architect, and/or soil scientist which demonstrates that the following factors have been fully considered:<section prefix='(1)'>Particle composition of fill material does not have a tendency toward excessive natural compaction;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Volume and distribution of fill will not cause wave deflection to adjacent properties; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Slope of fill will not cause wave run-up or ramping.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>No man-made alteration of sand dunes or mangrove stands which will increase potential flood damage shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Lattice work or decorative screening shall be allowed below the base flood elevation provided it is not part of the structural support of the building and is designed so as to breakaway under abnormally high tides or wave action without damage to the structural integrity of the building on which it is to be used and provided the following design specifications are met:<section prefix='(1)'>Material shall consist of lattice, mesh screening or unreinforced concrete block and shall satisfy all provisions in Section 11C-2(h).</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>If aesthetic lattice work screening or unreinforced concrete block (breakaway walls) is utilized, such enclosed space shall not be designed for human habitation, but shall be designed to be used only for parking of vehicles, building access, or limited storage of maintenance equipment used in connection with the premises. Areas enclosed by unreinforced concrete block (breakaway walls) exceeding two hundred ninety-nine (299) square feet in size will be considered the lowest floor for flood insurance purposes and therefore higher insurance premiums will result.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Prior to construction, plans for any structures that will have lattice work or decorative screening or a breakaway wall, shall be submitted to the county official for approval.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Any alteration, repair, reconstruction or improvement to a structure shall not enclose the space below the lowest floor except with lattice work, decorative screening, as provided for in Section 11C-4(e), or concrete as provided by Section 11C-2(h).</section><section prefix='(i)'>A registered professional engineer or architect shall certify that the structure is securely anchored to adequately anchored pilings or columns to withstand velocity waters and hurricane wave wash.</section><section prefix='(j)'>No manufactured homes, except in existing manufactured home parks and manufactured home subdivisions, shall be placed within this zone, provided all of the anchoring and elevation standards of Sections 11C-4(i) and 11C-4(b)(2) are met.</section><section prefix='(k)'>All recreational vehicles placed within this area shall either:<section prefix='(1)'>Be fully licensed and ready for highway use; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>The recreational vehicle shall meet all the requirements for new construction, including anchoring and elevation requirements of Sections 11C-4(i) and 11C-4(b)(2); or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Be on the site for fewer than one hundred eighty (180) consecutive days. A recreational vehicle is ready for highway use if it is on its wheels or jacking system, is attached to the site only by quick disconnect type utilities and security devices and has no permanently attached structures.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-75, ยง 1, 11-3-87; Ord. No. 92-150, ยง 1, 12-1-92)</history></law>