<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='2'>Chapter 11C DEVELOPMENT WITHIN FLOOD HAZARD DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11C-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Development within Special Flood Hazard (SFH) Areas.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002235</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11C-5. Development within Special Flood Hazard (SFH) Areas.<section prefix='(a)'>No new construction or substantial improvement of any residential structure or manufactured home shall be permitted in SFH Areas, and no building permit referred to in Section 11C-3 of this chapter shall be issued therefor, unless said new construction or substantial improvement has the lowest floor (including basement) elevated to or above the level of the regulatory flood (100-year flood). Electrical, plumbing and other attendant utilities are prohibited below the base flood elevation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No new construction or substantial improvement of any nonresidential structure shall be permitted in SFH Areas, and no building permit referred to in Section 11C-3 of this chapter shall be issued therefor, unless said new construction or substantial improvement has the lowest floor (including basement) elevated to or above the level of the regulatory flood (one-hundred-year flood), or if the lowest permitted floor level of such nonresidential structure (including basement) is below the regulatory flood level then such nonresidential structure together with attendant utility and sanitary facilities shall be floodproofed up to one (1) foot above the level of the regulatory flood; provided that the lowest floor level of such nonresidential structure (including basement) shall be not more than ten (10) feet below the regulatory flood level.</section><section>Where floodproofing is utilized for a particular structure, a registered professional engineer or architect shall certify that the floodproofing methods are adequate to withstand the flood depth, pressures, velocities, impact and uplift forces associated with the base flood, and a record of such certificates indicating the specific elevation (in relation to mean sea level) to which such structures are floodproofed shall be maintained with the designated official.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All manufactured homes placed, or substantially improved, on individual lots or parcels, in expansions to existing manufactured home parks or subdivisions, and in new manufactured home parks, shall meet all of the requirements for new construction, including elevation and anchoring.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All manufactured homes placed or substantially improved in an existing manufactured home park or subdivision shall be elevated so that:<section prefix='(1)'>The lowest floor of the manufactured home is elevated no lower than the level of the base flood elevation; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>The manufactured home chassis is supported by reinforced piers or other foundation elements of at least an equivalent strength, of no less than thirty-six (36) inches in height above grade.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The manufactured home shall be securely anchored to the adequately anchored foundation system to resist flotation, collapse and lateral movement.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In an existing manufactured home park or subdivision in which a manufactured home has incurred "substantial damage" as the result of a flood, any manufactured home placed or substantially improved shall meet the standards of Section 11C-5(d)(1) and (3).</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>All recreational vehicles placed on sites shall meet the requirements of Section 11C-4(k).</section><section prefix='(f)'>Elevated buildings. New construction or substantial improvements of elevated buildings that include fully enclosed areas formed by foundations and other exterior walls below the base flood elevation shall be designed to preclude finished living space except allowable uses i.e. parking, limited storage and building access and shall be designed to allow for the entry and exit of floodwaters to automatically equalize hydrostatic flood forces on exterior walls. Designs for complying with this requirement must either be certified by a professional engineer or architect or meet the following minimum criteria:<section prefix='(1)'>Provide a minimum of two (2) openings having a total net area of not less than one (1) square inch for every square foot of enclosed area subject to flooding;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The bottom of all openings shall be no higher than one (1) foot above grade; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Openings may be equipped with screens, louvers, valves or other coverings or devices provided they permit the automatic flow of floodwaters in both directions;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Electrical, plumbing, and other utility connections are prohibited below the base flood elevation;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Access to the enclosed area shall be the minimum necessary to allow for parking of vehicles (garage door) or limited storage of maintenance equipment used in connection with the premises (standard exterior door) or entry to the living area (stairway or elevator); and</section><section prefix='(6)'>The interior portion of such enclosed area shall not be partitioned or finished into separate rooms or air conditioned.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Floodways. Located within areas of special flood hazard are areas designated as floodways. Since the floodway is an extremely hazardous area due to the velocity of floodwaters which carry debris and potential projectiles and has erosion potential, the following provisions shall apply:<section prefix='(1)'>Prohibit encroachments, including fill, new construction, substantial improvements and other developments unless certification (with supporting technical data) by a registered professional engineer is provided demonstrating that encroachments shall not result in any increase in flood levels during occurrence of the base flood discharge;</section><section prefix='(2)'>If Section 11C-5(f)(1) is satisfied, all new construction and substantial improvements shall comply with all applicable flood hazard reduction provisions of Section 11C-5</section><section prefix='(3)'>Prohibit the placement of manufactured homes (mobile homes), except in an existing manufactured home (mobile home) park or subdivision. A replacement manufactured home may be placed on a lot in an existing manufactured home park or subdivision provided the anchoring standards of Section 11C-5(c) and (d) and the elevation standards of Section 11C-5(a) are met.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-75, ยง 1, 11-3-87; Ord. No. 92-150, ยง 1, 12-1-92)</history></law>