<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='2'>Chapter 11C DEVELOPMENT WITHIN FLOOD HAZARD DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11C-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Application of chapter.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002237</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11C-7. Application of chapter.<section prefix='(a)'>This chapter shall apply to and be enforced in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Flood Insurance Rate Map (FIRM) for Miami-Dade County, as amended effective November 4, 1987, together with the Flood Insurance Study (FIS) therein, and as amended effective January 20, 1993 , July 17, 1995, and as amended effective September 11, 2009, together with the Flood Insurance Study (FIS) therein, are hereby adopted and incorporated herein by reference hereto. The FIRM and FIS shall be kept on file, available to the public for public inspection and copying, in the offices of the Department of Planning and Zoning, Department of Environmental Resources Management and the Department of Public Works. Any changes, additions, or deletions to the FIRM or to the FIS for Miami-Dade County shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance. The County shall mail a courtesy notice of any change in the FIRM or to the FIS, as amended from time to time, to all property owners in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County affected by such change. Failure to mail or receive said courtesy notice shall not affect the validity of any such change or this chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The provisions of this chapter shall constitute minimum standards throughout unincorporated Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-75, § 1, 11-3-87; Ord. No. 92-150, § 1, 12-1-92; Ord. No. 95-129, § 1, 7-11-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 7, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 09-66, § 1, 7-21-09)</history></law>