<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00022' order_by='00022' level='2'>Chapter 11D DISEASED PALM TREES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11D-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Trees may be removed by County; lien for expenses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002254</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 11D-7. Trees may be removed by County; lien for expenses.<section>If within twenty (20) days after mailing of the notice no hearing has been requested and the trees described in the notice have not been removed, the Director of the Park and Recreation Department shall have the trees removed by Dade County at the expense of the property owner. If a hearing has been held and has concluded adversely to the property owner, the Director of the Park and Recreation Department shall have the trees removed by Dade County at the expense of the property owner.</section><section>After removal of the trees the Director of the Park and Recreation Department or the County Manager shall certify to the Director of Finance the expense incurred and shall include a copy of the notice above-described and a copy of the decision of the County Manager, or his designated assistant, if a hearing was held, whereupon such expense shall become payable within thirty (30) days, after which a special assessment lien and charge will be made upon the property, which shall be payable with interest at the rate of six (6) percent per annum from the date of such certification until paid.</section><section>Such lien shall be enforceable in the same manner as a tax lien in favor of Dade County and may be satisfied at any time by payment thereof including accrued interest. Upon such payment the Clerk of the Circuit Court shall, by appropriate means, evidence the satisfaction and cancellation of such lien upon the record thereof and notify the Tax Collector of such satisfaction. Notice of such lien shall be filed in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court and recorded among the public records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-99, ยง 7, 12-3-74)</history></law>