<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='2'>Chapter 12 ELECTIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>12-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Voter solicitation at polling places.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002265</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 12-10. Voter solicitation at polling places.<section prefix='(a)'>Restrictions. No person may solicit voters within fifty (50) feet of the entrance to any polling place, or polling room where the polling place is also a polling room, on the day of any election.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Exceptions. Solicitation shall not be restricted if:<section prefix='(1)'>Conducted from a separately marked area within the fifty-foot zone, which may be designated by the Supervisor of Elections, so as not to disturb, hinder, impede, obstruct or interfere with voter access to the polling place or polling room entrance; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The solicitation activities and subject matter are clearly and easily identifiable by the voters as an activity in which they may voluntarily participate; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Conducted on property within the fifty-foot zone which is a residence, established business, private property, sidewalk, park or property traditionally utilized as a public area for discussion; however, no such solicitation shall be permitted within the fifty-foot zone on a public sidewalk or other means of access to the polling room if it impedes, obstructs, or interferes with voter access to the polling room or polling place.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Polling room means the actual room in which ballots are cast.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Polling place means the building which contains the polling room where ballots are cast.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Solicitation includes but it is not limited to:<section prefix='a.'>Seeking or attempting to seek any vote, fact, opinion or contribution;</section><section prefix='b.'>Distributing or attempting to distribute any political or campaign material, leaflet or handout;</section><section prefix='c.'>Conducting a poll;</section><section prefix='d.'>Seeking or attempting to seek a signature on any petition; and</section><section prefix='e.'>Selling or attempting to sell any item.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-64, ยง 1, 7-11-89)</history></law>