<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='2'>Chapter 12 ELECTIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>12-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Reports to the Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002258</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 12-1. Reports to the Board.<section>The County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee shall prepare and deliver, between sixty and ninety days prior to any Primary or General election, a report to the Board of County Commissioners detailing the Department of Elections' preparations for such election. The report shall, at a minimum, contain: (1) an analysis of the anticipated voter turnout; (2) the anticipated utilization of absentee voting, early voting and Election Day voting by Miami-Dade County voters; (3) the steps taken by the Department to ensure that voters are able to cast ballots in a reasonable amount of time; (4) a summary of the equipment and personnel to be deployed at early voting locations and Election Day precincts; and (5) any additional budgetary or legislative requests necessary to perform the duties of the Department at the General Election. The County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee shall also prepare and deliver, between thirty and sixty days after any Primary or General election, a report to the Board of County Commissioners detailing the performance of the Department of Elections during such election. The report shall, at a minimum, contain: (1) an analysis of the voter turnout; (2) the amount of time taken by voters to cast ballots; (3) any irregularities or problems in the Department's conduct of the election or in the voting process; and (4) budgetary or legislative recommendations for improvement of the voting experience in future elections. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code to the contrary, such reports shall be placed on the agenda of the next regularly scheduled meeting of the Board of County Commissioners and shall be heard at a time certain to be set by the Chairperson.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-13, ยง 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>