<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='2'>Chapter 12 ELECTIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>12-14.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Absentee Ballot Campaigning Reporting Requirement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002270</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 12-14.1. Absentee Ballot Campaigning Reporting Requirement.<section prefix='(1)'>Each campaign treasurer designated by a candidate for County or municipal office in Miami-Dade County shall, at the time of filing any contribution or expenditure reports otherwise required by law, file an additional electronic report with the officer responsible for receiving such candidate's contribution or expenditure reports. The report shall identify the names of all paid campaign workers, whether employed by the campaign or any consultant or agent of the campaign, participating in the campaign or undertaking any other activities regarding absentee ballots. The report shall be filed on a form created by the Supervisor of Elections for such purpose.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any candidate failing to file a report as required by this section on the designated due date shall be subject to a fine of $50.00 per day for the first three (3) days and, thereafter, $500.00 per day for each day late not to exceed $5,000.00. Such fine shall not be an allowable campaign expense and shall be paid only from the personal funds of the candidate. Any candidate may appeal or dispute the fine to the Miami-Dade County Commission on Ethics and Public Trust based upon, but not limited to, unusual circumstances surrounding the failure to file on the designated due date, and may request, and shall be entitled to, a hearing before the Commission on Ethics and Public Trust, which shall have the authority to waive the fine in whole or in part. Any such appeal or dispute shall be made within twenty (20) days after receipt of notice that payment is due or such appeal or dispute shall be waived.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Candidates for County and municipal office in Miami-Dade County may not direct or knowingly permit any paid or volunteer campaign worker to violate any provision of the Miami-Dade County Code or Florida Law regarding the conduct of absentee voting. Any such candidate found to violate this subsection by the Commission on Ethics and Public Trust shall, in addition to any other civil or criminal penalties provided by law, shall be subject to the penalties provided in Section 2-11.1(bb) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-05, ยง 1, 1-23-13)</history></law>