<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Preblast survey and notification.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002298</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-15. Preblast survey and notification.<section>In order to provide a baseline record of the condition of a structure against which the effects of blasting can be assessed, to help the user to maintain good community relations, and to provide possible protection against later legal claims of damage, the user shall offer, at his or her cost, the following preblast survey and notification for each new blast site:<section prefix='(a)'>All structures within a Scaled-Distance Factor of 150 of the proposed blast site shall be inspected by an independent, recognized seismologist, vibration engineer, structural engineer, or their representative. The Scaled-Distance Factor shall be determined by the following formula: Scaled-Distance Factor = D/W where W is the charge weight, in pounds, of explosives per delay and D is the distance, in feet, from the blast site to the structure not owned by the user. If occupants of a structure refuse inspection or access is not possible, the user shall notify the Director in writing of the address of said structure.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The preblast survey inspection shall consist of complete documentation of all visible interior and exterior defects observed at the structures examined. A list of all preblast surveys shall be forwarded to the Director for approval no later than five (5) days prior to the planned commencement of blasting. A location map indicating the streets and structures involved shall be submitted together with this list.</section><section prefix='(c)'>An update survey of any additions, modifications or renovations requiring a building permit shall be performed on previously inspected structures if requested by a resident or owner.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The user shall provide written notification of pending blast operations to all residents within one (1) mile of the proposed blast site at least ten (10) but no more than thirty (30) days prior to the commencement of blasting. The written notification shall describe the blasting which will take place, its expected effects, and how to contact the user or his or her representative with any blast related complaints or claims.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If blasting is suspended in an area for a period of ninety (90) days or longer, renotification of all residents within one (1) mile shall be accomplished at least seven (7) days prior to the recommencement of blasting.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>