<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-19</section_number>
<catch_line>Notice to purchasers of residential property of rock mining operations where blasting is permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002302</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-19. Notice to purchasers of residential property of rock mining operations where blasting is permitted.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person constructing a residential structure located within two (2) miles of a permitted rock mining operation where blasting is permitted shall, prior to the issuance of the first development permit, record in the public records a notice that the proposed development is located within two (2) miles of a blasting site. The notice shall provide the location of the blasting site and that such blasting is regulated by Chapter 13 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Notice shall be given to and signed by buyers contemporaneous with signing purchase contracts within said developments.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director of the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department and the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning shall maintain detailed maps of all permitted rock mining operations where blasting is permitted within Miami-Dade County. Any developer may request a written opinion from the Director of Public Works as to whether his or her development is located within the two-mile area.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Directors of the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department and Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning shall provide adequate notice of this section with the official application forms for development permits.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 8, 9-3-98)</history></law>