<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Misfires.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002296</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-13. Misfires.<section prefix='(a)'>The blaster shall inspect the entire blast site for misfires before allowing other personnel to return to the blast area.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If a misfire is found, the blaster shall provide the proper safeguards for excluding all personnel from the blast area.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No other work shall be done except that necessary to remove the hazard of the misfire. Only those personnel necessary to do the work shall remain at the blast site.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No attempt shall be made to extract explosive materials from a misfired hole. A new primer shall be inserted, and the hole shall be refired. If refiring presents a hazard, the explosive materials may be washed out with water, or, where the misfire is under water, blown out with air.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If there are any misfires using cap and fuse, all personnel shall stay out of the blast site for at least one (1) hour. If there are any misfires using other nonelectric detonators (i.e., other than cap and fuse) or using electric detonators, all personnel shall stay out of the blast site for at least thirty (30) minutes.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Misfires shall be handled under the direction of a qualified blaster.</section><section prefix='(g)'>If a misfire is suspected, all initiating circuits (electric or non-electric) shall be carefully traced and a search made for unexploded charges.</section><section prefix='(h)'>No drilling or digging, except as necessary to safely remedy a misfire problem, shall be allowed until all misfires have been detonated or until the authority having jurisdiction approves the resumption of work.</section><section prefix='(i)'>All misfires or premature detonations shall be reported in writing to the Director within three (3) days of such occurrence. The blaster shall provide information regarding the date and time of the occurrence, type of explosives and initiation system used, and the cause of the malfunction if it is known.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>