<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Use and handling of explosives.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002294</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-11. Use and handling of explosives.<section prefix='(a)'>Blasting operations shall be conducted during the hours of 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. except that the Director of the Public Works Department may extend the blasting time to all daylight hours for sites remote from residential development. Blasting shall not be done on Sundays or legal holidays except in emergencies involving the health, safety and welfare of the public.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The handling and firing of explosives shall be performed by the person possessing a County blaster license or by County helper license holders under his or her direct supervision who are at least eighteen (18) years old. When two (2) or more blasters are working together, one (1) shall be the blaster-in-charge designated by the user or the blasters themselves.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall handle explosives while under the influence of intoxicants, or narcotics.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall smoke or carry matches while handling explosives or while in the vicinity thereof.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No open flame light shall be used in the vicinity of explosives.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Whenever blasting is being conducted in the vicinity of gas, electric, water, fire alarm, telephone, telegraph or steam utilities which may be affected by adverse effects as prescribed by Section 13-14(a), (b), and (c), the user shall notify the appropriate representative of such utilities at least forty-eight (48) hours, excluding days other than business days, in advance of blasting, specifying the location and intended time of such blasting. Verbal notice shall be confirmed with written notice. In an emergency this time limit may be waived by the Director. The user shall comply with all applicable notification provisions of Chapter 556 of Florida Statutes, "Underground Facility Damage Prevention and Safety Act," as amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Blasting operations shall be conducted in accordance with nationally recognized good practice.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Before a blast is fired, the person in charge shall make certain that all surplus explosives are in a safe place, all persons and vehicles are at a safe distance or under sufficient cover, and a loud warning signal has been sounded.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Firing with cap and fuse will not be approved for use unless specifically approved for job site by the Director.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Due precautions shall be taken to prevent accidental discharge of electric blasting caps from current induced by radio or radar transmitters, lighting, adjacent power lines, dust storms or other sources of extraneous electricity. These precautions shall include:<section prefix='(1)'>The suspension of all blasting operations and removal of persons from the blast area during the approach and progress of an electric storm.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The posting of signs warning against the use of mobile radio transmitters on all roads within three hundred fifty (350) feet of the blasting operations.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Compliance with nationally recognized good practice when blasting in the vicinity of radio transmitters or power lines.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>When blasting is done in congested areas or in close proximity to a building, structure, railway, highway or any other installation that may be damaged, the blast shall be covered before firing, with a mat constructed so that it is capable of preventing rock from being thrown into the air.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Tools used for opening packages of explosives shall be constructed of nonsparking materials.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Empty boxes and paper and fiber packing materials which have previously contained high explosives shall not be used again for any purpose, but shall be destroyed by burning at an approved isolated location out of doors, and no person shall be nearer than one hundred (100) feet after the burning has started.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Explosives shall not be abandoned.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Personal vehicles shall not be stopped or parked within five hundred (500) feet of a magazine or blast site. The Director may waive this provision for certain vehicles as requested by the user in written application. This section is not intended to exclude vehicles used in the blasting or quarrying operation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>