<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Adverse effects.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002297</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-14. Adverse effects.<section prefix='(a)'>Maximum allowable airblast measured at the nearest building or structure not owned by the user, or when measured at a distance of five thousand two hundred eighty (5,280) feet from the blast shall not exceed one hundred twenty-nine (129) decibels when measured by an instrument having a flat frequency response over a range of at least 6 to 200 hertz. If the airblast is measured with an instrument having a flat frequency measure over a range of at least 2 to 200 hertz, the corresponding limit is one hundred thirty-three (133) decibels.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Fly rock traveling in the air or along the ground:<section prefix='(1)'>Shall remain within the controlled blast area and;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Shall not be cast from the blast site more than one-half (½) the distance to the nearest inhabited building within or outside the controlled blast area.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Ground vibration shall be measured as particle velocity. The maximum allowable peak particle velocity shall not exceed 0.75 inch per second measured at the nearest building or structure not owned by the user or when measured at a distance of five thousand two hundred eighty (5,280) feet from the blast when the nearest structure not owned by the user is more distant than one (1) mile from the blast. Particle velocity shall be recorded in three (3) mutually perpendicular directions. The maximum allowable peak particle velocity shall apply to each of the three (3) measurements.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Whenever blasting in the vicinity of a utility as set forth in Section 13-11(f) the user shall protect said utility from damage by establishment of a maximum allowable vibration level submitted by the user and agreed to in writing by the person from the utility who has authority to enter into said agreement. If there is a dispute between the user and the utility, the Director shall determine the maximum allowable vibration level.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, § 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>