<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Exceptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002285</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-2. Exceptions.<section>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as applying to:<section prefix='(a)'>The armed forces of the United States or the State militia.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Explosives in forms prescribed by the official United States Pharmacopoeia.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The sale or use of fireworks as defined in Article 29 of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as may be amended from time to time, hereinafter referred to as the "County Fire Code."</section><section prefix='(d)'>The possession, transportation and use of small arms, ammunition or special industrial explosive devices.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The use of explosives or blasting agents by the United States Bureau of Mines, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the United States Secret Service, or police and fire departments acting in their official capacity.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The manufacture, sale or transportation of explosives and blasting agents, or their storage as regulated by Article 28 of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as may be amended from time to time, hereinafter referred to as the "County Fire Code," except that storage of explosives and blasting agents on blasting sites is herein regulated.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The following three situations, but only with respect to the application of amendments in Sections 13-7, 13-15, 13-18, and 13-22 to those three specific situations, on the effective date of the amendments: (1) there is an existing unexpired county user permit for the use of explosives on a specific site, (2) a property has had a final plat approval by the Board of County Commissioners within the past year, or (3) a plat has been recorded within the past five (5) years. The properties covered by this exception shall be governed by the Code as it existed prior to the adoption of the above enumerated amendments.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>