<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-4</section_number>
<catch_line>County licenses and/or user permits required; types.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002287</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-4. County licenses and/or user permits required; types.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to conduct an operation that requires the use of explosives or blasting agents, acquire, possess, purchase, handle, dispose of, store or use same on any site without first obtaining a county license and/or user permit issued under and pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. The requirements of this chapter shall not relieve any person from compliance with the provisions of Chapter 552 of the Florida Statutes and all rules and regulations promulgated by the State Fire Marshal and Article 28 of the County Fire Code.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to purchase or store explosives or blasting agents, to conduct an operation that requires the use of explosives or blasting agents, to drill boreholes for the purpose of blasting or to engage in blasting at any site without first obtaining a County user permit. This restriction shall not include the drilling of exploratory test borings at a minimum distance of fifty (50) feet apart.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It shall be unlawful for any individual to perform or supervise the handling or detonation of explosives or blasting agents at any site without first obtaining a County blaster license.</section><section prefix='(d)'>It shall be unlawful for any individual to handle explosives while assisting a blaster without first obtaining a helper's license. A person possessing a helper's license may only handle explosives at an approved site under the direct supervision of an individual possessing a County blaster license.</section><section prefix='(e)'>County licenses and/or user permits required by Section 13-4(a) shall not be issued for:<section prefix='(1)'>Liquid nitroglycerin.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Nitrocellulose in a dry and uncompressed condition in quantity greater than ten (10) pounds net weight in one (1) package.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Fulminate of mercury in a dry condition and fulminate of all other metals in any condition except as a component of manufactured articles not hereinafter forbidden.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Explosive compositions that ignite spontaneously or undergo marked decomposition, rendering the products or their use more hazardous, when subjected for forty-eight (48) consecutive hours or less to a temperature of one hundred sixty-seven (167) degrees Fahrenheit (seventy-five (75) degrees Celsius).</section><section prefix='(5)'>New explosives until approved by the United States Department of Transportation, except that County licenses and/or user permits may be issued to educational, governmental or industrial laboratories for instructional or research purposes.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Explosives condemned by the United States Department of Transportation.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Explosives not packed or marked in accordance with the "Hazardous Materials Regulations of the United States Department of Transportation."</section><section prefix='(8)'>Explosives containing an ammonium salt and a chlorate.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>