<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Appeals from refusal to issue a County license or user permit and from revocation of a County license or user permit; public hearing; waiver of prior conviction.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002289</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-6. Appeals from refusal to issue a County license or user permit and from revocation of a County license or user permit; public hearing; waiver of prior conviction.<section>Any individual who is denied or refused a County license or any person who is denied or refused a County user permit for reasons other than as provided in or whose County license or user permit has been revoked by the Director of the Public Works Department for reasons other than as provided in, may appeal to the Construction Trades Qualifying Board Division A, by filing a written petition of review setting forth the reasons why his application for a County license or user permit should have been granted, provided, however, that the Construction Trades Qualifying Board shall have no jurisdiction to entertain any such appeal unless a written petition or request for review is filed with the Secretary of the Construction Trades Qualifying Board within thirty (30) days after the date upon which the applicant receives notice that his application for a County license or user permit has been denied or refused or revoked. When an appeal has been filed, the Construction Trades Qualifying Board shall conduct a public hearing to determine whether the applicant qualifies for a County license or user permit. The Construction Trades Qualifying Board shall not authorize the granting of a County license or user permit unless it finds and determines that the applicant is qualified under the provisions of. The prohibition against issuance of a County license or user permit to any person who has been convicted of a felony may be waived by the Construction Trades Qualifying Board, provided that such conviction occurred more that ten (10) years prior to the date of filing the application, and that the applicant has rehabilitated himself or herself completely.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>