<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='2'>Chapter 13 EXPLOSIVES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>13-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Application for County user permit for lake excavation within the urban development boundary; public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002290</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 13-7. Application for County user permit for lake excavation within the urban development boundary; public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners.<section prefix='(a)'>Except in the case of a two (2) pound County user permit all County user permit applications for lake excavations that lie within the urban development boundary (UDB) as shown on the adopted comprehensive master plan as authorized by Section 2-114 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, must be approved by the Board of County Commissioners. A County user permit application for a lake excavation that lies within the UDB shall be verified by the owner or the lessee of the property upon which the work is proposed. If the application for a County user permit for a lake excavation that lies within the UDB is verified by a lessee, an affidavit from the owner of the property indicating that the owner has no objection to the work proposed shall be submitted with the application.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In addition to the application requirements of Section 13-5, a County user permit application for a lake excavation within the UDB which is filed with the Director of the Public Works Department shall include, as a minimum, the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Evidence of ownership or a lease of the property upon which the lake excavation is proposed. Said evidence of ownership or lease may include, at the discretion of the Public Works Department, an affidavit of ownership or lease executed by the owner and/or lessee of the property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Three (3) copies of a plan or sketch of the proposed lake excavation(s) to include location, size and depth.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A written statement signed by the County user permit applicant or the applicant's authorized agent stating that, if approval is granted for the proposed work by the Board of County Commissioners, complete and detailed plans and calculations of the proposed work shall be prepared by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual. Said plans and calculations shall be subject to the review and approval of the Public Works Department.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Certification by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida, who is qualified by education and experience in the area of construction that, to the best of the engineer's knowledge and belief, the proposed work does not violate any laws, rules or regulations of the State of Florida or any provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County which may be applicable.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A geotechnical report prepared and signed by an engineer licensed in the State of Florida having expertise in the geotechnical field. This geotechnical report shall provide a concise soil and rock strata description of the area proposed to be excavated, supported by the appropriate soil boring results of the site.<section>The geotechnical report must give full consideration for excavating the lakes without the use of explosives. If explosives are recommended, impact to nearby residential, commercial or industrial areas must be addressed. The report should state how the requirements of this chapter will be met.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Names and addresses from the latest County tax rolls of all owners of property within one (1) mile of the perimeter of the proposed lake excavation.</section><section prefix='(7)'>If the proposed work is within an incorporated area of the County, a letter from the zoning department of that incorporated area, stating that the proposed usage of the property upon which the proposed work would occur does not violate any zoning law applicable to the area of the proposed work.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The applicant, at his or her discretion, may provide evidence of public interest relating to the proposed work.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Obtaining approval from the Board of County Commissioners:<section prefix='(1)'>The Director of the Public Works Department shall review the County user permit application for the proposed lake excavation that lies within the UDB and shall make a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners of approval, denial, or approval subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions for the proposed work. The Director's recommendation shall be based upon the applicable evaluation factors set forth in Section 13-7(d) of this Code. The Board of County Commissioners shall hold a public hearing concerning the proposed lake excavation that lies within the UDB. A notice of the time and place of said public hearing shall be published by the applicant in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County a minimum of fourteen (14) days prior to the public hearing. Said notice shall include a brief description of the proposed work and the location of the proposed work. A courtesy notice containing substantially the same information set forth in said published notice shall be mailed by the County to those parties whose names appear on the application as the owners of property within one (1) mile of the perimeter of the proposed lake excavation. Failure to mail or receive said courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken hereunder. The Board of County Commissioners shall, after holding the public hearing, approve, deny, or approve subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions, the lake excavation proposed under the permit application based upon the applicable evaluation factors set forth in Section 13-7(d) of this Code.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the Board of County Commissioners approves a permit application, the Public Works Department shall issue the County user permit subject to the conditions, limitations or restrictions required by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director of the Public Works Department is authorized from time to time to change, amend or modify the imposed conditions and limitations regarding any County user permit in order to meet the purpose for which they were imposed if changing conditions or circumstances so dictate and after first considering recognized standards and references, any relevant historical data, studies, and results obtained during the regulation of blasting operations in Miami-Dade County, the adverse effects under Section 13-14, and the guidelines enumerated under Section 13-18. The Director of the Public Works Department is further authorized to revoke a County user permit for failure of the permittee to comply with any conditions, restrictions, or limitations placed on such County user permit.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Factors for evaluation of County user permit applications within the UDB: Miami-Dade County Public Works Department shall base its recommendation for approval, denial or approval subject to conditions, limitations, or restrictions, and the Board of County Commissioners shall make its decision for approval, denial, or approval subject to conditions, limitations or restrictions, for any of the permits provided for under this article, upon the following evaluation factors, when applicable:<section prefix='(1)'>Potential adverse effects of the proposed blasting project as prescribed by Section 13-14 with respect to preventing damage to property, preventing personal injury or loss of life, protecting the public health, welfare and safety and the reduction of nuisance.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Conformance with all applicable federal, state and local laws and regulations.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners as to approval or denial from the municipality within which the proposed work is located.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All materials submitted with the application as required by this section.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Appeals:<section prefix='(1)'>Any individual or person appearing of record at any hearing held pursuant to this section may, within thirty (30) days, appeal the decision of the Board of County Commissioners to the Circuit Court.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any person whose County user permit, which has been authorized by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to this section, is subsequently revoked by the Director of the Public Works Department may, within thirty (30) days, appeal such revocation to the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Time of completion of blasting work; extension of completion time; timely application for extension of time.<section prefix='(1)'>All blasting work authorized by a County user permit for a lake excavation within the UDB issued pursuant to this article shall begin no later than three (3) months after Board of County Commission approval and shall be completed within eighteen (18) months from the date of the issuance of the first County user permit for said lake excavation or any extension thereof, unless another period of time is provided by the Board of County Commissioners as set forth in the resolution authorizing approval for the issuance of a County user permit.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Extensions of time for completion of work being performed pursuant to a County user permit issued pursuant to this article may be granted by the Director of the Public Works Department or his designee provided that:<section prefix='a.'>The application form for the extension of time is filed at least thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of the County user permit.</section><section prefix='b.'>The application form for the extension of time is filed at least thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of the County user permit.</section><section prefix='c.'>The Director has determined that the applicant for the extension of time has affirmatively established by competent factual data and information in the application that:<section prefix='1.'>There have been no substantial changes in the surrounding area that may be affected by the permitted work.</section><section prefix='2.'>Neither an adverse impact nor cumulative adverse impact will occur if the extension of time is granted.</section><section prefix='3.'>The work authorized by the County user permit has been performed, to date, in accordance with the County user permit and its restrictions, limitations or conditions.</section><section prefix='4.'>The applicant for the extension of time has agreed to any additional conditions, limitations or restrictions if required by the Director.</section></section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Applications for extensions of time which are not timely filed pursuant to Section 13-7(f)(2) hereinabove shall be returned to the applicant. The applicant shall be required to file an application for a new County user permit pursuant to the provisions of this article.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-45, ยง 1, 3-19-96)</history></law>