<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Fire alarms.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002316</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-10. Fire alarms.<section prefix='(1)'>Purpose of regulation. The purpose of this section is to place responsibility on the alarm user to prevent, by use of appropriate mechanical, electrical, or other means, false fire alarms.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Scope of regulations. The provisions of this section shall apply throughout the geographical area serviced by the Metropolitan Dade Fire and Rescue Service District.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Alarm user means the person or other entity that owns, possesses, controls, occupies or manages any premises as defined below.</section><section prefix='(b)'>False fire alarm means a signal from a fire alarm system that elicits a response by the Fire Department when no actual or threatened fire-related emergency exists. This definition includes signals activated by negligence, accident, mechanical failure, and electrical failure; signals activated intentionally in nonemergency situations; and signals for which the actual cause of activation is unknown. It is a rebuttable presumption that a fire alarm is false if personnel responding from the Fire Depart- ment do not discover any evidence of fire or other emergency after following normal Fire Department operating procedures in investigating the incident. An alarm is not false if the alarm user proves that (1) an individual activated the alarm based upon a reasonable belief that a fire-related emergency existed; (2) the alarm system was activated by lightning or an electrical surge that caused physical damage to the system, as evidenced by the testimony of a licensed alarm system contractor who conducted an on-site inspection and personally observed the damage to the system; or (3) the alarm was activated by vandals.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Fire alarm system means any assembly of equipment, mechanical or electrical, arranged to signal the occurrence of fire-related emergency requiring urgent attention and to which Fire Department personnel may reasonably be expected to respond, but does not include such alarms installed in residential buildings of four (4) units or less.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Premises means the building or structure or portion of a building or structure upon which is installed or maintained, a fire alarm system.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Fire alarms; posting requirements. A fire alarm user shall conspicuously post at the main entrance to the alarm user's premises a notice stating (1) the name of an individual or alarm company able and authorized to enter the premises and deactivate the alarm; (2) emergency telephone numbers by which those individuals can be reached at all times; and (3) the name and address of the alarm user. The information must be kept current and failure to update this information within forty-eight (48) hours of any change constitutes a violation of this section.</section><section prefix='(5)'>False fire alarms prohibited. No fire alarm user shall cause, allow, or permit its fire alarm system to give three (3) or more false alarms in any calendar year.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Inspection requirements. After the second and each additional false fire alarm in one (1) calendar year, the alarm user must, within thirty (30) days, file a written certificate with the Fire Department from a licensed fire alarm contractor stating that the fire alarm system has been inspected since the last false fire alarm and is functioning properly.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Penalties. Each violation of this section shall be punished as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>For a first violation of Section 14-10(4), by a fine of two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00).</section><section prefix='(b)'>For a second and each additional violation of Section 14-10(4), by a fine of five hundred dollars ($500.00).</section><section prefix='(c)'>For the third false fire alarm in one (1) calendar year, by a fine of five hundred dollars ($500.00).</section><section prefix='(d)'>For the fourth and each additional false fire alarm in one (1) calendar year, by a fine of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00).</section><section prefix='(e)'>For each violation of Section 14-10(6), a fine of two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00).</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>Enforcement. The section shall be enforced by the code enforcement provisions of Chapter 8CC of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-46, ยง 1, 5-17-88)</history></law>