<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Burnt Motor Vehicles; Owner's Statement to the Miami-Dade County Fire Department.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002317</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-11. Burnt Motor Vehicles; Owner's Statement to the Miami-Dade County Fire Department.<section prefix='(1)'>Whenever an insured motor vehicle suffers loss or damage caused by fire or explosion within the jurisdiction of the Miami-Dade County Fire Department, the vehicle's owner of record shall submit to the Miami-Dade County Fire Department a statement signed under penalty of perjury setting forth the owner's knowledge of the incident (the "Owner's Statement"). The Owner's Statement shall contain such information as may reasonably be required by the Fire Chief, and shall be on such forms as may be prescribed by the Fire Chief.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The investigation of the Miami-Dade County Fire Chief shall not be deemed to be completed until receipt by the Fire Chief of the Owner's Statement completed to the reasonable satisfaction of the Fire Chief. No record relating to the investigation, including but not limited to fire incident reports, documents, papers, letters, maps, diagrams, tapes, photographs, films, sound recordings, and evidence shall be made public or subject to subpoena until the investigation is completed.</section><section prefix='(3)'>By exception, the records relating to the investigation shall be made public:<section prefix='(a)'>When in the reasonable discretion of the Fire Chief, the department is in possession of sufficient evidence to conclude the investigation notwithstanding the absence of the Owner's Statement; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>When otherwise required by law.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>The Miami-Dade Fire Department may in its discretion waive the requirements of this section upon a determination that the loss or damage to the motor vehicle was accidental.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-248, ยง 1, 12-3-02)</history></law>