<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure for obtaining permit.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002308</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-2. Procedure for obtaining permit.<section prefix='(a)'>Filing of application; required information; form. All applications for permits under Sections 14-1 through 14-6 shall be filed with the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Chief and shall set forth in detail the full name and address of the applicant, the date and time the fire is to be set, the kind or type of fire to be set, the area to be burned, what safeguards will be taken to protect the public and any other property from injury, and such other information as may be prescribed by the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Chief. The Metropolitan Dade County Fire Chief shall prescribe the form of application and furnish such application forms to applicants upon request.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Grounds for nonissuance of permit. Permit shall not be issued when the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Chief has good reason to believe that the proposed fire or burning will endanger the public health, safety, welfare or other property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Application filing fees authorized. The County Manager may establish a schedule of filing fees to cover the cost of investigating and processing applications for permits.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Contents of permit. The permit issued hereunder shall show the time when the fire will be set, the area to be burned, the persons authorized to set such fire, and such special conditions as are necessary to protect life and property.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-44, § 2, 11-29-60; Ord. No. 66-37, §§ 3, 4, 9-7-66)</history></law>