<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-43</section_number>
<catch_line>Resolution of conflict of laws.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002335</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-43. Resolution of conflict of laws.<section prefix='(A)'>In the event of a conflict between (i) the requirements of the South Florida Building Code, as same may be amended from time to time, and (ii) the requirements of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and this article, as all of same may be amended from time to time, the conflict shall be resolved by agreement between the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, in favor of the requirement of either the South Florida Building Code or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or this article which provides the greatest degree of life safety or alternatives which would provide an equivalent degree of life safety and equivalent method of construction.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Any decision made by the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, may be appealed to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board.<section prefix='(1)'>If the decision of the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is to apply the provisions of either the South Florida Building Code or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or this article, the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board may not alter the decision unless the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board determines that the application of the South Florida Building Code or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or this article is not reasonable.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the decision of the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is to adopt an alternative to the South Florida Building Code, South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and this article, the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall give due regard to the decision rendered by the aforesaid officials and may modify that decision if the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board adopts a better alternative, taking into consideration all relevant circumstances.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In any case in which the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board adopts alternatives to the decision of the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, such alternatives shall provide a degree of life safety and method of construction equivalent to the degree of life safety and method of construction provided by the decision of the aforesaid building code and fire code enforcement officials.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>In the event that the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, are unable to agree on a resolution of the conflict between the requirements of (i) the South Florida Building Code and (ii) the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and this article, the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall resolve the conflict in favor of the requirement which provides the greatest degree of life safety or alternatives which would provide an equivalent degree of life safety and an equivalent method of construction.</section><section prefix='(D)'>In the event of any conflict between a requirement of (i) this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and (ii) a requirement of Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, or the rules promulgated by the State Fire Marshal pursuant to Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, or the rules promulgated by the State Fire Marshal pursuant to Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, as said rules may be amended from time to time, the provision which established the most stringent standard shall prevail.</section><section prefix='(E)'>In the event of any conflict between a provision of (i) this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and (ii) a provision of any other County or municipal ordinance, code or regulation, the provisions of subsections (A), (B) and (C) shall apply if the conflict is with a requirement of the South Florida Building Code, or, if the conflict is with a provision other than the South Florida Building Code, then the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>