<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-49</section_number>
<catch_line>South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002342</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-49. South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer.<section prefix='(A)'>There is hereby created and established the position of South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer. The South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer shall be appointed by the County Manager after considering the recommendations of the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board. Said officer shall be exempt from the classified service and shall serve at the will of the County Manager. The Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board shall supervise the activities of said officer and may recommend the replacement of said officer.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The County Manager may appoint and employ personnel to assist the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, subject to the appropriation of funds and approval of salaries by the Board of County Commissioners. Such personnel may include members of a South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Team who shall work under the direct supervision of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer. The Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board may recommend persons to the County Manager for appointment to the aforesaid team.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer or his designees shall have the following powers, duties and responsibilities:<section prefix='(1)'>To perform inspections of any property or premises or thing in the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Dade County for the purpose of determining whether or not the jurisdiction having fire safety and fire prevention responsibilities is adequately or uniformly enforcing the provisions of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. No such inspection shall occur unless the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is notified of the inspection prior to the occurrence in the inspection.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To order any person within any jurisdiction in Dade County, Florida, to comply with the provisions of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. Such order shall superseded and nullify the particular orders or actions of the fire officials of the particular jurisdiction; however, no such order shall be issued until the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, is afforded a reasonable period of time to obtain compliance. Said reasonable period of time shall be determined by and in the sole discretion of the South Florida Fire Prevention Enforcement Officer. The South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer shall provide a copy of the order to the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, and to the governing body of the particular jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To report to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board all actions taken by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer and Team on no less than a monthly basis.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To report, on no less than an annual basis, to the Board of County Commissioners, all activities of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer and Team.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The powers enumerated in this section shall be in addition to and not a limitation of or in derogation of any other powers granted to the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer by any other provision of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or by state law, rule or regulation, as all of same may be amended from time to time. No other County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall exercise any of the powers granted to the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer by this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or by State law, rule or regulation, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>