<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-42</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum fire safety standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002334</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-42. Minimum fire safety standards.<section prefix='(A)'>The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall be a minimum standard for the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall not apply to buildings and structures subject to the uniform fire safety standards promulgated pursuant to Section 633.022, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall not apply to buildings and structures subject to the minimum fire safety standards adopted pursuant to Sections 394.879 and 396.176, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(D)'>The requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall be a minimum fire safety standard code. A municipality with fire safety responsibilities may adopt more stringent fire safety standards. Minimum fire safety standards shall be met by every occupancy, facility, building, structure, premises, device, or activity to which said standards apply.</section><section prefix='(E)'>The new building or structure requirements set forth in the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall apply only to buildings or structures for which the building permit is issued on or after January 1, 1988.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Subject to the provisions of subsection (G) herein, the existing building or structure requirements set forth in the S.F.F.P.C. and this article shall apply to buildings or structures for which the building permit was issued or the building or structures were constructed prior to January 1, 1988.</section><section prefix='(G)'>With respect to existing buildings, the Legislature of the State of Florida has recognized that it is not always practical to apply any or all of the requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article and that physical limitations may require disproportionate effort or expense with little increase in life safety.<section prefix='(1)'>Prior to applying the requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article to an existing building, the chief fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall determine that a threat to life safety or property exists.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If a threat to life safety or property exists the chief fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall apply the applicable requirements of the S.F.F.P.C. and this article to the extent practical to assure a reasonable degree of life safety and safety of property.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The chief of fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall fashion a reasonable alternative which affords an equivalent degree of life safety and safety of property.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The decisions of the chief fire official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, under subsection (G) may be appealed to the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board.</section></section><section prefix='(H)'>Nothing in this section shall preclude a municipality, County, or special district from requiring a structure to be maintained in accordance with S.F.F.P.C. and this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>