<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-53.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Plan review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002347</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-53.1. Plan review.<section prefix='(A)'>No County or municipal officer, agent, employee, agency, or Board shall issue any permit for construction, erection, alteration, repair, or demolition until the chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, in conjunction with the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, has reviewed the plans and specifications for such proposal and both of the aforesaid code enforcement officials, or their designees, have determined that the plans are in compliance with the South Florida Building Code, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Any building or structure which is exempt from the County or municipal building permit process shall not be required to have its plans reviewed pursuant to (A) above.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Industrial construction on sites where design, construction, and fire safety are supervised by appropriate design and inspection professionals and which contain adequate in-house Fire Departments and rescue squads shall not be exempt from review of plans and inspections.</section><section prefix='(D)'>The County or municipality shall issue a permit to construct, erect, alter, repair, or demolish any building where the plans and specifications for such proposal comply with the South Florida Building Code, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(E)'>The chief building code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, shall require of every threshold building that all plans for the building which are required to be signed and sealed by the architect or engineer of record contain a statement that, to the best of the architect's or engineer's knowledge, the plans and specifications comply with the South Florida Building Code, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, this article, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or supplement the provisions of Part IV of Chapter 553, Florida Statutes, relating to factory-built housing.</section><section prefix='(G)'>One- and two-family detached residential dwelling units shall not be subject to plan review by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee.</section><section prefix='(H)'>One- and two-family detached residential dwelling units shall be subject to inspection by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, pursuant to Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or as provided by law, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>