<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-56</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement; procedure; remedies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002350</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-56. Enforcement; procedure; remedies.<section prefix='(A)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to violate or to permit, allow, let or suffer any violation of: Any of the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as all of same may be amended from time to time; any condition, limitation or restriction which is part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; lawful orders of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; lawful orders of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; and consent agreements. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by this article or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, shall have the following judicial remedies:<section prefix='(1)'>To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of: Any of the provisions of this article or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; any lawful order of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; any lawful order of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time; any condition, limitation, or restriction which is part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any consent agreement.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) for each violation of: Any of the provisions of this article or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; any lawful order of chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; any lawful order of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time; any condition, limitation, or restriction which is part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any consent agreement.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief to recover any sums expended and costs incurred for:<section prefix='(i)'>Tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating, or remedying violations of: This article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and fire safety standard adopted by a municipality which are more stringent in accordance with Section 633.025(5), Florida Statutes, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any lawful order of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee; or any lawful order of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer; or any condition, limitation, or restriction which is a part of a permit issued pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, as all of same may be amended from time to time; or any consent agreement.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Restoration of the air, waters, property, animal life, aquatic life and plant life within the County or municipality of their former condition.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalties to be imposed and recovered hereunder.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>