<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-55</section_number>
<catch_line>Attorneys' fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002349</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-55. Attorneys' fees.<section>Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person in favor of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or in favor of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, to enforce any of the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, prevails, the appellate court shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or for the attorney of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, who prosecuted the suit in which the recovery was had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all pending or prospective civil actions, legal or equitable, filed by the chief fire code enforcement official of any jurisdiction in Dade County, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, to enforce the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or any more stringent municipal fire safety standard. Cessation, correction or remediation of any violation of the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or of any more stringent fire safety standard whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, to enforce the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or a more stringent municipal fire safety standard, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, for which attorneys' fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>