<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-57</section_number>
<catch_line>Civil penalty and restitution fund.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002351</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-57. Civil penalty and restitution fund.<section prefix='(A)'>The sums recoverable by the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer pursuant to Section 14-56(A)(2) and (3) shall be deposited (i) in a separate County fund for sums recovered by the chief fire code enforcement official of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department, or his designee, with respect to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Dade County under the fire safety jurisdiction of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department as well as sums recovered by the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer with respect to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Dade County, or (ii) in separate municipal funds for sums recovered by the chief fire code enforcement official, or his designee, of the following municipalities: The City of Miami Beach, the City of Miami, the City of Hialeah, and the City of Coral Gables.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The aforesaid separate County and separate municipal funds shall only be used to pay for the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Tracing, investigating, controlling, abating, and remedying violations of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Restoration of the air, waters, property, animal life, aquatic life and plant life within the County or municipality to their former condition.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Fire safety and prevention, planning, protection, and programming.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Responding to and attempting to resolve citizen complaints against violations or possible violations of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rule and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Investigation, preparation, and prosecution of civil and criminal actions, pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, to enforce the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>No part of such separate County and separate municipal funds shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.</section></section></text></law>