<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-53</section_number>
<catch_line>Permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002346</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-53. Permits.<section prefix='(A)'>No person shall operate, utilize or occupy, or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be operated, utilized or occupied any facility, instrumentality or real property, in the unincorporated or incorporated areas of Dade County, which is required to obtain a permit issued by the Fire Department having jurisdiction pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code without such a valid permit or in violation of any condition, limitation or restriction which is part of such a permit.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The criterion for issuance of a permit by the Fire Department having jurisdiction shall be compliance with the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or, within a municipality, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. The Fire Department having jurisdiction may require conditions, limitations and restrictions as part of any permit if said conditions, limitations, or restrictions are consistent with this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, within a municipality, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The Fire Department having jurisdiction may deny the issuance of, suspend or revoke any permit for failure to comply with the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or, within a municipality, any fire safety standards adopted by a municipality which are more stringent than the fire safety standards in this article, or in the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or in the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(D)'>The Fire Department having jurisdiction may deny the issuance of any such permit or revoke or suspend any such permit for failure to comply with the conditions, limitations and restrictions of any such permit.</section><section prefix='(E)'>No such permits shall be required for the aforesaid facilities, instrumentalities and real property existing on the effective date of this section until one hundred twenty (120) days from the effective date of this section.</section><section prefix='(F)'>All applications for permits pursuant to this section shall be on a form prescribed by the Fire Department having jurisdiction and accompanied by the required fee. The fees shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners for permits within the jurisdiction of the Metropolitan Dade County Fire Department. The fees shall be established by the governing body of the City of Miami Beach, the City of Miami, the City of Hialeah and the City of Coral Gables for such permits within the respective jurisdictions of the aforesaid municipalities.</section><section prefix='(G)'>The permit fees payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate County fund, or, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, in separate municipal funds, to be used exclusively by the Fire Department of the jurisdiction to pay for the costs of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Investigation, preparation, and prosecution of civil and criminal actions, pursuant to this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, to enforce the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Monitoring, permitting, and inspection of facilities, instrumentalities, and real property to determine and seek to insure compliance with this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Responding to and attempting to resolve citizen complaints against violations or possible violations of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and in the case of the aforesaid municipalities, fire standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Fire safety and prevention planning, protection, and programming.</section></section><section prefix='(H)'>No part of such separate County and separate municipal funds shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid. The amount of said fees shall be reasonably regulated to the cost of the services and regulation provided.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>