<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-54</section_number>
<catch_line>Consent agreements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002348</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-54. Consent agreements.<section>The chief fire enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, may, in the official's or his designee's discretion, and the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer may, in the officer's discretion, terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this article or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code upon execution of a written consent agreement between the chief fire enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Dire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, and the persons who are the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance by said persons with the applicable provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and in the case of a municipality, fire safety standards adopted by the municipality which are more stringent than the provisions in this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, as all of same may be amended from time to time. The consent agreement may, in the discretion of the chief fire code enforcement official, or his designee, or in the discretion of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, provide the following: Posting of a surety, bond, or other security to assure compliance; costs and expenses of the Fire Department having jurisdiction or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer for investigation, enforcement, testing, monitoring, and litigation, including attorneys' fees; civil penalties; remedial or corrective action. An executed written consent agreement shall not be evidence of a prior violation of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, or, in the case of a municipality, of any municipal ordinance. Such consent agreement shall not be deemed to impose any limitation upon any investigation or action of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer or chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, in the enforcement of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code or, in the case of a municipality, any municipal ordinance. The consent agreement shall not constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State or local laws and ordinances. Executed written consent agreements are hereby deemed to be lawful orders of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate offense under this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and, in the case of a municipality, an applicable municipal ordinance, by the persons who executed the consent agreement, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees, and attorneys; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of which each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, and in the case of a municipality, any applicable municipal ordinance. Decisions and actions of the chief fire code enforcement official, or his designee, or of the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, pursuant to this section or the written consent agreements provided herein, shall not be subject to review by the Dade County Fire Prevention and Safety Appeals Board or by any other County or municipal Board, officer, agent or employee.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>