<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-58</section_number>
<catch_line>Standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002352</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-58. Standards.<section prefix='(A)'>The following standards of the National Fire Protection Association, Battery-March Park, Quincy, MA 02269, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>NFPA 1-1982, Fire Prevention Code, which shall only apply to combustible fibers.</section><section prefix='(2)'>NFPA 10-1991, Standard for Portable Fire Extinguishers.</section><section prefix='(3)'>NFPA 11-1988, Standard for Low Expansion Foam and Combined Agent Systems.</section><section prefix='(4)'>NFPA 11A-1988, Standard for Medium and High Expansion Systems.</section><section prefix='(5)'>NFPA 12-1989, Standard on Carbon Dioxide Extinguishing Systems.</section><section prefix='(6)'>NFPA 12A-1989, Standard on Halon 1301 Fire Extinguishing Systems.</section><section prefix='(7)'>NFPA 12B-1990, Standard on Halon 1211 Fire Extinguishing Systems.</section><section prefix='(8)'>NFPA 13-1989, Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems.</section><section prefix='(9)'>NFPA 13A-1987, Inspection, Testing and Maintenance of Sprinkler Systems.</section><section prefix='(10)'>NFPA 13D-1989, Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems in One- and Two-Family Dwellings and Mobile Homes.</section><section prefix='(11)'>NFPA 13R-1989, Installation of Sprinkler Systems in Residential Occupancies up to Four Stories in Height.</section><section prefix='(12)'>NFPA 14-1990, Standard for the Installation of Standpipe and Hose Systems.</section><section prefix='(13)'>NFPA 15-1990, Standard for Water Spray Fixed System for Fire Protection.</section><section prefix='(14)'>NFPA 16-1991, Standard for the Installation of Deluge Foam-Water Sprinkler and Foam Water Spray Systems.</section><section prefix='(15)'>NFPA 16A-1988, Standard for the Installation of Closed-Head Foam-Water Sprinklers and Foam-Water Spray Systems.</section><section prefix='(16)'>NFPA 17-1990, Standard for Dry Chemical Extinguishing Systems.</section><section prefix='(17)'>NFPA 17A-1990, Wet Chemical Extinguishing Systems.</section><section prefix='(18)'>NFPA 20-1990, Standard for the Installation of Centrifugal Fire Pumps.</section><section prefix='(19)'>NFPA 22-1987, Standard for Water Tanks for Private Fire Protection.</section><section prefix='(20)'>NFPA 24-1987, Standards for the Installation of Private Fire Service Mains and Their Appurtenances.</section><section prefix='(21)'>NFPA 26-1988, Supervision of Valves Controlling Water Supplies for Fire Protection.</section><section prefix='(22)'>NFPA 30-1990, Flammable and Combustible Liquids Code.</section><section prefix='(23)'>NFPA 30A-1990, Automotive Service Station Code.</section><section prefix='(24)'>NFPA 31-1987, Standard for the Installation of Oil Burning Equipment.</section><section prefix='(25)'>NFPA 32-1990, Standard for Dry Cleaning Plants.</section><section prefix='(26)'>NFPA 33-1989, Standard for Spray Application Using Flammable and Combustible Materials.</section><section prefix='(27)'>NFPA 34-1989, Standard for Dipping and Coating Processes Using Flammable Combustible Liquids.</section><section prefix='(28)'>NFPA 35-1987, Standard for the Manufacture of Organic Coatings.</section><section prefix='(29)'>NFPA 40-1988, Standard and Handling of Cellulose Nitrate Motion Picture Film.</section><section prefix='(30)'>NFPA 40E-1986, Standard for the Storage of Pyroxylin Plastics.</section><section prefix='(31)'>NFPA 43A-1990, Standard for the Storage of Liquid and Solid Oxidating Materials.</section><section prefix='(32)'>NFPA 43B-1986, Standards for Storage of Organic Peroxide Formulation.</section><section prefix='(33)'>NFPA 43C-1986, Standards for Storage of Gaseous Oxidizing Material.</section><section prefix='(34)'>NFPA 43D-1986, Standard for Storage of Pesticides in Portable Containers.</section><section prefix='(35)'>NFPA 45-1986, Standard of Fire Protection for Laboratories Using Chemicals.</section><section prefix='(36)'>NFPA 46-1990, Storage of Forest Products.</section><section prefix='(37)'>NFPA 49-1991, Hazardous Chemicals Data.</section><section prefix='(38)'>NFPA 50-1990, Bulk Oxygen Systems at Consumer Sites.</section><section prefix='(39)'>NFPA 50B-1989, Liquefied Hydrogen Systems at Consumer Sites.</section><section prefix='(40)'>NFPA 51-1987, Standard for the Design and Installation of Oxygen-Fuel Gas Systems for Welding, Cutting and Allied Processes.</section><section prefix='(41)'>NFPA 51A-1989, Acetylene Cylinder Charging Plants.</section><section prefix='(42)'>NFPA 51B-1989, Standard for Fire Prevention and Use of Cutting and Welding Processes.</section><section prefix='(43)'>NFPA 52-1988, Compressed Natural Gas Vehicular Fuel Systems.</section><section prefix='(44)'>NFPA 54-1988, National Fuel Gas Code.</section><section prefix='(45)'>NFPA 58-1989, Standard for the Storage and Handling of Liquefied Petroleum Gases.</section><section prefix='(46)'>NFPA 61A-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosions in Facilities Manufacturing and Handling Starch.</section><section prefix='(47)'>NFPA 61B-1980, Standards for the Prevention of Fires and Explosions in Grain Elevators and Facilities Handling Bulk Raw Agricultural Commodities.</section><section prefix='(48)'>NFPA 61C-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosions in Feed Mills.</section><section prefix='(49)'>NFPA 61D-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosion in the Milling of Agriculture Commodities for Human Consumption.</section><section prefix='(50)'>NFPA 65-1989, Standard for the Processing and Finishing of Aluminum.</section><section prefix='(51)'>NFPA 69-1986, Explosion Venting Systems.</section><section prefix='(52)'>NFPA 70-1990, National Electrical Code.</section><section prefix='(53)'>NFPA 71-1989, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Central Station Signaling Systems.</section><section prefix='(54)'>NFPA 72-1990, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Local Protective Signaling Systems.</section><section prefix='(55)'>NFPA 72E-1987, Standard on Automatic Fire Detectors.</section><section prefix='(56)'>NFPA 72G-1989, Guide for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Notification Appliances for Protective Signaling Systems.</section><section prefix='(57)'>NFPA 72H-1988, Guide for Testing Procedures for Local, Auxiliary, Remote Station and Proprietary Protection Signaling Systems.</section><section prefix='(58)'>NFPA 74-1989, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Household Fire Warning Equipment.</section><section prefix='(59)'>NFPA 75-1989, Standard for the Protection of Electronic Computer/Data Processing Equipment.</section><section prefix='(60)'>NFPA 80-1990, Standard for Fire Doors and Windows.</section><section prefix='(61)'>NFPA 82-1990, Standard on Incinerators, Waste and Line Handling Systems and Equipment.</section><section prefix='(62)'>NFPA 85A-1987, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosions in Fuel Oil and Natural Gas-Fired Single Burner Boiler-Furnaces.</section><section prefix='(63)'>NFPA 85B-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosions in Natural-Fired Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.</section><section prefix='(64)'>NFPA 85D-1989, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosion in Fuel Oil-Fired Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.</section><section prefix='(65)'>NFPA 85E-1985, Standard for the Prevention of Furnace Explosions in Pulverized Coal-Fired Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.</section><section prefix='(66)'>NFPA 85F-1988, Standard for the Installation and Operation of Pulverized Fuel Systems.</section><section prefix='(67)'>NFPA 85G-1987, Furnace Implosions in Multiple Burner Boiler-Furnaces.</section><section prefix='(68)'>NFPA 86-1990, Standard for Ovens and Furnaces, Design, Location and Equipment.</section><section prefix='(69)'>NFPA 88A-1985, Standard for Parking Structures.</section><section prefix='(70)'>NFPA 88B-1985, Standard for Repair Garages.</section><section prefix='(71)'>NFPA 90A-1989, Standard for the Installation of Air Conditioning and Ventilating Systems.</section><section prefix='(72)'>NFPA 90B-1989, Standard for the Installation of Warm Air Heating and Air Conditioning Systems.</section><section prefix='(73)'>NFPA 91-1990, Standard for the Installation of Blower and Exhaust Systems.</section><section prefix='(74)'>NFPA 92B-1991, Smoke Management Systems in Mall Atria and Large Areas.</section><section prefix='(75)'>NFPA 96-1991, Standard for the Installation of Equipment for the Removal of Smoke and Grease-Laden Vapors from Commercial Cooking Equipment.</section><section prefix='(76)'>NFPA 97M-1988, Glossary of Terms Relating to Chimneys, Vents, and Heat-Producing Appliances.</section><section prefix='(77)'>NFPA 99-1990, Standard for Health Care Facilities.</section><section prefix='(78)'>NFPA 99B-1990, Hypobaric Facilities.</section><section prefix='(79)'>NFPA 101-1991, Safety to Life From Fire In Buildings and Structures.</section><section prefix='(80)'>NFPA 101M-1988, Manual on Alternative Approaches to Life Safety.</section><section prefix='(81)'>NFPA 102-1986, Standard for Assembly Seating, Tents and Air-Supported Structures.</section><section prefix='(82)'>NFPA 110-1988, Standard for Emergency and Standby Power Systems.</section><section prefix='(83)'>NFPA 120-1988, Standard for Coal Preparation Plants.</section><section prefix='(84)'>NFPA 150-1991, Fire Safety in Racetrack Stables.</section><section prefix='(85)'>NFPA 211-1988, Standard for Chimneys, Fireplaces, Vents and Solid Fuel Burning Appliances.</section><section prefix='(86)'>NFPA 214-1988, Water Cooling Towers.</section><section prefix='(87)'>NFPA 220-1985, Standard on Types of Building Construction.</section><section prefix='(88)'>NFPA 231-1990, Standard for Indoor General Storage.</section><section prefix='(89)'>NFPA 231C-1991, Standard for Rack Storage of Materials.</section><section prefix='(90)'>NFPA 231D-1989, Standard for Storage of Rubber Tires.</section><section prefix='(91)'>NFPA 231E-1989, Storage of Baled Cotton.</section><section prefix='(92)'>NFPA 231F-1987, Standard for Storage of Rolled Paper.</section><section prefix='(93)'>NFPA 232-1986, Standard for the Protection of Records.</section><section prefix='(94)'>NFPA 241-1989, Standard for Safeguarding Building Construction and Demolition Operations.</section><section prefix='(95)'>NFPA 251-1990, Standard Methods of Fire Tests of Building Construction and Materials.</section><section prefix='(96)'>NFPA 252-1990, Standard Methods of Fire Tests of Door Assemblies.</section><section prefix='(97)'>NFPA 253-1990, Standard Method of Fire Tests for Critical Radiant Flux of Floor Covering Systems Using a Radiant Heat Energy Source.</section><section prefix='(98)'>NFPA 255-1990, Standard Method of Test of Surface Burning Characteristics of Building Materials.</section><section prefix='(99)'>NFPA 256-1987, Standard Methods of Fire Tests of Roof Coverings.</section><section prefix='(100)'>NFPA 257-1985, Standard for Fire Tests of Window Assemblies.</section><section prefix='(101)'>NFPA 259-1987, Standard Test Method for Potential Heat of Building Materials.</section><section prefix='(102)'>NFPA 303-1990, Fire Protection Standards for Marinas and Boatyards.</section><section prefix='(103)'>NFPA 307-1990, Standard for the Construction and Fire Protection of Marine Terminals, Piers and Wharves.</section><section prefix='(104)'>NFPA 327-1987, Standard Procedure for Cleaning or Safeguarding Small Tanks and Containers.</section><section prefix='(105)'>NFPA 385-1990, Standard for Tank Vehicles for Flammable and Combustible Liquids.</section><section prefix='(106)'>NFPA 386-1990, Standard for Portable Shipping Tanks for Flammable and Combustible Liquids.</section><section prefix='(107)'>NFPA 395-1988, Standard for Storage of Flammable and Combustible Liquids on Farms and Isolated Construction Projects.</section><section prefix='(108)'>NFPA 407-1990, Aircraft Fuel Servicing.</section><section prefix='(109)'>NFPA 409-1990, Aircraft Hangars.</section><section prefix='(110)'>NFPA 416-1987, Construction and Protection of Airport Terminal Buildings.</section><section prefix='(111)'>NFPA 418-1990, Roof-Top Heliport Construction and Protection.</section><section prefix='(112)'>NFPA 480-1987, Storage, Handling and Protecting of Magnesium.</section><section prefix='(113)'>NFPA 490-1986, Code for the Storage of Ammonium Nitrate.</section><section prefix='(114)'>NFPA 491M-1991, Hazardous Chemical Reactions.</section><section prefix='(115)'>NFPA 495-1990, Manufacture, Transportation, Storage and Use of Explosive Materials.</section><section prefix='(116)'>NFPA 501A-1987, Standard for Firesafety Criteria for Mobile Home Installations, Sites and Communities.</section><section prefix='(117)'>NFPA 501C-1990, Standard for Firesafety Criteria for Recreational Vehicles.</section><section prefix='(118)'>NFPA 501D-1990, Standards for Firesafety Criteria and Recreational Vehicle Parks and Campgrounds.</section><section prefix='(119)'>NFPA 651-1987, Standard for the Manufacture of Aluminum and Magnesium Powder.</section><section prefix='(120)'>NFPA 654-1988, Prevention of Fire and Dust Explosions in Chemical, Dye, Pharmaceutical and Plastic Industries.</section><section prefix='(121)'>NFPA 655-1988, Prevention of Sulfur Fires and Explosions.</section><section prefix='(122)'>NFPA 664-1987, Prevention of Fires and Explosions in Wood Processing and Wood Working Facilities.</section><section prefix='(123)'>NFPA 701-1989, Standard Methods of Fire Tests for Flame Resistant Textiles and Films.</section><section prefix='(124)'>NFPA 703-1985, Standard for Fire Retardant Impregnated Wood and Fire Retardant Coatings for Building Materials.</section><section prefix='(125)'>NFPA 704-1990, Standard System for the Identification of the Fire Hazards of Materials.</section><section prefix='(126)'>NFPA 907M-1988, Investigation of Fires of Electrical Origin.</section><section prefix='(127)'>NFPA 1123-1990, Standard for Public Display of Fireworks.</section><section prefix='(128)'>NFPA 1221-1988, Standard for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Public Fire Service Communications.</section><section prefix='(129)'>NFPA 1962-1988, Standard for the Care, Use and Maintenance of Fire Hose.</section><section prefix='(130)'>NFPA 1963-1985, Screw Threads and Gaskets for Fire Hose Connections.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>The following standards of the American National Standards Institute, Inc., 1430 Broadway, New York, N.Y. 10018, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>Identification of Piping Systems, ANSI A13.1-1981</section><section prefix='(2)'>Safety Code for Fixed Ladders, ANSI A14.3-1974</section><section prefix='(3)'>Safety Code for Elevators and Escalators, ANSI A17.1-1984</section><section prefix='(4)'>Standard for Compressed Gas Cylinder Valve, Outlet and Inlet Connections, ANSI B-57 I 1965</section><section prefix='(5)'>Power Piping, ANSI B31.1-1983</section><section prefix='(6)'>Fuel Gas Piping, ANSI B31.2-1968</section><section prefix='(7)'>Chemical Plant and Petroleum Refinery Piping, ANSI B31.3-1984</section><section prefix='(8)'>Liquid Petroleum Transportation Piping Systems, ANSI B31.4-1979</section><section prefix='(9)'>Gas Transmission and Distribution Piping Systems, ANSI B31.8-1982</section><section prefix='(10)'>Building Services Piping Code, ANSI B31.9-1982</section><section prefix='(11)'>Manual for Determining the Remaining Strength of Corroded Pipelines, ANSI B31G-1984</section><section prefix='(12)'>Refrigeration Piping, ANSI B31.5-1983</section><section prefix='(13)'>Safety Code for Mechanical Refrigeration, ANSI 15-1978</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>The following standards of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 345 East 47th Street, New York, N.Y. 10017, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>Safety Code for Elevators and Escalators, A17.1-1984</section><section prefix='(2)'>Unfired Pressure Vessel Code 1980</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>The following standards of the Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., 1285 Walt Whitman Road, Melville, Long Island, N.Y. 11747, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>UL647-1983, Standard for Unvented Kerosene-Fired Room Heaters and Portable Heaters.</section></section><section prefix='(E)'>The following standards of the Compressed Gas Association, Inc., 1235 Jefferson Davis Highway, Arlington, VA 22202, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>CGA Pamphlet V-5, Standard for Noninterchangeable Low-Pressure Connections for Medical Gases, Air, and Suction</section><section prefix='(2)'>CGA Pamphlet G-1, Acetylene</section><section prefix='(3)'>CGA Pamphlet G-2, Anhydrous Ammonia</section><section prefix='(4)'>CGA Pamphlet G-3, Sulphur Dioxide</section><section prefix='(5)'>CGA Pamphlet G-4, Oxygen</section><section prefix='(6)'>CGA Pamphlet G-5, Hydrogen</section><section prefix='(7)'>CGA Pamphlet P-1, Safe Handling of Compressed Gases</section><section prefix='(8)'>CGA Pamphlet P-2, Characteristics and Safe Handling of Medical Gases</section><section prefix='(9)'>CGA Pamphlet V-5, Diameter-Index Safety System</section></section><section prefix='(F)'>The following standards of the American Petroleum Institute, 2101 L Street, N.W., Washington D.C., are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>API 620-1990 Rules for Design and Construction of Large, Welded, Low-Pressure Storage Tanks</section><section prefix='(2)'>API 1604-1987, Removal and Disposal of Used Underground Petroleum Storage Tanks</section></section><section prefix='(G)'>The following standards of the American Society for Testing Materials, 1916 Race Street, Philadelphia PA, 19103, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>ASTM B88-81, Seamless Copper Tube</section><section prefix='(2)'>ASTM D56-77, Flash Point by Tag Closed Tester</section><section prefix='(3)'>ASTM D86-62, Standard Method of Test for Distillation of Petroleum Products</section><section prefix='(4)'>ASTM Flash and Fire Points by Cleveland Cup</section><section prefix='(5)'>ASTM D93-75, Flash Point by Pensky-Maltens Closed Tester</section><section prefix='(6)'>ASTM D323-72, Vapor Pressure of Petroleum Products</section><section prefix='(7)'>ASTM D3243-73, Flash Point of Aviation Turbine Fuels by Setaflash Closed Tester</section><section prefix='(8)'>ASTM D3278-73, Flash Point of Liquids by Setaflash Closed Tester</section><section prefix='(9)'>ASTM E84-81a, Surface Burning Characteristics of Building Materials</section><section prefix='(10)'>ASTM E136-79, Non-Combustibility of Elementary Materials</section></section><section prefix='(H)'>The following standards of the Institute of Makers of Explosives, 1575 I Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20005, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>Pamphlet No. 1, Standard Storage Magazine</section><section prefix='(2)'>Pamphlet No. 20, Radio Frequency Radiation Hazard in Use of Electric Blasting Caps</section></section><section prefix='(I)'>The following standards of the Fertilizer Institute, 1015—18th Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20006, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>Definition and Test Procedures for Ammonium Nitrate Fertilizer</section></section><section prefix='(J)'>The following standards of the Architectural Fabric Structures Institute, 1800 Pickwick Avenue, Glenview, IL 60025-1377, are hereby adopted by reference as if fully set forth herein:<section prefix='(1)'>ASI-1977, Air Structures Design and Standards Manual.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, § 3, 12-15-87; Ord. No. 90-150, § 2, 12-18-90; Ord. No. 92-35, § 1, 5-5-92)</history></law>