<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-62</section_number>
<catch_line>Inspections; inspection warrants.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002356</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-62. Inspections; inspection warrants.<section prefix='(A)'>Any duly authorized representative of the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, may, at any reasonable time, enter, monitor, sample, test, and inspect, as often as may be necessary, any property, premises, building or place, public or private, residential or nonresidential, owner-occupied or nonowner occupied, within the jurisdiction, for the purpose of: Ascertaining and causing to be corrected any conditions which may cause or contribute to a fire; or which conditions may endanger life and property due to fire; to enforce the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, and any municipal ordinance containing fire safety standards which are more stringent than the foregoing; and to investigate the cause, origin, circumstances of every fire occurring within the jurisdiction which is suspicious in nature or which involves the loss of life or injury to person or by which property has been damaged.</section><section prefix='(B)'>No person shall refuse reasonable entry or access to the duly authorized representative who requests entry for any of the purposes set forth in (A) above and who presents appropriate credentials identifying himself.</section><section prefix='(C)'>No person shall obstruct, hamper, or interfere with any such inspection, entry, monitoring, testing, or sampling.</section><section prefix='(D)'>An inspection, entry, monitoring, testing and sampling, pursuant to this section may be conducted only after:<section prefix='(1)'>Consent for the entry, inspection, testing, monitoring and sampling is received from the owner or person in charge of the property, building, premises or place; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>An inspection warrant as provided in this section or by law is obtained.</section></section><section prefix='(E)'>An inspection warrant as authorized by this article may be issued by a judge of any County Court or Circuit Court of this State which has jurisdiction of the place or thing to be searched.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Upon proper affidavit being made, an inspection warrant may be issued pursuant to the provisions of this article for the following causes shown:<section prefix='(1)'>When it is reasonable to believe that the properties or items to be inspected may be connected with or contain evidence of the violation of any of the provisions of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, or any fire safety standard of a municipality which is more stringent than the foregoing; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>When the inspection sought is an integral part of a scheme of systematic routine or area inspections based upon reasonable legislative or administrative standards and neutral criteria.</section></section><section prefix='(G)'>Before issuing an inspection warrant, the judge shall examine on oath or affirmation the applicant and any other witness and shall satisfy himself of the existence of cause as set forth in (F) above for granting such application.</section><section prefix='(H)'>If the judge is satisfied that cause for the inspection warrant exists, the judge may issue the warrant particularly describing the place, dwelling, item, structure or premises to be inspected and designating on the warrant the purpose and limitations of the inspection.</section><section prefix='(I)'>An inspection warrant shall be effective for the time specified therein, but not for a period of more than fourteen (14) days unless it is extended or renewed by the judge who signed and issued the original warrant upon satisfying himself that such extension or renewal is in the public interest. Such inspection warrant must be executed and returned to the judge by whom it was issued within the time specified in the warrant or within the extended or renewed time. After the expiration of such time, the warrant, unless executed, is void.</section><section prefix='(J)'>An inspection pursuant to an inspection warrant shall not be made by means of forcible entry, except that the judge may expressly authorize a forcible entry when facts are shown which are sufficient to create a reasonable suspicion of a violation which, if such violation existed, would be an immediate threat to health or safety or when facts are shown establishing that reasonable attempts to serve a previous warrant have been unsuccessful.</section><section prefix='(K)'>Each jurisdiction in Dade County with fire safety responsibilities shall prepare and institute a fire safety and fire prevention inspection program for routine and area inspections within each such jurisdiction based upon specific, objective and neutral criteria and standards contained in written plans prepared by each of said jurisdictions. No inspection warrant shall be issued within the jurisdiction based upon cause under (F)(2) of this section, unless and until the written plan of the jurisdiction aforesaid is approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>