<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-65</section_number>
<catch_line>Liens.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002359</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-65. Liens.<section>Owners of real property shall be liable for the sums expended by the County or municipality pursuant to of this article when the violation occurred or continued to exist or appeared imminent upon the real property aforesaid, regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the aforesaid violation. All sums expended by the county or municipality pursuant to of this article shall constitute and are hereby imposed as special assessments against the real property aforesaid, and until fully paid and discharged or barred by law, shall remain liens equal in rank and dignity with the lien of County or municipal ad valorem taxes and superior in rank and dignity to all other liens, encumbrances, titles and claims in, to or against the real property involved. All such sums shall become immediately due and owing to the County or municipality upon expenditure by the County or municipality and shall become delinquent if not fully paid within sixty (60) days after the due date. All such delinquent sums shall bear a penalty of fifteen (15) percent per annum. Unpaid and delinquent sums, together with all penalties imposed thereon, shall remain and constitute special assessment liens against the real property involved for the period of five (5) years from the due date thereof. Said special assessment liens may be enforced by the County or municipality by any of the methods provided in Chapter 85, Florida Statutes, or, in the alternative, foreclosure proceedings may be instituted and prosecuted by the County or municipality pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 173, Florida Statutes, or the collection and enforcement of payment thereof may be accomplished by any other method provided by law. All sums recovered by the County or municipality pursuant to this provision shall be deposited by the County or municipality into the fund from which said sums were expended.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87; Ord. No. 90-150, ยง 4, 12-18-90)</history></law>