<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-67</section_number>
<catch_line>Sprinkler systems, fire pumps, and other extinguishing systems.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002361</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-67. Sprinkler systems, fire pumps, and other extinguishing systems.<section prefix='(1)'>Purpose. The purpose of this section is to seek to obtain proper installation, operation, maintenance, testing, and supervision of sprinkler systems, fire pumps, and other fire extinguishing systems, and to seek to obtain compliance with Chapter 633, Florida Statutes, the Florida Fire Prevention Code, the Florida Administrative Code Rule 69A-48 and Rule 69A-60, NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code, NFPA 13 (2002 Edition) Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems, NFPA 13R (2002 Edition) Standard for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems in Residential Occupancies up to and Including Four Stories in Height, and this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Scope of Regulations. The provisions of this section shall apply to all sprinkler systems, except one- and two-family dwelling unit sprinkler systems, within the geographical area of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>New Sprinkler Systems. All new sprinkler systems shall be supervised in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition) National Fire Alarm Code.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Compliance with Section 14-66
                      Sprinkler systems, fire pumps and other extinguishing systems required to be supervised in accordance with NFPA 72 (2002 Edition), by any applicable code, or this section shall be installed, maintained, serviced and operated in accordance with all applicable codes and standards and Section 14-66 of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-27, ยง 1, 3-4-08)</history></law>