<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='2'>Chapter 14 FIRE PREVENTION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SOUTH FLORIDA FIRE PREVENTION CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14-63</section_number>
<catch_line>Orders.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002357</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14-63. Orders.<section prefix='(A)'>Whenever evidence has been received establishing that a violation of this article, the South Florida Fire Prevention Code, the rules and regulations of the State Fire Marshal, or any fire safety standards of a municipality which are more stringent than any of the foregoing, has occurred or may reasonably be expected to occur, the chief fire code enforcement official of the jurisdiction, or his designee, or the South Florida Fire Prevention Code Enforcement Officer, or both, may issue, in their discretion, a notice to correct the violation or a citation to cease the violation and cause the same to be served upon the violator by personal service or certified mail to the violator's last known address or post office box or by posting a copy in a conspicuous place at the premises of the violation. Failure to claim the certified mail shall be deemed to be complete and proper service. Such notice or citation shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation and specify a reasonable time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. Reasonable time herein means the shortest practicable time to rectify or stop the violation. Such notice or citation may require the violator to restrict, cease or suspend use or operation of the facility or premises. Any orders hereunder may be enforced as provided in Section 14-56 of this article. This provision shall not be construed to require the issuance or service of a notice of violation or citation to cease or other order prior to initiating proceedings against a violator pursuant to Section 14-56 of this article.</section><section prefix='(B)'>For the purposes of this article, a violator shall mean the owner, lessee and any other person responsible for the condition of the premises. In the case of a corporation it shall also mean the resident agent, any director or officer. In the case of a partnership it shall also mean any partner.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-89, ยง 3, 12-15-87)</history></law>