<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00027' order_by='00027' level='2'>Chapter 14B FOOD AND FOOD SERVICE ESTABLISHMENTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. MINIMUM STANDARDS OF HYGIENE FOR PUBLIC FOOD SERVICE ESTABLISHMENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>14B-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002373</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 14B-12. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>For the purposes of this article, the term "public food service establishment" is defined hereby to mean every building or portion of a building, vehicle (motorized or nonmotorized), wagon or mobile food unit that is maintained and operated as a place where food and/or drink is regularly prepared, served and/or sold to the public for human consumption, including, but not limited to, any restaurant, cafeteria, lunchroom, lunch counter or soda fountain, food service establishment, food processing plant or food outlet. For the purposes of this section, the phrases "food service establishment," "food processing plant" and "food outlet" mean and include those establishments similarly defined in Chapters 10D-13, 10D-14 and 10D-15, Florida Administrative Code.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For the purposes of this article, the term "kitchen" is defined hereby to mean the area of a public food service establishment where food is prepared or cooked or stored for future preparation or cooking.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For the purposes of this article, the terms "inspect" and "inspection" are defined hereby to mean open to the view of authorized persons, at any time during working hours. "Inspection" includes the ability to photograph the kitchen area.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-60, ยง 2, 6-5-73; Ord. No. 75-83, ยง 1, 10-15-75)</history></law>