<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Resource recovery and management facility permitting.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002429</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-18. Resource recovery and management facility permitting.<section>All resource recovery and management facilities in Miami-Dade County shall be required to obtain an operating permit, pursuant to Section 24-35.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='(a)'>The director of the Department of Solid Waste Management or his designee shall review all resource recovery and management operation permit applications, and shall make a recommendation to the director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management regarding such application, subject to conditions. The Department of Solid Waste Management shall charge and collect a fee for resource recovery and management facility operating permit application review. This charge shall be established by separate administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. In reviewing the application, the director of the Department of Solid Waste Management or his designee shall consider the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Whether operation of the facility as proposed will have an adverse impact on the county's ability to meet its financial obligations for existing county solid waste management facilities.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whether operation of the facility as proposed will have an adverse impact on the County's ability to meet operating requirements for any solid waste management facility operated under contract with the County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Whether operation of the facility as proposed will have an adverse impact on the County's ability to comply with all State and Federal regulations governing solid waste management activities.</section><section>The director of the department shall, concurrently with the effective date of this ordinance, implement regulations establishing procedures for evaluating the impacts set forth above.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The permittee shall charge and collect (a) fee(s) for specified county-wide solid waste management programs at the rate(s) established by separate administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Funds collected shall be submitted to the Department of Solid Waste Management by the 15th day of the month following the month in which collection of the fee(s) occurred.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-155, ยง 4, 12-15-92)</history></law>