<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-17.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Application for permit.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002411</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-17.1. Application for permit.<section>Applications for a permit shall be made to the Department upon such form and in such manner as shall be prescribed by the Director, said form to elicit the following information and to be accompanied by supporting documents and such other information as may be required by the Department from time to time:<section prefix='(a)'>Name of applicant. If the applicant is a partnership or corporation, the name(s) and business address(es) of the principal officers and stockholders and other persons having any financial or controlling interest in the partnership or corporation. Provided, however, that if the corporation is a publicly owned corporation having more than twenty-five (25) shareholders, then only the names and business addresses of the local managing officers shall be required.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Character of applicant. The applicant for a permit under this section, if an individual, or in the case of a firm, corporation, partnership, association or organization, any person having any financial, controlling or managerial interest therein, shall be of good moral character. In making such determination the following information, which shall be submitted by applicant, shall be considered:<section prefix='(1)'>Penal history. If the applicant is an individual, a record of all convictions and the reasons therefor shall be provided by the applicant. If the applicant is other than an individual, then the record of all convictions and the reason therefor of the principal controlling officers of applicant shall be provided. Provided, however, that in the case of a publicly held corporation having twenty-five (25) or more shareholders, then only the aforementioned information applicable to its local managing officers shall be required.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Fingerprints. The fingerprints of the persons mentioned in this subsection, a full set of which, for each of such persons shall accompany the application. Such service may be obtained from the Metro-Dade Police Department.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Business history. Whether such applicant has operated a solid waste collection-removal business, waste tire transporting business or tire business in this or another state under a franchise, permit or license and if so, where and whether such franchise, permit or license has ever been revoked or suspended and the reasons therefor.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Existence of business entity. If applicant is a corporation, applicant shall submit proof of incorporation in good standing in the state of incorporation and, if a foreign corporation, applicant shall provide information certifying that applicant is qualified to do business in the State of Florida. If applicant is other than a corporation and is operating under a fictitious name, applicant shall be required to submit information that such fictitious name is registered and held by applicant.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Equipment and method of operation. The applicant for a permit shall possess equipment capable of providing safe and efficient service. In making such a determination and approving the method of operation for each applicant, the Department shall require the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>The type, number and complete description of all equipment to be used by the applicant for providing service pursuant to this chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A statement that the applicant will use County-owned facilities for disposing of all solid waste which the applicant collects and removes, or those facilities not owned by the County which have been approved by the State Department of Environmental Regulation.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The names of customers and the addresses of each location served. Permittees applying for permit renewals shall not be required to submit the information specified in Section 15-17.1(c)(3) above, but shall instead be required to submit the information specified in Section 15-17.9</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Landscaping businesses applying for permits to use neighborhood trash and recycling centers and/or County-owned solid waste management facility(ies) for disposal of clean yard trash shall be exempt from (c)(3) above, and shall instead supply the information specified in Section 15-17.9(d).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Persons applying for a Waste Tire Generator or Waste Tire Transporter permit shall be exempt from (b)(1)—(3) and (c)(1), (2) above and shall instead supply the information specified in Section 15-17.9</section><section prefix='(f)'>Insurance requirements. The applicant for a permit shall maintain insurance as specified herein and shall furnish a public liability policy to the Department and also file with the Department a certificate of insurance for all policies written in the applicant's name. This certificate shall provide that the policies contain an endorsement requiring that the Department shall be furnished with ten (10) days' written notice by registered mail prior to cancellation or material changes in the policies.<section prefix='(1)'>Comprehensive general liability. The applicant shall carry in his own name a policy covering his operations in an amount not less than three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury and fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per occurrence for property damage liability. Landscaping businesses applying to use (a) neighborhood trash and recycling center(s) and/or County-owned solid waste management facilities for the disposal of clean yard trash shall not, as a condition of the permit to use a neighborhood trash and recycling center(s) and/or County-owned solid waste management facilities be required to maintain comprehensive general liability insurance. Persons applying for a Waste Tire Generator permit or Waste Tire Transporter permit shall not, as a condition of the permit be required to maintain comprehensive general liability insurance.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Vehicle liability insurance. Applicants for a General permit shall maintain vehicle liability insurance covering each vehicle utilized in the business of solid waste collection and disposal in an amount not less than one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) combined single limit per occurrence. All other permittees are required to maintain vehicle liability insurance covering each vehicle in an amount not less than the minimum required by Florida law for the type of vehicle insured.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Liability of the County and the Department. The above insurance requirements shall not be construed as imposing upon the County or the Department or any official or employee thereof any liability or responsibility for injury to any person or property by the insured, his agents or employees.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Application fee. The department shall charge and collect permit application fees at the rates established by separate administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Separate fees shall be established for permits according to the type of permit issued, as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>General.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Small owner-operator landscaping business.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Waste Tire Generator.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Waste Tire Transporter.</section></section></section><section>The completed application shall be submitted to the Department. Upon receipt of a completed application, the Director or his designated representative shall review said application and, if satisfactory in all respects, and after payment of required fees pursuant to Sections and shall issue the required permit.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 82-105, § 1, 11-2-82; Ord. No. 89-5, § 5, 1-17-89; Ord. No. 89-73, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 91-123, § 8, 10-15-91; Ord. No. 92-3, § 1, 1-21-92; Ord. No. 92-20, § 6, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 92-43, § 7, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 94-198, § 3, 11-1-94; Ord. No. 02-166, § 24, 9-19-02; Ord. No. 03-180, § 4, 7-22-03)</history></law>