<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Special collections, fees, extra charges.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002407</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-14. Special collections, fees, extra charges.<section>Any special collections or waste services not covered by this chapter which are performed by the department shall be performed pursuant to such conditions as may be specified by the Director. The department shall charge and collect fees for such special collections or waste services as approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>Whenever a violation of this chapter involving unlawful placement or disposal of materials occurs, and the department undertakes removal and disposal of such materials, the department shall charge and collect fees for such services at the rates established by separate administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>Refusal or delay in rendering payment for any special collection performed as outlined in this chapter shall constitute the basis for adding such unpaid charges to regular waste fee assessment accruing against the property where such special collections are made, and are hereby imposed as special assessment liens against the real property aforesaid, and until fully paid and discharged, or barred by law, shall remain liens equal in rank and dignity with the lien of County ad valorem taxes and superior in rank and dignity to all other liens, encumbrances, titles and claims in, to or against the real property involved, and when delinquent, shall bear interest and may be enforced and collected pursuant to the provisions of(a) of this chapter when applicable.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-12, § 3.08, 6-9-59; Ord. No. 72-6, § 6, 2-1-72; Ord. No. 75-112, § 1, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 82-105, § 1, 11-2-82; Ord. No. 89-5, § 3, 1-17-89; Ord. No. 92-43, § 5, 5-19-92)</history></law>