<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-17</section_number>
<catch_line>Permits required by the Department of Solid Waste Management.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002410</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-17. Permits required by the Department of Solid Waste Management.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to remove, collect or transport for hire or salvage any solid waste or recyclable material over the streets or public right-of-way within any unincorporated area of the County, any unincorporated area that is incorporated subsequent to the effective date of this ordinance, and any unincorporated area that is annexed to an existing municipality subsequent to the effective date of this ordinance, without first applying for and receiving the appropriate solid waste permit from the Department to carry on such a business.</section><section prefix='(2)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to remove, collect or transport within Miami-Dade County five (5) or more waste tires for hire without a Waste Tire Transporter Permit from the Department of Solid Waste Management.</section><section prefix='(3)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to sell, trade or otherwise transfer new, used, or waste tires within Miami-Dade County without a Waste Tire Generator Permit from the Department of Solid Waste Management.</section><section>Permits issued by the Department are as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>General: Applies to any person engaged in the business of solid waste collection, removal, or transport for hire or salvage, or any person engaged in the business of recyclable materials collection, removal or transport for hire or salvage.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Landscaping business: Applies to landscaping businesses as a requirement to enable them to use neighborhood trash and recycling centers, and (a) use County-owned solid waste management facility(ies) designated by the Director, for disposal of clean yard trash only.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Waste tire generator: Applies to any person that is either principally or partially engaged in the selling, trading or otherwise transferring of new, used or waste tires, whether such transactions are for cash, barter or without consideration.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Waste tire transporter: Applies to any person transporting five (5) or more waste tires for hire.</section></section><section>Permits required by this section shall be in addition to any other permits, registration or occupational license which may be required by Federal, State or Local law.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Exemptions. The provisions of this section shall not apply to:<section prefix='(a)'>Commercial or multi-family residential establishments for the sole purpose of hauling the trash or recyclable material of its own tenants or occupants.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Persons who use entity owned or leased vehicles to transport tires for the purpose of retreading between entity owned or franchised retail tire outlets and retread facilities owned or franchised by the same entity.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The provisions of this section shall not apply to organized events to clean up improperly disposed waste tires or other organized environmental cleanup activities.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-12, § 4.02, 6-9-59; Ord. No. 60-22, § 3, 7-26-60; Ord. No. 72-26, § 3, 5-16-72; Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 82-105, § 1, 11-2-82; Ord. No. 91-95, § 13, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 92-20, § 5, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 94-198, § 2, 11-1-94; Ord. No. 95-174, § 10(Att. D), 9-20-95; Ord. No. 96-30, § 2, 2-6-96; Ord. No. 02-166, § 24, 9-19-02; Ord. No. 03-180, § 3, 7-22-03)</history></law>