<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-17.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Identification of equipment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002418</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-17.8. Identification of equipment.<section>All equipment delivering waste to a Miami-Dade County solid waste management facility must be identified in the manner described in this section: All permit decals for any vehicle permitted under this Chapter shall be permanently affixed to the passenger side windshield of the vehicle. Failure to permanently affix said decal shall be unlawful and may be enforced as prescribed in of this Chapter. All markings must be in letters and numerals at least two (2) inches in height.<section prefix='(a)'>General hauler permittees: Equipment must be conspicuously and permanently marked-on both sides of the automotive unit with the name of the hauler, Miami-Dade County permit number, vehicle number, tare weight and cubic yard capacity. Identical information must also be marked on all trailer and container units.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Landscaping businesses having a valid permit issued by the Department to dispose at other than neighborhood trash and recycling centers: Equipment must be conspicuously and permanently marked-on both sides of the automotive unit with the name of the company and vehicle number.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Landscaping businesses having a valid permit issued by the Department to dispose at the neighborhood trash and recycling centers: Equipment must be conspicuously and permanently marked-on both sides of the automotive unit with the name of the company.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 82-105, § 1, 11-2-82; Ord. No. 92-20, § 7, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 99-91, § 8, 7-27-99; Ord. No. 02-166, § 24, 9-19-02; Ord. No. 03-180, § 5, 7-22-03)</history></law>