<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-17.9</section_number>
<catch_line>Information required of permittees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002419</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-17.9. Information required of permittees.<section>On an annual renewal basis, each permittee shall supply the following information on a form and in the manner prescribed by the Director:<section prefix='(a)'>A listing, which is organized as prescribed by the Director, as of the reporting date, of the names and addresses of customers, and the addresses of each location served. For each customer on the list, the private hauler will indicate the following: (1) whether the customer served is (i) a multi-family residential establishment, (ii) commercial establishment, (iii) subject to the Disposal Facility Fee pursuant to Section 15-25.2 of this Chapter; and (2) whether the service provided is solid waste collection, recycling, or a combination of both; and, if the service is recycling, (3) a listing of those materials being recycled at each customer location; and (4) the name of a customer contact person who can provide additional information regarding the recycling program.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A summary of the number of tons of solid waste collected quarterly based on scheduled service, as of the reporting date.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A summary of the number of tons of recyclable material collected and marketed quarterly, on a schedule and format prescribed by the Department.</section><section prefix='(d)'>businesses that receive permits to use neighborhood trash and recycling centers and/or a County-owned solid waste management facility(ies) for disposal of clean yard trash shall be exempt from (a) and (b) above and shall instead supply the following information in a manner prescribed by the Director:<section prefix='(1)'>Miami-Dade County Occupational license as proof of a business location in Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Waste tire generators shall supply the following information in lieu of the information required by sections (a), (b), (c) and (d) herein, on a form and in a manner prescribed by the director:<section prefix='(1)'>An accounting of the number of new, used and recapped tires received from suppliers.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The number of new, used and recapped tires transferred to others.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The number of waste tires removed from the premises, and corresponding removal dates.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The name and permit number of the waste tire transporter(s) employed to remove waste tires.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Waste tire transporter shall supply the following information in lieu of the information required by sections (a), (b), (c) and (d) herein, on a form and in a manner prescribed by the Director;<section prefix='(1)'>An accounting of the number of waste tires collected from each waste tire generator and corresponding collection date(s).</section><section prefix='(2)'>The name and permit number of the waste tire generator from which waste tires were collected.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Copies of the scalehouse receipts for waste tires delivered to a waste tire processing facility(ies). Receipts must show the volume in cubic yards or weight in tons of waste tires delivered, the delivery date and location in or out of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 82-105, § 1, 11-2-82; Ord. No. 91-123, § 11, 10-15-91; Ord. No. 92-3, § 2, 1-21-92; Ord. No. 92-20, § 8, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 94-198, § 4, 11-1-94; Ord. No. 02-166, § 24, 9-19-02; Ord. No. 03-180, § 6, 7-22-03; Ord. No. 06-172, § 2, 11-28-06)</history></law>