<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-25.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative findings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002434</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-25.1. Legislative findings.<section>The Board hereby finds and declares that the County has the legal responsibility to provide for solid waste disposal facilities at a level-of-service that satisfies the concurrency requirements of the Local Government Comprehensive Planning and Land Development Regulation Act. The Board further finds and declares that Miami-Dade County has the legal responsibility and authority to provide, or cause to be provided, safe and sanitary solid waste collection, transportation, and disposal services within Miami-Dade County in accordance with Article VIII, Section 6(1)(e), of the 1968 Florida Constitution and Article 1, Section 1.01(9) and (21), Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter. Moreover,(9) of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter specifically provides the Board of County Commissioners with the power to "provide and regulate......waste and sewage collection and disposal and water supply and conservation programs.</section><section>This Board further finds and declares that collection, transportation, and disposal of solid waste from residential, commercial, industrial, institutional and other establishments and improved properties in the Disposal Facility Fee Area is a matter of serious concern to the health, safety and welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County. The Board further finds and declares that collection, transportation, and disposal of solid waste generated in the Disposal Facility Fee Area are essential public services. The Board further finds and declares that imposition of a Disposal Facility Fee on private haulers operating in the Disposal Facility Fee Area is the best and most practical means to meet its legal responsibilities to make available County solid waste disposal capacity, the revenues from which shall be used to pay County solid waste management system costs.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-174, ยง 9(Att. C, ยง 2), 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-30, ยง 3, 2-6-96; Ord. No. 06-172, ยง 3, 11-28-06)</history></law>