<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Solid waste collection services, container usage, condition and location.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002383</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-2. Solid waste collection services, container usage, condition and location.<section>Every commercial and multi-family residential establishment shall utilize the solid waste collection services of either the proper governmental agency able to provide such services or that of a licensed solid waste hauler authorized to perform such services by the Director of the Department. Each residential unit, multi-family residential establishment or commercial establishment located in any area where Miami-Dade County solid waste collection and disposal service is provided shall have a sufficient number of garbage cans, plastic garbage bags or portable containers to accommodate all garbage, bundled yard trash or other trash to be removed by Miami-Dade County or other approved contractors. All solid waste to be removed by Miami-Dade County shall be placed at curbside in front of property in such a manner as not to obstruct pedestrian passage, except that collections will be made from alleyways where there is clear and safe access for passage of heavy equipment. An exception to this rule is a handicapped person, per determination of the Director.</section><section>It shall be unlawful for any person to set out for collection any waste containers which do not conform to the provisions of this chapter or which contain other defects likely to hamper the collection of or injure the person collecting the contents hereof are illegal. Such containers shall be promptly replaced by the owner or user of the container upon the receipt of written notice of said defect. At no time will the Department service any such illegal containers. Portable containers declared a public nuisance or to be unserviceable with no identifying marks visible to enforcement officers shall be removed at the discretion of the Director.</section><section>It shall be unlawful for any person to place or cause, let, allow, permit or suffer the placement of any uncontainerized waste at curbside, right-of-way or street edge at any time except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-12, § 2.03, 6-9-59; Ord. No. 72-6, § 2, 2-1-72; Ord. No. 77-56, § 2, 7-19-77; Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 82-105, § 1, 11-2-82; Ord. No. 91-95, § 2, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 92-43, § 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 99-91, § 2, 7-27-99)</history></law>