<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-2.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Mandatory separation of recyclable materials from solid waste stream.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002389</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-2.6. Mandatory separation of recyclable materials from solid waste stream.<section prefix='(a)'>All occupants of every multi-family residential establishment and every residential unit are required, in accord with the collection program provided at that location, to separate, from all other solid waste collected or received by Miami-Dade County or any other collector, the following materials:<section prefix='(1)'>Newspaper;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Glass;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Aluminum cans;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Steel cans;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Plastics.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>All occupants of every commercial establishment are required to separate, from all other solid waste collected or received by Miami-Dade County or any other collector, those three selected materials from the following list that are included in the program established at that location in compliance with Section 15-2.3<section prefix='(1)'>High grade office paper;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Mixed paper;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Corrugated cardboard;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Glass;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Aluminum;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Steel;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Other metals/scrap production materials;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Plastics;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Textiles;</section><section prefix='(10)'>Wood.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Occupants of multi-family residential establishments and commercial establishments may, as an alternative to the requirements of this section, separate recyclable materials in accordance with the modified recycling program established at their place of business or residence in compliance with Section 15-2.4. Modified recycling programs shall include those providing for:<section prefix='(1)'>A lesser number of recyclable materials than the required minimum.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Substitution of recyclable materials not listed in Section 15-2.6</section><section prefix='(3)'>Post-collection separation of recyclable material for commercial establishments, and for those multi-family residential establishments for which separation of recyclable material on the premises is wholly, physically impractical, provided, however, that those modified recycling programs providing for post-collection separation of recyclable material for either commercial or multi-family residential establishments shall be allowed which have been established in compliance with Section 15-2.4 pursuant to contracts in existence as of July 21, 1992.</section></section><section>The county manager shall, within six (6) months of the effective date of this Ordinance Number 92-78, adopt and implement regulations establishing procedures requiring commercial and multi-family residential establishments and residential units to place these materials in specialized receptacles, or to handle them in any other manner which the county manager determines shall facilitate the recycling of such materials.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-78, ยง 1, 7-21-92)</history></law>