<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-24</section_number>
<catch_line>Schedule of solid waste collection and disposal fees, records to be kept.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002432</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-24. Schedule of solid waste collection and disposal fees, records to be kept.<section>Effective October 1, 1981, in any area in which solid waste collection services are provided by the Department, it shall be the responsibility of each person who is the owner of a lot, tract or parcel of land upon which a residential unit or multi-family residential establishment is located, to pay for residential solid waste collection services, on the tax bill, in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 197 of the Florida Statutes, as amended.<section prefix='(a)'>Residential units. The department shall charge and collect fees for solid waste services at the rates established by separate administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. In the event any single family residential unit is found to in fact have been illegally converted into multi-family residential units, the Department of Solid Waste Management of Miami-Dade County, upon notification and to the extent permitted by state law, will assess additional fees for the additional services provided by the Department on said property. This fee will be billed in accordance with the fee schedule for single family residential units approved by the Board of County Commissioners and will be assessed as to each of the additional units discovered for up to three (3) preceding years.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Commercial or multi-family residential establishments. The department shall charge and collect fees based on the type, quantity and frequency of service, as approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Residential and multi-family residential units receiving Miami-Dade County recycling services that are not receiving garbage and trash collection from the County shall pay for weekly curbside recycling service according to the fee schedule established by separate administrative order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section>The Department shall maintain complete and accurate records of the costs and expenditures for providing waste collection services, and shall provide the County Manager and the County Commission with periodic statements and reports showing such costs and expenditures. The County Commission shall make periodic adjustment of the fees, assessments and charges for waste collection and disposal services in accordance with the cost analysis of providing such services.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-12, § 3.07, 6-9-59; Ord. No. 60-22, § 5, 7-26-60; Ord. No. 67-25, § 2, 4-7-67; Ord. No. 67-81, § 1, 10-17-67; Ord. No. 69-82, § 1, 11-26-69; Ord. No. 72-6, § 8, 2-1-72; Ord. No. 75-112, § 3, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 82-44, § 1, 6-1-82; Ord. No. 82-89, § 1, 9-17-82; Ord. No. 83-97, § 1, 10-18-83; Ord. No. 89-5, § 11, 1-17-89; Ord. No. 89-89, § 7, 9-19-89; Ord. No. 90-16, § 2, 3-6-90; Ord. No. 90-100, § 7, 9-19-90; Ord. No. 91-95, § 20, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 92-43, § 10, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 99-34, § 1, 4-13-99)</history></law>