<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-25.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Disposal Facility Fee payable to County.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002435</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-25.2. Disposal Facility Fee payable to County.<section>It shall be unlawful for any private hauler operating in the Disposal Facility Fee Area to either collect, transport, or deliver solid waste for disposal without payment of a Disposal Facility Fee to the County as prescribed herein.</section><section>By the twenty-fifth day of each month, all private haulers operating in the Disposal Facility Fee Area shall file a Disposal Facility Fee report with the Director and pay all Disposal Facility Fees owed to the County for the preceding month. The Disposal Facility Fee report shall be filed on forms provided by the County and shall include the private hauler's monthly receipts for solid waste collection and disposal service for all accounts subject to the Disposal Facility Fee for the preceding month, which report shall be subject to audit by the County. The report shall also include a calculation on Disposal Facility Fees owed to the County for the previous month in an amount equal to fifteen (15) percent of the total monthly receipts for solid waste collection and disposal service, which monthly receipts shall not include Disposal Facility Fees assessed by the private hauler to the customer.</section><section>An additional monthly surcharge, equal to one (1) percent of the Disposal Facility Fee amount for the preceding month shall be payable to the County if the fifteen (15) percent Disposal Facility Fee is not paid or the Disposal Facility Fee report is not filed by the twenty-fifth of the month by the private hauler.</section><section>Two and one half (2.5) percent of the monthly Disposal Facility Fee amount payable to the County may be retained by each private hauler to help defray administrative costs associated with this fee, including accounting and auditing costs.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-174, § 9(Att. C, § 3), 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-30, § 4, 2-6-96; Ord. No. 96-143, § 7, 9-18-96; Ord. No. 97-156, § 7, 9-17-97; Ord. No. 98-143, § 7, 9-18-98; Ord. No. 06-172, § 4, 11-28-06)</history></law>