<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-2.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Modified recycling programs allowed.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002387</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-2.4. Modified recycling programs allowed.<section prefix='(a)'>Recycling programs which incorporate modifications, substitutions or reductions to the requirements of Sections 15-2.2 and 15-2.3 may be submitted to the Department for approval. Approval, rejection, or approval with conditions of the proposed modified recycling program shall be determined by the Department. The Department shall consider the following factors in evaluating the proposed modified recycling program:<section prefix='(1)'>Whether the establishment operates a recycling program, and is self-hauling the materials to a recyclable material vendor.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whether the establishment generates a lesser number of recyclable materials than the required minimum.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Whether the establishment generates and recycles materials not listed in Section 15-2.2 or Section 15-2.3 hereof, as applicable.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Whether the establishment is contracting with a permitted private hauler for collection services, which services provide for a post-collection separation of recyclable material, and which:<section prefix='(i)'>Generate recyclable materials which comply, in kind and quantity, with the recycling requirements provided for in Section 15-2.2 or Section 15-2.3 hereof, as applicable; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Utilize a materials separation facility which is permitted in accordance with all applicable federal, State and local laws.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person seeking approval of a modified recycling program shall submit an application in such form as is prescribed by the Department. All modified recycling programs shall be reviewed on a semiannual basis and applicants shall be required to confirm or revise the information contained in their applications at that time.</section><section>An application for approval of a modified recycling program shall include, but not be limited to, the following documentation, as appropriate to the specific application:<section prefix='(1)'>Supporting documentation to evidence self-haul activities, which shall include proof of source-separation activities and copies of receipts from recyclable material purchasers.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A waste composition study of the waste generated by the applicant, which shall cover a representative time period of no shorter than one (1) week.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A copy of the applicable contract with a post-collection separation facility, specifying materials and volumes recycled which are attributable to the applicant.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-123, ยง 6, 10-15-91)</history></law>