<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-2.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002390</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-2.7. Enforcement.<section>The provisions of Ordinance Number 92-78 shall be enforced by the county manager pursuant to the final promulgated regulations of this ordinance. Such regulations shall provide that, during the initial twelve-month period of intense education efforts (which shall begin on August 10, 1992, regardless of whether final regulations have been promulgated at that time), Miami-Dade County shall not prosecute individuals who unknowingly fail to separate from all other solid waste the materials required to be separated by this ordinance. The regulations shall provide that during the subsequent six-month period warning tickets shall be issued to all persons who fail to separate the required materials regardless of knowledge or intent. Prior to February 10, 1994, the county manager shall propose for the approval of the board of county commissioners regulations for enforcement of this ordinance to be implemented beginning on February 10, 1994. If such regulations propose an amendment to of the Code of Miami-Dade County, a public hearing before the board of county commissioners shall be required prior to implementation.</section><section>The provisions of shall apply to the incorporated and unincorporated areas, and shall be enforced by Miami-Dade County unless the county and the city agree, in writing; that the city shall enforce this ordinance within the municipality or that the city is operating a recycling program that meets the minimum standards. Any municipality may establish and enforce its own ordinance provided such ordinance is equivalent to or more stringent than the provisions of this ordinance.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-78, ยง 2, 7-21-92)</history></law>