<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-33</section_number>
<catch_line>Advance of funds for operating expenses, automotive vehicles of the Department, establishment of a reserve fund.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002445</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-33. Advance of funds for operating expenses, automotive vehicles of the Department, establishment of a reserve fund.<section prefix='(a)'>Upon the recommendation of the County Manager, and subject to appropriate budget transfer approved by the County Commission, funds for payment of operating expenses of the Department may be advanced, allocated and transferred from the general contingency fund on a temporary basis, provided adequate provision is made for the reimbursement of such advances within the budget year in which such funds are advanced, and provided further that the aggregate amount of such funds advanced shall not at any time exceed sixty (60) percent of the accounts receivable of the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Funds for the purchase of trucks, truck bodies and other automotive vehicles and equipment for use by the Department may be budgeted in the general fund automotive equipment account, provided adequate provisions are made for reimbursement of such advances in the current budget of the Department, and provided further that no such advances shall be made except upon approval of the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Funds may be allocated in a reserve fund entitled "reserve for maintenance and purchase of new equipment that is in excess of expenditures utilized by the Department for revenue collection in a given fiscal year." This specific fund shall be established to provide for the unanticipated increases in the maintenance and purchase of mobile equipment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-40, ยง 1, 11-22-60; Ord. No. 81-108, ยง 1, 9-15-80; Ord. No. 89-5, ยง 14, 1-17-89)</history></law>