<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-5.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibition of commingling of yard trash and other forms of solid waste; joint and several liability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002398</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-5.2. Prohibition of commingling of yard trash and other forms of solid waste; joint and several liability.<section prefix='(a)'>Commingling of yard trash and other forms of solid waste prohibited. After December 31, 1991, the following acts shall be a violation of this section:<section prefix='(1)'>The placement of yard trash at the curbside or other designated garbage collection area, by any person, for collection and disposal as garbage.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The placement of commingled yard trash at the curbside or other designated trash collection area, by any person, for collection and disposal.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Delivery of commingled yard trash, by any person, to a County neighborhood trash and recycling center.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Delivery, by any person, of yard trash commingled with garbage to a solid waste management facility.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Failure, of any person, to deliver a surcharged load of commingled yard trash and garbage to a designated solid waste management facility after having been rerouted from another solid waste management facility.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Failure, by any person utilizing a neighborhood trash and recycling center for disposal of clean yard trash, to place clean yard trash in designated containers or areas for clean yard trash at neighborhood trash and recycling centers.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Delivery, by any person, of yard trash, clean yard trash, or commingled yard trash to a Class I lined landfill for disposal.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Joint and several liability. When a violation of this section involves a vehicle which is registered to a permittee, with regard to said violation, the driver of the vehicle shall be jointly and severally liable with the owner(s) and operator(s) of the permittee to whom the vehicle is registered, as applicable.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-95, ยง 7, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 92-20, ยง 3, 3-17-92)</history></law>