<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='2'>Chapter 15 SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>15-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Geographical service areas adjoining County solid waste management facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002402</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 15-9. Geographical service areas adjoining County solid waste management facilities.<section>Whenever the County plans, constructs, purchases, leases, or operates a solid waste management facility, the Board of County Commissioners may by resolution, designate one or more areas to be serviced by such facility. Within three (3) months from the designation of such geographical service area or upon completion of the construction of such facility, or at such time as the County Commission shall designate, it shall be unlawful to dispose of solid waste within such area except by or through the designated solid waste management facility. The Board of County Commissioners may enlarge or contract the said contiguous geographical service area depending upon the volumes of solid waste generated within the area and the capacity of the solid waste management facility.</section><section>Where the Board of County Commissioners prohibits the disposal of solid waste, within a geographical service area, except through a designated solid waste management facility, the Board may prohibit any person, firm, corporation, municipality or political subdivision from transporting solid waste from the geographical service area to any other portion of the county when, in the board's opinion, such transport will overload the solid waste management facilities became a danger to the public health, welfare and safety of the citizens of the other portion of the County or will in any manner work to detriment of the public health, welfare and safety of the citizens of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>Nothing herein shall, however, prohibit the voluntary source separation of recyclable solid waste materials by the generators of these waste materials or the collection, transportation or processing of such materials within Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 67-27, § 1, 4-25-67; Ord. No. 79-115, § 2, 12-18-79; Ord. No. 81-108, § 1, 9-15-81; Ord. No. 91-95, § 11, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 92-155, § 3, 12-15-92)</history></law>