<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Tax exemptions for renovations for historic properties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002470</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-18. Tax exemptions for renovations for historic properties.<section prefix='(a)'>Scope of tax exemptions. A method is hereby created for the Board of County Commissioners, at its discretion, to allow tax exemptions for the restoration, renovation, or rehabilitation of historic properties. The exemption shall apply to one hundred (100) percent of the assessed value of all improvements to historic properties which result from restoration, renovation, or rehabilitation made on or after the effective date of this ordinance. The exemption applies only to taxes levied by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. The exemption does not apply to taxes levied for the payment of bonds or to taxes authorized by a vote of the electors pursuant to Section 9(b) or Section 12, Article VII of the Florida Constitution. The exemption does not apply to personal property. The exemption under this ordinance does not apply to properties within a community redevelopment area previously or hereafter established pursuant to Part III of Chapter 163, Florida Statutes, by either the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County or the governing body of any city or other municipality within Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Duration of tax exemptions. Any exemption granted under this section to a particular property shall remain in effect for ten (10) years. The Board of County Commissioners shall have the discretion to set a lesser term if requested by the property owner in its original application and covenant. The term of the exemption shall be specified in the resolution approving the exemption. The duration of the exemption as established in the resolution granting the exemption shall continue regardless of any change in the authority of the County to grant such exemptions or any change in ownership of the property. In order to retain an exemption, however, the historic character of the property, and improvements which qualified the property for an exemption, must be maintained in their historic state over the period for which the exemption was granted.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Eligible properties and improvements.<section prefix='(1)'>Property is qualified for an exemption under this section if:<section prefix='(A)'>At the time the exemption is granted the property:<section prefix='(1)'>Is individually listed in the National Register of Historic Places pursuant to the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, as amended; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Is a contributing property to a national-register-listed district; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Is designated as a historic property, or as a contributing property to a historic district, under the terms of a local preservation ordinance; and</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>The Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board has certified to the Board of County Commissioners that the property for which an exemption is requested satisfies paragraph (A).</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>In order for an improvement to a historic property to qualify the property for an exemption, the improvement must:<section prefix='(A)'>Be consistent with the United States Secretary of Interior's Standards for Rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix='(B)'>Be determined by the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board to meet criteria established in rules adopted by the Department of State.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Applications. Any person, firm, or corporation that desires an ad valorem tax exemption for the improvement of a historic property must, prior to construction, file with the Office of Historic Preservation a written application on an approved form. The application must include the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>The name of the property owner and the location of the historic property;</section><section prefix='(2)'>A description of the improvements to real property for which an exemption is requested and the date of commencement of construction of such improvements;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Proof, to the satisfaction of the Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board, that the property this is to be rehabilitated or renovated is a historic property under this section;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Proof, to the satisfaction of the Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board, that the improvements to the property will be consistent with the United States Secretary of Interior's Standards for Rehabilitation and will be made in accordance with guidelines developed by the Department of State;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Other information identified in appropriate Department of State regulations, or requested by the Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>If the property is within the jurisdiction of the Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board, a completed application for a certificate of appropriateness for the qualifying restoration, renovation, or rehabilitation.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Required covenant. To qualify for an exemption, the property owner must enter into a covenant or agreement with the Board of County Commissioners for the term for which the exemption is granted. The form of the covenant or agreement must be established by the Department of State and must require that the character of the property, and the qualifying improvements to the property, be maintained during the period that the exemption is granted. The covenant or agreement shall be binding on the current property owner, transferees, and their heirs, successors, or assigns. Violation of the covenant or agreement results in the property owner being subject to the payment of the differences between the total amount of taxes which would have been due in March in each of the previous years in which the covenant or agreement was in effect had the property not received the exemption and the total amount of taxes actually paid in those years, plus interest on the difference calculated as provided in Section 212.12(3), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Review By Historic Preservation Board. The Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board, or its successor, is designated to review applications for exemptions. The Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board must recommend that the Board of County Commissioners grant or deny the exemption. Such reviews must be conducted in accordance with rules adopted by the Department of State. The recommendation, and the reasons therefor, must be provided to the applicant and to the Board of County Commissioners before consideration of the application at an official meeting of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Approval By Board of County Commissioners. A majority vote of the Board of County Commissioners shall be required to approve a written application for exemption. Such exemption shall take effect as provided in the resolution. The Board of County Commissioners shall include the following in the resolution approving the written application for exemption:<section prefix='(1)'>The name of the owner and the address of the historic property for which the exemption is granted.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The period of time for which the exemption will remain in effect and the expiration date of the exemption.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A finding that the historic property meets the requirements of this section.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 93-15, ยง 1, 3-2-93; Ord. No. 99-90, ยง 2, 7-27-99; Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 16, 3-11-03)</history></law>