<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-17</section_number>
<catch_line>Incentives.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002469</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-17. Incentives.<section>All properties designated as individual sites or as designated properties within a district shall be eligible, upon application by the owner(s), for any available financial assistance set aside for historic preservation by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County contingent on the availability of funds and the scope of the project as described in the application.</section><section>It is the policy of Miami-Dade County to assist the owners of historic properties through the development of a Conservation Easement Program to obtain applicable state and federal tax benefits, pursuant to sections 193.505 &amp; 704.06, Florida Statutes and any other governing law, provided that the Board of County Commissioners shall approve the acceptance, terms, and conditions of any conservation easement before it is accepted by the County. The Historic Preservation Board may promulgate the rules for such Historic Conservation Easements and model covenants that shall be used by the County upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners. The Historic Preservation Board is authorized to apply for grants and other sources of funding for the creation of historic grant and loan programs. Any funds received shall be placed in a Historic Preservation Trust Fund and used only for the purposes for which they were received. The Historic Preservation Board is authorized to promulgate rules and model agreements for such a program which shall be used by the County upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-13, ยง 16, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 82-99, ยง 1, 10-19-82; Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 15, 3-11-03)</history></law>