<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Certificates to dig.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002466</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-14. Certificates to dig.<section prefix='(I)'>Within an archeological or paleontological zone, new construction, filling, digging, the removal of trees, or any other activity that may alter or reveal an interred archeological or paleontological site shall be prohibited without a certificate to dig. All applications to all appropriate municipal or County agencies involving new construction, large-scale digging, the removal of trees or any other activity that may reveal or disturb an interred archeological or paleontological site, in an archeological or paleontological zone shall require a certificate to dig before approval. Based on the designation report for the archeological or paleontological zone, a complete application for a certificate to dig and any additional guidelines the Board may deem necessary, the staff of the Board shall, within ten (10) days from the date the completed application has been filed, approve the application for a certificate to dig by the owners of a property in a designated archeological or paleontological zone. The certificate to dig may be made subject to specified conditions, including but not limited to conditions regarding site excavation. In order to comply with the site excavation requirements of the certificate to dig, the applicant may agree to permit the County Archeologist to conduct excavation from the time of the approval of the certificate to dig until the effective date thereof. The findings of the staff shall be mailed to the applicant by registered mail promptly. The applicant shall have the opportunity to challenge the staff decision or any conditions attached to the certificate to dig by requesting a meeting of the Board. The Board shall convene within thirty-five (35) days after such a request and shall make every effort to review and reconsider the original staff decision to arrive at an equitable decision. The decision of the Board shall be reduced to writing within seven (7) days from the date of the meeting.</section><section prefix='(II)'>Approved certificates to dig. Approved certificates to dig shall contain an effective date not to exceed sixty (60) days at which time the proposed activity may begin, unless the Board decides to designate the site in question as an individual site or district pursuant to Section 16A-10 in which all the rules and regulations pertaining to the designation process shall apply from the date the designation report has been filed.</section><section prefix='(III)'>[Work to conform to certificate; stop work order.] All work performed pursuant to the issuance of a certificate to dig shall conform to the requirements of such certificate. It shall be the duty of the appropriate government agencies and the staff of the Board to inspect from time to time any work pursuant to such certificate to assure compliance. In the event work is performed not in accordance with such certificate, the official designated by the County Manager pursuant to Section 16A-11(IX)[VIII] shall be empowered to issue a stop work order and all work shall cease. No person, firm or corporation shall undertake any work on such projects as long as such stop work order shall continue in effect.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-13, ยง 13, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 82-99, ยง 1, 10-19-82; Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 14, 3-11-03)</history></law>