<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Designation process and procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002461</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-10. Designation process and procedure.<section prefix='(I)'>[Criteria.] The Board shall have the authority to designate areas, places, buildings, structures, landscape features, archeological and paleontological sites and other improvements or physical features, as individual sites, districts or archeological or paleontological zones that are significant in Miami-Dade County's history, architecture, paleontology, archeology or culture and possess an integrity of location, design, setting, materials, workmanship or association, or:<section prefix='(a)'>Are associated with distinctive elements of the cultural, social, political, economic, scientific, religious, prehistoric, paleontological and architectural history that have contributed to the pattern of history in the community, Miami-Dade County, south Florida, the State or the nation; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Are associated with the lives of persons significant in our past; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Embody the distinctive characteristics of a type, period, style or method of construction or work of a master; or that possess high artistic value; or that represent a distinguishable entity whose components may lack individual distinction; or</section><section prefix='(d)'>Have yielded, or are likely to yield information in history or prehistory; or</section><section prefix='(e)'>Are listed in the National Register of Historic Places.</section></section><section prefix='(II)'>[Properties not generally considered; exceptions.] Certain properties, which include cemeteries, birthplaces, properties owned by religious institutions or used for religious purposes, structures that have been moved from their original locations, properties commemorative in nature and properties that have achieved significance within the last fifty (50) years, will not normally be considered for designation. However, such properties will qualify if they are integral parts of districts that do meet the criteria, or if they fall within the following categories:<section prefix='(a)'>A religious property deriving primary significance from architectural or artistic distinction of historical importance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A building or structure removed from its location but which is primarily significant for architectural value, or is the surviving structure most importantly associated with an historic event or person.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A birthplace or grave of an historical figure of outstanding importance if there is no other appropriate site or building directly associated with his/her productive life.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A cemetery which derives its primary significance from graves of persons of transcendent importance, from age, distinctive design features, or from association with historic events.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A property primarily commemorative in intent if design, age, tradition or symbolic value has invested it with its own historical significance.</section><section prefix='(f)'>A property or district achieving significance within the past fifty (50) years if it is of exceptional importance.</section></section><section prefix='(III)'>[Investigation and designation report.] Prior to the designation of an individual site, a district, or an archeological zone, an investigation and designation report must be filed with the Board. The format of these reports may vary according to the type of designation; however, all reports must address the following: The historical, cultural, architectural or archeological significance of the property or properties being recommended for designation; a recommendation of boundaries for districts and archaeological zones and identification of boundaries of individual sites being designated; a recommendation of standards to be adopted by the Board in carrying out its regulatory function under this chapter with respect to certificates of appropriateness and certificates to dig. Where a report is filed recommending designation of a district, the report must identify those properties, if any, within the district which are not historically or architecturally compatible with structures in the district. The standards for regulating such nonconforming properties shall provide that a certificate of appropriateness may be required only for new construction on such properties. All reports shall take into consideration projected, proposed or existing public improvements and developmental or renewal plans.</section><section prefix='(IV)'>Procedure.<section prefix='(a)'>Petition of the owner. The owner(s) of any property in unincorporated Miami-Dade County may petition this Board for designation of their property as an individual site, district or archeological zone provided that they appear before the Board with sufficient information to warrant the investigation of the property for future designation and the Board finds that the property may be worthy of designation. The Board shall, based on its findings, either direct the staff to begin the designation process or deny the petition. Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to restrict the power of the Board to initiate the designation process pursuant to this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Directive of the Board. The Board shall, upon recommendations from staff or the acceptance of petitions pursuant to part (IV), subsection (a) of this section, direct staff to begin the designation process by preparing a designation report, pursuant to part (III) of this section and any other standards the Board may deem necessary, and submitting this report according to the procedures described herein.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notification of owner. For each proposed designation of an individual site, district or archeological zone, the Board is encouraged to obtain the permission of the property owner(s) within the designated area, and is responsible for mailing a copy of the designation report to the owner(s) as notification of the intent of the Board to consider designation of the property at least fifteen (15) days prior to a public hearing held pursuant to this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notification of government agencies. Upon filing of a designation report, the Secretary of the Board shall immediately notify the appropriate building and zoning department, the appropriate public works department and any other County or municipal agency, including agencies with demolition powers, that may be affected by said filing.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notification of a public hearing. For each individual site, district or archeological zone proposed for designation, a public hearing must be held no sooner than fifteen (15) days and within sixty (60) days from the date a designation report has been filed with the Board. Owners of record or other parties having an interest in the proposed designated properties, if known, shall be notified of the public hearing by certified mail to the last known address of the party being served; however, failure to receive such notice shall not invalidate the same as such notice shall also be perfected by publishing a copy thereof in a newspaper of general circulation at least ten (10) days prior to the hearing. Owners shall be given an opportunity at the public hearing to object to the proposed designation.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Requirement of prompt decision and notification. Within seven (7) days of a public hearing on a proposed individual site, district or archeological zone, the Board shall by written resolution state its decision to approve, deny or amend the proposed designation and shall direct the Secretary of the Board to notify the following of its actions with a copy of the resolution:<section prefix='(1)'>The appropriate building and zoning department,</section><section prefix='(2)'>The County Clerk,</section><section prefix='(3)'>The appropriate municipal clerk when necessary,</section><section prefix='(4)'>Owner(s) of the affected property and other parties having an interest in the property, if known,</section><section prefix='(5)'>The appropriate planning department,</section><section prefix='(6)'>The appropriate public works department, and</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any other County or municipal agency, including agencies with demolition powers, that may be affected by this action,</section><section prefix='(8)'>Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>[Amendment or rescission.] The Board may amend or rescind any designation provided it complies with the same manners and procedures used in the original designation.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Moratorium. Upon the filing of a designation report by the staff, the owner(s) of the real property which is the subject matter of the designation report or any individual or private or public entity shall not:<section prefix='(1)'>Erect any structure on the subject property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Alter, restore, renovate, move or demolish any structure on the subject property until such time as final administrative action, as provided by this chapter, is completed.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Recording of designation. The Board shall provide the Clerk of the Circuit Court with all designations for the purpose of recording such designation and the Clerk of the Circuit Court shall thereupon record the designation according to law.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-13, ยง 10, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 82-99, ยง 1, 10-19-82; Ord. No. 88-28, ยง 2, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 10, 3-11-03)</history></law>