<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002455</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-4. Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Archeological or paleontological zone: An area designated by this chapter which is likely to yield information on the paleontology, history and prehistory of Miami-Dade County based on prehistoric settlement patterns in Miami-Dade County as determined by the results of the Miami-Dade County historic survey. These zones will tend to conform to natural physiographic features which were the focal points for prehistoric and historic activities and paleontology.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Certificate of appropriateness: A certificate issued by the Board permitting certain alterations or improvements to a designated individual site or property in a designated district.<section prefix='(a)'>Regular certificate of appropriateness: A regular certificate of appropriateness shall be issued by the staff of the Preservation Board, based on the guidelines for preservation approved by the Board.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Special certificate of appropriateness. For all applications for a special certificate of appropriateness involving the demolition, removal, reconstruction or new construction at an individual site or in a district, a special certificate of appropriateness is required that is issued directly by the Board.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Certificate to dig: A certificate that gives the Board's permission for certain digging projects that may involve the discovery of as yet unknown or known archeological or paleontological sites in an archeological or paleontological zone. This certificate is issued by staff of the Board based on the guidelines for preservation approved by the Board.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Certificate of recognition: A certificate issued by the Board recognizing properties designated pursuant to this chapter.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Demolition: The complete constructive removal of a building on any site.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Districts: A collection of archeological or paleontological sites, buildings, structures, landscape features or other improvements that are concentrated in the same area and have been designated as a district pursuant to this chapter.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Exterior: All outside surfaces of a building or structure.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Guidelines for preservation: Criteria established by the Preservation Board to be used by staff in determining the validity of applications for a regular certificate of appropriateness and any certificate to dig and to establish a set of guidelines for the preservation of buildings in south Florida.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Historic Preservation Board: A board of citizens created by this chapter as described in Sections 16A-5 through 16A-9</section><section prefix='(10)'>Historic survey: A comprehensive survey compiled by the Historic Preservation Division of the Miami-Dade County Office of Community and Economic Development involving the identification, research and documentation of buildings, sites and structures of any historical, cultural, archeological, paleontological or architectural importance in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Individual site: An archeological site, a paleontological site, building, structure, place or other improvement that has been designated as an individual site pursuant to this chapter. Under the provisions of this chapter interior spaces may be regulated only where a building or structure is a designated individual site and where its interiors are specifically designated.</section><section prefix='(12)'>National Register of Historic Places: A federal listing maintained by the U.S. Department of the Interior of buildings, sites, structures and districts that have attained a quality of significance as determined by the Historic Preservation Act of 1966 as amended.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Ordinary repairs or maintenance: Work done to prevent deterioration of a building or structure or decay of or damage to a building or structure or any part thereof by restoring the building or structure as nearly as practicable to its condition prior to such deterioration, decay or damage.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Owner of a designated property: As reflected on the current Metropolitan Miami-Dade County tax rolls or current title holder.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Undue economic hardship: Failure to issue a certificate would place an onerous and excessive financial burden upon the owner that would amount to the taking of the owner's property without just compensation.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Landscape feature: Any improvement or vegetation including, but not limited to outbuildings, walls, courtyards, fences, shrubbery, trees, sidewalks, planters, plantings, gates, street furniture and exterior lighting.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-13, ยง 4, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 82-99, ยง 1, 10-19-82; Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 5, 3-11-03)</history></law>