<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Powers and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002460</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-9. Same—Powers and duties.<section>The Historic Preservation Board shall have the following enumerated powers and duties:<section prefix='(1)'>Adopt or amend rules of procedure.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Designate individual sites, districts and archeological and paleontological zones.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Issue or deny certificates of appropriateness and certificates to dig.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Approve historical markers and issue certificates of recognition for individual sites and designated properties in a district.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Recommend zoning and building code amendments to the proper authorities.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Establish guidelines for preservation and criteria for issuance by staff of regular certificates of appropriateness.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Promote the awareness of historic preservation and its community benefits.</section><section prefix='(8)'>No actions of this Board will supersede or be construed as superseding the authority of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Review and update the historic survey for its quality and professional merit, and validate the findings of the survey as bona fide and sincere.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Implement the authority of this chapter and fulfill the tasks set forth for this Board by the County Commissioners in this chapter and other ordinances.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Record and maintain records of the Board's actions and decisions.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Follow and abide by the laws of the United States of America, the State of Florida and Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Provide an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Review and make recommendations to the Office of Historic Preservation regarding any grant proposals reviewed by the Office of Historic Preservation, including but not limited to Community Development Block Grants.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-13, § 9, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 03-38, § 9, 3-11-03)</history></law>