<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-13.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Demolition By Neglect Prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002465</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-13.1. Demolition By Neglect Prohibited.<section prefix='(1)'>Affirmative Maintenance Required. The owner of a property designated pursuant to this chapter either individually or as a contributing part of a district shall comply with all applicable codes, laws and regulations governing the maintenance of property. It is the intent of this section to preserve from deliberate or inadvertent neglect the exterior features of such properties and the interior portions thereof when maintenance is necessary to prevent deterioration and decay of the property. All such properties shall be preserved against such decay and deterioration and shall be free from structural defects through prompt corrections of any of the following defects:<section prefix='(a)'>Facades which may fall and injure the subject property, adjoining property, or members of the public.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Deteriorated or inadequate foundation, defective or deteriorated flooring or floor supports, deteriorated walls or other vertical structural supports.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Members of ceilings, roofs, ceiling and roof supports or other horizontal members which sag, split or buckle due to defective material or deterioration.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Deteriorated or ineffective waterproofing of exterior walls, roofs, foundations or floors, including broken windows or doors.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any fault or defect in the property which renders it structurally unsafe, insufficiently protected from weathering, or not properly watertight.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Undue Economic Hardship. A property owner who believes that application of this section creates an undue economic hardship may apply for a variance under section 16A-12</section><section prefix='(3)'>Enforcement.<section prefix='(a)'>Notice and Administrative Enforcement. When a Miami-Dade County Code Enforcement Officer learns of a violation of section (1), he or she shall give notice in writing of the violation to the owner, with specific written details of the corrective action necessary to remedy the violation. Such notice shall be given personally, by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, or by posting on the property when the address of the owner cannot be located. The property owner shall have 30 days from the date of such notice to perform the corrective action. Thereafter, the Miami-Dade County Code Enforcement Officer may issue a civil citation pursuant to chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Action For Injunction And Remedial Relief; Lien on Property. If the Property Owner fails to take corrective action within the 30 day period provided in section 3(a), Miami-Dade County may file an action seeking: an injunction ordering the property owner to take corrective action; an order authorizing Miami-Dade County to enter onto the property to make the corrective actions; and civil penalties. The Court shall order an injunction providing such remedies if Miami-Dade County proves that the owner has violated this ordinance and such violation threatens the integrity or existence of an individual site or a contributing structure within a district. Such civil action may be initiated in the name of Miami-Dade County at the discretion of the County Manager upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the Historic Preservation Board. Settlements of such lawsuits may be obtained in the same manner. Nothing herein shall prevent the Board of County Commissioners from initiating or assuming direction of the lawsuit, at its discretion. In the event that the Court authorizes Miami-Dade County to enter onto the property to take the required corrective action, the Court shall also order that the cost of the corrective action shall constitute a lien against the property, accruing interest at the statutory rate for judgments until satisfied.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Civil Penalties. Violation of this section shall be punished by a civil penalty of five hundred dollars. After expiration of the thirty day period provided in section (3)(a), each day that the corrective action is not taken shall constitute a separate violation.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 13, 3-11-03)</history></law>