<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-3.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Municipal Historic Preservation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002453</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-3.1. Municipal Historic Preservation.<section prefix='(1)'>County Technical and Legal Support for Municipal Preservation. The Director of the Office of Historic Preservation and the County Attorney's Office may provide a requesting municipality with technical and legal assistance in preservation matters. Such assistance is not intended to replace the municipality's own commitment of resources to preservation or to divert resources from the County's own preservation responsibilities.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Timeframes for Municipalities to Enact Historic Preservation Ordinances.<section prefix='(a)'>Municipalities incorporated prior to July 1, 1982 were given the option to adopt their own municipal historic preservation ordinances or be governed by the County ordinance. The following municipalities enacted their own ordinances: Coral Gables, Hialeah, Homestead, Miami, Miami Beach, Miami Shores, Miami Springs, Opa-locka, and South Miami.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Municipalities incorporated after July 1, 1982 but before the effective date of this ordinance have until one year after the effective date of this ordinance to adopt their own preservation ordinances.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Municipalities incorporated after the effective date of this ordinance have until one year after the effective date of their incorporation to adopt their own preservation ordinances.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Status of Designated Properties After Transition of Jurisdiction. In the event that a municipality assumes jurisdiction of historic preservation from Miami-Dade County by enacting an ordinance as provided in this section, all properties previously designated by the Miami-Dade Historic Preservation Board shall have the status and protections of properties designated under the municipality's historic preservation ordinance unless and until such designation is removed by formal action of the municipality pursuant to its ordinance. The same rule shall apply if the County assumes jurisdiction from a municipality.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Minimum Standards for Municipal Ordinances.<section prefix='(a)'>To comply with the minimum standards for historic preservation ordinances a municipal ordinance shall contain provisions:<section prefix='(1)'>that establish a historic preservation board which shall be empowered to designate individual sites or districts and to issue certificates of appropriateness; or to advise the city commission regarding such matters. In this regard, this ordinance shall constitute authority for a municipality to delegate to its preservation board the power to designate sites and districts and issue certificates of appropriateness.</section><section prefix='(2)'>that provide procedures for the municipality, its staff, the Director of the Miami-Dade County Office of Historic Preservation, and private parties to recommend the initiation of designations of historic districts and individual historic sites, whether residential, commercial, industrial or other, pursuant to due notice to affected parties, legally-enforceable standards, quasi-judicial hearings, and appeals to court;</section><section prefix='(3)'>that protect designated sites or districts by preventing the issuance of building, construction, zoning, and demolition permits or the significant change of appearance of such sites or districts until a written certificate of appropriateness has been issued;</section><section prefix='(4)'>that protect property owners by procedures (1) to de-designate properties and (2) to vary or modify historic regulation based upon economic hardship pursuant to due notice to affected parties, legally-enforceable standards, quasi-judicial public hearings, and appeals to courts;</section><section prefix='(5)'>that provide economic incentives for preservation;</section><section prefix='(6)'>that regulate and prevent the demolition of historic buildings by neglect, and</section><section prefix='(7)'>that establish the Secretary of Interior's Standards for Rehabilitation as standards governing preservation, although a municipality may establish additional standards.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>It is a violation of the minimum standards of this Chapter for a municipal historic preservation ordinance<section prefix='(1)'>to exempt an otherwise historic property from historic regulation or designation on the basis that the owner did not consent to the regulation or designation;</section><section prefix='(2)'>to allow the issuance of a permit for the demolition of a historically-regulated property unless, after a public hearing pursuant to the ordinance, a variance based upon economic hardship has been granted or a certificate of appropriateness to demolish based on express standards in the ordinance has been issued. In this regard, it is a violation of the minimum standards of this Chapter to permit the issuance of a certificate of appropriateness for demolition based solely upon the passage of a certain amount of time after the owner has applied to demolish.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Municipalities that have already enacted historic preservation ordinances as of the effective date of this ordinance shall have 365 days from the effective date of this ordinance to bring their ordinances into compliance with these minimum standards.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The minimum standards created in these sub-section shall not apply to any municipality that is recognized as a Certified Local Government by the Florida Secretary of State.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Guidelines for Municipal Enforcement. Municipalities are encouraged to comply with the following guidelines, but these guidelines shall not serve as minimum standards:<section prefix='(a)'>have a quorum appointed to its historic preservation board at least 9 months in any 12 month period;</section><section prefix='(b)'>conduct public meetings of its historic preservation board no less than 6 times in every calendar year;</section><section prefix='(c)'>provide sufficient professional staff to its historic preservation board to allow the board to conduct its business, including evaluating properties and districts for designation, reviewing and issuing certificates of appropriateness, holding quasi-judicial hearings, and otherwise enforcing the terms of its historic preservation ordinance;</section><section prefix='(d)'>conduct a separate public hearing to consider for designation each property within its jurisdiction listed on the National Register of Historic Places; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>produce at least one designation report per calendar year until all properties in its jurisdiction listed as historically significant on the City or the County's last survey have been considered.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Municipality Shall File Annual Report. Municipalities that exercise jurisdiction of historic preservation shall annually file a report with the Clerk of the Board of the Miami-Dade County Commission. This report shall briefly state the name, address and qualification of its historic preservation board members; when each member joined and, if applicable left the board; the name, address and telephone number of its historic preservation staff members and consultants; and the number of designation reports and certificates of appropriateness prepared and considered in that year. Attached to the report shall be a copy of the minutes of the meetings of the municipality's historic preservation board for that year and any designation reports and certificates of appropriateness prepared by its staff during that year.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Municipal Authority To Obtain Continuances Before Unsafe Structure Agencies. A municipality that has enacted its own historic preservation ordinance in accordance with this section may obtain continuances before unsafe structure agencies as set forth in section 16A-11 (VI) (b) of this Chapter. For this limited purpose, "Director," "staff," and "Board" as used in that section shall refer to their counterparts in the municipality. The authority provided by this sub-section shall be interpreted only to expand, and not to limit, the discretion of a municipality.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 3, 3-11-03)</history></law>