<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Economic Hardship.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002463</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-12. Economic Hardship.<section>Where, by reason of particular site conditions and restraints, or because of unusual circumstances applicable solely to the particular applicant property, strict enforcement of the provisions of this chapter would result in serious undue economic hardship to the applicant, the Board shall have the power to vary or modify adherence to this chapter; provided always that its requirements ensure harmony with the general purposes hereof and will not adversely affect Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='(a)'>In any instance where there is a claim of undue economic hardship, the owner shall submit, by affidavit, to the Board at least fifteen (15) days prior to the public hearing, the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>For all property:<section prefix='(i)'>The amount paid for the property, the date of purchase and the party from whom purchased;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The assessed value of the land and improvements thereon according to the two (2) most recent assessments;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Real estate taxes for the previous two (2) years;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Annual debt service, if any, for the previous two (2) years;</section><section prefix='(v)'>All appraisals obtained within the previous two (2) years by the owner or applicant in connection with his purchase, financing or ownership of the property;</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Any listing of the property for sale or rent, price asked and offers received, if any; and</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Any consideration by the owner as to profitable adaptive uses for the property; and</section><section prefix='(viii)'>All cost estimates or reports relating to the demolition of the property obtained within the previous two (2) years;</section><section prefix='(ix)'>All cost estimates or reports relating to the rehabilitation or restoration of the property obtained within the previous two (2) years;</section><section prefix='(x)'>All reports relating to the engineering, architectural, or construction feasibility of rehabilitating or restoring the property obtained within the previous two (2) years; and</section><section prefix='(xi)'>All reports relating to the economic feasibility of restoring or rehabilitating the property obtained within the previous two (2) years, including market studies.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>For income-producing property:<section prefix='(i)'>Annual gross income from the property for the previous two (2) years;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Itemized operating and maintenance expenses for the previous two (2) years; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Annual cash flow, if any, for the previous two (2) years.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Board may require that an applicant furnish such additional information as the Board believes is relevant to its determination of undue economic hardship. The owner shall permit access to the subject property for the purpose of inspections and/or appraisals required by the board or preservation officer. In the event that any of the required information is not reasonably available to the applicant and cannot be obtained by the applicant, the applicant shall file with his affidavit a statement of the information which cannot be obtained and shall describe the reasons why such information cannot be obtained.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 82-99, ยง 1, 10-19-82; Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 12, 3-11-03)</history></law>