<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='2'>Chapter 16A HISTORIC PRESERVATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>16A-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Scope of regulations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002452</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 16A-3. Scope of regulations.<section prefix='(1)'>This chapter is intended to and shall govern incorporated and unincorporated Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The regulatory jurisdiction of the Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board pursuant to this Chapter shall extend to:<section prefix='(a)'>all property located in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(b)'>all property located in incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County except where the municipality has enacted its own historic preservation ordinance in accordance with section 16A-3.1</section><section prefix='(c)'>archeology and paleontology zones and sites in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County except where the municipality has enacted its own historic preservation ordinance in accordance with section 16A-3.1 and the municipality, within 365 days of the effective date of this ordinance, enacts an ordinance that (1) expressly retains jurisdiction over archeology and paleontology zones and sites, (2) adopts regulations as least as protective of archeology and paleontology zones and sites as those in this Chapter, and (3) commits the municipality to retain sufficient archeological personnel or consultants to enforce such regulations; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>the enforcement of the minimum standards established by this Chapter as set forth in this Chapter.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Nothing contained herein shall be deemed to supersede or conflict with applicable building and zoning codes. Provisions contained herein shall be cumulative and read in conjunction with other provisions of the Miami-Dade County Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-13, ยง 3, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 82-99, ยง 1, 10-19-82; Ord. No. 03-38, ยง 2, 3-11-03)</history></law>