<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Notice of violations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002485</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-11. Notice of violations.<section>Whenever the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant finds and determines that there has been a violation of the minimum housing standards established by this article, he shall give notice of such violation to the owner. Such notice shall be in writing, shall specify the violation and shall specify the time for compliance. Such notice shall specify that the violation must be corrected or a building permit for the work required to correct the violation must be obtained from the County or appropriate municipal building and zoning department having jurisdiction within the time specified in the notice and that final compliance must conform to the requirements of the South Florida Building Code. Such notice shall contain an outline of the remedial action which, if taken, will constitute compliance with the requirements of this article. Such notice shall inform the owner of the right to apply to the Hearing Officer for a hearing and review of matters within the notice as provided in Sections and herein. Such notice shall also inform the owner that failure to comply will result in enforcement action as provided in or of this Code. Such notice shall be served upon the owner. Such notice shall be deemed to be properly served and binding upon the property involved if a copy is served by certified mail return receipt requested, addressed to the owner's last known address. If the owner cannot be served by certified mail, a copy of the notice shall be posted in a conspicuous place on the facilities or premises involved. Such notice shall state the date of posting.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-30, ยง 1.11, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 65-32, ยง 3, 4-20-65; Ord. No. 88-15, ยง 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 07-148, ยง 1, 10-2-07)</history></law>