<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. INFILL HOUSING INITIATIVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-124.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Affordability controls.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002563</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-124.2. Affordability controls.<section prefix='(a)'>Initial sale.<section prefix='(1)'>Every eligible home required to be established under this article shall be offered for sale to a qualified household to be used as their own primary residence.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In order to assure the purpose of the infill program as set forth in Section 17-121, steps shall be taken by the County to encourage a mix of housing prices that are affordable to both low and moderate income households.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No less than sixty (60) days prior to offering any eligible home, the developer shall notify the County of such offering. The notification from the developer shall set forth the size, sales price, and location of each eligible home offered and shall provide a description of each eligible home's finishes and availability. The County may request additional information from the developer or other property owner as it deems necessary.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Upon notification from the developer, the County shall make such notice available to eligible households through its web site and other locations designated by the County.</section><section prefix='(5)'>If the County determines an eligible household qualifies for an eligible home, the County will issue a certificate of qualification declaring the household a qualified household. In order to receive a certificate of qualification, an eligible household must have completed a homeownership counseling course and met the eligibility requirements of a low or moderate income household.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Resale. Subject to the mortgage recorded against the eligible home in favor of the County, any qualified household that intends to sell his or her eligible home prior to the expiration of the control period shall provide written notification to the County pursuant to subsection (c) of this section. Upon resale of an eligible home, each household must ensure that a prospective qualified household has received a valid certificate of qualification.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Control of resale prices.<section prefix='(1)'>The eligible home may be resold, but only to a qualified household. Any owner of an eligible home shall notify the County in writing of his or her intent to offer the eligible home for resale.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The maximum sales price permitted on resale of an eligible home shall be based on the following:<section prefix='(i)'>a formula that takes into account the price paid by the current owner and any increases tied to an index of area incomes during the period in which the current owner owned the home;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>documented costs for property improvements that are permanent in nature and not for decoration or maintenance purposes.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Prior to closing a sale, the seller of the eligible home shall submit to the County for approval (which approval shall not be unreasonably withheld or delayed):<section prefix='(i)'>a copy of the proposed sales contract; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>an affidavit signed by the owner of the eligible home and the new qualified household attesting to the accuracy of all documents and conditions of the sale.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>No resale of an eligible home shall be considered to be in compliance with this article until all required documents and affidavits have been submitted to and approved by the County.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The County shall either approve or disapprove all required documents and affidavits in writing within fifteen business days after they are submitted to the County. If the County disapproves such documents or affidavits then the County shall provide the owner, in writing, the reasons for such disapproval and an opportunity to correct any deficiencies, and provide adequate and appropriate documentation.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Foreclosures, bankruptcy, probate and other proceedings.<section prefix='(1)'>If any qualified household of an eligible home defaults on his or her mortgage with the County and said default is not cured within the applicable time periods, then the whole debt secured by said mortgage, with all interest thereon, and all other amounts thereby secured shall, at the option of the County, become immediately due and payable. In the event any qualified household of an eligible home fails to cure the default, the County shall have the right to legally enforce the term of the mortgage or collect the debt in any action at law, including but not limited to a proceeding in foreclosure. Any proceeds, including any expenses or expenditures incurred and recovered by the County, shall be deposited into a separate account or into any affordable housing trust fund established by the County and shall not be commingled with any other funds.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In any suit, action or proceeding, including without limitation bankruptcy, probate or any other suit, action or proceeding affecting the eligible home, any monies recovered by the County shall be deposited into a separate account designated for such purposes or any affordable housing trust fund established by the County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding subsection e(1) and (2), in the event of default by a qualified household on any senior mortgage associated with an eligible home, the County Manager is authorized to pay off said senior mortgage and assume ownership of the eligible home by using funds from the affordable housing trust fund. The defaulting qualified household shall be required to vacate the eligible home. The County Manager is further authorized to purchase any eligible home that is sold as a result of any suit, action or proceeding, including but not limited to foreclosure, bankruptcy, probate or any suit, action or proceeding affecting the eligible home. The County Manager shall report each such purchase to the Board of County Commissioners at the next Board meeting following the purchase of the eligible home.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-04, ยง 5, 1-25-07)</history></law>