<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. AFFORDABLE HOUSING TRUST FUND OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-133</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002574</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-133. Membership.<section prefix='(1)'>Members. The governing body of the Trust shall be a Board of Trustees composed of nine (9) members, none of whom shall be employees of the Miami-Dade County. The members shall be the following:<section prefix='(a)'>One (1) member representing the financial or investment banking community;</section><section prefix='(b)'>One (1) member nominated by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioner's Committee which has jurisdiction over housing and community and economic development;</section><section prefix='(c)'>One (1) member with a background in public sector budgeting and finance;</section><section prefix='(d)'>One (1) member nominated by the Metro-Miami Action Plan Trust;</section><section prefix='(e)'>One (1) member nominated by the Dade Affordable Housing Advisory Board;</section><section prefix='(f)'>One (1) member nominated by Miami-Dade Housing Finance Authority;</section><section prefix='(g)'>One (1) member representing the non-profit developer community;</section><section prefix='(h)'>One (1) member representing the insurance community; and</section><section prefix='(i)'>One (1) member from the private home builders community.</section></section><section>The Chair of the Board of the County Commissioners shall contact each of the entities referenced in (1) to obtain the names of interested and eligible persons and their resumes. The Chair shall obtain a pool of no less than three (3) names of candidates per seat on the Trust. Upon receipt of the names all candidates, the Chair shall forward them by resolution to the Board of County Commissioners. From the pool of candidates for each seat, the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint one (1) eligible person to serve as a member of the Board of Trustees.</section><section>Individuals shall be appointed based on the following criteria:<section prefix='(a)'>Knowledge of and demonstrable service to the affordable housing community;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Representation of the diverse populations of the Miami-Dade County community, including the proportional representation of women; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Special expertise in affordable housing.</section></section><section>Members of the Trust shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Vacancies on Board of Trustees. Vacancies on the Board of Trustees shall be filled in the same manner by which the original Trustees were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons who represent the demographic composition of the entire community.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Qualifications of Members. Each member of the Board of Trustees shall be a permanent resident and duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, unless the Board of County Commissioners waives the residency requirement by a two-thirds () vote of its membership, and shall be of an outstanding reputation of integrity, responsibility, and commitment to serving the community.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Tenure and Removal of Members. All members shall serve staggered terms of three (3) years each, provided, however, of the original Board of Trustees, two (2) members shall serve for a term of one (1) year; two (2) members shall serve for a term of two (2) years; and three (3) members shall serve for a term of three (3) years. No trustee shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by two-thirds () vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners. Trustees may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Organization of the Board of Trustees.<section prefix='(a)'>Officers. The Trust shall organize after the members thereof have qualified to serve and shall, each fiscal year, elect one (1) of its voting members as chairperson and one (1) of its voting members as vice-chairperson and shall designate a secretary who may or may not be a member of the Board, and such other officers as the Trust may determine to be necessary. In addition, the Trust shall make, adopt and amend by-laws, rules and regulations for its own governance and for the operation, governance, restoration, preservation and maintenance of designated facilities.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Meetings. The Trust shall hold regular meetings, no less then six (6) times per year, and such other meetings, as it deems necessary. Five (5) members shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Trust and all meetings shall be duly noticed to the public.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Committees. The chairperson shall nominate and the Trust shall appoint the chairperson and members of such committees as the Trust shall find helpful to their mission, however, no authority to act or speak in the name of the Trust shall be delegated to a committee. Each committee shall be chaired by a duly appointed member of the Trust, however, committee membership may include persons who are not members of the Trust. The Trust may establish or eliminate committees at its discretion.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Applicability of County rules and procedures. The Trust shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Sec. 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Voting Requirements. Trustees may not designate alternates to vote on their behalf or vote by proxy.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Attendance requirement. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, any board member shall be automatically removed if, in a given fiscal year:<section prefix='(i)'>He or she is absent from two (2) consecutive meetings without an acceptable excuse;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>He or she is absent from three (3) of the Trust's meetings without an acceptable excuse; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Whether excused or not, he or she misses two-thirds () of the Trust's meetings in a given fiscal year. A member shall be deemed absent from a meeting when he or she is not present at the meeting at least seventy-five (75) percent of the time. An "acceptable excuse" is defined as an absence for medical reasons, business reasons, personal reasons, or any other reason which the Trust, by a two-thirds () vote of the membership, deems appropriate. By a two-thirds () vote of the members of the full Board of Trustees, the provisions of this section may be waived.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>The County Manager shall provide to the Trust adequate staff and support services to enable it to carry out its purposes.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-15, ยง 1, 2-6-07)</history></law>