<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. AFFORDABLE HOUSING TRUST FUND OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-131</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002572</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-131. Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Adjusted for family size means adjusted in a manner that results in an income eligibility level that is lower for households having fewer than four people, or higher for households having more than four people, than the base income eligibility determined as provided in subsection (4), subsection (5), subsection (6), or subsection (9), based upon a formula established by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Affordable means that monthly rents or monthly mortgage payments including taxes and insurance do not exceed 30 percent of that amount which represents the percentage of the median annual gross income for the households as indicated in subsection (4), subsection (5), subsection (6), or subsection (9). However, it is not the intent to limit an individual household's ability to devote more than 30 percent of its income for housing, and housing for which a household devotes more than 30 percent of its income shall be deemed affordable if the first institutional mortgage lender is satisfied that the household can afford mortgage payments in excess of the 30 percent benchmark.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Affordable housing means any real and personal property located within Miami-Dade County which is designed and intended for the primary purpose of providing decent, safe, and sanitary residential units that are designed for home ownership or rental for extremely low, very low, low, and moderate income persons.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Extremely-low-income persons or extremely low-income household means one or more natural persons or a family whose total annual household income does not exceed 30 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the state.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Low-income person or low-income household means one or more natural persons or a family that has a total annual gross household income that does not exceed 80 percent of the median annual income adjusted for family size for households within Miami-Dade County. With respect to rental units, the low-income household's annual income at the time of initial occupancy may not exceed 80 percent of the area's median income adjusted for family size. While occupying the rental unit, a low-income household's annual income may increase to an amount not to exceed 140 percent of 80 percent of the area's median income adjusted for family size.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Moderate-income person or moderate-income household means one or more natural persons or a family that has a total annual gross household income that does not exceed 120 percent of the median annual income adjusted for family size for households within Miami-Dade County. With respect to rental units, the moderate-income household's annual income at the time of initial occupancy may not exceed 120 percent of the area's median income adjusted for family size. While occupying the rental unit, a moderate-income household's annual income may increase to an amount not to exceed 140 percent of 120 percent of the area's median income adjusted for family size.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Rent means ongoing monthly rental assistance. The term does not include initial assistance to tenants, such as grants or loans for security and utility deposits.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Sales price or value means, in the case of acquisition of an existing or newly constructed unit, the amount on the executed sales contract. For eligible persons who are building a unit on land that they own, the sales price is determined by an appraisal performed by a state-certified appraiser. The appraisal must include the value of the land and the improvements using the after-construction value of the property and must be dated within 12 months of the date construction is to commence. The sales price of any unit must include the value of the land in order to qualify as affordable housing. In the case of rehabilitation or emergency repair of an existing unit that does not create additional living space, sales price or value means the value of the real property, as determined by an appraisal performed by a state-certified appraiser and dated within 12 months of the date construction is to commence or the assessed value of the real property as determined by the county property appraiser. In the case of rehabilitation of an existing unit that includes the addition of new living space, sales price or value means the value of the real property, as determined by an appraisal performed by a state-certified appraiser and dated within 12 months of the date construction is to commence or the assessed value of the real property as determined by the county property appraiser, plus the cost of the improvements in either case.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Very-low-income person or very-low-income household means one or more natural persons or a family that has a total annual gross household income that does not exceed 50 percent of the median annual income adjusted for family size for households within Miami-Dade County. With respect to rental units, the very-low-income household's annual income at the time of initial occupancy may not exceed 50 percent of the area's median income adjusted for family size. While occupying the rental unit, a very-low-income household's annual income may increase to an amount not to exceed 140 percent of 50 percent of the area's median income adjusted for family size.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-15, ยง 1, 2-6-07)</history></law>