<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. INFILL HOUSING INITIATIVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-125.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Rental of Property.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002565</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-125.1 Rental of Property.<section>The County in its sole discretion may allow developers to rent eligible homes on a temporary basis if the developer can demonstrate to the County's satisfaction that they have made a good faith effort to sell the eligible home. The term "good faith effort" shall include, but is not limited to, marketing of the eligible home by listing the home on the multiple listing service for a minimum of three months, placing a "For Sale" sign on the property, and reducing the original asking price. In the event the developer is able to demonstrate that it has used good faith efforts to sell the eligible home and the County permits the rental of said home, the County shall require the developer to rent the eligible home to families who are eligible participants in one of the County's or other local municipality's rental housing assistance programs, including but not limited to, the Section 8 Housing Choice Voucher (HCV) Program administered by the Miami-Dade Public Housing and Community Development, or its successor agency or department or the Household Exiting Emergency Shelter, Transitional Housing and Domestic Violence programs administered by the Miami-Dade County Homeless Trust. The County shall determine prior to authorizing a developer to rent an eligible home whether the rental of said home is consistent with all applicable state and federal laws and regulations.</section><section>Upon the County's approval to rent any eligible home, each developer shall be required to comply with all applicable federal and state housing laws and regulations. Developers shall also be required to rent the eligible homes for a minimum of one year and will not be permitted to sell said eligible home during the first year it is rented, unless it is sold to the existing tenant.</section><section>This section of the Code shall sunset on April 16, 2014, unless extended by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-25, ยง 3, 4-6-10; Ord. No. 12-35, ยง 1, 5-1-12)</history></law>