<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. INFILL HOUSING INITIATIVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-124</section_number>
<catch_line>Transfer or sale of property.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002561</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-124. Transfer or sale of property.<section prefix='(a)'>Transfer or Sale of Property. Pursuant to all applicable state and County laws, any County owned parcel or parcels of property identified as appropriate for infill housing may be transferred or sold to a qualified developer for the development of infill housing subject to the requirements of Section 17-126 of this article. Notwithstanding this requirement, the County Manager is authorized to approve a conveyance of an infill property previously conveyed by the County to a qualified developer when a municipality or any other governmental entity desires said property in exchange for another infill property of equal or greater value. Said transferred infill property shall be subject to the restrictions set forth in Section 17-124(c) and (d).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Clear Title. To the extent that it is feasible and allowed by law, title to the property shall be cleared of all liens, taxes and other encumbrances prior to transfer or sale by the County to a qualified community development corporation or a qualified developer. The title may be cleared through:<section prefix='(1)'>Forgiveness of County liens as established in Section 17-126 of this article;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Cancellation of County-held tax certificates as allowed by state law;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Payment of liens;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Development of incentives for private, municipal and other governmental lienholders to release liens; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>By any other available means.</section></section><section>However, pursuant to Section 125.411 of the Florida Statutes, as amended, the County shall only convey the interest of the County and shall not warrant title.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Reverter Clause/Affordability Period. County deeds conveying title of any properties to a qualified community development corporation or qualified developer, under this Infill Housing Initiative, shall contain a reverter to the County in the event the property has not been reasonably developed or rehabilitated within one year of conveyance. Any eligible infill housing that is developed under this Infill Housing Initiative shall remain as affordable housing for at least thirty (30) years.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Declaration of Restrictive Covenants. Prior to the initial sale of an eligible home, a declaration of restrictive covenants running with the land, approved in form by the County, shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County which contains such language as is necessary to carry out the purposes of this article. Said declaration of restrictive covenants shall specify that:<section prefix='(1)'>The restrictions of this article shall run with the land for the entire control period; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The covenant will bind the applicant, any assignee, mortgagee, or buyer, and all other parties that receive title to or interest in the property. These covenants shall be senior to all instruments securing permanent financing; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>The covenant shall be controlled for a minimum of twenty (20) years and shall automatically reset every 20 years for a maximum of 60 years, except that in the event an eligible home is owned for an entire 20-year control period by the same individual(s), said individual(s) shall automatically be released from the Declaration of Restrictive Covenants.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Every eligible home constructed or rehabilitated pursuant to this article shall be offered for sale to qualified households to be used as their primary residence. A qualified household that has purchased an eligible home shall not lease said eligible home; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>Prior to the sale of an eligible home during the control period, the eligible home's owner shall obtain the County's written approval as set forth in Section 17-124.2(c); and</section><section prefix='(6)'>The initial sales price of the eligible housing shall not be offered for a price greater than the current maximum eligible home's sales price of affordable housing as determined by the County at the time of sale or its current appraised value, whichever is lower; and</section><section prefix='(7)'>The County reserves its right of first refusal to purchase the eligible home prior to or at the end of control period, if it becomes available for purchase and there are no eligible persons to purchase said home. The County shall have sixty (60) days after receiving written notification from the owner that the eligible home is for sale, to advise the owner in writing of the County's intent to exercise its right of first refusal or to provide the owner with written notification of the County's intent to waive its right of first refusal. The County Manager is authorized to negotiate and execute any contracts to purchase the available eligible home, without prior approval from the Miami-Dade Board of County Commissioners, from the funds earmarked in the a separate account or any trust fund designated for this purpose. Notwithstanding this authorization to purchase, the County Manager shall bring to the Board of County Commissioners a resolution seeking ratification of said purchase at the next available Board meeting following the purchase of the eligible home.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-47, ยง 4, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 07-04, ยง 3, 1-25-07)</history></law>