<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. INFILL HOUSING INITIATIVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-124.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Eligibility of households for eligible housing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002562</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-124.1. Eligibility of households for eligible housing.<section prefix='(a)'>Eligibility requirements to purchase an eligible home shall be pursuant to an administrative order approved by the Board of County Commissioners and shall be based on household size and income. An eligible household must receive a certificate of qualification from the County or other outside agency authorized by the County to qualify households, to become a qualified household, in accordance with the procedures prescribed by the administrative order.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each qualified household purchasing an eligible home shall be required to record a mortgage in favor of Miami-Dade County with an amount equal to the value of the land at the time of the initial sale of the home. A promissory note shall be executed by each qualified household and secured by said mortgage. Said mortgage shall set forth the same covenants, along with the refinancing and resale restrictions as those included in the restrictive covenants required by this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Eligibility for continued ownership of an eligible home shall be contingent upon the qualified household's use of the eligible home as his or her primary residence. A qualified household that no longer occupies the home as their primary residence shall be in default of the mortgage recorded against the eligible home by the County and the Declaration of Restrictive Covenants.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Effective January 1st of the year following the recording of the declaration of restrictive covenants in the Public Records stating that the home must remain affordable the assessed value of the homes constructed through the Infill Housing Program will reflect consideration of the aforementioned restriction. To ensure that the assessed value of the affordable home reflects consideration of the aforesaid restrictions, County shall submit a copy of the recorded covenant to the Miami-Dade Property Appraiser's Office immediately after closing. Upon receiving said covenant, the Property Appraiser's Office will make a notation in the records available to the public that the home is subject to affordable housing restrictions and, for subsequent assessments during the control period, will ensure that the assessed value reflects consideration of the housing restrictions.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Subject to the availability of funding, the County will provide affordable mortgage loans through the use of Surtax and SHIP funds to qualified households who purchase infill housing. In order to receive a mortgage loan, the qualified household must meet the eligibility requirements for the funding.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-04, ยง 4, 1-25-07)</history></law>