<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. INFILL HOUSING INITIATIVE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-126</section_number>
<catch_line>Forgiveness of county liens.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002566</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-126. Forgiveness of county liens.<section prefix='(a)'>Notwithstanding any other provision contained in the Code of Miami-Dade County, the County Manager may release or satisfy any County lien placed on a publicly or privately owned property if the property has been approved by the County Manager for the Infill Housing Initiative and the private owner records in the public records a declaration of restrictive covenants in a form approved by the County as set forth in Section 17-124(d).<section prefix='(2)'>County liens which may be released or satisfied by the County include but are not limited to: civil restitution liens; code enforcement liens; demolition liens; hospital liens; judgment liens; lot clearing liens; minimum housing standard liens; mortgage liens; nuisance abatement liens; public defender liens; stormwater utility liens; waste liens; water and sewer liens; and welfare liens. The provisions of this article do not pertain to ad valorem tax liens or privately-held tax certificates nor do they pertain to special assessment liens as defined in the Home Rule Charter, Article 1, Section 1.01(A)(11) and in Section 18-14 of Miami-Dade County Code.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The satisfaction of the County lien(s) shall be recorded in the Official Record Book of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County shall not release or satisfy any County liens on a property owned by the person whose actions resulted in the County liens being placed on the property. The County shall not release or forgive any County liens on a property owned by the immediate family or a firm, corporation, partnership or business entity of a person whose actions resulted in the liens being placed on the property. For purposes of this section, "person" shall mean any individual, business, corporation, partnership, firm, organization, or other type of entity. For purposes of this section, "immediate family" shall mean spouse, child, parent, niece, nephew, aunt, uncle, grandparent, grandchild or anyone having one of these relationships by law.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Release of a County lien under this article does not prohibit the County from collecting the sum underlying the lien by other legal means. Release of a County lien does not mean that a violation underlying the lien has been cured.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-47, ยง 6, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 07-04, ยง 7, 1-25-07)</history></law>