<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LOCAL HOUSING ASSISTANCE PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-102</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of the Local Housing Assistance Program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002550</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-102. Establishment of the Local Housing Assistance Program.<section>Miami-Dade County shall use any funds received from the State Housing Initiative Partnership Program (the "SHIP Program") and other sources, to implement Miami-Dade County's Local Housing Assistance Program, which is hereby created and established. Assistance provided under this program to persons and families will be secured by a mortgage or a grant agreement. The Miami-Dade County Local Housing Assistance Program shall consist of the following components:<section prefix='(a)'>Housing Development Assistance. The Housing Development Assistance component provides funding to defray the costs of land acquisition, site development, new construction, rehabilitation and/or other costs associated with the development of single-family homeownership and affordable rental housing units. It is the intent of this program to increase housing opportunities for very-low, low and moderate income persons by encouraging the creation and rehabilitation of affordable housing units.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Down Payment Assistance. The Down Payment Assistance component provides down payment, and closing costs assistance to qualified very-low, low and moderate-income persons to assist in the purchase of rehabilitated or newly constructed single-family homeownership affordable housing units.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Housing Rehabilitation. The Housing Rehabilitation component provides financing to single-family homeowners to assist them in making necessary repairs to their home. The house must be owner-occupied as the homeowner's primary place of residence.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Homeownership Assistance. The Homeownership Assistance component provides funds to very-low, low and moderate-income persons to acquire newly-constructed and existing homeownership affordable housing units.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Home Buyer Education and Counseling. The Home Buyer Education and Counseling component provides education and counseling to eligible persons regarding the purchase and financing of single-family affordable housing units. Homebuyer counseling is a requirement for homeownership assistance.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Other strategies/components. Miami-Dade County will develop and implement other affordable housing strategies/components, inclusive of Surtax programs within Section 29-7 of the County Code that are in accordance with Sections 420.9070 through 420.9079 of the Florida Statutes, Chapter 9I-37 of the Florida Administrative Code, and other federal and local requirements. Such strategies/components will conform to the local housing assistance plan and shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-70, ยง 2, 4-18-95; Ord. No. 97-65, ยง 3, 5-20-97; Ord. No. 07-18, ยง 2, 2-6-07)</history></law>