<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-144</section_number>
<catch_line>Affordability controls.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002585</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-144. Affordability controls.<section prefix='(A)'>Initial sale or rental.<section prefix='(1)'>Every WHU established under this article and Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County, shall be offered for sale or rental to an eligible household to be used for his or her own primary residence.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Sixty (60) days prior to offering any new WHU for sale or rent, the developer or other property owner shall notify the Department of such offering. The notice shall set forth the number, size, price established by applicable administrative order, and location of the WHU offered and shall provide a description of each WHU's finishes and availability. The Department may request additional information from the developer or other property owner as it deems necessary.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Upon notification from the developer or other property owner, the Department shall make such notice available to eligible households through its web site, a prominently located posting at the Department, and other locations designated by the County.</section><section prefix='(4)'>If the Department determines an eligible household qualifies for the rental or owner-occupied WHUs, the Department will issue a certificate of qualification. In order to receive a certificate of qualification, an eligible household must provide an affidavit that the WHU will be its primary residence.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A qualified household that has purchased a WHU shall not lease said WHU.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Upon resale or re-rental of a WHU, each qualified household must first obtain a valid certificate of qualification from the prospective eligible household.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Right of first refusal.<section prefix='(1)'>Initial Sale. The developer or other property owner of a WHU shall agree to execute a document consistent with a model restriction prepared by the Department, granting to the County, among other things, the County's right of first refusal to purchase the WHU in the event that a qualified household does not execute a contract for purchase within six (6) months from the date the WHU is offered for sale. In the event that no qualified household purchases a WHU within six (6) months from the date the WHU is first offered by the developer or other property owner, the Director shall recommend to the County Manager whether the County should exercise its right of first refusal to purchase the WHU at the WHU sales price. If the County Manager concurs, the Director shall notify the developer or other property owner of the County's decision. The County Manager is authorized to exercise the right of first refusal provided hereunder, with funds allocated from the Affordable Housing Trust Fund established pursuant to Section 17-129, et. seq., Code of Miami-Dade County or any other authorized source, for the direct and exclusive purpose of providing workforce housing for those households meeting the workforce housing eligibility requirements. Notwithstanding this authorization to purchase, the County Manager shall bring to the Board of County Commissioners a resolution seeking ratification of said purchase at the next available Board meeting following the purchase of the WHU.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Resale. Any qualified household that intends to sell its WHU prior to the expiration of the control period shall provide written notification to the Department pursuant to subsection (C) below. In the event the qualified household does not execute a contract for purchase within six (6) months from the date the WHU is first offered for resale, the County shall have a right of first refusal to purchase the WHU. The Director shall recommend to the County Manager whether the County should exercise its right of first refusal to purchase the WHU at the WHU sales price. If the County Manager concurs, the Director shall notify the qualified household of the County's decision. The County Manager is authorized to purchase the WHU, without prior approval from the Miami-Dade Board of County Commissioners, from the funds earmarked in the Affordable Housing Trust Fund, which has been established pursuant to Section 17-129 et seq., Code of Miami-Dade County, or any other authorized source, for the direct and exclusive purpose of providing workforce housing for those households meeting the workforce housing eligibility requirements. Notwithstanding this authorization to purchase, the County Manager shall bring to the Board of County Commissioners a resolution seeking ratification of said purchase at the next available Board meeting following the purchase of the WHU.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Control of resale prices.<section prefix='(1)'>The maximum sales price, with the exception of sales under order of court, permitted on resale of a WHU shall be the lesser of:<section prefix='(a)'>the maximum sales price for a WHU as set by the Department at the time of resale to an eligible household; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>the market value of the unit for sale.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The WHU may be resold to any eligible household. Any qualified household that has purchased a WHU shall notify the Department in writing of his or her intent to offer the WHU for resale. The qualified household shall not sell the WHU for an amount in excess of the allowable WHU sales price.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Before closing a sale, the seller of the WHU shall submit to the Department for approval (which approval shall not be unreasonably withheld or delayed):<section prefix='(a)'>a copy of the proposed sales contract;</section><section prefix='(b)'>a signed copy of the buyer's certification of qualification (if not provided by the Department); and</section><section prefix='(c)'>an affidavit signed by the seller and the buyer attesting to the accuracy of all documents and conditions of the sale.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>No resale of a WHU shall be considered to be in compliance with this article until all required documents and affidavits have been submitted to and approved by the Department.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Department shall either approve or disapprove all required documents and affidavits in writing no later than five (5) business days after they are submitted to the Department. The Department's failure to issue such approval or disapproval within the required time period shall result in such documents and affidavits being deemed approved. If the Department disapproves such documents or affidavits then the Director shall provide the seller, in writing, with reasons for such disapproval and an opportunity to correct any deficiencies.</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Resale requirements during the control period. The County Manager may adopt additional requirements for reselling WHUs consistent with this article, including without limitation a requirement that within forty-eight (48) hours prior to closing, a seller submit to the Department for approval:<section prefix='(1)'>a copy of the proposed sales contract, including a list and the price of any personal property included in the sale;</section><section prefix='(2)'>a signed copy of the settlement sheet; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>an affidavit signed by the seller and buyer attesting to the accuracy of all documents and conditions of the sale.</section></section><section prefix='(E)'>Foreclosures and other proceedings.<section prefix='(1)'>If any qualified household of a WHU defaults on its mortgage with the County and said default is not cured within the applicable time periods, then the whole debt secured by said mortgage, with all interest thereon, and all other amounts thereby secured shall, at the option of the County, become immediately due and payable. In the event any qualified household of a WHU fails to cure the default, the County shall have the right to legally enforce the term of the mortgage or collect the debt in any action at law, including but not limited to a proceeding in foreclosure. Any proceeds, including any expenses or expenditures incurred and recovered by the County, shall be deposited in the Affordable Housing Trust Fund. These funds shall not be commingled with any other funds deposited into the Affordable Housing Trust Fund that are not associated with the WHU program, but shall be deposited into a separate account.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In any suit, action or proceeding, including without limitation bankruptcy, probate or any other suit, action or proceeding affecting the WHU, any monies recovered by the County shall be deposited into the Affordable Housing Trust Fund.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding subsection E (1) and (2), in the event of default by a qualified household on any senior mortgage associated with a WHU, the County Manager is authorized to pay off said senior mortgage and assume ownership of the WHU by using funds from the Affordable Housing Trust Fund for resale to an eligible household. The defaulting qualified household shall be required to vacate the WHU as authorized by law. The County Manager is further authorized to purchase any WHU that is sold as a result of any suit, action or proceeding, including but not limited to foreclosure, bankruptcy, probate or any other suit, action or proceeding affecting the WHU. Notwithstanding this authorization to purchase, the County Manager shall bring to the Board of County Commissioners a resolution seeking ratification of said purchase at the next available Board meeting following the purchase of the WHU.</section></section><section prefix='(F)'>Rental WHU Requirements.<section prefix='(1)'>All qualified households must be provided a lease with a minimum period of twelve (12) months. The lease must comply with all applicable federal and state laws. The lease shall include without limitation provisions that specify the maximum household size allowed in the unit; a prohibition against subleasing; and a requirement that the qualified household shall report any changes in household size or income during the tenancy. Qualified households shall comply with all monitoring requirements established by the Department.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If a qualified household's income increases above the maximum allowed income levels, the qualified household may choose to remain in the WHU for the remainder of the lease term. If the formerly qualified household and the developer or other property owner agree to extend the lease term, the developer or other property owner shall make the next comparable vacant unit at the covered development available to an eligible household at the WHU rent.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 19, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>