<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-142</section_number>
<catch_line>Compliance procedures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002583</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-142. Compliance procedures.<section prefix='(A)'>Workforce Housing Declaration of Restrictive Covenants and Workforce housing agreement<section prefix='(1)'>Every WHU established pursuant to Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall be offered for sale or rental to a qualified household to be used for his or her own primary residence. The County, through the Director, shall publish a pricing schedule of rental and sales prices for WHUs in accordance with this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any developer or other property owner offering a WHU for initial sale or rental shall record in the public records one or more covenants or declarations of restrictions in a form approved by the County. Such covenants or declarations of restrictions shall include the WHU Agreement, and such further arrangements, restrictive covenants, and resale or rental restrictions as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this article. The developer or other property owner must execute and record a declaration of restrictive covenants assuring that:<section prefix='(a)'>the restrictions of this article shall run with the land for the entire control period;</section><section prefix='(b)'>the covenants will bind the applicant, any assignee, mortgagee, or buyer, and all other parties that receive title to or interest in the property. These covenants shall be senior to all instruments securing permanent financing.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Each qualified household purchasing a WHU shall be required to record a mortgage in favor of Miami-Dade County. A promissory note shall be executed by each qualified household and secured by said mortgage. Said mortgage shall set forth the same covenants, along with the refinancing and resale restrictions as those included in the restrictive covenants required by this section, and shall requirement of acknowledgment of the County's right of first refusal as set forth in section 17-135(B) and (C).</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>WHUs offered for sale during the initial or any control period shall not be offered for a price greater than the current maximum WHU sales price as determined by the Department at the time of sale.</section><section prefix='(C)'>A new twenty (20) year control period shall commence upon any resale and/or transfer to a new owner of such WHU within the initial 20-year control period. Any WHU that is owned for an entire 20 year control period by the same individual(s), shall be released from the sales price restrictions under the program. Upon the expiration of the control period the County shall record in the public records of Miami-Dade County an instrument or document releasing the WHU from the restrictive covenant required by this program.</section><section>A WHU may not be resold during the control period set forth herein for an amount that exceeds the WHU sales price set by administrative order. Prior to offering the dwelling unit for sale during the control period, the WHU owner shall obtain the Director's written approval of the WHU sales price.</section><section>The covenants recorded by each developer or other property owner of WHUs shall state in said covenant that the unit is subject to the following provisions:<section prefix='1.'>The covenants shall be senior to all instruments securing permanent financing, and shall bind all assignees, mortgagees, purchasers and other successors in interest.</section><section prefix='2.'>The total aggregate amount of principal and accrued interest for all financing secured by an individual upon his or her initial purchase of a WHU shall not exceed 105% of the loan-to-value. Any financing in excess of the lesser of (1) Department's maximum WHU sales price at the time of closing; or (2) the property's appraised value shall not be secured by any interest in the applicable individual WHU.</section></section><section>No sale, transfer or foreclosure shall affect the validity of the covenants except as expressly set forth in the provisions of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 19, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>