<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='3'>ARTICLE X. COMMUNITY AFFORDABLE HOUSING STRATEGIES ALLIANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-150</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002591</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-150. Organization.<section prefix='(a)'>The CAHSA shall establish, adopt, and amend bylaws, rules, and regulations for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The CAHSA shall elect a chairperson and a chair-elect from among its members, who shall serve at the will of CAHSA. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the initial chairperson shall be the person serving as chairperson of the CAHSA Task Force pursuant to Resolution R-558-06.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The chair-elect shall act as chairperson in the absence or inability of the chairperson.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The CAHSA shall have assistance from staff designated by the County Manager and other governmental entities and legal representation from the County Attorney's Office. The staff shall maintain and keep the records of the CAHSA; prepare, in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, resolutions or correspondences as CAHSA may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of CAHSA, subject to budgetary limitations.</section><section prefix='(e)'>In order to transact any business or to exercise any power vested in the CAHSA, a quorum consisting of no less than eleven (11) voting members shall be present.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The CAHSA shall not transact business or exercise its powers unless a majority of the quorum in attendance agrees to the activity. The chairperson, or five (5) CAHSA members upon written request to the chairperson, may call for a special meeting.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The CAHSA may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-121, ยง 1, 9-4-07)</history></law>