<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-140</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002581</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-140. Definitions.<section>The definitions contained in Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County, shall apply to this chapter in addition to the following:<section prefix='(1)'>"Area median income" means the median income level for the Miami-Dade County Metropolitan Statistical Area, as established and defined in the annual schedule published by the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, and adjusted for household size.</section><section prefix='(2)'>"Certificate of qualification" means a certificate issued by the Department establishing a qualified household's eligibility to purchase or rent a workforce housing unit ("WHU"). Certificates of qualification shall be valid for 12 months. The certification criteria are set by administrative order.</section><section prefix='(3)'>"Condominium" means that form of ownership of real property created pursuant to Chapter 718 of the Florida Statutes, which is comprised entirely of units that are owned by one or more persons, and which there is, appurtenant to each unit, an undivided share in common elements.</section><section prefix='(4)'>"Condominium conversion" has the meaning established by sections 718.604—718.622 of the Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(5)'>"Control period" means each 20-year period during which the affordability restrictions imposed by this article shall apply. The control period begins at the time of any sale or resale of the affected unit by every new WHU owner.</section><section prefix='(6)'>"Covered development" means all developments providing WHUs or monetary contributions in lieu thereof pursuant to Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(7)'>"Department" means, unless otherwise indicated, the Office of Community and Economic Development for the Miami-Dade Housing Agency or any successor agency.</section><section prefix='(8)'>"Developer" means any person, firm, corporation, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, or any entity or combination of entities that apply for development orders or permits for residential dwelling units seeking to utilize the density or intensity bonus available pursuant to Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County Florida, but does not include the state or any county, municipality, or any governmental entity.</section><section prefix='(9)'>"Director" means, unless otherwise indicated, the Director of the Office of Community and Economic Development for the Director of the Miami-Dade Housing Agency, or designee.</section><section prefix='(10)'>"Eligible household" means, subject to the provisions of section 17-134 hereof, a household whose total income is between 65% and 140% of Area Median Income.</section><section prefix='(11)'>"Eligible household income" means any income derived from any proposed occupants of a WHU who are 18 years of age or older and who will use the WHU as their primary residence.</section><section prefix='(12)'>"Household" means any natural person who occupies a WHU as his or her primary residence.</section><section prefix='(13)'>"Market rate dwelling units" means all dwelling units in a covered development that are not WHUs as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(14)'>"Qualified household" means an eligible household that has received a certificate of qualification from the Department.</section><section prefix='(15)'>"Workforce housing unit rent" or "WHU rent" means rents that do not exceed the monthly Fair Market Rent as determined for Miami-Dade County by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (published annually at http://www.huduser.org/datasets/fmr/fmrs/index.asp?data=fmr06).</section><section prefix='(16)'>"Workforce housing unit sales price" or "WHU sales price" shall mean the sales price set by the Director pursuant to an administrative order, not to exceed an amount affordable at the maximum workforce housing target income range, as defined in Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County, taking into account (a) family size: (b) an annual fixed interest rate based on a thirty (30) year mortgage term; (c) payment of up to five percent (5%) down payment by a qualified household; and (d) an estimation of annual property taxes, assessments, loan insurance and financing fees, allowances for property maintenance and repairs, homeowners insurances, homeowner association fees, if any, and allowances for utilities.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, § 19, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1(2), 5-6-08)</history></law>