<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LOCAL HOUSING ASSISTANCE PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-103</section_number>
<catch_line>Administration and implementation of Miami-Dade County's Local Housing Assistance Program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002551</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-103. Administration and implementation of Miami-Dade County's Local Housing Assistance Program.<section prefix='(a)'>The Housing Finance Authority of Miami-Dade County, Office of Community and Economic Development ("OCED"), Miami-Dade Housing Agency ("MDHA") or its successor department shall be responsible for implementation and administration of the Local Housing Assistance Program and will implement the Local Housing Assistance Program in conjunction with a Local Housing Partnership which is defined in Section 17-105 of this article. At a minimum, the Housing Finance Authority of Miami-Dade County, OCED, or Miami-Dade Housing Agency shall be responsible for the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Overseeing the receipt and expenditure of SHIP Program and other housing program funds assigned by the County Manager in accordance with applicable guidelines including the State Housing Initiatives Partnership Act and the Miami-Dade County Affordable Housing Program Guidelines;</section><section prefix='(2)'>coordinating with state agencies, municipalities within Miami-Dade County and other public and private entities to promote the construction and development of affordable housing; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>evaluating the effectiveness of the County's Local Housing Assistance Program and providing recommendations to the County Manager on an annual basis as to the performance of the program.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The cost of administering Miami-Dade County's Local Housing Assistance Program with SHIP Program funds shall not exceed ten (10) percent of the local housing distribution of SHIP Program funds deposited into the Local Housing Assistance Trust Fund.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The revised affordable housing program will operate in conjunction with and as an integral part of the housing plans and strategies contained in the new Consolidated Plan required to receive and expend funds from Community Development Block Grant, HOME Investment Partnership, and Emergency Shelter Grant from the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-70, ยง 3, 4-18-95; Ord. No. 97-65, ยง 3, 5-20-97; Ord. No. 07-18, ยง 3, 2-6-07; Ord. No. 07-98, ยง 1, 7-10-07)</history></law>