<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-24</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum standards for light and ventilation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002497</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-24. Minimum standards for light and ventilation.<section>No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit for the purpose of living, sleeping, cooking, or eating therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>(a)Every habitable room shall have at least one (1) window or skylight facing directly to the outdoors. The minimum total window area which provides light to each habitable room shall be not less than ten (10) percent of the floor area of such room. Whenever exterior walls or other light-obstructing structures are located less than three (3) feet from the window and extend above the ceiling of the room, such a window shall not be deemed to face directly to the outdoors and shall not be included in the required minimum total window area. Whenever the only window in a room is a skylight-type window located in the top of such room, the minimum total window area of such skylight shall not be less than fifteen (15) percent of the total floor area of the room. Skylights shall not be a substitute for the window requirements in sleeping rooms.<section prefix='(b)'>Kitchens and dining rooms will be exempt from the requirements of subsection (1)(a) of this section, providing they meet the requirements in subsections (2) and (6) of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If any two (2) habitable rooms, excluding sleeping rooms, are separated by a common wall and either room lacks the required window area, but meets all three (3) exceptions listed below, such rooms shall be considered in compliance with this subsection:<section prefix='(i)'>The common wall separating the two (2) rooms must provide an opening equal to twenty-five (25) percent of the total wall area.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>If the opening so provided is a doorway, it must be unobstructed and have a minimum width of thirty (30) inches.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>One (1) of the two (2) rooms must provide the required light and ventilation for the total combined floor area of the two (2) rooms.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Every habitable room shall be ventilated by openable areas equal to fifty (50) percent of the required minimum window area, as set forth in subsection (1) of this section or by equivalent mechanical ventilation as approved by the inspecting officer.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Every bathroom, shower room and water closet compartment shall comply with the light and ventilation requirements for habitable rooms contained in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, except that no window or skylight shall be required in adequately ventilated bathrooms, shower rooms and water closet compartments equipped with an approved mechanical ventilating system which automatically becomes operational when the bathroom switch is turned on.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Every door, window or other device opening to outdoor space and used or intended to be used for ventilation shall be provided with an approved type of screen for protection against mosquitoes, flies and other insects.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Every opening beneath a dwelling, including basement or cellar windows and crawl space, shall be equipped with an approved type of screening or lattice work to keep out large animals.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Every habitable room of a dwelling shall contain at least two (2) separate floor or wall-type electrical convenience outlets, or one (1) such convenience outlet and one (1) ceiling-type electric light fixture. Every bathroom, shower room, water closet, compartment and laundry room shall contain at least one (1) properly installed ceiling or wall-type electric light fixture. The switches shall be so located and installed as to avoid the danger of electrical shock.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Every hall and stairway located in a structure used for human habitation shall be provided with not less than one (1) footcandle of natural light throughout or with properly installed electric lighting facilities which provide not less than one (1) foot-candle of illumination throughout and which are controlled by the occupants of the structure and available at all times.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-30, § 2.02, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 67-14, §§ 4, 5, 3-7-67; Ord. No. 74-11, § 2, 3-20-74; Ord. No. 78-7, § 1, 2-21-78)</history></law>