<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-25</section_number>
<catch_line>Requirements relating to the safe and sanitary maintenance of dwellings and dwelling units.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002498</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-25. Requirements relating to the safe and sanitary maintenance of dwellings and dwelling units.<section>No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit, for the purpose of living, sleeping, cooking, or eating therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>All foundation walls shall be structurally sound, reasonably rodentproof, and maintained in good repair. Foundation walls shall be considered to be sound if they are capable of bearing imposed loads and are not deteriorated.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Every dwelling unit shall be reasonably weathertight, watertight and rodentproof. Floors, walls, ceilings and roofs shall be capable of affording adequate shelter and privacy and shall be kept in good repair. Windows and exterior doors shall be reasonably weathertight, watertight, and rodentproof, and shall be maintained in good working condition. All parts of the structure that show evidence of rot or other deterioration shall be repaired or replaced.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Every inside and outside stairway, porch, and every appurtenance thereto, shall be maintained in a safe condition and be capable of supporting loads which normal use may impose.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Every chimney and smoke pipe, and all flue and vent attachments thereto, shall be maintained in such condition that there will be no leakage or backing up of smoke and noxious gases into the dwelling.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All exterior surfaces subject to deterioration shall be properly maintained and protected from the elements by paint or other approved protective coating applied in a workmanlike fashion.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Every plumbing fixture, water pipe, waste pipe and drain shall be maintained in good sanitary working condition, free from defects, leaks and obstructions.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The floor surface of every water closet compartment, bathroom and shower room shall be maintained so as to be reasonably impervious to water and so as to permit such floor to be easily kept in a clean and sanitary condition.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Every supplied facility, piece of equipment, or utility required in this code shall be maintained in a safe and satisfactory working condition. No owner or occupant shall cause any service, facility, equipment, or utility required in this code to be removed from or discontinued for any occupied dwelling or dwelling unit except for such temporary interruption as may be necessary while actual repairs, replacement, or alterations are in process.</section><section prefix='(9)'>For these purposes, every owner of a building containing three (3), or more, dwelling units, shall provide the continuing services of a person or persons solely to assure that the minimum requirements of maintenance and sanitation, as provided by this article, are maintained on the premises at all times. The landlord shall provide the tenant with the name, address, and phone number of the person or persons providing the continuing services. Said notice shall be given to the tenant by either posting the notice in a conspicuous place at the building site or by supplying the tenant with the information at the inception of the lease. The landlord is further charged with informing the tenant of any change of name, address, or phone number of the person or persons providing the continuing service.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-30, ยง 2.03, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 73-36, ยง 1, 4-3-73)</history></law>