<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-29</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum standards for hotels and rooming houses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002502</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-29. Minimum standards for hotels and rooming houses.<section>No person shall operate a hotel or rooming house, or shall occupy or let to another for occupancy, any hotel unit or rooming unit which does not meet with all of the other standards of this code, except as provided by the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>No person shall operate a hotel or rooming house unless he has complied with all of the licensing and permit requirements of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Every room occupied for sleeping purposes by one (1) person shall contain at least seventy (70) square feet of floor space and every room occupied for sleeping purposes by more than one (1) person shall contain at least fifty (50) square feet of floor space for each occupant thereof. Every room occupied for sleeping purposes shall have a minimum width of eight (8) feet and an average floor to ceiling height of seven (7) feet.</section><section prefix='(3)'>At least one (1) flush water closet, lavatory basin and bathtub or shower, properly connected to an approved water system and sewer system or an approved septic tank installation and absorption bed, and in good working condition, shall be supplied for each six (6) persons or fraction thereof residing within a hotel or rooming house, including members of the operator's family whenever they share the use of said facilities. In a hotel or rooming house where rooms are let only to males, flush urinals may be substituted for not more than one-half the required number of water closets. All water closets, urinals, bathtubs, or showers shall be located within a room or rooms which afford privacy to the user and are not more than one (1) story removed from the hotel or rooming unit of any occupant intended to share the facilities. All such facilities shall be so located within the hotel or rooming house as to be accessible to the occupants of each hotel or rooming unit sharing such facilities without going outside of the building or without going through a dwelling, hotel, or rooming unit of another occupant. Every lavatory basin, bathtub or shower shall be supplied with hot and cold water at all times.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No cellar or basement space shall be used as a habitable room or as a hotel or rooming unit.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall change supplied bed linen and towels at least once each week and prior to the letting of any room to any occupant. The operator shall be responsible for maintaining all supplied bedding in a clean and sanitary manner.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for the sanitary maintenance of all walls, floors, ceilings and other parts, and further, he shall be responsible for the sanitary maintenance of the entire premises where all of the building is under the control of such operator.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Every window of every hotel or rooming unit shall be supplied with shades, draw drapes, or other devices or materials which, when properly used, will afford privacy to the occupant of the hotel or rooming unit. No cooking shall be permitted in hotel and rooming units which are not equipped with approved kitchen facilities and do not meet minimum dwelling unit standards.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Every hotel or rooming structure and hotel or rooming unit of types of construction I, II, III, IV and V as defined by Chapters 17, 18, 19, 20, 21 and 22 respectively of the South Florida Building Code shall have means of egress which conform to the standards of Chapter 31 of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire codes, fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Every hotel or rooming structure of type of construction V, built before December 31, 1957 where the structural and other elements of the building consist primarily of wood, having one (1) or two (2) hotel or rooming units above the ground floor, shall have a minimum of two (2) separate means of egress which are remote from each other or at least one (1) means of egress with stairs that are constructed of either noncombustible materials or made safe by approved fire resistive modifications as may be required. Each such means of egress shall be easily accessible from every hotel or rooming unit on the specified floor without passing through any other hotel, rooming, or dwelling unit. Every hotel or rooming structure of type of construction V, where the structural and other elements consist primarily of wood having three (3) or more hotel, rooming or dwelling units, shall have means of egress which conform with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire code, fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.</section><section prefix='(9)'>The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for keeping the premises free from the accumulation of rubbish at all times.</section><section prefix='(10)'>The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for the prompt and sanitary disposal of all garbage through the use of approved mechanical equipment or by placing it in the required containers.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for providing and hanging all window and door screens.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The operator of every hotel or rooming house shall be responsible for the extermination of any insects, rodents, vermin, or other pests therein and shall be further responsible for such extermination on the entire premises where all of the building within which the hotel or rooming house is contained is leased or rented by the operator. Whenever infestation is caused by failure of the owner to maintain the building in a reasonably insectproof or ratproof condition, extermination shall be the responsibility of the owner.</section><section prefix='(13)'>It shall be the duty of the operator of every hotel or rooming house to report to the Miami-Dade County Health Department within twenty-four (24) hours the name of any person living in the hotel or rooming house who is believed to be afflicted with any communicable disease.</section><section prefix='(14)'>No owner shall let for occupancy any rooming unit or hotel unit that is not provided with adequate heating facilities of an approved type properly installed and maintained in safe and good working condition as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Adequate heating facilities are hereby defined as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Permanent space heating equipment capable of heating two-thirds of the habitable rooms to a minimum air temperature of seventy (70) degrees Fahrenheit to be measured three (3) feet above floor when outside temperature is forty-five (45) degrees Fahrenheit, or permanent space heating equipment with capacity of five (5) Btu's per hour of input per cubic foot of habitable room space within two-thirds of the habitable rooms.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The five (5) Btu's per hour input standard is based on a heating unit with seventy (70) percent rating of input-to-output efficiency, an appropriate correction factor will be applied when the proposed heating unit exceeds an input-to-output efficiency rating of seventy (70) percent. Heating units supplied on the basis of this calculation will otherwise comply with the standards described elsewhere in this subsection.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Permanent heating equipment is defined as heating equipment properly connected to a flue or vent or, if electric, properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch circuit.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Habitable room shall mean a room or enclosed floor space used or intended to be used for living or sleeping purposes, excluding bathrooms, shower rooms, water closet compartments, laundries, pantries, foyers, connecting corridors, closets and storage spaces.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Heating equipment shall be installed and maintained in accordance with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any calculations necessary for the installation of permanent heating equipment to assure adequate heating capacity as defined in this section shall be made in accordance with the standards established in the current edition of the "Heating Ventilating Air-Conditioning Guide," published by the American Society of Heating, Refrigeration and Air-Conditioning Engineers, Inc. (ASHRAE).</section><section prefix='(g)'>Oil heaters, gas heaters, and wood-stoves must be connected to a properly installed vent, said vent conforming to the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Electric heaters will be of a type readily fixed into position and must be properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch-circuit.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Any portable heating device approved by the Underwriters' Laboratories, Inc., or a properly installed fireplace may be used as an accessory heating unit.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Accessory heating units will be deemed to be supplementary to the permanent-heating equipment and shall not be considered when calculating the adequacy of the permanently installed heating equipment except as specified in subsection (14)(m).</section><section prefix='(k)'>Only those accessory heating units which are acceptable under the provisions of the City of Miami and Miami-Dade County Fire Code, the Florida State Hotel and Restaurant Commission regulations, and other regularly adopted regulations will be used.</section><section prefix='(l)'>The use of unsafe heaters or cooking stoves and the use of cooking stoves, including ovens, for heating purposes is hereby prohibited.</section><section prefix='(m)'>The requirements of subsection (14) shall not apply to units or hotel units in existence on March 17, 1969, provided that either a gas pipe outlet or an electrical outlet and circuit are present for the use of gas space heaters or portable electrical space heaters.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-30, ยง 2.07, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 68-78, ยง 2, 12-17-68; Ord. No. 71-24, ยง 2, 3-4-71; Ord. No. 74-44, ยง 3, 6-18-74)</history></law>