<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-30</section_number>
<catch_line>Designation of dwellings, hotels and rooming houses, unfit for human habitation and procedures for placarding.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002503</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-30. Designation of dwellings, hotels and rooming houses, unfit for human habitation and procedures for placarding.<section>The designation of dwellings, dwelling units, hotels and rooming houses as unfit for human habitation and the procedure for placarding as unfit for human habitation of such unfit dwellings, dwelling units, hotels and rooming houses shall be carried out in compliance with the following requirements: Any dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit which shall be found to have any of the following defects, shall be designated by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant as unfit for human habitation and shall be so placarded.<section prefix='(a)'>One (1) which is so damaged, decayed, dilapidated, unsanitary, unsafe, or vermin infested that it creates a serious hazard to the health or safety of the occupants or of the public.</section><section prefix='(b)'>One (1) which lacks illumination, ventilation or sanitation facilities adequate to protect the health or safety of the occupants or of the public.</section><section prefix='(c)'>One (1) which because of its general condition or location is unsanitary or otherwise dangerous to the health or safety of the occupants or of the public.</section></section><section>Any dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit declared unfit for human habitation by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant shall be so designated by posting a placard in a conspicuous place on the structure.</section><section>A dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit deemed to be unfit for human habitation and placarded as such by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant shall be vacated within thirty (30) days of placarding as ordered by Team Metro and shall not be used for human habitation again until written approval is secured from, and the placard removed by Team Metro. Team Metro shall order the removal of the placard whenever the defect or defects upon which the placarding actions were based have been eliminated.</section><section>No person shall deface or remove the placard from any dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel, hotel unit, rooming house or rooming unit which has been deemed to be unfit for human habitation and placarded as such by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant, except as provided in the foregoing subsection.</section><section>Any person whose property has been placarded as unfit for human habitation may request and shall be granted a hearing on the matter before the Hearing Officer.</section><section>Where the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant determines that a building is an unsafe building within the provisions of Section 202 of the South Florida Building Code, he shall immediately report the matter to the Building Official.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-30, § 2.08, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 65-32, § 4, 4-20-65; Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 10, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 07-148, § 8, 10-2-07)</history></law>