<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-48</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Duties and powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002517</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-48. Same—Duties and powers.<section>The powers of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall include the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The enforcement of the provisions of this article and rules and regulations promulgated hereunder, and all County ordinances, codes, rules and regulations pertaining to housing and the use and occupancy of dwellings, and all rules and regulations of the Florida State Board of Health and the Florida Hotel and Restaurant Commission, in cooperation with such state agencies, in the City of Miami.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Investigate complaints and institute enforcement actions necessary to abate all violations of County regulations governing the use and occupancy of housing facilities. In addition to inspections resulting from complaints, inspections may be made at the request of the owner of the subject property provided such requested inspections are for the purpose of qualifying for participation in a governmental program. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have the power and authority to charge and collect fees for making inspections. The fees charged shall be as set forth in the Team Metro fee schedule, as established by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Make appropriate surveys and inspections to determine whether the provisions of this article are being complied with, and whether minimum housing standards are being maintained within the City of Miami.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Make inspections of housing premises, facilities and equipment in accordance with procedures prescribed by this article to determine whether the provisions of this article are being complied with, and make recommendations for methods by which minimum housing standards may be more effectively maintained.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Render all possible assistance and technical advice to persons operating and maintaining housing facilities, premises and equipment.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Establish, operate and maintain a continuous program for monitoring and inspection of housing facilities in the City of Miami designed to provide accurate data and information as to whether the minimum standards established by this article are being complied with and whether the level of adequate housing facilities is increasing or decreasing in the City of Miami.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning all matters relating to minimum housing standards and the advantages of adequate housing facilities.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Render all possible assistance and cooperation to federal, State and local agencies and officials in the accomplishment of effective minimum housing standards and controls.</section><section prefix='(9)'>The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have the power and authority to charge and collect fees as described in Section 17-48(2) herein for rendering inspection assistance in accordance with the Team Metro fee schedule, as established by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time and to recover the costs of enforcement as provided for in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Make periodic reports concerning the status of minimum housing standards and the enforcement of the provisions of this article, and recommendations concerning the improvement of minimum housing standards and controls.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Perform such other administrative duties as may be assigned by the County Manager.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 9, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 81-16, § 1, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 10, 9-3-98)</history></law>