<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-44</section_number>
<catch_line>Construction and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002513</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-44. Construction and applicability.<section>The provisions of this article shall be applicable solely within the territorial limits of the City of Miami, Florida. Every portion of a building or premises used or intended to be used for any dwelling purpose, except temporary housing in times of local emergency, disaster or necessity, shall comply with the provisions of this article, irrespective of when such building shall have been constructed, altered or repaired; and irrespective of any permits or licenses which shall have been issued for the use or occupancy of the building or premises, for the construction or repair of the building, or for the installation or repair of equipment or facilities, prior to the effective date of this article. This article is intended and shall be construed as establishing minimum standards for the initial and continued occupancy of all buildings. It is not intended to replace, modify, supersede or diminish the standards established for the construction, repair, alteration or use of buildings, equipment or facilities by the South Florida Building Code (Ordinance No. 57-22, as amended). In any case where any provision of this article is found to be in conflict with a material and controlling provision of zoning regulations, the South Florida Building Code, or any other County or municipal ordinance, code or regulation, or any rules or regulations of the Florida State Board of Health, the provision which establishes the highest standard shall prevail. All County and municipal departments, officials and employees who have the duty, responsibility or authority to issue permits or licenses in regard to the use and occupancy of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, or rooming units, or similar facilities, shall conform to the provisions of this article, as a minimum standard.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, ยง 5, 3-5-68)</history></law>