<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-43</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002512</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-43. Legislative intent.<section>The intent and purpose of this article is to protect the public health, safety, morals and welfare of all the people of the City of Miami, Florida, by establishing minimum standards governing the condition, occupancy, and maintenance of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, rooming units and premises; establishing minimum standards governing utilities, facilities, and other physical components and conditions essential to make dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, rooming units, and premises safe, sanitary, and fit for human habitation; fixing certain responsibilities and duties of owners, operators, agents, and occupants of dwellings, and dwelling units, rooming houses, and rooming units; authorizing and establishing procedures for the inspection of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, and rooming units, and the condemnation and vacation of those dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, and rooming units unfit for human habitation; and fixing penalties for the violations of the provisions of this article, and to set forth a procedure for the granting of variances to the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter in cases of extreme hardship, where the health, safety, welfare and morals of the occupants of a given unit, or the public at large, will not be detrimentally affected, and where literal enforcement of the code would offer no meaningful advantage to the occupants of a unit or to the public at large. The article is hereby declared to be remedial and essential to the public interest, and it is intended that this article be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes as stated above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, ยง 4, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 76-28, ยง 1, 3-16-76)</history></law>