<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-50</section_number>
<catch_line>Authorized inspections.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002519</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-50. Authorized inspections.<section>The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall be authorized to make inspections to determine the condition of dwellings, dwelling units, rooming houses, rooming units, hotels, hotel units, and premises in order to safeguard the health, safety, morals and welfare of the public. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall be authorized to enter any dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, hotel, hotel unit, or premises at any reasonable time, or at such other time as may be necessary in an emergency, for the purpose of performing the duties of such office under this article, in accordance with the procedures herein prescribed. Except in emergencies endangering the public health, safety and welfare, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall enter a dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, hotel, hotel unit, or premises only upon the prior consent of the person lawfully in occupancy thereof or the person having legal right of possession thereof, or in accordance with the provisions of this section. When the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or any enforcing officer has reason to believe that any dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, hotel, hotel unit, or premises is in violation of the provisions of this article, or when such officer deems it necessary to make an inspection to determine whether a facility is in violation of the minimum housing standards established by this article, such officer shall request permission to make an inspection from the person lawfully in occupancy thereof or from the person having the legal right of possession thereof. In the event that such person refuses to consent to the inspection, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or enforcing officer may apply to the County Court or Circuit Court for the issuance of an inspection warrant to be served by an officer duly authorized by law to serve inspection warrants and make arrests for violations of this article. The inspection warrant shall issue in accordance with the requirements of the United States Supreme Court case of v. 18 L. Ed. 2d 930, 87 S. Ct. 1727 (1967) and Florida Statutes, Sections 933.20—933.30 and shall authorize entry into and inspection of the premises described therein. Refusal to permit an inspection pursuant to an inspection warrant authorized by this section shall constitute a violation of this article and shall subject the violator to the penalties prescribed herein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 11, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 71-52, § 5, 6-15-71; Ord. No. 80-61, § 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 86-47, § 1, 6-17-86)</history></law>