<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-58.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Recovery of enforcement costs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002528</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-58.1. Recovery of enforcement costs.<section prefix='(a)'>The entire costs incurred by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer in enforcing the provisions of this chapter shall be paid by the owner, including but not limited to, the cost of enforcement inspections, preparation of enforcement, reports, photographs, title searches, postage and other administrative costs for enforcement and collection. The owner of any multi-unit dwelling containing four (4) or more dwelling units, rooming units, or hotel/motel units or combination thereof which is subject to the registration certificate requirements of Section 17-20 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County shall only be liable for enforcement costs levied and imposed pursuant to this section, if such enforcement costs collectible hereunder exceed the annual registration certificate fee special assessments collected for the building in which such dwelling is contained. The costs of enforcement shall be paid within thirty (30) days of the owner's receipt of the Team Metro's bill itemizing the enforcement costs incurred in enforcing this chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall file among his records a fair and accurate statement of each item of expense with the date of execution of any action authorized by this chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Team Metro may institute a civil suit to recover such expenses against the property or may cause such expenses to be charged against the real property as a lien, upon recordation of an enforcement lien in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida. A lien will remain on the real property after recordation as provided herein until such costs are fully paid and discharged, or barred by law.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Liens created pursuant to Section 17-58.1(c) may be discharged and satisfied by payment to Team Metro of the amount specified in the notice of lien, together with interest thereon from the date of the filing of the lien computed at the rate of eighteen (18) percent per annum, together with the administrative costs, filing and recording fees and fees paid to file a satisfaction of the lien in the public records. When any such lien has been discharged, the Department of Team Metro shall promptly cause evidence of the satisfaction and discharge of such lien to be recorded in the public records. Any person, firm, corporation or legal entity, other than the present owner of the property involved, who pays any such unsatisfied lien shall be entitled to receive an assignment of the lien held by the County and shall be subrogated to the rights of the County in respect to the enforcement of such lien, as permitted by law.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-15, ยง 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 10, 9-3-98)</history></law>