<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-53</section_number>
<catch_line>Recording of final order.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002522</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-53. Recording of final order.<section>Whenever a notice of violation becomes a final order, or whenever the violations specified in the notice have not been corrected within the time specified in the notice, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall file a copy of such final order or other appropriate instrument indicating that violations of the minimum housing standards established by this article exist upon the property involved, in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, who shall cause the same to be recorded among the public records of Miami-Dade County, in an appropriate book provided for such purpose. The recordation of such final order or other appropriate instrument as herein provided shall constitute constructive notice to any subsequent purchasers, transferees, grantees, mortgagors, mortgagees, lessees, lienors, and all persons having, claiming or acquiring any interest in the property described therein, or affected thereby. When the violations specified in the said final order shall have been corrected, and all costs of enforcement as provided hereinafter are paid, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have recorded a certificate certifying that the violations have been corrected and cancelling the final order. All such final orders shall contain the proper legal description of the property involved. The cost of recording the original final order and the certificate of cancellation shall also be recoverable as costs from the owner of record of the property prior to recording the certificate of cancellation. Any person acquiring any interest in or to property described in a final order after recordation thereof shall be bound by the provisions thereof, and shall take the property subject to the requirements set forth in the final order. All such persons acquiring an interest in or to property for which a final order has been recorded under this section shall comply with the requirements thereof, and shall be subject to all of the other provisions of this chapter. Provided, however, that if the time for appeal from the final order as provided in Sections and has not run as of the time of conveyance, the new owner or transferee of an interest in or to property shall have ten (10) days from the date upon which the transfer of property interest is effective as to him within which to appeal the final order to the Hearing Officer. If an appeal of the final order has been perfected but a final decision of the Hearing Officer has not been rendered, the new owner or transferee may exercise all of the rights of appeal which would have been accorded to the prior owner or transferor.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 14, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 71-52, § 7, 6-15-71; Ord. No. 80-63, § 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 80-141, § 1, 12-16-80; Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 07-148, § 14, 10-2-07)</history></law>