<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-59</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum standards for basic equipment and facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002529</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-59. Minimum standards for basic equipment and facilities.<section>No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit, for the purpose of living, sleeping, cooking, or eating therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Every dwelling unit shall contain not less than a kitchen sink, lavatory, tub or shower and water closet, all in good working condition and installed in accordance with the South Florida Building Code. Sink, lavatory, tub or shower shall be supplied with adequate hot and cold water.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Every dwelling unit shall contain a room which affords privacy to a person within said room and which is equipped with a flush water closet and a lavatory basin in good working condition and properly connected to an approved water system and sewer system or an approved septic tank installation including an approved absorption bed. No privy shall be constructed or continued in operation after the effective date of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Every dwelling unit shall contain a room which affords privacy to a person within said room and which is equipped with a bathtub or shower in good working condition and properly connected to an approved water system and sewer system or an approved septic tank installation including an approved absorption bed.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Every kitchen sink, lavatory basin, and bathtub or shower required under the provisions of this section shall be properly connected with both hot and cold water lines.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Every dwelling shall have water heating facilities which are properly installed, maintained in safe and good working condition, and properly connected with the hot water lines required under the provisions of the preceding paragraphs. Such water heating facilities shall be capable of supplying on demand to all the required fixtures a continuous supply of hot water, as spelled out below. The following shall be used as a minimum guide:</section></section><section>   WHERE CENTRAL HOT WATER IS   SUPPLIED FOR MULTI-FAMILY   HOUSING UNITS:<section>Where dwelling units have individual water heaters, there shall be provided a system capable of supplying one hundred forty (140) degree water in an amount of sixteen (16) gallons per bedroom per three (3) hours.</section><section>An adequately designed solar system is acceptable if there is incorporated in the design a thermostatically controlled booster with Btu input equivalent to that specified above.</section><section>Instantaneous or tankless systems are acceptable if they are designed to raise the required volume of water seventy (70) degrees Fahrenheit. The required volume of water shall be determined by the fixture unit method as set forth in the National Bureau of Standards BMS 66.</section><section>All such facilities shall be of an approved type, connected and maintained all as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Every occupied dwelling unit shall be provided with an installed nonportable cooking facility which shall not be capable of being carried easily by one (1) person, and shall have at least two (2) top burners. Vacant dwelling units shall be provided with utility connections for such facility.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Every dwelling unit shall have adequate garbage disposal facilities or garbage storage containers.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Every dwelling structure and dwelling unit of types of construction I, II, III, IV and V as defined by Chapters 17, 18, 19, 20, 21 and 22 respectively of the South Florida Building Code shall have means of egress which conform to the standards of Chapter 31 of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire codes, fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Every dwelling structure of type of construction V, built before December 31, 1957, where the structural and other elements of the building consist primarily of wood, having one (1) or two (2) dwelling units above the ground floor, shall have a minimum of two (2) separate means of egress which are remote from each other or at least one (1) means of egress with stairs that are constructed of either noncombustible materials or made safe by approved fire resistive modifications as may be required. Each such means of egress shall be easily accessible for every dwelling unit on the specified floor without passing through any other dwelling unit. Every dwelling structure of type of construction V, where the structural and other elements consist primarily of wood having three (3) or more dwelling units, shall have means of egress which conform with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire codes, fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.</section><section prefix='(9)'>In every owner-occupied dwelling unit not intended to be let for occupancy containing space heating facilities, such facilities shall be properly installed and maintained in safe and good working conditions as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.<section>Every dwelling and dwelling unit which is let or intended to be let for occupancy shall have adequate space heating facilities which are properly installed and maintained in safe and good working condition as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto. Adequate heating facilities are hereby defined as follows:</section><section prefix='(a)'>Permanent space heating equipment capable of heating two-thirds of the habitable rooms to a minimum air temperature of seventy (70) degrees Fahrenheit to be measured three (3) feet above floor when outside temperature is forty-five (45) degrees Fahrenheit, or permanent space heating equipment with capacity of five (5) Btu's per hour of input per cubic foot of habitable room space within two-thirds of the habitable rooms.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The five (5) Btu's per hour input standard is based on a heating unit with seventy (70) percent rating of input-to-output efficiency; an appropriate correction factor will be applied when the proposed heating unit exceeds an input-to-output efficiency rating of seventy (70) percent. Heating units supplied on the basis of this calculation will otherwise comply with the standards described elsewhere in this subsection.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Permanent heating equipment is defined as heating equipment properly connected to a flue or vent or, if electric, properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch circuit.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Habitable room shall mean a room or enclosed floor space used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking or eating purposes, excluding bathrooms, shower rooms, water closet compartments, laundries, pantries, foyers, connecting corridors, closets and storage spaces.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Heating equipment shall be installed and maintained in accordance with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any calculations necessary for the installation of permanent heating equipment to assure adequate heating capacity as defined in this section, shall be made in accordance with the standards established in the current edition of the "Heating, Ventilating, Air-Conditioning Guide," published by the American Society of Heating and Air-Conditioning Engineers, Inc.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Oil heaters, gas heaters, and wood-stoves must be connected to a properly installed vent, said vent conforming to the provisions of the South Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Electric heaters will be of a type readily fixed into position and must be properly installed and permanently connected to an adequately wired and sized branch circuit.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Any portable heating device approved by the Underwriters' Laboratories, Inc., or a properly installed fireplace may be used as an accessory heating unit.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Accessory heating units will be deemed to be supplementary to the permanent heating equipment and shall not be considered when calculating the adequacy of the permanently installed heating equipment except as specified in subsection (9)(m).</section><section prefix='(k)'>Only those accessory heating units which are acceptable under the provisions of the City of Miami and Miami-Dade County Fire Code, the Florida State Hotel and Restaurant Commission regulations, and other regularly adopted regulations will be used.</section><section prefix='(l)'>The use of unsafe heaters or cooking stoves and the use of cooking stoves, including ovens, for heating purposes is hereby prohibited.</section><section prefix='(m)'>The requirements of subsection (9) shall not apply to dwelling units in existence on March 17, 1969, provided that either a gas pipe outlet or an electrical outlet and circuit are present for the use of gas space heaters or portable electrical space heaters.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 20, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 68-77, § 1, 12-17-68; Ord. No. 71-24, § 1, 3-4-71; Ord. No. 74-44, § 5, 6-18-74)</history></law>