<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-51</section_number>
<catch_line>Notice of violations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002520</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-51. Notice of violations.<section prefix='(a)'>Whenever the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his assistant finds and determines that there has been a violation of the minimum housing standards established by this article he shall give notice of such violation to the owner. Such notice shall be in writing, shall specify the violations, and shall specify the time for compliance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Such notice shall specify that permits, if necessary, for the work required to correct the violations must be obtained from the Building Official of the City of Miami within the time specified in the notice and that the violation must be corrected within the time specified in the notice, and that final compliance must conform with the requirements of the South Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Such notice shall contain an outline of the remedial action which, if taken, will constitute compliance with the requirements of this article. Such notice shall inform the owner of the right to apply to the Hearing Officer for a hearing and review of matters within this notice as provided in Sections 17-57 and 17-58. Such notice may also inform the person or persons to whom it is directed that failure to comply may result in enforcement action as provided for in Section 17-55 or Chapter 8CC of this Code. Such notice shall be served upon the owner. Such notice shall be deemed to be properly served and binding upon the property involved if a copy is served by certified mail return receipt requested, addressed to the owner's last known address, or if the owner cannot be served by certified mail, a copy of the notice shall be posted in a conspicuous place on the facilities or premises involved. Such notice shall state the date of posting.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, ยง 12, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 69-87, ยง 1, 12-3-69; Ord. No. 88-15, ยง 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 07-148, ยง 12, 10-2-07)</history></law>