<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-58</section_number>
<catch_line>Hearing Officer's additional duties in City of Miami.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002527</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-58. Hearing Officer's additional duties in City of Miami.<section>The Hearing Officer established by of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall have the following additional duties in the City of Miami:<section prefix='(1)'>Hear and determine appeals from actions and decisions of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer in accordance with the provisions of Sections 17-57 and 17A-15</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Hearing Officer shall have the power and authority to hear and pass upon all appeals from the enforcement officer's refusal to grant extension of time for compliance with the provisions of this article and Chapter 17A and notices issued by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer. Applications for extensions of time for compliance shall be considered and determined on the basis of the public interest and welfare and not merely on economic benefit to the applicant. Applications shall be granted only when it is established that the requested extension of time for compliance will not be detrimental to the occupants or to the public health, safety and welfare of the public at large.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Hearing Officer shall not have the power or authority to grant applications for variances to this code, except under the following circumstances:<section prefix='1.'>When the Hearing Officer specifically finds, upon a showing by the applicant, that an extreme hardship as defined in Section 17-46 or 17A-5 exists; and</section><section prefix='2.'>When the Hearing Officer finds that such hardship circumstance is one in which the granting of a variance will not detrimentally affect the health, safety, morals or welfare of the occupants or the public.</section><section prefix='(b)'>When the Hearing Officer finds that the application for variance meets the requirements of subsection (a) above, the Hearing Officer may determine that such variance is necessary for a period of one (1) year or less and in that event the Hearing Officer shall recite the exact date on which the variance shall terminate and by which compliance shall be effected.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When the Hearing Officer finds that the application for variance meets the requirements of subsection (a) above, and further finds that such hardship variance should be granted for a period of greater than one (1) year, the Hearing Officer shall grant a "continuing variance." Such variance shall apply only to the code violations specifically considered and approved by the Hearing Officer. Such continuing variance shall remain in effect for only so long as those conditions which the Hearing Officer shall attach to each such variance are complied with. The conditions which shall attach to such continuing variance shall include, but not be limited to:<section prefix='1.'>That ownership of the particular unit involved shall remain unchanged; or, in the alternative, the Hearing Officer may grant a continuing variance which shall run with and attach to the property so long as the usage thereof remains unchanged;</section><section prefix='2.'>That the occupancy and usage of said unit shall remain unchanged;</section><section prefix='3.'>That no structural modification or alteration affecting that portion or portions of the unit which is the subject of this variance shall be made except such modification or alteration which is necessary to accomplish compliance with this chapter or Chapter 17A</section><section prefix='4.'>That failure to comply with the conditions upon which said variance has been granted shall require the enforcement officer to file a notice of violation in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d) hereof, which shall cause the existence of any such continuing variance to be reviewed for a determination of whether such variance should be revoked by the Hearing Officer;</section><section prefix='5.'>Other such conditions deemed necessary by the Hearing Officer based upon its consideration of the facts and circumstances of each case; and</section><section prefix='6.'>That said unit shall be annually inspected by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer to determine the compliance with the conditions of the variance and to determine that changes have not taken place which shall cause a dangerous threat to the health, safety, morals, or welfare of the occupant of said unit or to the public at large.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>If the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall, after the annual or periodic inspection provided for in subsection (c)6 above, determine that the conditions attached to any continuing variance have not been complied with, the officer shall file a notice of violation of the terms of said variance in accordance with the notice provisions of Section 17-51 of this chapter or Section 17A-9 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and the officer shall schedule the matter for hearing before the Hearing Officer. The person served with the notice of violation shall have the burden of showing the Hearing Officer why such variance should not be terminated.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 17-53 or Section 17A-11, any variance granted by the Hearing Officer for extreme hardship shall be recorded as a final order. The recording of any such variance shall include a list of all conditions which the Hearing Officer shall have attached and a list of the specific violations for which the Hearing Officer has granted the variance. Any other variance granted by the Hearing Officer shall continue to be recorded as provided by Section 17-53 or Section 17A-11</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, § 19, 3-5-68; Ord. No. 73-48, § 4, 5-1-73; Ord. No. 76-28, § 3, 3-16-76; Ord. No. 80-64, § 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 07-148, § 17, 10-2-07)</history></law>