<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-62</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum space, use and location requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002532</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-62. Minimum space, use and location requirements.<section>No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit for the purpose of living therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Every dwelling unit shall contain a minimum gross floor area of at least one hundred fifty (150) square feet for the first occupant, one hundred (100) square feet for each of the next two (2) occupants, and at least seventy-five (75) square feet for each occupant thereafter. Floor space shall be calculated on the basis of total habitable room area.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In every dwelling unit of two (2) or more habitable rooms, every room occupied for sleeping purposes by one (1) occupant shall have a minimum gross floor area of at least eighty (80) square feet. Every room occupied for sleeping purposes by more than one (1) occupant shall have a minimum gross floor area of fifty (50) square feet per occupant. Every room used for sleeping purposes shall have a minimum width of eight (8) feet. Kitchens shall not be used for sleeping purposes. Porches shall not be used as permanent sleeping quarters.</section><section prefix='(3)'>At last one-half of the floor area of every habitable room shall have a ceiling height of at least seven (7) feet. Any portion of a room having a ceiling height of less than five (5) feet shall not be considered in computing the total floor area of such room.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No dwelling or dwelling unit containing two (2) or more sleeping rooms shall be so arranged that access to a bathroom, shower room, or water closet compartment intended for use by occupants of more than one (1) sleeping room can be had only by going through another sleeping room or outside the structure, nor shall room arrangements be such that access to a sleeping room can be had only by going through another sleeping room, bathroom, shower room, or water closet compartment.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No cellar or basement space shall be used as a habitable room or dwelling unit.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, ยง 23, 3-5-68)</history></law>