<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002480</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-6. Definitions.<section>In construing the provisions of this article, where the context will permit and no definition is provided herein, the definitions provided in Chapter 4 of the South Florida Building Code shall apply. The following words and phrases when used in this article shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section:<section prefix='(1)'>Approval shall mean approved by the head of the enforcement agency or his authorized representatives.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Basement shall mean that portion of a building having less than one-half its clear floor-to-ceiling height below the average finished grade of the ground adjoining the building and its ceiling not more than six (6) feet above said grade.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Cellar shall mean that portion of a building having one-half or more than one-half of its clear floor-to-ceiling height below the average finished grade of the ground adjoining the building.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Dwelling shall mean any building, including, to the extent not inconsistent with State or Federal law, a manufactured home or mobile home, which is wholly or partly used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating, provided that temporary housing as hereinafter defined shall not be regarded as a dwelling.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Dwelling unit shall mean any room or group of rooms located within a dwelling and forming a single habitable unit with facilities used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Enforcing agency shall mean the minimum housing enforcement officer of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County and the municpal housing inspector as defined in subsection (15.2)</section><section prefix='(7)'>Enforcing officer shall mean any employee of the enforcing agency charged with the responsibility of making inspections of buildings and premises and issuing violation notices when necessary. The term shall be synonymous with inspecting officer.</section><section prefix='(7.1)'>Extreme hardship shall describe a condition existing in a case before the Board when a dwelling or dwelling unit does not fully comply with the provisions of the minimum housing code but is structurally sound and does not have safety deficiencies, and when the repair of such structure, in order to assure compliance with the code, would result in great economic hardship to the owner or the occupant of said unit, with commensurately little benefit to the owner or occupant and to the public at large.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Garbage shall mean the animal and vegetable waste resulting from the handling, preparation, cooking and consumption of food.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Habitable area shall mean two (2) or more habitable rooms.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Habitable room shall mean a room or enclosed floor space used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking, or eating purposes, excluding bathrooms, shower rooms, water closet compartments, laundries, pantries, foyers, connecting corridors, closets and storage spaces.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Head of enforcement agency shall mean the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(11.1)'>Hot water shall mean water heated by a system capable of supplying one hundred forty (140) degrees Fahrenheit water temperature in the amounts of sixteen (16) gallons per bedroom per three (3) hours as set forth in Section 1.17(10) subsection (5) of the Rules and Regulations Governing the Enforcement of the Minimum Housing Standards Ordinance.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Hotel shall mean any dwelling or commercial building, or any part of any dwelling or commercial building, containing one (1) or more hotel units in which space is let by the owner or operator on a predominantly temporary basis to three (3) or more persons who are not husband or wife, son or daughter, mother or father, sister or brother of the owner or operator. Motels and buildings offering dormitory-type sleeping accommodations shall be included in this category.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Hotel unit shall mean any room or group of hotel rooms forming a single habitable unit used or intended to be used for living and sleeping, but not for cooking and eating purposes. Motel units and dormitory-type sleeping accommodations shall be included in this category.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Infestation shall mean the presence of any insects, rodents, vermin, or other pests.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Inspecting officer shall be synonymous with the term enforcing officer as previously defined.</section><section prefix='(15.1)'>Means of egress shall mean a continuous path of travel from any point in a building or structure to the open air outside at ground level and consists of three (3) separate and distinct parts:<section prefix='(a)'>The way of exit access,</section><section prefix='(b)'>The exit, and</section><section prefix='(c)'>The means of discharge from the exit.</section><section>A means of egress comprises the vertical and horizontal means of travel and may include the room space, doorway, corridor, hallway, passageway, stairs, ramps, lobby, escalator, and other paths of travel.</section><section prefix='(a)'>Exit access shall mean that portion of a means of egress which leads to an entrance to an exit.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Exit shall mean that portion of a means of egress which is separated from the area of the building from which escape is to be made by walls, floors, doors or other means which provide the protected path necessary for the occupants to proceed with reasonable safety to the exterior of the building.<section>Note: An interior aisle, corridor, hallway or other means of travel used to reach an exit door or doorway is not an exit, except where the maximum allowable distance of travel to an exit is exceeded, at which point the aisle or corridor shall be treated as part of an exit or [it] is located, arranged, and enclosed as to constitute an integral part of an exit facility.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Exit discharge shall mean that portion of a means of egress between the termination of the exit at the exterior of the building and ground level.</section></section><section prefix='(15.2)'>Municipal housing inspector shall mean a municipal employee designated by the County Manager pursuant to an interlocal agreement to enforce the provisions of this chapter within the territorial limits of a municipality. Any reference to minimum housing enforcement officer in this chapter shall also mean municipal housing inspector except in Section 17-7</section><section prefix='(16)'>Occupant shall mean any person over one (1) year of age living, sleeping, cooking, eating in, or having actual possession of a dwelling, dwelling unit, hotel unit, or rooming unit.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Operator shall mean any person who has charge, care, or control of a building, or part thereof, in which dwelling units, hotel units, rooming units, or dormitory-type sleeping accommodations are let.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Owner or record owner shall mean any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity, who individually or jointly or severally with others, holds the legal or beneficial title to any dwelling, dwelling unit, rooming house, rooming unit, facilities, equipment or premises subject to the provisions of this article. The term shall include the owner's duly authorized agent, a purchaser, devisee, fiduciary, property holder or any other person, firm, corporation or legal entity having a vested or contingent interest, or a taxpayer as defined in Florida Statutes Section 192.001(13), as may be amended from time to time. It is intended that this term shall be construed as applicable to the person, firm, corporation or legal entity responsible for the construction, maintenance and operation of the building, facilities or premises involved.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Premises shall mean any occupied or unoccupied building, accessory structure, lot, parcel of land, or any part thereof, used or intended to be used for residential purposes.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Rooming house shall mean any dwelling, or part of any dwelling, containing one (1) or more rooming units in which space is let by the owner or operator on a predominantly permanent basis to three (3) or more persons who are not husband or wife, son or daughter, mother or father, sister or brother of the owner or operator. For the purpose of this code, boarding houses are included in this category.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Rooming unit shall mean any room or group of rooms, forming a single habitable unit, used or intended to be used for living and sleeping but not for cooking or eating purposes.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Rubbish shall mean all combustible and non-combustible waste materials except garbage. The term shall include residue from the burning of wood, coal, coke and other combustible materials, paper, rags, cartons, boxes, wood, excelsior, rubber, leather, tree branches, yard trimmings, tin cans, metal, mineral matter, glass and crockery.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Supplied shall mean paid for, furnished, or provided by or under control of the owner or operator.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Temporary housing shall mean any structure used for human shelter which is not attached to the ground, to another structure, or in a permanent manner to any utilities system. Manufactured homes or mobile homes shall not be designated as temporary housing. For the purpose of this Code, living quarters for migratory agricultural workers shall be defined as temporary housing.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Meaning of certain words. Whenever the words "dwelling," "dwelling unit," "hotel," "hotel unit," "rooming house," "rooming unit" and "premises" are used in this article, they shall be construed as though they were followed by the words "or any part thereof."</section><section prefix='(26)'>Any reference in this article to the words "approved," "adequate," "adequately," "properly installed," "properly connected," or "properly constructed," shall have reference to those standards set out in the South Florida Building Code, the Rules of the State Board of Health, Chapters 5, 15 and 26A of the Metropolitan Code, and any other enactment of law applicable to the structure or particular portion or system of the structure under inspection by the enforcing agency.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-30, § 1.06, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 69-46, § 1, 7-23-69; Ord. No. 74-11, § 1, 3-20-74; Ord. No. 74-44, § 1, 6-18-74; Ord. No. 76-27, § 2, 3-16-76; Ord. No. 88-15, § 1, 3-15-88; Ord. No. 92-117, § 1, 10-13-92; Ord. No. 92-147, § 1, 11-17-92)</history></law>