<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CITY OF MIAMI MINIMUM HOUSING STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-63</section_number>
<catch_line>Responsibilities of owners and occupants.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002533</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-63. Responsibilities of owners and occupants.<section>No person shall occupy, or let to another for occupancy, any dwelling or dwelling unit for the purpose of living therein, which does not comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Every dwelling unit shall be clean, sanitary and fit for human habitation.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Every occupant of a dwelling or dwelling unit shall keep in a clean and sanitary condition that part of the dwelling, dwelling unit and premises thereof which he occupies and controls, including yards, lawns, courts and driveways. The provisions of this subsection shall also apply to vacant lots and to premises of business establishments located in proximity to dwellings and dwelling units.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Every owner of a building containing three (3) or more dwelling units shall be responsible for maintaining in a clean and sanitary condition the shared or public areas of the dwelling and premises thereof. For this purpose, every owner of a building containing three (3) or more dwelling units shall provide the continuing services of a person or persons solely to assure that minimum requirements of maintenance and sanitation as provided by this article are maintained on the premises at all times.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Exterior premises shall be kept free from the excessive growth of weeds, grass and other flora. The term "excessive" shall be interpreted as detrimental to the health, safety, or welfare of the occupants or the public. The provisions of this subsection shall also apply to vacant lots and to the premises of building establishments located in proximity to dwellings and dwelling units.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Every occupant of a dwelling unit shall keep all plumbing fixtures, sanitary facilities, appliances and equipment therein in a clean and sanitary condition and shall exercise reasonable care in the proper use and operation thereof.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Every occupant of a dwelling or dwelling unit shall dispose of rubbish, garbage and other waste materials in an approved sanitary manner. Garbage shall be placed in the garbage disposal facilities or storage containers required by this article.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Every occupant of a dwelling containing a single dwelling unit shall be responsible for the extermination of any insects, rodents, vermin, or other pests therein or on the premises. Every occupant of a dwelling unit in a building containing more than one (1) dwelling unit shall be responsible for such extermination whenever his dwelling unit is the only one infested, except that whenever such infestation is caused by the failure of the owner to carry out the provisions of this article, extermination shall be the responsibility of the owner. In every dwelling containing one (1) or more units, the owner shall exterminate all infestations of any insects, rodents, vermin or other pests therein or on the premises except where such pests are the responsibility of the occupant as provided in the preceding sentence.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Every owner of a dwelling or dwelling unit shall, before renting or subletting to another occupant, provide approved door and window screens whenever such screens are required under the provisions of this article and shall repair or replace them when necessary.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Upon commencement of each occupancy, the owner of every dwelling unit which is let for occupancy, furnished, shall initially deliver to the occupant personal property constituting housekeeping equipment, which is operable, clean, safe and sanitary.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Every owner of a dwelling shall grade and maintain the exterior premises so as to prevent the accumulation of stagnant water thereon.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Animals and pets shall not be kept in any dwelling or dwelling unit or on any premises in such a manner as to create insanitary conditions or constitute a nuisance.</section><section prefix='(12)'>No owner shall let for occupancy any dwelling unit that is not provided with adequate heating facilities of an approved type properly installed and maintained in safe and good working condition as provided in the South Florida Building Code and any applicable fire regulations or ordinances now in existence or adopted subsequent hereto.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-14, ยง 24, 3-5-68)</history></law>