<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. PUBLIC NUISANCES ON LEASED PROPERTY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-82</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002543</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17-82. Definitions.<section>[As used in this article the following words and terms shall have the meanings respectively ascribed:]<section prefix='(1)'>Dwelling unit means:<section prefix='a.'>A structure or part of a structure that is rented for use as a home, residence, or sleeping place by one person or by two or more persons who maintain a common household.</section><section prefix='b.'>A mobile home rented by a tenant.</section><section prefix='c.'>A structure or part of a structure that is furnished, with or without rent, as an incident of employment for use as a home, residence, or sleeping place by one or more persons.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Landlord means the owner or lessor of a dwelling unit.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Tenant means any person entitled to occupy a dwelling unit under a rental agreement.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Premises means a dwelling unit and the structure of which it is a part and a mobile home lot and the appurtenant facilities and grounds, areas, facilities, and property held out for the use of tenants generally.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Public nuisance means any place or premise which within a six-month period has been used on more than two (2) occasions:<section prefix='a.'>As the site of the unlawful sale or delivery of controlled substances, or</section><section prefix='b.'>By a youth and street gang for the purpose of conducting a patter of youth and street gang activity, or</section><section prefix='c.'>For prostitution, or solicitation of prostitution, or</section><section prefix='d.'>For illegal gambling, or</section><section prefix='e.'>For the illegal sale or consumption of alcoholic beverages, or</section><section prefix='f.'>For lewd or lascivious behavior, or</section><section prefix='g.'>Any premise or place declared to be a nuisance by Florida Statute, Section 823.05 or Section 823.10 as they may be renumbered or amended from time to time.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Rental agreement means any written agreement, or oral agreement if for less duration than one (1) year, providing for use and occupancy of premises.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-113, ยง 1(B), 6-9-94)</history></law>