<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='2'>Chapter 17A VACANT STRUCTURES STANDARDS, MINIMUM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17A-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer—Powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002601</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17A-6. Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer—Powers.<section>In addition to the powers found in Sections and of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have the following powers:<section prefix='(1)'>The enforcement of the provisions of this chapter and any rules and regulations promulgated hereunder.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Investigate complaints and institute actions to correct violations of this chapter and initiate action through private contractors or his own employees to have vacant housing structures secured as warranted. In addition to inspections resulting from complaints, inspections may be made at the request of the owner of the subject property, provided such requested inspections are for the purpose of qualifying for participation in a governmental program. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have the power and authority to charge and collect for making such inspections.<section>The fees charged shall be as set forth in the Team Metro fee schedule as established by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>To make appropriate surveys and inspections to determine whether the provisions of this chapter are being complied with in Metropolitan Miami-Dade County and make recommendations for methods by which this chapter can be more effectively enforced and the standards herein raised.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To render all possible assistance and technical advice to owners and operators.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To publish and disseminate information to the public concerning all matters relating to this chapter.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Render all possible assistance and cooperation to federal, State and local agencies and officials in the accomplishment of effective minimum standards and controls.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer shall have the power and authority to charge and collect fees in accordance with the Team Metro fee schedule as amended from time to time and recover the costs of enforcement as provided for in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(8)'>To perform such other administrative duties as may be assigned by the County Manager.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-65, § 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 81-14, § 1, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 88-29, § 1, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 89-52, § 1, 6-6-89; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-228, § 1, 12-19-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 11, 9-3-98)</history></law>