<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='2'>Chapter 17A VACANT STRUCTURES STANDARDS, MINIMUM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17A-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Standards for maintenance and appearance of vacant structures and vacant premises.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002612</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17A-16. Standards for maintenance and appearance of vacant structures and vacant premises.<section>Every vacant structure and vacant premises shall comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Every foundation wall shall be structurally sound, reasonably rodentproof, and maintained in good repair.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Exterior walls and roofs shall be kept in good repair.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Windows and exterior doors shall be weathertight, watertight and rodentproof and shall be maintained in good condition.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All exterior areas that show evidence of rot or other deterioration shall be repaired or replaced.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Every exterior stairway, porch and appurtenance shall be maintained in good repair.</section><section prefix='(6)'>All exterior surfaces subject to deterioration shall be properly maintained and protected from the elements by paint or other approved protective coating applied in a workmanlike fashion.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Every utility connection shall be free from defects, disconnected, removed or otherwise made safe.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Vacant dwelling units shall be provided with utility connections for the following type of facility: an installed nonportable cooking facility which shall not be capable of being carried easily by one (1) person and which shall have at least two (2) top burners.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Every plumbing fixture, waterpipe, wastepipe, and drain shall be free from defects, leaks, and obstructions.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Exterior premises shall be kept free from the excessive growth of weeds, grass, and other flora. The term "excessive growth" shall mean growth which is detrimental to the public health, safety, and welfare and which generally detracts from the appearance of the neighborhood.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Vacant housing structures shall be weathertight, watertight, clean, sanitary, and free from infestation, rubbish, and garbage.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Vacant structures shall be secure at all times. The owner or operator of any vacant structure found unguarded and open as aforesaid shall be given notice of such violation by the enforcing officer unless enforcement action is initiated by the Building Official in accordance with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code, in which case notice of the violation will be provided as required therein. The notice shall require immediate action to secure and seal the vacant structure in a manner that abates temporarily the unsafe conditions by using concrete blocks, storm shutters, or other materials of the same durability as determined by the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and construction methods which are in keeping with good workmanship and appearance, and are otherwise in compliance with the South Florida Building Code. In no event shall a vacant structure remain secured by the use of concrete blocks, storm shutters, or similar materials for a period exceeding one hundred eighty (180) days as that period may be extended pursuant to the South Florida Building Code. Prior to the expiration of the stated period, the vacant structure must be completed and brought into full compliance with the South Florida Building Code. Failure to comply with this requirement shall constitute a violation of this section. Swimming pools are to be secured by filling in with sand, or by fencing or by using another approved method as determined by the minimum housing enforcement officer. Vacant structures temporarily ordered secured as provided aforesaid shall not be used or occupied until written approval is given by the enforcing agency. The provisions of this section shall be complementary to, and not in derogation of, the provisions of the South Florida Building Code relating to unsafe structures.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-65, § 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 88-29, § 1, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 89-52, § 1, 6-6-89; Ord. No. 93-56, § 1, 5-20-93; Ord. No. 95-228, § 1, 12-19-95)</history></law>