<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='2'>Chapter 17A VACANT STRUCTURES STANDARDS, MINIMUM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17A-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative findings and intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002597</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17A-2. Legislative findings and intent.<section>The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby finds and declares that in recent years and at present an increased number of vacant structures exists, especially in buildings which house multiple families, the maintenance and appearance of which are often neglected by the owners thereof, It is furthermore found and declared by this Board that said vacant structures often become open, unsecured, vandalized, or used for illicit purposes by trespassers, resulting in conditions that are unhealthy, unsafe, unsightly, and a blight upon the neighborhood and the community at large, and that the establishment of minimum standards for the maintenance and appearance of vacant structures will improve the security and quality of life in general of persons living nearby, will prevent blight and decay, and will safeguard the public health, safety, morals and welfare.</section><section>The intent and purpose of this chapter is to protect the public health, safety, morals and welfare of all the people of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, by establishing minimum standards governing the maintenance and appearance of vacant structures; fixing certain responsibilities and duties of owners, operators and agents of vacant structures; authorizing and establishing procedures for the inspection of vacant structures; fixing penalties for the violation of the provisions of this chapter; setting forth a procedure for enforcement of this chapter and for the granting of variances to the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter in cases of extreme hardship, when the health, safety, welfare and morals of the neighborhood, community and the public at large will not be detrimentally affected thereby, and where literal enforcement of this chapter would offer no meaningful benefit or advantage to the neighborhood, community and public at large; and by prohibiting human habitation in vacant structures found unsafe and ordered secured until written approval is given by the enforcing agency. This chapter is hereby declared to be remedial and essential to the public interest, and it is intended that this chapter be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes as stated above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-65, ยง 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 95-228, ยง 1, 12-19-95)</history></law>