<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='2'>Chapter 17A VACANT STRUCTURES STANDARDS, MINIMUM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17A-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Appeals from actions or decisions of Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002611</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17A-15. Appeals from actions or decisions of Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer.<section>Any person aggrieved by any action or decision of the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer may appeal to the Minimum Housing Appeals Board by filing with the Board, within ten (10) days after the date of the action or decision complained of, a written notice of appeals which shall set forth concisely the action or decision appealed from and the reasons or grounds for the appeal. The Board shall set such appeal for hearing at the earliest possible date and cause notice thereof to be given to the appellant and the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer. The Board shall hear and consider all facts material to the appeal and render a decision promptly. The Board may affirm, reverse or modify the action or decision appealed from, provided that the Board shall not take any action which conflicts or nullifies any of the provisions of this chapter. The Board shall specifically state in its decision the date by which compliance must be made. The decision of the Board shall be final. No rehearing or reconsideration shall be considered except when granted by majority vote of the Board. Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Board on appeal taken to it, including, but not limited to, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer, may apply to the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County for a review by writ of certiorari in accordance with the applicable Florida Appellate Rules.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-65, ยง 1, 6-17-80)</history></law>