<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='2'>Chapter 17A VACANT STRUCTURES STANDARDS, MINIMUM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17A-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Notice of violations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002604</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17A-9. Notice of violations.<section>Whenever the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or his or her assistant finds and determines that there has been a violation of the standards established by this chapter, he or she shall give notice of such violation to the owner and any operators. Such notice shall be in writing, shall specify the violation, and shall specify the time for compliance. Such notice shall specify that the violation must be corrected or a building permit for the work required to correct the violation must be obtained from Team Metro or appropriate municipal Building and Zoning Department and that final compliance must conform to the requirements of the South Florida Building Code. Such notice shall contain an outline of the remedial action which, if taken, will constitute compliance with the requirements of this chapter. Such notice shall inform the owner and any operators of the right to apply to the Minimum Housing Appeals Board for a hearing and review of matters within the notice and advise that failure to comply or appeal may result in the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer's securing the vacant structure without further notice to the owner or a hearing. Such notice may also inform the person or persons to whom it is directed that failure to comply may result in enforcement action as provided for in or of this Code. Such notice shall be served upon the owner and any operators. Such notice shall be deemed to be properly served and binding upon the owner and upon any operators and upon the vacant structure or vacant premises involved if a copy is served by certified mail return receipt requested, addressed to the owner's and/or operator's last known address. If the owner cannot be served by certified mail, a copy of the notice shall be posted in a conspicuous place on the vacant structure or vacant premises involved. Such notice shall state the date of posting.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-65, § 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 88-29, § 1, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 89-52, § 1, 6-6-89; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-228, § 1, 12-19-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 11, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 08-134, § 10, 12-2-08)</history></law>