<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='2'>Chapter 17A VACANT STRUCTURES STANDARDS, MINIMUM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17A-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Inspection of vacant housing structures and vacant premises.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002603</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17A-8. Inspection of vacant housing structures and vacant premises.<section>The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall be authorized to make inspections to determine the condition of vacant commercial structures, vacant dwellings, vacant dwelling units, vacant rooming houses, vacant rooming units, vacant hotels, vacant hotel units, and vacant premises in order to safeguard the health, safety, morals and welfare of the public. The Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall be authorized to enter any vacant commercial structure, vacant dwelling, vacant dwelling unit, vacant rooming house, vacant rooming unit, vacant hotel, vacant hotel unit or vacant premises at any reasonable time, or at such other time as may be necessary in an emergency, for the purpose of performing the duties of such office under this chapter, in accordance with the procedures herein prescribed. Except in emergencies endangering the public health, safety and welfare, the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer and enforcing officers shall enter a vacant commercial structure, vacant dwelling, vacant dwelling unit, vacant rooming house, vacant rooming unit, vacant hotel, vacant hotel unit, or vacant premises only upon the prior consent of the owner, operator or the person having legal right of possession thereof, or in accordance with the provisions of this section. When the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or any enforcing officer has reason to believe that any vacant commercial structure, vacant dwelling, vacant dwelling unit, vacant rooming house, vacant rooming unit, vacant hotel, vacant hotel unit or vacant premises is in violation of the provisions of this chapter, or when such officer deems it necessary to make an inspection to determine whether a vacant structure or vacant premises is in violation of the standards established by this chapter, such officer shall request permission to make an inspection from the owner or operator thereof or from the person having the legal right of possession thereof. In the event that such person refuses to consent to the inspection the Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer or enforcing officer may apply to the County Court or Circuit Court for the issuance of an inspection warrant to be served by an officer duly authorized by law to serve inspection warrants and make arrests for violations of this chapter. The inspection warrant shall issue in accordance with the requirements of law, including Florida Statutes, Sections 933.20—933.30, and shall authorize entry into and inspection of the premises described therein. Refusal to permit an inspection pursuant to an inspection warrant authorized by this section shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shall subject the violator to the penalties prescribed herein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-65, § 1, 6-17-80; Ord. No. 86-47, § 2, 6-17-86; Ord. No. 95-228, § 1, 12-19-95)</history></law>