<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00033' order_by='00033' level='2'>Chapter 17B METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY DEMOLITION OF UNINHABITABLE STRUCTURES ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17B-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative findings and intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002619</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17B-2. Legislative findings and intent.<section>The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby finds and declares that in recent years and at present an increased number of uninhabitable structures exist, the maintenance of which is often neglected by the owners thereof. It is furthermore found and declared by this Board that said structures often become open, unsecured, vandalized, or used for illicit purposes by trespassers, resulting in conditions that are unhealthy, unsafe, unsightly, and a blight upon the neighborhood and community at large, and that the demolition of uninhabitable structures will improve the security and quality of life in general of persons living nearby, will prevent blight and decay, and will safeguard the public health, safety, morals and welfare. In particular, and without prejudice to the above findings, it is found and declared by the Board that said structures are often used for the distribution and consumption of narcotics and other controlled substances thereby constituting a health and safety hazard to the public and community at large.</section><section>The intent and purpose of this chapter is to protect the health, safety, morals, and welfare of all the people of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, by establishing standards governing the demolition of certain structures; authorizing and establishing procedures for the demolition of the same and setting forth a procedure for the enforcement of this chapter by prohibiting human habitation in and ordering the demolition of structures found uninhabitable. This chapter is hereby declared to be remedial and essential to the public interest, and it is intended that this chapter be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes as stated above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-59, ยง 1, 7-5-88)</history></law>