<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00034' order_by='00034' level='2'>Chapter 17C METROPOLITAN DADE COUNTY DEMOLITION OF MOBILE HOMES AND REMOVAL OF DEBRIS FROM MOBILE HOME PARKS RENDERED UNINHABITABLE BY HURRICANE ANDREW AFTER ITS AFTERMATH</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17C-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002638</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17C-5. Definitions.<section>When used in this chapter the following terms shall have the meanings set forth below:<section prefix='(1)'>Mobile home means a moveable or portable detached single-family dwelling designed for and capable of being used for long-term occupancy, designed to be transported after fabrication on its own permanent chassis and wheels, arriving at the site substantially complete,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Mobile home park means a place set aside and offered by a person or public body, for either direct or indirect remuneration of the owner, lessor, or operator of such place, for the parking or accommodation of mobile homes utilized for sleeping or eating,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Uninhabitable mobile home park means those mobile home parks which meet the criteria set forth in Section 17C-13</section><section prefix='(4)'>Owner means the taxpayer with respect to the real property concerned as reflected in the most recently certified real property ad valorem tax roll of Metropolitan Dade County; provided however, where the records of the Dade County Property Appraiser indicate that ownership of the property has changed, the owner shall be the taxpayer as reflected by such records.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Minimum Housing Enforcement Officer means any employee of the enforcement agency charged with the responsibility of making inspections of mobile home and trailer parks damaged by Hurricane Andrew and premises and issuing orders when necessary to effectuate the provisions of this chapter.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-90, ยง 1, 9-2-92)</history></law>