<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00034' order_by='00034' level='2'>Chapter 17C METROPOLITAN DADE COUNTY DEMOLITION OF MOBILE HOMES AND REMOVAL OF DEBRIS FROM MOBILE HOME PARKS RENDERED UNINHABITABLE BY HURRICANE ANDREW AFTER ITS AFTERMATH</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17C-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Uninhabitable mobile home parks.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002646</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 17C-13. Uninhabitable mobile home parks.<section prefix='(1)'>Mobile home parks shall be uninhabitable when as a result of damage caused by Hurricane Andrew all or a substantial majority of the mobile homes located at such parks:<section prefix='(a)'>Are vacant, unguarded and open at doors, windows or roof,</section><section prefix='(b)'>Are open at windows, doors or roof,</section><section prefix='(c)'>There is unwarranted accumulation of debris or other combustible material therein or on the land or lot on which such mobile homes are or were situated.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The condition of the parks, or land or lot upon which the mobile homes are or were situated creates hazards with respect to means of egress and fire protection,</section><section prefix='(e)'>Have a falling away, hanging loose or loosening of any sidings, or other building material,</section><section prefix='(f)'>Have deterioration of their structural parts,</section><section prefix='(g)'>Are practically or fully destroyed,</section><section prefix='(h)'>Have an unusual sagging or leaning out of plumb which is caused by deterioration or over-stressing,</section><section prefix='(i)'>Have electrical or mechanical installations or systems create a hazardous condition,</section><section prefix='(j)'>Have an unsanitary condition by reasons of inadequate or malfunctioning sanitary facilities or waste disposal systems, or</section><section prefix='(k)'>Have a condition which creates, allows or threatens to generate widespread or epidemic health or safety hazards.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>All mobile homes located in a mobile home park which park has been found to be uninhabitable as provided herein shall be subject to demolition and the debris removed therefrom.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-90, ยง 1, 9-2-92)</history></law>