<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='2'>Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Sewer service charges—Establishing, collecting, disposition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002659</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18-12. Sewer service charges—Establishing, collecting, disposition.<section>In the case of any district created and established under the provisions of this article for acquiring, constructing, reconstructing or installing a sewerage system, the Board shall fix rates, fees and other charges (herein called sewer service charges) for the use of and for the services and facilities furnished or to be furnished by, such system, to be paid by the owner, tenant or occupant of each lot or parcel of land which may be connected with such system. The Board may revise such sewer service charges from time to time. Such sewer service charges shall be so fixed and revised as to provide funds sufficient at all times:<section prefix='(a)'>To pay the cost of maintaining, repairing and operating such system, including the amount required under any contract for the acceptance of sewage for treatment and disposal, and to create reserves for such purposes, and to provide for renewals and replacements.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To pay such portion of the amount required in each year for paying the principal of and the interest on bonds issued on account of such system and to provide for such reserves therefor as the Board may deem equitable. The Board shall charge and collect the sewer service charges so fixed or revised, and such sewer service charges shall not be subject to supervision or regulation by any commission, Board, bureau or agency of the state.<section>Any such sewer service charges shall be just and equitable, and may be based or computed either upon the quantity of water used or upon the number and size of sewer connections or upon the number and kind of plumbing fixtures in use in the premises connected with such system or upon the number or average number of persons residing or working or otherwise connected with such premises or upon the type or character of such premises or upon any other factor affecting the use of the sewerage system or upon any combination of the foregoing factors.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-7, § 13, 2-9-60; Ord. No. 64-26, § 1, 7-7-64)</history></law>