<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='2'>Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Manufacturing or industrial plants; connections to sanitary sewer system; shutting off water for nonpayment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002660</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18-13. Same—Manufacturing or industrial plants; connections to sanitary sewer system; shutting off water for nonpayment.<section>In cases where the character of the sewage from any manufacturing or industrial plant, building or premises is such that it imposes an unreasonable burden upon the sewerage system, an additional charge may be made therefor, or the Board may, if it deems it advisable, compel such manufacturing or industrial plant, building or premises to treat such sewage in such manner as shall be specified by the Board before discharging such sewage into such system.</section><section>The owner, tenant or occupant of each lot or parcel of land within the district served or to be served by a sanitary sewer and upon which lot or parcel a building shall have been constructed for residential, commercial or industrial use, shall, if so required by the rules and regulations of the Board, connect such building with such sanitary sewer, and shall cease to use any other method for the disposal of sewage, sewage waste or other polluting matter. All such connections shall be made in accordance with rules and regulations which shall be adopted from time to time by the Board, which rules and regulations may provide for a charge for making any such connection in such reasonable amount as the Board may fix and establish.</section><section>The Board may adopt such rules and regulations as it may deem necessary to enforce the collection of any such sewer service charges, including (but without limitation) provisions for shutting off the supply of water, for making deposits in advance to secure the payment of such sewer service charges, and for disconnecting premises from the sanitary sewers.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-7, § 13, 2-9-60; Ord. No. 64-26, § 1, 7-7-64)</history></law>