<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='2'>Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18-21</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional method for financing local improvements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002670</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18-21. Additional method for financing local improvements.<section>The Board is hereby authorized and empowered to construct or acquire local improvements, as defined in of this article and to levy and collect special assessments upon property specially benefited by such local improvements, in accordance with the provisions of, as heretofore or hereafter amended, insofar as the same may be applicable, without the necessity of creating and establishing under the provisions of this article a special taxing district embracing the territory specially benefited by each such local improvement. Such construction or acquisition shall be authorized by ordinance adopted by the Board which shall set forth the location of the local improvement and a description thereof by its material, nature, character and size, a general description of the territory within which special assessments are to be levied, the estimated cost of the improvement, and also the part of such cost that is to be specially assessed, and shall fix the place, date and hour for a public hearing on the confirmation of such ordinance. Copies of such ordinance shall be published, posted and mailed in the manner provided by subdivision (d) of of this article. At the time and place stated in such ordinance, or to which an adjournment may be taken by the Board, the Board shall receive and hear objections of interested persons to the construction or acquisition of the local improvement, or to the levy of special assessments therefor, or to any defect in the proceedings or which question any of the powers of the Board under this section, and the Board may then or thereafter confirm such ordinance with such modifications, if any, as it may deem advisable and which do not enlarge the local improvement or the territory to be specially assessed, or increase the part of the cost thereof which is to be specially assessed.</section><section>The cost of any local improvement constructed or acquired under the provisions of this section may be paid from the special fund which is hereby created and designated "Miami-Dade County Capital Improvement Fund," to the credit of which there may be deposited such amounts as may be appropriated by the Board from time to time. If such cost shall be paid from said fund, the proceeds of all special assessments levied on account of the construction or acquisition of such local improvement shall be deposited to the credit of said fund.</section><section>The Board is further authorized and empowered to issue revenue bonds of the County to pay all or a part of the cost of any project, and to levy and collect special assessments upon property specially benefited by such project in accordance with the provisions of said, as heretofore or hereafter amended, insofar as the same may be applicable, without the necessity of creating and establishing under the provisions of this article a special taxing district embracing the territory specially benefited by such project, and to pledge to the payment of such bonds, in addition to the pledge of revenues, the proceeds of such special assessments.</section><section>In the case of any water system improvement or sewerage system improvement the Board may enter into a contract with a municipality or a private water or sewer company whereby (a) the municipality or private water or sewer company will construct the improvement and pay the entire cost thereof, will fix and collect rates and charges for water furnished by the water system, or sewage services furnished by the sewerage system and will pay the cost of maintaining, repairing and operating the same as provided by contract with the County, (b) title to the water system or sewerage system, as the case may be, shall vest in said municipality or private water or sewer company, and (c) the Board shall pay over to the municipality all or a part of the proceeds of all such special assessments as collected.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-26, ยง 1, 7-7-64; Ord. No. 83-114, ยง 1, 12-6-83)</history></law>