<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='2'>Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Purposes for which districts created.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002649</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18-2. Purposes for which districts created.<section>Special taxing districts may be created and established in Miami-Dade County, Florida, under the provisions of this article for the purpose of acquiring, constructing, reconstructing and installing any of the following public improvements or of providing any of the following special services within such districts:<section prefix='(a)'>Water systems,</section><section prefix='(b)'>Sewerage systems,</section><section prefix='(c)'>Storm sewers,</section><section prefix='(d)'>Street improvements,</section><section prefix='(e)'>Sidewalk improvements,</section><section prefix='(f)'>Police and fire protection,</section><section prefix='(g)'>Recreation facilities,</section><section prefix='(h)'>Street lighting,</section><section prefix='(i)'>Incinerators,</section><section prefix='(j)'>Beach erosion control, and</section><section prefix='(k)'>Such other facilities or services which may be deemed essential by the Board.</section></section><section>Any such special taxing district may embrace not only an unincorporated area in the County but also all or a part of one (1) or more municipalities in the County; provided however, that no such district shall be comprised solely of a municipality or embrace all or a part of a municipality without the approval of the governing body of such municipality. It is the intent of this article to provide for the construction and the financing of public improvements and of providing services in areas in the County where such improvements and services could not conveniently be made available otherwise, that the cost of such improvements and services be borne on an equitable basis by those who receive the benefits thereof, and that property receiving special benefits be assessed in proportion to but not in excess of such special benefits.</section><section>Special taxing districts may be created and established for the purpose of providing street lighting in new subdivisions developed in the unincorporated areas of the County. The creation and establishment of such districts in new subdivisions shall be in accordance with the procedures hereinafter set forth, except that the petitions for the creation and establishment of such districts shall be signed by the owners of all property within the proposed district and by all persons, firms or corporations having any right, title or interest in and to the property involved, including mortgagees and other lien holders. The owners of the property embraced within the proposed district shall guarantee payment of all costs and expenses incident to the creation of such district and shall pay the entire cost of providing street lighting within the district for the first year. Such owners shall execute and file an appropriate surety bond in the form prescribed or approved by the County, providing for payment of the cost of creating the district and providing street lighting for the first year.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-7, ยง 2, 2-9-60; Ord. No. 62-47, ยง 1, 12-4-62; Ord. No. 64-26, ยง 1, 7-7-64)</history></law>