<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='2'>Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SAFE NEIGHBORHOOD IMPROVEMENT DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18-41</section_number>
<catch_line>Safe Neighborhood Improvement Districts; definition; methods of creation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002687</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18-41. Safe Neighborhood Improvement Districts; definition; methods of creation.<section prefix='(a)'>Safe Neighborhood Improvement District means a district located in an area in which more than fifty (50) percent of the land is used for residential purposes, or in an area in which more than fifty (50) percent of the land is used for commercial, office, business or industrial purposes and where there is a plan to reduce crime through the implementation of crime prevention through environmental design, environmental security or defensible space techniques.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Such a district may be created by one (1) or more of the following methods:<section prefix='(1)'>Local Government Neighborhood Improvement District. The Board may create a Local Government Neighborhood Improvement District by the enactment of a separate ordinance for each district as provided by Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Property Owner's Association Neighborhood Improvement District.<section prefix='a.'>The Board may create a Property Owners' Association Neighborhood Improvement District by enacting a separate ordinance for each district as provided by Florida Statutes;</section><section prefix='b.'>An incorporated property owners' association representing seventy-five (75) percent of all owners of property within a proposed district meeting all statutory requirements may petition the Miami-Dade County Board for the creation of a Property Owners' Neighborhood Improvement District as provided by Florida Statutes for the area encompassed by the property owner by members of the association.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Special Neighborhood Improvement District. The Board may declare the need for and create a Special Neighborhood Residential or Business Improvement District by the enactment of a separate ordinance for each district as provided under Florida Statutes.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-39, ยง 2, 5-3-88)</history></law>