<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='2'>Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Bonds—Power to issue; limitations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002652</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18-5. Bonds—Power to issue; limitations.<section>To provide funds for paying the cost of the project for which a district shall have been created under the provisions of this article, or the cost of any extensions, enlargements or improvement of the project, bonds of such district may be issued as hereinafter provided in an amount, including any bonds then outstanding, not exceeding twenty-five (25) percentum of the assessed valuation of all property within the district (including homesteads) as shown by the last preceding assessment roll of the County. But no such bonds shall be issued unless the issuance of such bonds shall have been approved by a majority of the votes cast in an election in which a majority of the qualified electors residing in such district shall participate. Such election shall be called, noticed and conducted and the result thereof determined and declared in the manner required by law for the issuance of bonds of the County. The question submitted at such elections shall be substantially in the following form:</section><section>"Shall bonds of (here insert the name or designation of the District) in an aggregate principal amount not exceeding $ be issued for the purpose of such bonds to bear interest at a rate not exceeding the maximum rate permitted by law, to be issued at one (1) time or from time to time in series and to mature, or the bonds of each series to mature, in annual installments, beginning not more than five (5) years and ending not more than thirty (30) years after the date of the bonds, both the principal and interest of such bonds to be payable from taxes if and to the extent that special assessments and revenues shall be insufficient for such purpose"?</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-7, § 6, 2-9-60; Ord. No. 64-26, § 1, 7-7-64; Ord. No. 70-47, § 1, 6-9-70)</history></law>