<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='2'>Chapter 18 IMPROVEMENT AND SPECIAL-PURPOSE DISTRICTS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Issuance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002653</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18-6. Same—Issuance.<section>If a majority of the qualified electors residing in the district shall participate in such election and if a majority of the votes cast at such election shall approve the issuance of such bonds, the Board may provide by ordinance at one (1) time or from time to time for the issuance of such bonds. The bonds of each series shall be dated, shall bear interest at such rate or rates not exceeding the maximum rate permitted by law, shall mature in annual installments, the first installment to be made payable not more than five (5) years and the last installment not more than thirty (30) years from the date of the bonds, as may be determined by the Board, and may be made redeemable before maturity, at the option of the Board, at such price or prices and under such terms and conditions as may be fixed by the Board prior to the issuance of the bonds. The Board shall determine the form and the manner of execution of the bonds, including any interest coupons to be attached thereto, and shall fix the denomination or denominations of the bonds and the place or places of payment of principal and interest, which may be at any bank or trust company within or without the state.</section><section>In case any officer whose signature or a facsimile of whose signature shall appear on any bonds or coupons shall cease to be such officer before the delivery of the bonds, such signature or such facsimile shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if he/she had remained in office until such delivery, and any bond may bear the facsimile signature of, or may be signed by, such person or persons as at the actual time of execution of such bond shall be the proper officer or officers to sign such bond although at the date of such bond such person or persons may not have been such officer or officers. All bonds issued under the provisions of this article are hereby declared to have all the qualities and incidents of negotiable instruments under the negotiable instruments law of the State. The bonds may be issued in coupon or in registered form, or both, as the Board may determine, and provision may be made for the registration of any coupon bonds as to principal alone and also as to both principal and interest, for the reconversion into coupon bonds of any bonds registered as to both principal and interest, and for the interchange of registered and coupon bonds. The Board may sell such bonds in such manner, either at public or private sale, and for such price, as it may determine to be for the best interests of the district but no such sale shall be made at a price less than ninety-seven (97) percentum of the principal amount of the bonds.</section><section>Prior to the preparation of definitive bonds, the Board may, under like restrictions, issue interim receipts or temporary bonds, with or without coupons, exchangeable for definitive bonds when such bonds shall have been executed and are available for delivery. The Board may also provide for the replacement of any bonds which shall become mutilated or shall be destroyed or lost.</section><section>The issuance of such bonds shall not be subject to any limitations or conditions contained in any other law, and bonds may be issued under the provisions of this article without obtaining the consent of any commission, Board, bureau or agency of the State or of any municipality, and without any other proceedings or the happening of any other conditions or things than those proceedings, conditions or things which are specifically required by this article.</section><section>The proceeds of the bonds shall be used solely for the payment of the cost of the project for which such bonds shall have been authorized and shall be disbursed in the manner provided by the ordinance authorizing the issuance of such bonds. If the proceeds of the bonds of any issue shall exceed the amount required for the purpose for which such bonds shall have been issued, the surplus shall be set aside and used only for paying the principal of and the interest on such bonds. In the event that the actual cost of the project exceeds the estimated cost, the Board may issue additional bonds to cover the deficiency, subject to the same restrictions as contained herein for the original issue of bonds.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-7, § 7, 2-9-60; Ord. No. 64-26, § 1, 7-7-64; Ord. No. 70-47, § 2, 6-9-70)</history></law>