<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00036' order_by='00036' level='2'>Chapter 18A MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LANDSCAPING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18A-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Committee of landscape adjustment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002696</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18A-9. Committee of landscape adjustment.<section prefix='(A)'>In unincorporated Miami-Dade County, the members of the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee or their designees shall constitute the Committee of Landscape Adjustment.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The Committee of Landscape Adjustment, upon receipt of an application for adjustment of landscaping requirements shall have the authority and duty to consider and act upon such application. The application shall be filed on forms prescribed by the County, executed and sworn to by the owner or tenant of the property concerned or by authorized agents as evidenced by written power of attorney, and accompanied by a fee for processing of the application, as provided by Administrative Order.</section><section prefix='(C)'>In the application, the applicant shall state clearly and in detail what adjustment of landscaping requirements are being requested and the reasons such adjustments are warranted, and shall accompany the application with such supplementary data, such as sketches, surveys and statistical information as is deemed necessary to substantiate the adjustment.</section><section prefix='(D)'>The Committee of Landscape Adjustment may approve, modify or deny the requested adjustment, but shall approve or modify such request only if it determines that approval of any adjustment would not be contrary to the public interest and would be in keeping with and would preserve the intent of this chapter. The Committee of Landscape Adjustment shall not consider requests for variance from the requirements of Chapter 24, the Miami-Dade County Environmental Protection Code, including specimen tree and natural forest community variance requests. Any such requests shall be made according to the provisions of Sections 24-48 and 24-49 of the Code. Additionally, the Committee of Landscape Adjustment shall not have authority to modify or adjust any part of Chapter 33 of the Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Committee of Landscape Adjustment shall meet on a regular basis to act on pending application(s), and shall post their decision in the form of a short, concise statement of the action taken on a conspicuous bulletin board that may be seen by the public at reasonable times and hours in the office of the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Within fourteen (14) days after posting of decision, but not thereafter, any decision of the Committee of Landscape Adjustment may be appealed to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board as prescribed in Chapter 33 for appeals of administrative decisions; otherwise, it shall become final.</section><section prefix='(G)'>The Community Zoning Appeals Boards or the Board of County Commissioners shall have the authority to grant adjustment from this chapter as part of a zoning application.</section><section prefix='(H)'>Each municipality may establish or assign an existing board, committee, or other similar body to review adjustments and to establish criteria for landscape adjustment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-222, ยง 2, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 97-16, ยง 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 98-13, ยง 1, 1-13-98; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 36, 9-3-98)</history></law>