<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00036' order_by='00036' level='2'>Chapter 18A MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LANDSCAPING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18A-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Short title and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002688</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18A-1. Short title and applicability.<section prefix='(A)'>[Title.] This chapter shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Landscape Ordinance".</section><section prefix='(B)'>Applicability.<section prefix='(1)'>This chapter shall be a minimum standard and shall apply to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas, and in the unincorporated area shall be enforced by the County and in the incorporated areas shall be enforced by the municipalities; provided, any municipality may establish and enforce more stringent regulations as such municipality may deem necessary; and in the event the provisions hereof are not enforced within any municipality, the County shall enforce same.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The provisions of this chapter shall be considered minimum standards and shall apply to all public and private development when a permit is required, except for the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Existing attached and detached single family and duplex dwellings, including any future additions or expansions shall be exempt from the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Bonafide agricultural activities. Any property receiving an agricultural classification and assessment pursuant to Section 193.461 Florida Statutes, substantiated by a plan submitted indicating the area with the agricultural classification.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Except as provided for in Section 33-284.63(A) of this Code, development within the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District pursuant to Article XXXIII(I) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida shall be exempt from the provisions of this chapter.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Existing development as defined in Section 18A-3(O) shall only be required to comply with the street tree requirements of Section 18A-6(C)(2) and parking lot buffers of Section 18A-6(I). This requirement shall not apply to existing attached and detached single family and duplex dwellings pursuant to subsection (2)(a) above. Parking lot buffer will not be required if inadequate area exists which will cause the elimination of any required parking pursuant to County or municipal code. The provisions of this subsection shall only apply where a building permit is required for external alterations or where a paving permit is required for expansion of parking areas. Routine maintenance such as re-roofing and painting shall not be considered external alterations.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-222, ยง 2, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-13, ยง 1, 1-13-98; Ord. No. 99-166, ยง 3, 12-16-99)</history></law>