<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00036' order_by='00036' level='2'>Chapter 18A MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LANDSCAPING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18A-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002690</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18A-3. Definitions.<section>The definitions contained in Chapters 24 and, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this chapter except as otherwise changed herein:</section><section>The maximum width of an accessway through the perimeter landscaped strip to an off-street parking or other vehicular use area shall be determined according to the Public Works Manual, Part I, Standard Details. No more than one (1) two-way accessway shall be permitted or any street frontage up to one hundred (100) lineal feet or no more than two (2) one-way accessways shall be permitted for any street frontage up to one hundred (100) lineal feet, such standards to be applicable to any property under one (1) ownership. Where such ownership involves over one hundred (100) feet of street frontage, one (1) additional two-way or two (2) additional one-way drives may be permitted for each additional one hundred (100) feet of frontage or major fraction thereof. The balance of such street frontage not involved with access ways shall be landscaped in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section>Industry-developed standards of practice for tree care. Acronym for American National Standards Institute.</section><section>An irrigation system with a programmable controller or timing mechanism.</section><section>Land used for the growing of food crops, nurseries for the growing of landscape material, the raising of livestock, horse farms, and other good faith agricultural uses, except any portion of the property not eligible for agricultural exemption.</section><section>An area of land which is set aside along the perimeter of a parcel of land in which landscaping is required to provide an aesthetic transition between different land uses and to eliminate or reduce the adverse environmental impact, and incompatible land use impacts.</section><section>For trees under four (4) inches in diameter, the trunk diameter measured at a height of six (6) inches above natural grade. For trees four (4) inches and greater in diameter, the trunk diameter measured at twelve (12) inches above natural grade.</section><section>Pruning required to avoid damage or danger related to structures, power distribution and property, as defined in the current ANSI A300 Standards.</section><section>A roof or building structure, extending over the sidewalk, open to the street and sidewalk, except for supporting columns or piers.</section><section>Area required as open space under or municipal codes for various zoning districts.</section><section>Those plant species listed in the Landscape Manual which tend to become nuisances because of their ability to invade proximal native plant communities or native habitats, but which, if located and cultivated properly may be useful or functional as elements of landscape design.</section><section>Diameter of a tree's trunk measured at a height four and one-half (4.5) feet above natural grade. In the case of multiple-trunk trees, the DBH shall mean the sum of each trunk's diameter measured at a height of four and one-half (4.5) feet above natural grade.</section><section>A method of scheduling an irrigation system to apply different quantities of water, and/or apply water at different frequencies as appropriate, for different hydrozones.</section><section>Proximate or directly associated land uses which are contradictory, incongruous, or discordant such as higher intensity residential, commercial or industrial uses located adjacent to lower intensity uses.</section><section>An imaginary vertical line extending from the outermost horizontal circumference of a tree's branches to the ground.</section><section>A residence building designed for, or used as the separate homes or residences of two (2) separate and distinct families, but having the appearance of a single family dwelling house. Each individual unit in the duplex shall comply with the definition for a one-family dwelling.</section><section>Devices which are used to control the discharge of irrigation water from lateral pipes.</section><section>Shall mean a site with structures that were legally approved through the issuance of a certificate of use and occupancy or a certificate of completion as of the effective date of this chapter.</section><section>A zone located no more than twenty-two (22) feet from a structure in a one hundred eighty (180) degree band from due east of the northeast point of the structure, to due south, to due west of the northwest point of the structure.</section><section>Lands that contain natural forest, wetland or native plant communities, rare and endangered plants and animals, endemic species, endangered species habitat, a diversity of species, outstanding geologic or other natural features, or land which functions as an integral and sustaining component of an existing ecosystem.</section><section>Plants with a similar likelihood of occurring in both wetlands and uplands, which are not recognized indicators of either wetland or upland conditions.</section><section>Practices, materials or actions developed by the Florida Yards and Neighborhood Program that help to preserve Florida's natural resources and protect the environment.</section><section>Is a partnership of the University of Florida/Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences, Florida's water management districts, the Florida Department of Environmental Protection, the National Estuary Program, the Florida Sea Grant College Program and other agencies, managed locally by the Miami-Dade Cooperative Extension Division of the Consumer Services Department.</section><section>Herbaceous plants other than grasses.</section><section>A natural rock or mineral formation.</section><section>That portion of domestic sewage emanating from residential showers, residential baths, residential bathroom washbasins, or residential clothes washing machines.</section><section>A dense, extensive growth of low-growing plants, other than turfgrass, normally reaching an average maximum height of not more than twenty-four (24) inches at maturity.</section><section>To flat-cut the top of a tree, severing the leader or leaders, or the removal of any branch three (3) inches or greater in diameter at any point other than the branch collar.</section><section>The removal of dead, diseased, decayed, or obviously weak branches two (2) inches in diameter or greater.</section><section>An unnaturally high temperature microclimate resulting from radiation from unshaded impervious surfaces.</section><section>A landscape barrier consisting of a continuous, dense planting of shrubs, not necessarily of the same species.</section><section>A plant having little or no woody tissue.</section><section>A sprayed application of seed, mulch and water.</section><section>A zone in which plant material with similar water needs are grouped together.</section><section>Bark that is embedded in a crotch between a branch and trunk or between co-dominant stems, causing a weakened structure.</section><section>A graphic representation depicting the materials to be used and dimensions to be met in the installation of the irrigation system.</section><section>A plan drawn at the same scale as the landscape plan, indicating location and specification of irrigation system components and other relevant information as required by this chapter.</section><section>A system of pipes or other conduits designed to transport and distribute water to keep plants in a healthy and vigorous condition.</section><section>Trellis, arbor, fountain, pond, garden sculpture, garden lighting, decking, patio, decorative paving, gazebo, and other similar elements.</section><section>Plants such as grass, ground cover, forbs, shrubs, vines, hedges, trees and non-living material such as rocks, pebbles, sand, mulch, or pervious decorative paving materials.</section><section>A plan indicating all landscape areas, stormwater retention/detention areas, areas which qualify to be excluded from maximum permitted lawn area, existing vegetation to be retained, proposed plant material, landscape legend, landscape features, planting specifications, and details, and all other relevant information in compliance with this chapter.</section><section>An area planted with lawn grasses.</section><section>An irrigation system in which control valves and switches are manually operated rather than operated by automatic controls.</section><section>A mixture of land uses such as provided in Traditional Neighborhood Development (TND), Planned Area Development (PAD), and Planned Development (PD).</section><section>Devices which have the ability to switch off an automatic irrigation controller after receiving a predetermined amount of rainfall or moisture content in the soil.</section><section>Materials customarily used in landscape design to retard erosion, weed infestation, and retain moisture and for use in planting areas.</section><section>Any residential development other than attached or detached single-family or duplex.</section><section>Attached and detached single-family developments that are planned as a total project and not as a single family unit on a single lot.</section><section>An area enhanced or landscaped with an appropriate mix of native tree, shrub and groundcover species that resembles a native plant community or natural forest community in structure and composition or is naturally occurring.</section><section>Plant species with a geographic distribution indigenous to all or part of Miami-Dade County. Plants which are described as being native to Miami-Dade County in botanical manuals such as, but not limited to, "A Flora of Tropical Florida" by Long and Lakela, are native plant species within the meaning of this definition. Plant species which have been introduced into Miami-Dade County by man are not native plant species.</section><section>A natural association of plants dominated by one (1) or more prominent native plant species, or a characteristic physical attribute.</section><section>All assemblages of vegetation designated as Natural Forest Communities on the Miami-Dade County Natural Forest Community Maps and approved by the Board of County Commissioners, pursuant to Resolution No. R-1764-84 and further defined in of the Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section>For the purpose of this chapter, net lot area shall be the area within lot boundaries of all lands comprising the site. Net lot area shall not include any portion of the abutting dedicated streets, alleys, waterways, canals, lakes or any other such dedications.</section><section>A private residence building used or intended to be used as a home or residence in which all living rooms are accessible to each other from within the building and in which the use and management of all sleeping quarters, all appliances for sanitation, cooking, ventilating, heating or lighting are designated for the use of one (1) family only.</section><section>A high pressure, high volume irrigation system.</section><section>A graphic representation of the plant installation depicting the materials to be used and dimensions to be met in the placement of plants and other landscape materials.</section><section>Those plant species listed in the Miami-Dade Landscape Manual which are demonstrably detrimental to native plants, native wildlife, ecosystems, or human health, safety, and welfare.</section><section>A self-supporting woody perennial plant normally growing to a height of twenty-four (24) inches or greater, characterized by multiple stems and branches continuous from the base.</section><section>A comprehensive plan drawn to scale indicating appropriate site elevations, roadways, and location of all relevant site improvements including structures, parking, other paved areas, ingress and egress drives, landscaped open space and signage.</section><section>A tree with any individual trunk which has a DBH of eighteen (18) inches or greater, but not including the following:<section prefix='(1)'>All trees listed in Section 24-49(4)(f);</section><section prefix='(2)'>Non-native fruit trees that are cultivated or grown for the specific purpose of producing edible fruit, including, but not limited to, mangos, avocados, or species of citrus;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Non-native species of the genus Ficus, and</section><section prefix='(4)'>All multitrunk trees in the palm family, except Acoelorrhaphe wrightii and Phoenix reclinata which have a minimum overall height of fifteen (15) feet.</section></section><section>An irrigation device which applies water to the soil or plant surface by fixed spray or mist nozzles.</section><section>a sprinkler head that provides aboveground or overhead irrigation.</section><section>An area of ground underlain with structural support in the form of grass pavers or stabilized soil prepared to withstand the load of intended vehicular use, such as automobiles, fire trucks and garbage trucks.</section><section>An area designed, built and used for temporary storage of stormwater. For purposes of this chapter, these areas are intended to be permanently exempt from wetland regulations.</section><section>A greenprint for Miami-Dade County as adopted by the Board of County Commissioners on March 6, 2007 as may be amended from time to time.</section><section>Tree abuse shall include:<section prefix='(1)'>Damage inflicted upon any part of a tree, including the root system, by machinery, construction equipment, cambium layer penetration, storage of materials, soil compaction, excavation, chemical application or spillage, or change to the natural grade.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hatracking.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Girdling or bark removal of more than one-third () of the tree diameter.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Tears and splitting of limb ends or peeling and stripping of bark resulting from improper pruning techniques not in accordance with the current ANSI A300 Standards.</section></section><section>The aerial extent of the branches and foliage of a tree as defined by the drip line.</section><section>A system including surface distribution elements (hose, pipe, etc.) which may be easily removed when landscape is established.</section><section>The complex of woody, fibrous, herbaceous and graminoid plant species that are typically associated with a natural forest community, native plant community, or native habitat.</section><section>Portions of a site, including but not limited to specimen trees, natural forest communities and native vegetation which are clearly delineated on site plans, plats, or recorded restrictions, or in some other legally binding manner that are to be protected from any tree or understory removal or effective destruction and maintained without any development.</section><section>A drawing provided at the same scale as the landscape plan which includes relevant information as required by this chapter.</section><section>A hard surface area designed or used for off-street parking and/or an area used for loading, circulation, access, storage, including fire trucks, garbage trucks, or display of motor vehicles.</section><section>A plant with a flexible stem which normally requires support to reach mature form.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-222, ยง 2, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-13, ยง 1, 1-13-98; Ord. No. 09-35, ยง 2, 5-5-09)</history></law>