<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00036' order_by='00036' level='2'>Chapter 18A MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LANDSCAPING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18A-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Preparer's certification of landscape compliance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002695</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18A-8. Preparer's certification of landscape compliance.<section prefix='(A)'>A preparer's Certification of Landscape Compliance bearing the original letterhead of the designing firm and licensing number shall be submitted to and approved by the Department of Planning and Zoning prior to issuance of any final Certificate of Use and Occupancy or Certificate of Completion. The preparer's Certification of Landscape Compliance shall contain a statement, signed and sealed by the landscape architect or by person(s) authorized to prepare plans by Chapter 481, Florida Statutes, who prepared the approved plans, that the landscape and irrigation plans have been implemented and that all requirements of this chapter have been met. Any changes or substitutions to the approved plan shall be approved by the original designing firm prior to the implementation of said changes and substitutions. All changes or substitutions to the approved plan shall be noted on all copies. Changes and substitutions of plant material shall be of similar quality, quantity and size, as originally approved and shall be in compliance with the intent and requirements of his chapter.</section><section prefix='(B)'>For a new single-family, duplex residence on its own lot or applicable existing development, the owner or owner's agent may certify in writing that landscape and irrigation have been installed according to approved plan(s).</section><section prefix='(C)'>The Department of Planning and Zoning shall have the right to inspect all projects for compliance prior to issuance of a Certificate of Use and Occupancy or Certificate of Completion.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Municipalities are not required to establish a Preparer's Certification of Landscape Compliance procedure.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-222, ยง 2, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-13, ยง 1, 1-13-98; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 36, 9-3-98)</history></law>