<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00037' order_by='00037' level='2'>Chapter 18B MIAMI-DADE COUNTY RIGHT-OF-WAY LANDSCAPE ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>18B-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose and intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002704</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 18B-2. Purpose and intent.<section>It is the intent of this chapter to establish minimum landscape standards for public rights-of-way in incorporated and unincorporated Miami-Dade County that enhance, improve and maintain the quality of the landscape, and to:<section prefix='(A)'>Promote Florida friendly principles through the use of drought-tolerant landscape species, grouping of plant material by water requirements, the use of irrigation systems that conserve the use of potable and nonpotable water supplies and restrictions on the amount of lawn areas.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Use landscape material, specifically street trees, to visually define the hierarchy of roadways, and to provide shade and a visual edge along roadways.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Prevent the destruction of the community's existing tree canopy and promote its expansion.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Provide for the preservation of existing natural forest communities and specimen sized trees in conformance with Section 24-49, as may be amended from time to time; re-establish native habitat where appropriate, and encourage the appropriate use of native plant material in the landscape.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Promote the use of trees and shrubs for energy conservation by encouraging cooling through the provision of shade and the channeling of breezes, thereby helping to offset global warming and local heat island effects through the added absorption of carbon dioxide and reduction of heat islands.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Contribute to the processes of air movement, air purification, oxygen regeneration, ground water recharge, and retention of stormwater runoff, as well as aiding in the abatement of noise, glare, heat, air pollution and dust generated by major roadways and intense use areas.</section><section prefix='(G)'>Reduce the negative impacts of exotic pest plant species and prohibit the use of noxious exotic plants which invade native plant communities.</section><section prefix='(H)'>Promote the use of trees to protect and buffer the effects of high winds on structures.</section><section prefix='(I)'>Promote the concept of planting the right tree or plant in the right place to avoid problems such as clogged sewers, cracked sidewalk and power services interruptions.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-36, ยง 1, 5-5-09)</history></law>