<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='2'>Chapter 19 RESPONSIBLE PROPERTY OWNER AND MERCHANT ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Maintenance Standards for Lots in Non-Residential Zoned Districts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002730</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19-14. Maintenance Standards for Lots in Non-Residential Zoned Districts.<section prefix='(A)'>It shall be the responsibility of the responsible party for any lot in a nonresidential zoned district to regularly maintain their property to prevent the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The growth or accumulation of any grass, weeds, non-native undergrowth or other dead plant life that exceeds the height of eighteen (18) inches from the ground for more than fifty (50) percent of the area to be maintained;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Storage or maintenance of junk, trash, abandoned property or solid waste on any lot.</section></section><section>All lots shall be maintained within one hundred (100) feet from the boundary line of any property with a building or structure or within one hundred (100) feet from the boundary line of any improved road. In the event that the remaining area constitutes less than twenty-five (25) percent of the total square footage of the lot, then the entire lot shall require maintenance action.</section><section prefix='(B)'>It shall be the responsibility of the responsible party for the property adjacent to a County right-of-way and in a non-residential zoned district to maintain the swale area which abuts their property.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Agricultural zoned property. When concerns or complaints are raised about agricultural properties, a compliance officer shall investigate. The Department shall apply the definition in Section 19-3(B) to determine a bonafide agricultural use. If the concern or complaint is deemed to be valid, a notice of evaluation shall be issued to the property owner or lessee. The property owner or lessee shall be given thirty (30) days from the date of such notice to correct the use or practice. If clarification of the use or practice is needed, an appropriate agricultural agency shall be consulted for information. If the property owner or lessee fails to correct the condition, enforcement action shall commence to require compliance with this code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-160, §§ 1, 2, 7-8-03; Ord. No. 08-134, § 8, 12-2-08)</history></law>