<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='2'>Chapter 19 RESPONSIBLE PROPERTY OWNER AND MERCHANT ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19-15.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Bicycle Racks and Litter Containers; Anti-littering Signage and Right-of-way and Overall Cleanliness of premises; Compliance with Site Plan Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002736</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19-15.5. Bicycle Racks and Litter Containers; Anti-littering Signage and Right-of-way and Overall Cleanliness of premises; Compliance with Site Plan Requirements.<section prefix='(A)'>Bicycle racks and litter bins shall be installed and maintained in accordance with the approved site plan and Section 33-122.3 of Miami-Dade County Code. Notwithstanding the approved site plan, the property owner shall be responsible for placing and maintaining bicycle racks and litter bins as required by County Code. It shall be prohibited to maintain litter bins and trash receptacles with overflowing trash and litter.</section><section>The bicycle parking spaces shall be located near one of the principal entrances to the building. The bicycle parking spaces should be in a highly visible, well lighted location that provides enough clear space to facilitate easy use and does not impede pedestrian traffic or handicap accessibility and is protected from the weather by being located under roof overhangs and canopies. The parking spaces may not be placed on the County maintained right-of-way. The design of the bicycle rack should permit the locking of the frame and at least one (1) wheel with a standard size "U" lock and accommodate the typical range of bicycle sizes. The bicycle rack shall: resist removal; be constructed to resist rust, corrosion and vandalism; and be properly maintained. All bicycle parking spaces shall be posted with a permanent and properly maintained above-ground sign. The bottom of the sign shall be at least five (5) feet above grade when attached to a building or seven (7) feet above grade for a detached sign, which may not be installed in the County maintained right-of-way. No permit shall be required for such signs.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The property owner or lessee shall be required to maintain his or her property (parking lot, drive ways, sidewalks, and common areas), as well as abutting right-of-way areas free and clear of litter and articles. Abutting area shall be defined as the public right-of-way immediately abutting the premises. The area to be maintained shall be from the edge of pavement to the property line and shall include sidewalk areas and swales.</section><section prefix='(C)'>All shopping centers, strip malls, grocery stores, restaurants or commercial establishments that sell takeout beverages or food shall provide a litter container near every entrance and at every 100 feet along any established pedestrian walkway within the footprint of such property. Litter containers shall be well designed and secured in a manner that will cause them to remain stationary where placed. They shall be maintained free of graffiti and overflow trash. Placement of the containers shall not interfere with access to the facilities by pedestrians or by individuals with disabilities, as required by the Americans with Disabilities Act Accessibility Guidelines in the Code of Federal Regulation, Title 36, Pt. 1191, App. A. The civil penalty for a violation of this section is $100.</section><section prefix='(D)'>All establishments that sell merchandise or food for take out, shall post an anti-litter sign in a prominently visible location outside the establishment, as well as at all drive through lanes for restaurants and retail sales establishments. All signs required under this section shall be a minimum of 14" by 14" in size and shall state: "Littering is Prohibited by Law - Punishable by a Minimum Fine of $250 under Section 8CC-10 of the Code of Miami Dade County".</section><section prefix='(F)'>All establishments shall provide screening for service areas, including waste disposal areas, if required by Chapter 33 of this Code, and shall otherwise comply with the site plan approved pursuant to Sec. 33-245.2 of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-160, §§ 1, 2, 7-8-03; Ord. No. 04-90, § 7, 5-11-04)</history></law>