<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='2'>Chapter 19 RESPONSIBLE PROPERTY OWNER AND MERCHANT ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19-15.12</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibited Display of Vehicles for Sale or as Advertising Devices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002743</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19-15.12. Prohibited Display of Vehicles for Sale or as Advertising Devices.<section prefix='(A)'>No vehicle shall be displayed for sale in a business or commercial premise unless the parcel has a zoning certificate of use for the sale of new or used vehicles.</section><section prefix='(B)'>No vehicle, trailer, or other mobile article shall be allowed to be used solely as an advertising device in a parking lot or nearby right-of-way. Any vehicle, trailer or other mobile article that remains in the same parked location for more than 72 hours and that contains commercial advertising or that meets the junk criteria in this Chapter shall be a prima facie violation of this subsection.</section><section prefix='(C)'>All violations of this section shall be punishable by a civil violation notice in the amount of one hundred dollars ($100.00) for the first vehicle on a first offense and five hundred dollars ($500.00) per vehicle for each additional vehicle and any repeat violation of this section. The County may place a lien on the vehicle and any real property owned by the violator in Miami-Dade County until all fines, enforcement costs, and administrative costs are paid by the violator. Any vehicle in violation of this section shall be towed if not removed by the owner. Vehicle owners shall be responsible for all fines, towing fees, storage fees, and any administrative and enforcement fees that result from the enforcement of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-160, §§ 1, 2, 7-8-03; Ord. No. 04-90, § 8, 5-11-04)</history></law>