<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='2'>Chapter 19 RESPONSIBLE PROPERTY OWNER AND MERCHANT ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Maintenance of Lots in Residential-Zoned Districts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002729</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19-13. Maintenance of Lots in Residential-Zoned Districts.<section prefix='(A)'>In accordance with Section 19-14, it shall be the responsibility of the responsible party for any lot in a residential-zoned district that is within 330 feet of a residential structure to regularly maintain their property to prevent the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Storage or maintenance of junk, trash, abandoned property or solid waste on any lot;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The growth or accumulation of any grass, weeds, non-native undergrowth or other dead plant life that exceeds the height of twelve (12) inches from the ground for more than ten (10) percent of the area to be maintained;</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>It shall be the responsibility of the responsible party for property in a residential-zoned district and adjacent to a County right-of-way to maintain the swale area which abuts their property.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Agricultural use within residential districts. When concerns or complaints are raised about agricultural use properties, a compliance officer shall investigate. If the concern or complaint is deemed to be valid, a notice of evaluation shall be issued to the property owner or lessee. The property owner or lessee shall be given thirty (30) days from the date of such notice to correct the use or practice. If clarification of the use or practice is needed, an appropriate agricultural agency shall be consulted for information. If the property owner or lessee fails to correct the condition, enforcement action shall commence to require compliance with this code.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Open-air storage in residential-zoned districts is subject to the following provisions:<section prefix='(1)'>Open-air storage of the following materials is prohibited:<section prefix='(a)'>Junk, as defined in this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Merchandise or manufacturing materials. Evidence of one or more of the following shall create a rebuttable presumption that merchandise or manufacturing materials are being stored on the premises:<section prefix='(i)'>Multiple boxes of uniform appearance bearing shipping labels;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Multiple articles of similar type in unused condition, including without limitation raw materials for manufacturing furniture and computer components;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Pallets containing multiple boxes;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>The residential address is being used as a business address or business delivery address.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Commercial equipment, including without limitation vending machines.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Motor vehicle parts, including without limitation automobile engines and transmissions.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Household furniture, including without limitation sofas and recliners.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Construction materials, including without limitation lumber and cement blocks.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Construction and demolition equipment, including without limitation cement mixers, jack hammers, and roof tar pots, provided, however, that light-use equipment customarily used for do-it-yourself home repair, including without limitation hand tools, power tools, and table saws, shall not be prohibited.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Properties with bona fide agricultural uses shall be exempt from this subsection.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-160, §§ 1, 2, 7-8-03; Ord. No. 04-90, § 5, 5-11-04; Ord. No. 08-134, § 7, 12-2-08; Ord. No. 11-100, § 2, 12-6-11)</history></law>