<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='2'>Chapter 19 RESPONSIBLE PROPERTY OWNER AND MERCHANT ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Declaration of legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002708</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19-2. Declaration of legislative intent.<section>The Board finds and determines that the neglect of property by property owners and the rapid, continuous growth and urban development of the unincorporated areas of this County require the reasonable and effective control and regulation of excessive growth and accumulation of weeds, and other certain plant life to the extent and in such manner as to cause infestation by rodents and feral animals, the breeding of mosquitoes and vermin, or to threaten or endanger the public health, or otherwise adversely affect the welfare of adjacent property or occupants. Further, the Board finds and determines that the accumulation of garbage and trash in violation of, Miami-Dade County Code requires reasonable and effective controls to protect the public health, safety and welfare of the community. Further, the Board finds that the maintenance of exterior premises of all improved property serves a public purpose in keeping property operating in a safe, sanitary and litter-free manner to prevent neighborhood blight and the deterioration of neighborhood character which, if unchecked, would have deleterious effect on the quality of life and the economic vitality of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>That portion of any lot or parcel is exempt from the vegetative provisions of this chapter where that lot, or parcel is designated as a Natural Forest Community, Environmental Endangered Land, Native Plant Community, Native Habitat, or a wetland as defined and described in(151) of the Code of Miami-Dade County or is owned by a governmental agency or not for profit company and is held, owned or maintained as a natural area.</section><section>That portion of any lot or parcel that currently has a bona fide agricultural use or has been given a State exemption for Agricultural Classification following generally accepted agricultural and management practices shall be processed in accordance with Sections and of this Chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-160, §§ 1, 2, 7-8-03; Ord. No. 11-100, § 1, 12-6-11)</history></law>