<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='2'>Chapter 19 RESPONSIBLE PROPERTY OWNER AND MERCHANT ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Storing junk or trash; depositing junk; characteristics of junk property; application to all zoning districts; prohibition of junk yards in residential districts; prohibition on expansion of existing junkyards in nonresidential districts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002724</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19-8. Storing junk or trash; depositing junk; characteristics of junk property; application to all zoning districts; prohibition of junk yards in residential districts; prohibition on expansion of existing junkyards in nonresidential districts.<section prefix='(A)'>Notwithstanding the maintenance schedules in this chapter, it shall be unlawful to deposit, store, or maintain, or to permit to be deposited, stored, or maintained, junk as defined in Sec. 19.3(J) of this Code, in or on any lot, parcel or tract of land or body of water in any zoning district, except within a legally established junkyard. The deposit of junk in a location authorized for waste collection is exempted from this section, provided the junk is not or does not become a nuisance, and provided the junk is collected by Miami-Dade County or a County-authorized commercial waste collector.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Pursuant to Miami-Dade County Code Sec. 33-15, no junkyard shall be permitted in a residential district.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Junk property which would be visible, at ground level, from a street or other public or private property but for the concealment of such junk property behind a wall, fence, hedge or other plant material or by the use of a vehicle cover, plastics, fabrics or other materials to form a tent, curtain partition or similar makeshift structure or device, shall be subject to this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-160, §§ 1, 2, 7-8-03; Ord. No. 04-90, § 2, 5-11-04)</history></law>