<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00039' order_by='00039' level='2'>Chapter 19A MOBILE HOMES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19A-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002745</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19A-2. Definitions.<section>In construing the provisions of this chapter and each and every word, term, phrase, or part hereof where the context will permit the definitions provided in Section 320.01, Florida Statutes, and as otherwise provided herein shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>Recreational vehicle: Classed under "motor vehicle," a recreational vehicle-type unit primarily designed as temporary living quarters for recreational, camping or travel use, which either has its own motive power or is mounted on or is drawn by another vehicle.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Travel trailer: Classed under "motor vehicle," a vehicular portable unit, mounted on wheels, of such a size or weight as not to require special highway movement permits when drawn by a motorized vehicle. It is primarily designed and constructed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping or travel use. It is of a body width of no more than eight (8) feet and a body length of no more than thirty-two (32) feet when factory-equipped for the road.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Camping trailer: Classed under "motor vehicle," a vehicular portable unit mounted on wheels and constructed with collapsible partial sidewalls which fold for towing by another vehicle and unfold at the campsite to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Truck camper: Classed under "motor vehicle," a portable unit, designed to be loaded onto, or affixed to, the bed or chassis of a truck, constructed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Motor home: Classed under "motor vehicle," a vehicular unit built on a self-propelled motor vehicle chassis, primarily designed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping or travel use.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Mobile home: Not classed as a "motor vehicle," includes any type of trailer or vehicle body, regardless of any appurtenances, additions or other modifications thereto, without independent motive power, manufactured upon an integral chassis or undercarriage and designed either for travel over the highways or for housing accommodations or both.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Owner: Includes any person, firm, corporation, or association controlling any vehicle by right of purchase, gift, lease or otherwise.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Final certificate of completion: An instrument issued by the Building Official certifying that all final inspections required for mobile homes, and motor vehicles used as housing, have been completed in accordance with State and local codes and regulations and that occupancy is approved.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Mobile home or motor vehicle used as housing: A mobile home or motor vehicle used as a dwelling place and located on the same site for fourteen (14) or more continuous days.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Coastal General Flood Hazard District: Shall mean that a portion of Dade County comprised of those areas designated "A" upon the official flood hazard boundary map issued and approved by the Federal Insurance Administrator dated August 14, 1970, and No. 12-025-0000-01 through 56 and as the same may, from time to time, be amended by the Federal Insurance Administrator.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-1, ยง 1, 1-4-77)</history></law>