<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00039' order_by='00039' level='2'>Chapter 19A MOBILE HOMES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19A-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Florida Statutes and State regulations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002744</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19A-1. Florida Statutes and State regulations.<section prefix='(A)'>Florida Statutes. Pursuant to Chapter 320, as amended, the following mandatory regulations set forth the minimum standards applicable to mobile homes and motor vehicles, as defined herein, used as housing:<section prefix='(1)'>All construction in mobile homes manufactured more than six (6) months after July 11, 1967, and sold or offered for sale in the State of Florida, shall meet the provisions of the American National Standards Institute Standard ANSI A-119-1; including body and frame construction and the installation of plumbing, heating and electrical systems.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Such vehicles shall be inspected where they are manufactured by the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles and shall bear a seal assuring compliance with the Standard ANSI A-119-1, as well as with such rules and regulations said Department deems necessary for effective administration and enforcement.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Such vehicles shall also bear the certification by the manufacturer that the vehicle to which the seal is attached meets or exceeds the provisions of the Standard ANSI A-119-1, except, where a used mobile home originally sold out of the State of Florida is resold in Florida, the dealer shall provide the certification.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Where a used mobile home, manufactured prior to July 11, 1967, is sold in the State of Florida, the seller shall provide certification that the vehicle meets the standards in effect at the time the vehicle was manufactured.</section><section prefix='(5)'>(a)The owner of a mobile home shall secure it to the ground by the use of anchors and tie downs so as to resist wind overturning and sliding.<section prefix='(b)'>A mobile home manufactured in accordance with the Standard ANSI A-119-1 and labeled "hurricane and windstorm resistive" shall be anchored according to the instructions furnished by the manufacturer and shipped within each unit.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A mobile home not meeting the ANSI Standard provisions shall be anchored as set forth in Section 19A-5 herein.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>The owner of a mobile home, or a motor vehicle used as housing, unless excepted by Section 19A-3, who resides in or is intending to reside in a trailer or mobile home park, or other authorized location in Florida, shall obtain a certificate of completion approving such use from the appropriate jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(7)'>After on-site inspection and compliance with federal, State and local codes and regulations, the final certificate of completion shall be issued.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>County ordinance. In the unincorporated areas, this chapter shall be enforced by the County Building Official.<section prefix='(1)'>In the incorporated areas, this chapter shall be enforced by the municipalities.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where this chapter is not enforced within a municipality the County shall enforce the same through the County Building Official.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No variance shall be granted from the provisions hereof.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-1, ยง 1, 1-4-77)</history></law>