<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00039' order_by='00039' level='2'>Chapter 19A MOBILE HOMES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>19A-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Foundations, piers and anchors.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002748</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 19A-5. Foundations, piers and anchors.<section prefix='(A)'>All mobile homes and motor vehicles used as housing shall be anchored and secured in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The following mandatory provisions are substantially the minimum standards set forth by the Dpartment of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, Division of Motor Vehicles, for blocking, anchoring and securing mobile homes and motor vehicles used as housing:<section prefix='(1)'>Foundations and piers.<section prefix='(a)'>Pier foundations shall be provided upon each main supporting beam running lengthwise in the frame of mobile homes and motor vehicles. Such foundations shall not exceed ten (10) feet center-to-center and shall be so located that the supporting beams extend no more than two (2) feet beyond the center line of the foundations, front or rear.<section>Double-wide structures will require twice the number of foundations and piers as is required for single-wide structures.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>All grass and other organic material shall be removed and the pier foundations shall be placed on stable soil, level rock or gravel, or embedded at least four (4) inches in sand or loam soil. Pier foundations shall be sixteen (16) inches by sixteen (16) inches by four (4) inches thick solid concrete, precast, poured-in-place, or the equivalent.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Corner piers shall be double blocked and all other piers shall be constructed of approved eight-inch by eight-inch by sixteen-inch concrete block, solid or cored with open cells vertical, centered on each pier foundation. A two-inch by eight-inch by sixteen-inch long wood plate, treated in accordance with paragraph 2913.2(a) of the South Florida Building Code, shall be placed on top of each pier with shim shingles fitted and driven tight between the wood plate and the main frame where necessary to provide uniform bearing.<section prefix='1.'>Single block piers shall be installed perpendicular to the main supporting beams.</section><section prefix='2.'>Piers over forty (40) inches in height shall be of double-block tiers, each tier turned ninety (90) degrees from the tier below and capped with four (4) inches of concrete, poured or the equivalent, and cushioned with pressure-treated wood shims or wood plate.</section><section prefix='3.'>Corner piers over three (3) blocks high shall be double-blocked tiers, each tier turned ninety (90) degrees from the tier below, and capped with four (4) inches of concrete, poured or the equivalent, and cushioned with pressure-treated wood shims or wood plate.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Other equivalent types of foundations and piers may be provided where approved by the Building Official.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Tie downs.<section prefix='(a)'>Each structure shall be provided with minimum anchorage according to Table 19A and all anchorage products and their installation shall be approved by the Building Official.</section></section></section><section>     TABLE<section> * Required around the perimeter only (outside main frame members only of both single-wide and double-wide structures).</section><section>** Perimeter frame-tie ground anchors may be located so as to provide common anchorage with over-roof ties. Over-roof ties are not required for double-wide units.</section></section><section>     TABLE 19A-A*<section> * This table only applies to those newly installed mobile homes or motor vehicles used as housing, located within the Coastal General Flood Hazard District designated "A" upon the official flood hazard boundary map issued and approved by the Federal Insurance Administrator and required by the established rules and regulations issued by the federal Department of Housing and Urban Development on October 26, 1976 in accordance with the National Flood Insurance Program.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Frame ties shall be attached to the main framing members (chassis) in a manner not allowing release under vibratory loading. Frame ties shall include approved one-half-inch drop-forged steel turn-buckles with welded eyes connected to approved ground anchors with wire rope having a breaking strength of not less than four thousand seven hundred fifty (4,750) pounds, or the equivalent. End ties shall attach not more than twenty-four (24) inches from each end of the frame.<section prefix='1.'>Intermediate ties shall be spaced at equal intervals according to the requirements tabulated in Table 19A</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Over-roof ties shall not contact with the structure except at adequately reinforced areas where the additional load will not damage such structure.<section prefix='1.'>Over-roof ties shall be approved straps capable of resisting an up-lift force of not less than thirty (30) pounds per square foot. The intermediate strap shall be located midway between the end straps.</section><section prefix='2.'>End over-roof ties shall be installed not more than twenty-four (24) inches from the end of the structure, or at the first stud-and-truss, and attach to the same ground anchor as the frame ties. Where frames do not extend to the rear wall of structure, frame ties shall attach not less than six (6) inches from the rear end of the frame. Intermediate over-roof ties shall then be located as midway between end ties as is feasible.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Other equivalent types of ground anchors, frame ties and over the roof ties may be provided where the design and installation procedure are approved by the Building Official.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Ground anchors. Ground anchors shall be of approved design and shall be one of the following:<section prefix='(a)'>A steel screw auger not less than six (6) inches in diameter at one end of a minimum five-eighths-inch diameter steel rod and a welded eye at the other end.<section prefix='1.'>Where installed, such augers shall penetrate the ground not less than three and one-half (3½) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>A five-eighths-inch diameter steel rod providing a six-inch hook at one end and a welded eye at the other, or a bent U-shaped five-eighths-inch rod with two (2) three-inch hooks, cast into a reinforced concrete slab not less than four (4) inches thick and one hundred (100) square feet in area.</section><section prefix='(c)'>An eyebolt or U-shaped anchor rod as described in subparagraph (b) above, cast at least six (6) inches into a poured-in-place concrete deadman at least six (6) inches in diameter and embedded not less than two (2) feet deep in rock.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Exceptions.<section prefix='(a)'>Single-wide mobile structures of a model year prior to 1971 shall be considered as complying with the provisions of this section where at least one (1) over-roof tie is provided at each end of such structure. Frame ties shall, however, be provided as tabulated in Table 19A herein.</section><section prefix='(b)'>End frame-ties only may be provided where mobile structures are located adjacent to a concrete slab, as set forth in subparagraph (3)(b) herein, providing the underside of the structure floor is twelve (12) inches or less above the surface of such slab and sixteen (16) inches or less above the ground surface beneath the structure, measured vertically.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Where a minimum of two-thirds the length of the frame of a mobile unit is supported by and attached to a structure which meets the requirements for uplift and overturning for permanent construction, as set forth in subsection 2306.4 of the South Florida Building Code, the tie down provisions of this chapter shall be considered as having been met.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-1, § 1, 1-4-77)</history></law>