<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Rules of procedure of County Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000070</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1. Rules of procedure of County Commission.<section>PART 1. GOVERNING RULES</section><section></section><section>Except as may be provided in the Charter, the code or by these rules, questions of order, the methods of organization and the conduct of business of the Commission shall be governed by the Mason's Manual of Legislative Procedure (1953 Edition).</section><section>PART 2. OFFICERS</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Chairperson.<section prefix='(1)'>Election, term, term limitation, and removal. A chairperson of the board of county commissioners shall be elected for a term of two (2) years by the vote of at least seven (7) commissioners at the regular commission meeting following the installation of the county commissioners during each even-numbered year. The chairperson's term shall commence on January 1 of the following year. The chairperson may be removed prior to the expiration of his or her term by the vote of nine (9) commissioners. No commissioner shall serve as chairperson of the county commission for more than two consecutive years.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Duties of chairperson. The chairperson shall:<section prefix='(a)'>Preside at all meetings of the commission and preserve strict order and decorum;</section><section prefix='(b)'>State every question coming before the commission and announce the decision of the commission on all matters coming before it;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Appoint the chairpersons, vice-chairpersons and members of all commission committees, including standing committees, ad hoc committees and subcommittees;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Convene committees of the whole;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Designate and supervise all persons who shall serve as employees of the entire county commission, as set forth in the pool budget, including employees of the Office of Legislative Analysis;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Have responsibility for the administration of the pool budget of the board of county commissioners, in conjunction with the manager;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Issue subpoenas, subpoenas duces tecum, and other necessary process to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of any books, letters, or other documentary evidence required by a committee, upon the request of the chairperson of any commission committee;</section><section prefix='(h)'>Schedule the meetings of all commission committees, in consultation with the committee chairperson and vice-chairperson, to provide each with an opportunity to meet without conflicting with the meetings of other committees;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Designate the arrangement and configuration of the county commission dais; and</section><section prefix='(j)'>Have responsibility for administering the Miami-Dade County Goodwill Ambassadors Program under the Office of Community Advocacy within the Office of the Chair, with administrative support from the Mayor or the Mayor's designee. The chairperson shall serve as an ex officio voting member of all commission committees but shall not count as a member of a committee for purposes of determining the existence of a quorum.</section><section>The chairperson shall serve as an ex officio voting member of all commission committees but shall not count as a member of a committee for purposes of determining the existence of a quorum.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Vice-chairperson.<section prefix='(1)'>Election, term, term limitation and removal. A vice-chairperson of the board of county commissioners shall be elected for a term of two (2) years by the vote of at least seven (7) commissioners at the regular commission meeting following the installation of the county commissioners during each even-numbered year. The term of office for the vice-chairperson of the board shall commence on January 1 of the following year. The vice-chairperson may be removed prior to the expiration of his or her term by the vote of at least seven (7) commissioners. No commissioner shall serve as vice-chairperson of the county commission for more than two consecutive years.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Duties of vice-chairperson. Unless the chairperson appoints the vice-chairperson as a voting member of a committee, the vice-chairperson shall serve as an ex officio non-voting member of each commission committee, but shall not count as a member of a committee on which he or she serves as a non-voting member for purposes of determining the existence of a quorum. The vice-chairperson of the board shall perform the duties of the chairperson in the event of the absence or incapacity of the chairperson. The vice-chairperson shall complete the unfinished term of any chairperson who resigns or is removed as chairperson of the commission.</section></section></section><section></section><section>The Clerk of the Circuit Court or a designated Deputy Clerk shall act as Clerk of the Commission. The Clerk of the Commission shall prepare the minutes and shall certify all ordinances and resolutions adopted by the Commission.</section><section></section><section>The County Attorney, or such member of the office of the County Attorney as may be designated, shall be available to the Commission at all meetings. The County Attorney shall act as parliamentarian, and shall advise and assist the Presiding Officer in matters of parliamentary law.</section><section></section><section>The Miami-Dade Police Director, or such other county official or employee as the Commission may designate, shall be the Sergeant-at-Arms at commission meetings, commission committee and subcommittee meetings and community council meetings. The Sergeant-at-Arms shall carry out all orders and instructions given by the Presiding Officer for the purpose of maintaining order and decorum at the meetings.</section><section>PART 3. MEETINGS</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>The commission shall hold regular meetings on the first and third Tuesday and Thursday of each month, or on such other days as may be set on the annual calendar of meetings approved by the commission. Notwithstanding any provision herein to the contrary, there shall be no regular meeting held on the same day as the installation ceremony of County Commissioners. The first regular meeting occurring after the installation ceremony shall take place within three (3) to [seven] (7) days after the ceremony on a date selected at least 120 days prior to the meeting. The date of such meeting shall be selected by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners, in consultation with the Mayor, the County Attorney, and the Clerk of the Board.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Unless otherwise determined by the Commission, regular meetings shall commence at 9:30 in the morning and shall end no later than 6:30 p.m. each day. Regular meetings may be otherwise postponed or canceled (1) by resolution or motion adopted at a regular meeting by a majority of the Commission members present, (2) by the chairperson and six (6) other members of the commission serving notice containing the required seven (7) signatures upon the clerk who shall provide public notice when a meeting is canceled, or (3) by the chairperson of the commission when: (a) the agenda for a meeting has not been provided to the members of the commission at least twenty-four (24) hours before the scheduled meeting; (b) the chairperson is in receipt of written communications from at least a majority of those commissioners then in office stating that said commissioners will not be attending the meeting; or (c) no action item has been placed on the agenda of a zoning or comprehensive development master plan meeting in compliance with the applicable notice requirements. All regular meetings shall be held in the Commission Chambers, Stephen P. Clark Center, 111 N.W. 1 Street, Miami, Florida 33128, or such location as may be approved by a majority of the Commission members present and shall be open to the public and all news media.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The commission shall consider and determine zoning matters at its regular meetings.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The second reading (public hearing) of the annual budget ordinance shall be considered at a meeting at which the said budget ordinance and the levy of the millage are the only items on the agenda.</section></section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Special meetings. A special meeting of the Commission may be called by a majority of the members of the Commission. Whenever a special meeting is called, a notice in writing signed by such majority shall be served upon the chairperson and the Clerk. Each signature by a commissioner shall constitute a representation that, at the time of affixing his or her signature to the notice, the commissioner has the present intention to attend the special meeting. The Clerk shall forthwith serve verbal and written notice upon each member of the Commission stating the date, hour and place of the meeting and the purpose for which such meeting is called, and no other business shall be transacted at that meeting. At least twenty-four (24) hours must elapse between the time the Clerk receives notice in writing and the time the meeting is to be held. A special meeting of the Board of County Commissioners may be cancelled (1) by resolution or motion adopted at a regular meeting by a majority of the Commission members present or (2) by seven (7) members of the Board of County Commissioners serving notice containing the required seven (7) signatures on the members of the Board of County Commissioners and upon the Clerk who shall provide public notice when a meeting is cancelled. The Commission chambers shall be made available for a special meeting whenever such a meeting is called.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Emergency meetings. An emergency meeting of the Commission may be called by the chairperson whenever in his or her opinion an emergency exists which requires immediate action by the Commission. Whenever such emergency meeting is called, the chairperson shall notify the Clerk who shall forthwith serve either verbal or written notice upon each member of the Commission, stating the date, hour and place of the meeting and the purpose for which it is called, and no other business shall be transacted at that meeting. At least twenty-four (24) hours shall elapse between the time the Clerk receives notice of the meeting and the time the meeting is to be held. An emergency meeting of the Board of County Commissioners may be cancelled (1) by resolution or motion adopted at a regular meeting by a majority of the Commission members present or (2) by seven (7) members of the Board of County Commissioners serving notice containing the required seven (7) signatures on the members of the Board of County Commissioners and upon the Clerk who shall provide public notice when a meeting is cancelled. The Commission chambers shall be made available for an emergency meeting whenever such a meeting is called.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If after reasonable diligence, it is impossible to give notice to each Commissioner, such failure shall not affect the legality of the meeting if a quorum is present. The minutes of each special or emergency meeting shall show the manner and method by which notice of such special or emergency meeting was given to each member of the Commission, or shall show a waiver of notice. All special or emergency meetings shall be open to the public and shall be held and conducted in the Commission Chambers, Stephen P. Clark Center, 111 N.W. 1 Street, Miami, Florida 33128, or other suitable location within Miami-Dade County, Florida. Minutes thereof shall be kept by the Clerk.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No special or emergency meeting shall be held unless notice thereof shall be given in compliance with the provisions of this rule, or notice thereof is waived by a majority of the entire membership of the Commission.</section></section><section></section><section>Whenever in these rules an action requires the signature of a commissioner, a signature is acceptable when the commissioner: (1) provides an original handwritten signature; (2) provides a facsimile of an original handwritten signature; or (3) authorizes use of the commissioner's stamp and the stamp is accompanied by a legible signature of the staffer authorized to utilize such stamp. The authority to use a commissioner's stamp shall be evidenced by a written document on file with the office of the chairperson and the county attorney.</section><section>PART 4. COMMITTEES</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Establishment of commission committees. The county commission shall convene as a committee of the whole within 30 days of the date of the election of the commission chairperson and vice-chairperson to make recommendations to the chairperson regarding: the number of standing county commission committees; the subject matter of the commission's standing committees; the number of members on each standing committee; and the maximum number, if any, of standing committees on which a commissioner may serve. Within thirty (30) days of the chairperson's receipt of the recommendations of the committee of the whole, the commission chairperson shall establish standing county commission committees, determine the subject matter of these committees, the maximum number, if any, of standing committees on which a commissioner may serve, and the number of members on each committee and shall establish any additional procedural rules of order consistent with this section which are necessary for the efficient and effective operation of the committee system.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Appointment of committee members. The chairperson of the county commission shall appoint the membership of each commission committee after he or she has received any written expressions of interest from commissioners as to their preferences for committee service.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Committee chairperson and vice-chairperson. A chairperson and a vice-chairperson of each commission committee shall be appointed by the chairperson of the commission and shall continue in office at the pleasure of the chairperson of the commission. The chairperson of the commission shall also appoint a chairperson for each subcommittee authorized by these rules and may designate a vice-chairperson, both of whom shall continue in office at the pleasure of the chairperson of the commission. The committee chairperson shall set the order of items on the committee agenda for each committee meeting. The chairperson shall preserve order and decorum and shall have general control of committee proceedings. If there is a disturbance or disorderly conduct during the committee meeting, the chairperson or vice-chairperson may require participants in the disturbance to clear the room. The vice-chairperson shall perform the duties of the chairperson in the absence of the chairperson. If the chairperson and vice-chairperson are absent, the committee may select one of its members to perform the duties of the chair for the meeting during which the chairperson and the vice-chairperson are absent.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Powers of commission committees. Commission committees and subcommittees are authorized:<section prefix='(1)'>To maintain a continuous review of the work and performance of county agencies and, notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in the Code, county boards within the jurisdiction of each committee;</section><section prefix='(2)'>To invite public officials, employees, and private individuals to appear before the committees or subcommittees to submit information;</section><section prefix='(3)'>To request reports from departments and, notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in the Code, county boards performing functions reasonably related to each committee's jurisdiction;</section><section prefix='(4)'>To complete interim projects assigned by the chairperson of the commission;</section><section prefix='(5)'>To review and make recommendations with regard to prospective agenda items, and to propose or amend the same; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in the Code, to conduct public hearings, unless state or federal law requires the county commission to conduct a given public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Ancillary powers. In order to carry out its duties, each commission committee shall be empowered to inspect and investigate the books, records, papers, documents, date, operations, and physical plant of any department, agency or entity of Miami-Dade County. The chairperson of a commission committee may request the chairperson of the commission to issue subpoenas, subpoenas duces tecum, and other necessary process to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of any books, letters, or other documentary evidence required by such committee. The chairperson of the commission may issue said process at the request of the committee chairperson. Any member of a standing committee or subcommittee may administer oaths and affirmations, in the manner prescribed by law to witnesses who appear before such committees to testify in any matter requiring evidence.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Committee and commission agendas. Administrative deadlines for printing the committee and commission agendas shall be established by the county Mayor and the county attorney that are sufficient to allow for timely printing of the committee and commission agendas. The commission chairperson, in consultation with the county attorney and county Mayor, shall assign all resolutions, ordinances for second reading, reports and other prospective agenda items received by the applicable administrative deadline to the appropriate committee agenda for consideration as required by these rules. Following any required committee consideration, the commission chairperson, in consultation with the county attorney and the county Mayor, shall place items on the appropriate commission agenda, as permitted by these rules. The Commission Auditor shall advise the Chairperson of any agenda item sponsored by the Mayor not in compliance with the provisions of Resolution No. R-530-10 prior to the Chairperson's assignment of such item to a committee or commission agenda. The Chairperson may determine, in his or her sole discretion, whether to place any item which is identified by the Commissioner Auditor as noncompliant, on any committee or commission agenda. A duly authorized designee of the county Mayor, the county attorney, the chairperson or the Commission Auditor may carry out the duties assigned to these persons pursuant to this paragraph.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Subcommittees. The chairperson of the county commission may appoint a subcommittee to study or investigate a specific matter falling within the jurisdiction of a standing committee or to consider legislation or policy issues referred to it. The chairperson of the commission shall be notified on completion of the assignment. Subcommittees shall exist only for the time period necessary to complete their assignments and report to their commission committees; provided, however, that subcommittees shall not be in existence for a period in excess of ninety (90) days, unless otherwise specified by the commission chairperson. Reports prepared by subcommittees shall be reviewed by the commission committee with jurisdiction over the subject matter of the report and accepted, amended, or rejected by majority vote of those committee members present.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Committee deliberations. A commission committee may take one of the following actions with respect to each matter referred to the committee for action:<section prefix='(1)'>Recommend favorably;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Recommend favorably with committee amendment(s);</section><section prefix='(3)'>Forward without recommendation, upon the unanimous vote of the members of the committee who are present;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Receive a report;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Lay the matter on the table resulting in the matter not being placed on an agenda of the county commission. A report submitted by a county board may not be laid on the table where the ordinance creating the county board requires that a report be submitted to the county commission; or</section><section prefix='(6)'>Defer or take no action on an item as set forth in the last sentence of this subparagraph for a maximum of two consecutive committee meetings. Deferral of or failure to act on a matter beyond two consecutive committee meetings shall cause the matter to be laid on the table, as set forth in the preceding subparagraph. Notwithstanding any other provision of these Rules of Procedure, whenever: (A) (i) an item is considered but does not receive a motion; (ii) a motion on an item does not receive a second; (iii) at least a majority plus one of the committee members are present and a majority of those committee members present votes against a motion; or (iv) the vote of the committee members on an item has resulted in a tie; and (B) No other available motion on an item is made and approved before the next item is called for consideration or before a recess or adjournment is called, whichever occurs first, the item shall be deemed to be laid on the table, as set forth in the preceding subparagraph; such item shall be reintroduced only in accordance with the renewal provisions of Rule 4.01(r). An item shall not be deemed laid on the table where the item is considered but no action is taken on the item due to loss of quorum or adjournment; or, less than a majority plus one of the committee members is present and a majority of those committee members present votes against a motion.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Committee consideration required. Except as provided elsewhere in these rules, no item shall be placed on a commission agenda or considered by the county commission, unless each committee to which the item has been referred has forwarded the item to the commission pursuant to Section 4.01(h)(1), (2), (3), or (4) above.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Exceptions to Committee Requirement.<section prefix='(1)'>An item that has not been considered by a committee may be placed on the agenda of the county commission if the chairperson of the committee to which the item has been referred requests a waiver in writing and the commission chairperson concurs.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Quasi-judicial items, special taxing districts, ordinances for first reading, consent agenda items, other than items related to certificates of transportation, district office fund allocations, special presentations, namings, renamings or co-designations of County roads, facilities or properties, approvals of namings, renamings or co-designations of federal, state or municipal roads, facilities or properties, citizens' presentations, bid protests, settlements, options to renew contracts, resolutions recommending the acceleration and deceleration of Building Better Communities General Obligation Bond Program funding of projects using unspent bond proceeds, including interest earnings and premium funds, resolutions urging an entity or person to take stated action, resolutions taking a position or seeking direction from the Board on legislation or administrative action at the federal, state or local level, resolutions related to contract lobbyist conflict waiver requests and resolutions expressing intent shall be heard directly by the county commission, items, awarding, granting, amending or relating to an award or grant of Targeted Jobs Incentive Fund, Qualified Targeted Industry Business incentives, property or utility tax exemptions in enterprise zones, or Brownfield Economic Development Initiative Loan Funds or similar incentives and tax exemption programs; provided, however, any such item relating to an award of Community Redevelopment Agency funding or Community Development Block Grant funding or other funding administered by the Public Housing and Community Development department, or successor department, shall not be excepted from committee review by this subsection (j)(2). On such items, the public shall have the same rights to participate and be heard at the county commission as they would have received had the item been heard in committee.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Whenever the committee of jurisdiction considers a proposed road closing in a commission district where the district commissioner is not a member of the committee of jurisdiction, the County Manager shall notify the commissioner prior to the meeting. Under such circumstances, the committee may only lay the item on the table if the district commissioner attends the commission meeting and states that he or she supports laying the matter on the table.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>Emergency matters; time sensitive matters. A matter that has not been considered by the committee(s) to which it is assigned may be placed on the agenda of the county commission by the chairperson to meet a public emergency as provided in Section 1.02 of the Home Rule Charter. Time sensitive matters with little or no financial impact on the county may be placed on an agenda of the county commission by the chairperson of the commission without having been considered by a committee.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Quorum. A quorum of any commission committee must be present in order for committee to take action. A majority of the members of each commission committee or subcommittee shall constitute a quorum.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Calling committee to order. The chairperson or, in the chairperson's absence, the vice-chairperson, shall call the committee to order at the time for which the meeting was noticed. On the appearance of a quorum the committee shall proceed with the order of business.</section><section prefix='(n)'>"3-day rule". A copy of each agenda item shall be furnished to the members of each committee and subcommittee not later than three (3) working days before a vote may be called on the item. The provisions of this rule shall be deemed waived unless asserted by a commissioner before the committee takes action on the resolution, ordinance, motion or other item in question.<section>Proposed committee agenda items not delivered in accordance with the preceding paragraph (except for alternates, and substitutes), shall not be placed on the committee agenda unless placed on the agenda at the request of the committee chair.</section></section><section prefix='(o)'>Members' attendance. Committee attendance requirements shall be established by the chairperson of the commission, after receiving recommendations by a commission committee of the whole regarding any attendance requirements. Any Commissioner who notifies the Committee Chairperson or the Clerk of the Board that he or she will be absent from a committee meeting prior to the start of such scheduled meeting shall be noted as excused in the minutes of the meeting. The Clerk of the Board shall note in the minutes when a Commissioner arrives at a committee meeting, if the Commissioner arrives after the meeting has commenced.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Majority vote required. Unless otherwise specified in these rules, an affirmative vote of voting members present, as long as a quorum is present, shall be required to act upon any ordinance, resolution, report or other matter considered by the committee.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Reconsideration. Any committee action taken pursuant to Rule 4.01(h) may be reconsidered only at the same meeting at which the action was taken. A motion to reconsider an item which has been laid on the table as set forth in Rule 4.01(h)(5) and (6) is out of order and no such motion may be reconsidered.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Renewal. Once an ordinance or resolution is laid on the table in a committee, the proposed ordinance or resolution may not be brought before that committee again during the three (3) month period following the date the item is laid on the table (subject to the provisions of Rule 4.01(q)), unless an application for renewal made by two-thirds () of the committee members is first submitted to the chairperson of the committee.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Statements of fiscal impact required for ordinances; exceptions. Prior to the public hearing of any ordinance, the county manager shall prepare a written statement setting forth the fiscal impact, if any, of the proposed ordinance. No public hearing on any ordinance shall be held, if the statement of fiscal impact is not submitted with the ordinance as part of the agenda. The provision of this rule shall not apply to any emergency ordinance or any budget ordinance.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Procurement items. Provided public notice, public hearing and other legal requirements can be met, and notwithstanding and prevailing over any provision to the contrary, all items approved at committee meetings recommending or rejecting award of contracts for public improvements, and purchases of supplies, materials, and services, including professional services, shall be placed on the agenda of the next regularly scheduled Board of County Commissioners meeting, unless placed on the agenda of a special meeting held sooner than the next regularly scheduled Board of County Commissioners meeting or unless the chairperson of the commission deems it necessary to place the item on another agenda.</section></section><section>PART 5. CONDUCT OF MEETINGS; AGENDA</section><section></section><section>Promptly at the hour set for each meeting, the members of the Commission, the County Attorney, the Manager and the Clerk shall take their regular stations in the Commission Chamber. The chairperson shall take the chair and shall call the Commission to order immediately. In the absence of the chairperson and vice-chairperson, the Clerk shall then determine whether a quorum is present and in that event shall call for the election of a temporary Presiding Officer. Upon the arrival of the chairperson or vice-chairperson, the temporary Presiding Officer shall relinquish the chair upon the conclusion of the business immediately before the Commission.</section><section></section><section>The Clerk shall call the roll of the members, and the names of those present shall be entered in the minutes. Any Commissioner who notifies the Chairperson or the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners that he or she will be absent from a County Commission meeting prior to the start of such scheduled meeting shall be noted as excused in the minutes of the meeting. The Clerk of the Board shall note in the minutes when a Commissioner arrives at a County Commission meeting, if the Commissioner arrives after the meeting has commenced.</section><section></section><section>A majority of the Commissioners then in office shall constitute a quorum. No ordinance, resolution or motion shall be adopted by the Commission without the affirmative vote of the majority of all the members present.</section><section></section><section>Should no quorum attend within thirty (30) minutes after the hour appointed for the meeting of the Commission, the chairperson or the Clerk may adjourn the meeting until another hour or day unless, by unanimous agreement, those members present select another time. The names of the members present and their action at such meeting shall be recorded in the minutes by the Clerk.</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Order of business.<section prefix='(1)'>There shall be an official agenda for every meeting of the Commission, which shall determine the order of business conducted at the meeting. The order of business for Tuesday meetings shall be as follows:<section prefix='1.'>Invocation as provided in Rule 5.05(g)<section>Roll call</section><section>Pledge of allegiance</section><section>Special presentations</section><section>Citizens' presentations</section><section>Reports of official county boards</section><section>Motion to set agenda</section><section>Commission auditor</section><section>Office of intergovernmental affairs</section></section><section prefix='2.'>Mayoral vetoes, mayoral reports.</section><section prefix='3.'>Consent agenda:<section prefix='a.'>Commissioner items.</section><section prefix='b.'>Departmental items.</section></section><section prefix='4.'>Ordinances for first reading.</section><section prefix='5.'>Public hearings which shall be scheduled for 9:30 a.m.</section><section prefix='6.'>Chairperson of the board of county commissioners.<section prefix='b.'>Policy matters for discussion by the board.</section></section><section prefix='7.'>Ordinances for second reading.</section><section prefix='8.'>Departments.</section><section prefix='9.'>Additional departmental items.</section><section prefix='10.'>Authorities, boards, councils and trusts.</section><section prefix='11.'>County commissioners.</section><section prefix='12.'>County manager [mayor].</section><section prefix='13.'>County attorney.</section><section prefix='14.'>Items subject to "4-day rule".</section><section prefix='15.'>Clerk of the board.</section><section prefix='16.'>Items scheduled for Thursday.</section><section prefix='17.'>Summer recess items.</section><section>The following items shall be considered consent agenda items and placed in section 3.a or b. of the agenda, as appropriate:</section><section prefix='1.'>Items approving or ratifying the submittal of grant applications and acceptance of grant awards, as long as required matching funds are appropriated in the County budget, as determined by the Office of Management and Budget.</section><section prefix='2.'>Resolutions ratifying contracts executed by the Mayor, as allowed by law or previous action of the Board (non-summer recess items).</section><section prefix='3.'>Resolutions approving in-kind contributions.</section><section prefix='4.'>Resolutions making district office fund allocations.</section><section prefix='5.'>Resolutions approving namings, renamings or codesignations of federal, state or municipal roads, facilities or properties.</section><section prefix='6.'>Items awarding, granting, amending or relating to an award or grant of Targeted Jobs Incentive Fund, Qualified Targeted Industry Business incentives and tax exemption programs.</section><section prefix='7.'>Resolutions approving donations of surplus County property, except those donations made for emergency purposes and to foreign governmental entities.</section><section prefix='8.'>Resolutions approving the issuance or transfer of certificates of transportation for passenger motor carriers.</section><section>Notwithstanding any provision herein to the contrary, first or second reading items, public hearing items, quasi-judicial items, and items requiring a supermajority vote of the board shall not be placed in the consent agenda section of the agenda.</section><section>Items shall be considered in the order in which they are placed on the agenda unless a majority of the commissioners determines to deviate from the printed agenda or in the discretion of the chairperson, certain matters should be taken out of order to help eliminate logistical concerns or exigent circumstances which would impede the proper functioning of the commission. During a commission meeting, commissioners may identify certain items for individual consideration (i.e., the "pull list"). Agenda items, including consent agenda items, not selected for individual consideration may be approved in a single vote.</section></section><section>The commission shall not take action upon any matter when it is first presented to the commission in a report or reports made by the County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(2)'>At Thursday meetings the following items of business shall be conducted in the following order:<section prefix='1.'>Special presentations and proclamations;</section><section prefix='2.'>Items scheduled for Thursday;</section><section prefix='3.'>Policy matters for discussion by the board;</section><section prefix='4.'>Zoning;</section><section prefix='5.'>Metropolitan planning organization (MPO);</section><section prefix='6.'>Workshops.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Authority to sponsor or present items on agenda.<section prefix='(1)'>Anything to the contrary notwithstanding, matters may only be presented or sponsored by a county commissioner, a commission committee, the county attorney and the clerk of the commission, except that the Mayor shall be able to present or sponsor: (1) reports which do not amend any policy established by the County Commission; (2) mayoral appointments; (3) solicitations for the purchase of goods and services, leases, construction contracts and debt obligations; (4) contracts for the purchase of goods and services and amendments thereto; (5) grant applications, grants and sub-grants; (6) leases of non-County-owned property and amendments thereto; (7) debt obligations and amendments thereto; (8) construction contracts and amendments thereto; (9) labor agreements and amendments thereto; (10) special taxing districts initiated by petition; (11) certificates of public convenience and necessity; (12) certificates of transportation; (13) quasi-judicial items; (14) other matters where the presentation or sponsorship by the Mayor is required by the Home Rule Charter or state or federal law; and (15) leases and licenses of County-owned property and amendments thereto if the Mayor first provides written notification to the Commissioner of the District wherein the County-owned property that is to be leased or licensed is located of the matter and the District Commissioner does not agree to present or sponsor such lease or license or amendment thereto within ten (10) days of the written notification. Any Commissioner or commission committee may present or sponsor any item which the Mayor is authorized to present or sponsor pursuant to the preceding sentence, except as provided otherwise in the Home Rule Charter, or state or federal law. Additionally, the committee chairperson of jurisdiction may, upon the written request of the Mayor or his or her designee, submit an item for placement on a committee or Commission agenda. Such an item shall, if requested by the committee chairperson of jurisdiction, be placed on the appropriate agenda, in accordance with the applicable rules of procedure, as an item sponsored by the committee of jurisdiction.<section>Anything to the contrary notwithstanding, private applications for amendment, modification, addition, or change to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan ("CDMP") shall be placed on the appropriate CDMP agenda after the Department of Sustainability Planning and Economic Enhancement or successor department has completed its review of the application as provided in of the Code and all required fees have been paid (hereinafter "completed private CDMP application"). Each completed private CDMP application and the accompanying ordinance and any related resolution shall: (i) be forwarded to the Office of the Agenda Coordinator for placement on the appropriate CDMP agenda; and (ii) be accompanied by a recommendation from the Mayor or his or her designee.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Proposed agenda items not delivered in accordance with subsection (c) hereof, or which have not been considered by any committee, (except for alternates, substitutes, and items not subject to committee review) shall not be placed on the agenda unless the chairperson of the committee which has jurisdiction over the item, if any, and the chairperson of the commission concur in writing.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>4-Day rule. A copy of each agenda item shall be furnished to the members of the commission not later than four (4) working days before a vote may be called on the item. The provisions of this rule shall be deemed waived unless asserted by a commissioner before the board takes action on the resolution, ordinance, motion or other item in question. The provisions of the rule may not be waived under Rule 7.01(n); however, this rule is not applicable to special or emergency meetings called pursuant to Rule 3.02, items related to the County's legislative package, resolutions recommending the acceleration and deceleration of Building Better Communities General Obligation Bond Program funding of projects using unspent bond proceeds, including interest earnings and premium funds, items approved at a committee meeting recommending or rejecting award of contracts for public improvements, and purchases of supplies, materials, and services, including professional services, and resolutions or motions directing the Mayor or his or her designee to prepare an item for consideration by the Commission.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Approval of minutes. Unless a reading of the minutes of a meeting is requested by a majority of the Commission, such minutes, when approved by the Commission and signed by the Presiding Officer and the Clerk, shall be considered approved without reading; provided that the clerk shall place a copy of the minutes of each meeting, as soon as they have been completed, at a designated place in the Clerk's office where they may be examined by the Commissioners prior to formal approval. A copy of such minutes shall, upon completion by the Clerk, be delivered to the County Manager and County Attorney. The minutes of prior meetings may only be approved by a majority of the Commissioners present at a meeting of the Commission, and upon such approval shall become the official minutes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Removal of public hearing items from the agenda. The sponsor of an item scheduled for public hearing shall be able to withdraw that item from the Commission agenda at any time prior to the commencement of the public hearing by written notification to the agenda coordinator.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Public hearings heard by committee. When a public hearing relating to an ordinance or resolution is conducted before a commission committee as authorized herein, no additional testimony from the public shall be permitted except by a majority vote of those members present before final action is taken; however, debate by commissioners shall be allowed.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Invocations before the County Commission and Committees.<section prefix='(1)'>It is the policy of the Board to allow for an invocation, which may include a prayer or a short solemnizing message, to be offered before its meetings for the benefit of the Board.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Although the invocation shall be listed in the agenda, it shall not be considered an agenda item for the meeting or part of the public business.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No member or employee of the Board or any other person in attendance at the meeting shall be required to participate in any invocation that is offered.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The invocation shall be voluntarily delivered by an individual selected by members of the Board on a rotating basis.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No invocational speaker shall receive compensation for his or her service.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Any invitation extended shall specify that the opportunity to offer a legislative invocation shall not be exploited to convert others to any particular faith, to advance any particular faith, or to disparage any other faith or belief.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Neither the Board nor the Clerk of the Board shall engage in any prior inquiry, review of, or involvement in, the content of any prayer to be offered by an invocational speaker.</section><section prefix='(8)'>This policy is not intended, and shall not be implemented or construed in any way, to affiliate the Board with, nor express the Board's preference for, any faith or religious denomination.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Summer Recess Items. During the Board's annual summer recess period, as determined by the County Calendar approved by the Board, the County Mayor or County Mayor's designee shall administer County business requiring approval of the Board, including the award of contracts and approval of change orders required to maintain essential health and safety activities pursuant to approved County procedures; application for grants; execution of grant agreements, related memoranda of understanding, and other intergovernmental cooperation agreements; application and execution of grants and agreements; receipt and expenditure of funds under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and authorization to perform any and all requirements of said Act; and receipt and expenditure of other funds which will be put in jeopardy, if not received and expended during the summer recess period. All summer recess items not otherwise excepted from committee review will be scheduled for the appropriate committee of jurisdiction and will be placed on the Board's agenda for ratification at the first regular meeting in the month of October.</section></section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Preparation and enactment of ordinances. The County Attorney, when requested, shall prepare ordinances and resolutions.<section>Ordinances may be introduced and listed by title and shall be read by title only before consideration by the Commission on first reading. On first reading of ordinances, there shall be no discussion by either County Commissioners, County staff or members of the public. On first reading only, the Commission may either vote for all ordinances in one (1) vote or may vote separately on any ordinance. At second reading, each ordinance shall be voted on individually.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Approval by County Attorney. All ordinances, resolutions and contract documents, before presentation to a commission committee or the commission, shall have been reduced to writing and shall have been approved as to form and legality by the county attorney. All reports or memoranda that supplement pending ordinances or resolutions shall be presented to the County Attorney for review and approval for placement on a Board agenda, when such reports or memoranda contain proposed amendatory language that can be used to formulate amendments to ordinances or resolutions. Prior to presentation all such documents may be referred to the head of the department under whose jurisdiction the administration of the subject matter of the ordinance, resolution or contract document would devolve. The county attorney shall communicate with a designated staff person from each commissioner's office regarding the preparation and tracking of agenda items.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Sponsorship. Any Commissioner may assume sponsorship of any ordinance, resolution, report or other matter.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Exception. The provisions of this Rule 5.06 shall not be applicable to zoning resolutions which shall be governed exclusively by chapter 33 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(e)'>When action to be taken by resolution or ordinance. All actions of the Commission may be taken by motion, resolution or ordinance except that any action of the Commission which provides for raising revenue, appropriating funds or incurring indebtedness (other than refunding indebtedness), or which provides a penalty or establishes a rule or regulation for the violation of which a penalty is imposed, shall be by ordinance.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Ordinances directly affecting municipalities. Any proposed county ordinances that would directly affect the jurisdiction or the duties of municipalities or their officers, or any proposed ordinances that may have a direct fiscal impact upon municipal governments in Miami-Dade County, shall be scheduled for second reading no sooner than six (6) weeks after its passage on first reading. At least four (4) weeks prior to the scheduled public hearing, the County Manager is directed to mail or e-mail a copy of the proposed ordinance to each city clerk, city attorney, city manager and the Executive Director of the Miami-Dade League of Cities, Inc. The County Manager's communication shall include the date of the scheduled public hearing and shall state that the proposed ordinance may have an impact upon municipalities. This subsection shall be construed as directory only, and failure to comply with the provisions hereof shall not affect the validity of any ordinance.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Prime sponsorship and co-sponsorship. When a resolution or ordinance is placed on the agenda at the request of a commissioner, the commissioner who requested the preparation of the item shall be designated as the prime sponsor. Any other commissioner who wishes to sponsor the resolution or ordinance shall be designated as a co-sponsor.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Items amended in committee. Any item on the commission agenda that has been amended in committee shall so indicate on the cover memorandum and include a brief description of the amendment. In addition, committee amendments shall be uniquely identified in the item itself so as to distinguish committee amendments from the original item, such as by underlining and strike-through in the case of a resolution amended in committee and by double underlining and double strike-through in the case of an ordinance amended in committee, or where such an approach would not clearly show committee amendments or is not practical, by providing footnotes or comments on the item.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Substitute and alternate items. Any item on a committee agenda or the commission agenda that is a substitute or alternate shall so indicate on the cover memorandum and include a brief description of how the item differs from the original item. In addition, differences between the original item and the substitute or alternate item shall be uniquely identified in the substitute or alternate item itself so as to distinguish it from the original item, such as by underlining and strike-through in the case of a resolution, by double underlining and double strike-through in the case of an ordinance, or where such approaches would not clearly show the differences or are not practical, by providing footnotes or comments on the item.</section></section><section><section prefix='(a)'>No Commissioner shall be a prime sponsor of a total of more than ten (10) action items on a single regular commission agenda unless the Chairperson of the Commission authorizes the placement of additional items on the agenda by a particular Commissioner when approving the agenda. As used in Rule 5.07(a), an "action item" means an ordinance for first reading or a resolution. This provision shall not be applied to ordinances or resolutions which are intended to correct scrivener's errors.</section><section prefix='(b)'>An agenda item shall be deemed withdrawn upon its third deferral. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to zoning applications or to applications to amend the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section></section><section></section><section>At the request of any commissioner at the first reading of any ordinance that regulates private business, land development or building code standards, the county manager shall prepare a written statement setting forth the fiscal impact, if any, of the proposed ordinance on the private business sector. No ordinance regulating private business, land development or building code standards shall be considered on second reading if the requested statement of fiscal impact on private business is not submitted with the ordinance as part of the agenda.</section><section>PART 6. PUBLIC PARTICIPATION</section><section></section><section>No person, except County officers or their representatives, shall be permitted on the dais unless authorized by the Presiding Officer or a majority of the Commission.</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Citizens' presentations. Any citizen shall be entitled to be placed on the official agenda of a regular meeting of the commission and be heard concerning any matter within the scope of the jurisdiction of the Commission. Only Commissioners and the County Manager may place a citizen on the official agenda. The deadline for placing a citizen on the agenda is noon on Monday of the week preceding the week of the meeting at which said citizen wishes to be heard. No action may be taken by the Commission on an item heard as a citizen's presentation unless two-thirds () of the members present deem that the issue requires immediate Commission action.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Public hearings. Any citizen shall be entitled to speak on any matter appearing on the official agenda under the section entitled "Public Hearings."</section><section prefix='(c)'>Public discussion on agenda items. No citizen shall be entitled as a matter of right to address the Commission on any matter listed on or added to the official agenda which is not scheduled for citizen's presentations, public hearing, discussion or debate.</section></section><section><section prefix='(a)'>The office of agenda coordinator shall prepare appropriate registration cards which should indicate the speaker's name, the agenda item on which he or she is speaking, and whether he or she is speaking in favor of or against the proposed item.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On the day of the Commission meeting, a person desiring to speak shall register with the Office of the Agenda Coordinator, at least fifteen (15) minutes prior to the commencement of the discussion on the item, at a registration table in the lobby of the Commission Chambers.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Failure to comply with the registration provisions of this rule shall prohibit a person from speaking on any item for which he or she is not properly registered.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In the event that the seats in the Commission Chambers are filled to capacity, the Office of the Agenda Coordinator shall provide appropriate overflow seating in an area where the Commission meeting is being monitored on television.</section></section><section></section><section>Each person, other than salaried members of the County staff, who addresses the Commission shall step up to a podium and shall give the following information in an audible tone of voice for the minutes:<section prefix='(a)'>Name;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Address;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Whether the person speaks on his or her own behalf, a group of persons, or a third party; or if the person represents an organization; and whether the view expressed by the speaker represents an established policy of the organization approved by the board or governing council;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Compensation, if any;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Whether the person or any immediate family member has a personal financial interest in the pending matter, other than as set forth in (d).</section></section><section>Unless further time is granted by the Commission, the statement shall be limited to five (5) minutes. All remarks shall be addressed to the Commission as a body and not to any member thereof. No person, other than Commissioners and the person having the floor, shall be permitted to enter into any discussion, either directly or through a member of the Commission, without the permission of the Presiding Officer. No question shall be asked a Commissioner except through the Presiding Officer.</section><section></section><section>Any person making impertinent or slanderous remarks or who becomes boisterous while addressing the Commission shall be barred from further appearance before the Commission by the Presiding Officer, unless permission to continue or again address the Commission is granted by the majority vote of the Commission members present.</section><section>No clapping, applauding, heckling or verbal outbursts in support or opposition to a speaker or his or her remarks shall be permitted. No signs or placards shall be allowed in the Commission Chamber. Persons exiting the Commission Chamber shall do so quietly.</section><section>The use of cell phones in the commission chambers is not permitted. Ringers must be set to silent mode to avoid disruption of proceedings. Individuals, including those on the dais, must exit the chambers to answer incoming cell phone calls. County employees may not use cell phone cameras or take digital pictures from their positions on the dais.</section><section>PART 7. RULES OF DEBATE</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Questions under consideration. When a motion is presented and seconded, it is under consideration and no other motion shall be received thereafter, except to adjourn, to lay on the table, to postpone, or to amend until the question is decided. These motions shall have preference in the order in which they are mentioned and the first two (2) shall be decided without debate. Final action upon a pending motion may be deferred until a date certain by a majority of the members present.</section><section prefix='(b)'>As to the Presiding Officer. The Presiding Officer, upon relinquishing the chair, may move, second debate and vote, subject only to such limitations as are by these rules imposed upon all members.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Getting the floor, improper references to be avoided. Every member desiring to speak for any purpose shall address the Presiding Officer, and upon recognition, shall be confined to the question under debate, avoiding all personalities and indecorous language.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Interruption; call to order; appeal a ruling of the chair. A member once recognized, shall not be interrupted when speaking unless it be a call to order or as herein otherwise provided. If a member be called to order, the member shall cease speaking until the question of order be determined by the Presiding Officer, and if in order the member shall be permitted to proceed. Any member may appeal to the Commission from the decision of the Presiding Officer upon a question of order, when, without debate, the Presiding Officer shall submit to the Commission the question, "Shall the decision of the Chair be sustained?" and the Commission shall decide by a majority vote.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Privilege of closing debate. The Commissioner sponsoring or moving the adoption of an ordinance, resolution or motion shall have the privilege of closing the debate.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Method of voting. Voting shall be by machine, roll call, voice vote or paper ballot. Upon every roll call vote the names of the Commissioners shall be called alphabetically by surname, except that the names shall be rotated after each roll call vote, so that the Commissioner who voted first on a preceding roll call shall vote last upon the next subsequent matter; provided, however, that the Presiding Officer shall always cast the last vote. The clerk shall call the roll, tabulate the votes, and announce the results. The vote upon every ordinance shall be taken by roll call or machine vote. The vote upon any resolution, motion or other matter may be by voice vote provided that the Presiding Officer or any Commissioner may require a roll call or machine vote to be taken upon any resolution or motion. Board appointments may be made by paper ballot which clearly identify the Commissioner voting.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Explanation of vote; conflicts of interest. There shall be no discussion by any Commissioner voting, and the Commissioner shall vote yes or no. Any Commissioner, upon voting, may give a brief statement to explain his or her vote. A Commissioner shall have the privilege of filing with the Clerk a written explanation of his or her vote. Any Commissioner with a conflict of interest on a particular matter shall refrain from voting or otherwise participating in the proceedings related to that matter and shall leave the Commission Chambers until the consideration of that matter is concluded. Any such Commissioner who does not leave the chambers shall be deemed absent for purposes of constituting a quorum, counting the vote, or for any other purpose.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Tie votes. Whenever action cannot be taken because the vote of the commissioners has resulted in a tie, and no other available motion on an item is made and approved before the next item is called for consideration or before a recess or adjournment is called, whichever occurs first, the item shall be removed from the agenda and shall be reintroduced only in accordance with the renewal provisions of Rule 7.01(1). Notwithstanding any rule of procedure to the contrary, in zoning and other quasi-judicial matters when action on a resolution results in a tie vote, and no other available motion on the resolution is made and approved before the next matter is called for consideration or before a recess or adjournment is called, whichever occurs first, such resolution shall be carried over to the next regularly scheduled meeting for the consideration of such quasi-judicial matters unless the commission designates a different time for such reconsideration.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Vote change. Any Commissioner may change his or her vote before the next item is called for consideration, or before a recess or adjournment is called whichever occurs first but not thereafter.</section><section prefix='(j)'>No motion or second. If an agenda item fails to receive a motion or second, it shall be removed from the agenda and shall be reintroduced only in accordance with the renewal provisions of Rule 7.01(l).</section><section prefix='(k)'>Reconsideration. An action of the commission may be reconsidered only at the same meeting at which the action was taken or at the next regular meeting thereafter. A motion to reconsider may be made only by a commissioner who voted on the prevailing side of the question and must be concurred in by a majority of those present at the meeting. A motion to reconsider an item resulting in a tie vote is not in order, and no such motion shall be reconsidered. A motion to reconsider shall not be considered unless at least the same number of commissioners is present as participated in the original vote, or upon affirmative vote of two-thirds () of those commissioners present. Adoption of a motion to reconsider shall rescind the action reconsidered.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Renewal. Once action is taken on a proposed ordinance or resolution, neither the same matter nor its repeal or rescission may be brought before the Commission again during the six-month period following the said action (subject to the provisions of Rule 7.01(k)), unless application for renewal by seven (7) Commissioners are first submitted to the Presiding Officer.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Expiration of postponed items. Once an item before the Board is postponed indefinitely, and no action is taken by the Board on such item for a period of six (6) months following the latest postponement, such item shall be deemed withdrawn. Consideration of the matter covered under the item shall require the introduction of a new item.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Adjournment A motion to adjourn shall always be in order and decided without debate.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Suspension of the rules. No rule of procedure adopted by this board shall be suspended except by an affirmative vote of two-thirds () of the Commissioners present.</section></section><section>PART 8. MAYORAL VETO AND COMMISSION OVERRIDE</section><section></section><section>The veto provisions of Section 1.10.A of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter shall be exercised exclusively in accordance with the terms and conditions of this rule.<section prefix='(a)'>Each ordinance and resolution finally adopted by the Commission shall contain a place for noting Mayoral approval or veto, and Commission override. The Mayor may indicate approval of any ordinance or resolution by signing it in the place provided, or the Mayor may permit the item to become effective in accordance with its terms by allowing ten (10) days to elapse without exercising a veto.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the Mayor determines to veto an ordinance, resolution, motion or budget line item, the Mayor shall personally sign a copy of the form set forth herein in the place so provided and shall indicate with specificity the reason(s) for the veto. The form shall be as follows:</section></section><section>OFFICE OF THE MAYORMIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA</section><section></section><section>VETO AND VETO MESSAGE</section><section></section><section>To: Honorable Chairperson and MembersBoard of County CommissionersMiami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>From: [Signature of Mayor]</section><section>, Mayor</section><section>Miami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>Pursuant to the authority vested in me under the provisions of Section 1.10.A of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, I hereby veto:<section>{state ordinance, resolution, motion or budget line item}</section><section>Veto message:</section><section prefix='(c)'>The completed form shall be submitted to the Clerk of the board on or before 4:30 p.m. on the tenth (10th) calendar day following final Commission enactment or adoption thereof. The Clerk's official date and time recorder stamp on the completed form shall conclusively determine compliance or noncompliance with the ten-day time frame.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Clerk shall place items vetoed by the Mayor, together with the completed veto forms, on the next regularly scheduled Commission agenda as the first substantive items for Commission consideration.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding any other rule of the Commission, items vetoed by the Mayor shall (1) not be subject to the "4-day rule" as provided in Rule 5.05(c); (2) not be deferred to a future meeting; (3) not require committee review; (4) not be subject to a motion to reconsider, except at the same meeting; (5) not require first reading; (6) not require publication or additional public hearings; or (7) not be amended if the item required special publication or a public hearing to be originally adopted or enacted.</section><section prefix='(f)'>A motion to override a mayoral veto shall be stated as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>"I move that [the ordinance, resolution or motion] be adopted and become effective notwithstanding the veto of the Mayor," or</section><section prefix='(2)'>"I move that [the specific line item in the budget] be restored to the ordinance and become effective notwithstanding the veto of the Mayor."</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>If two-thirds () of all commissioners present vote in favor of the motion as stated in subsection (f) above, the ordinance, resolution, motion or budget appropriation shall be deemed enacted or adopted and effective in accordance with its terms; otherwise, the Mayor's veto shall be deemed sustained.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The provisions of this rule shall not be waived under Rule 7.01(n).</section></section><section>PART 8.1. MAYORAL APPOINTMENT OF COUNTY MANAGER AND OF DEPARTMENT DIRECTORS OF THE ADMINISTRATIVE DEPARTMENTS OF THE COUNTY, AND COMMISSION DISAPPROVAL.</section><section></section><section>The authority and powers provided to the Mayor and the Commission under Sections C and D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter regarding the appointment of the County Manager and department directors of administrative departments shall be exercised exclusively in accordance with the terms and conditions of this rule.<section prefix='(a)'>The Mayor shall utilize the form provided herein to appoint the County Manager or a department director of an administrative department of the County. The Mayor shall personally sign a copy of the form in the place so provided and shall indicate with specificity the position, name, and qualifications of the person appointed. The form shall be as follows:<section>OFFICE OF THE MAYOR</section><section>MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA</section><section></section><section>MAYORAL APPOINTMENT</section><section></section><section>To: Honorable Chairperson and Members Board of County Commissioners Miami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>From: [Signature of Mayor]</section><section>, Mayor</section><section>Miami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>Pursuant to the authority vested in me under the provisions of Sections C and D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, I hereby appoint:</section><section>[insert name of person appointed]</section><section>to the position of:</section><section>[insert position to which the person is appointed].</section><section>The person's qualifications for this position are as follows:</section><section>[insert person's qualifications]</section><section>A copy of the person's resume shall be attached.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The completed form, together with the resume, shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board on or before 4:30 p.m. on the date of appointment. The Clerk's official date and time recorder stamp on the completed form shall conclusively determine date and time of submission of the form to the Clerk.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Clerk shall place appointments by the Mayor pursuant to Rule 8.1.01, together with the completed form and resume on the next regularly scheduled Commission agenda under the mayoral reports section of the agenda for Commission consideration.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notwithstanding any other rule of the Commission, appointments made by the Mayor pursuant to Rule 8.1.01 shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Not be subject to the "4-day rule" as provided in Rule 5.05(c);</section><section prefix='(2)'>Not be deferred to a future meeting;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Not require committee review;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Not be subject to a motion to reconsider, except at the same meeting; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Not require publication or public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>The Mayor shall make every effort to have the nominee attend the Commission meeting at which the appointment is presented. Commissioners may ask such questions as they deem appropriate at that time.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any Commissioner may move to disapprove a mayoral appointment made subject to this rule. A motion to disapprove a mayoral appointment shall be stated as follows:<section>"I move that the Mayor's appointment of [insert name of person appointed by the Mayor] as [insert the position to which such person was appointed by the Mayor] be disapproved."</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>If a two-thirds () majority of those Commissioners then in office vote in favor of the motion as stated in subsection (f) above, the appointment shall be deemed disapproved; otherwise, the appointment shall be deemed effective.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The provisions of this rule shall not be waived under Rule 7.01(n).</section></section><section></section><section>Notwithstanding any other rule of the Commission, the authority and powers provided to the Mayor and the Commission under D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter regarding the appointment of interim or acting department directors shall be exercised exclusively in accordance with the terms and conditions of this rule. An "interim or acting department director" shall mean a person who has been appointed by the Mayor as a department director of an administrative department of the County for a term of six months or less.<section prefix='(a)'>The Mayor shall utilize the form provided herein to appoint an interim or acting department director of an administrative department of the County. The Mayor shall personally sign a copy of the form in the place so provided and shall indicate with specificity the position, name, and qualifications of the person appointed. The form shall be as follows:<section>OFFICE OF THE MAYOR</section><section>MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA</section><section></section><section>MAYORAL APPOINTMENT</section><section></section><section>To: Honorable Chairperson and Members Board of County Commissioners Miami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>From: [Signature of Mayor]</section><section>, Mayor</section><section>Miami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>Pursuant to the authority vested in me under the provisions of Sections D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, I hereby appoint:</section><section>[insert name of person appointed]</section><section>to the position of:</section><section>[insert position to which the person is appointed].</section><section>The person's qualifications for this position are as follows:</section><section>[insert person's qualifications]</section><section>This appointment shall serve until: [insert date].</section><section>A copy of the person's resume shall be attached.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The completed form, together with the resume, shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board on or before 4:30 p.m. on the date of appointment. The Clerk's official date and time recorder stamp on the completed form shall conclusively determine date and time of submission of the form to the Clerk.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Chairperson of the County Commission may, at his or her discretion, place the appointment by the Mayor of an interim or acting department director, together with the completed form and resume on the next regularly scheduled Commission agenda under the mayoral reports section of the agenda for Commission consideration.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notwithstanding any other rule of the Commission, interim or acting appointments made by the Mayor shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Not be placed on a Commission agenda except as provided in Rule 8.1.02;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Not be subject to the "4-day rule" as provided in Rule 5.05(c);</section><section prefix='(3)'>Not be deferred to a future meeting;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Not require committee review;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Not be subject to a motion to reconsider, except at the same meeting; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Not require publication or public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>In the event the Chairperson of the County Commission places an interim or acting appointment on the Commission agenda, the Mayor shall make every effort to have the nominee attend the Commission meeting at which the appointment is presented. Commissioners may ask such questions as they deem appropriate at that time.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any Commissioner may move to disapprove a mayoral appointment made subject to this rule if said appointment is placed on the agenda by the Chairperson. In the event an interim or acting mayoral appointment of a department director is not placed on the Commission agenda by the Chairperson of the County Commission, any Commissioner may appeal the decision of the Chairperson upon a question of order, when, without debate, the presiding officer shall submit to the Commission the question: "Shall the decision of the Chairperson be sustained?" If the question to appeal the decision of the Chairperson is approved by a majority vote, a motion to disapprove the interim or acting mayoral appointment shall be in order. A motion to disapprove an interim or acting mayoral appointment shall be stated as follows:<section>"I move that the Mayor's appointment of [insert name of person appointed by the Mayor] as [insert the position to which such person was appointed by the Mayor] be disapproved."</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>If a two-thirds () majority of those Commissioners then in office vote in favor of the motion as stated in subsection (f) above, the appointment shall be deemed disapproved; otherwise, the appointment shall be deemed effective.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The provisions of this rule shall not be waived under Rule 7.01(n).</section><section prefix='(i)'>At the conclusion of the term of an interim or acting department director, any reappointment of the interim or acting director or of a new department director shall be subject to the requirements of Rule 8.1.01.</section></section><section>PART 9. ADDITIONAL ORDINANCESPRESCRIBING COUNTYCOMMISSION PROCEDURE</section><section></section><section>The mayor shall prepare and deliver a budgetary address annually to the people of the county in March. Such address shall be prepared after consulting with the budget director and shall set forth the mayor's funding priorities for the county. By July 15, the mayor shall prepare and submit a proposed budget in a line item format pursuant to containing a complete financial plan, including capital and operating budgets, for the ensuing fiscal year. Other formats, such as narrative, pie charts and graphs may also be used to supplement the line item format. The budget prepared and recommended by the mayor shall be presented by the mayor or his or her designee to the commission in a line item format pursuant to on or before the board adopts tentative millage rates for the ensuing fiscal year. A summary of the budget shall be published and the board shall hold hearings on and adopt a budget on or before the dates required by law.</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Resolutions regarding proposed naming, renaming or codesignation of Miami-Dade County roads, facilities or property shall be sponsored by the district commissioner where the property is located and shall be considered at public hearing.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Resolutions honoring outstanding individuals shall not be authorized for living individuals except as provided in subsection (d) hereof.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For every resolution honoring an individual without a personal and direct meaningful relationship to the Greater Miami area, the Board of County Commissioners shall, at the same time, honor an individual who has made a direct, significant contribution to this community.</section><section prefix='(d)'>This rule shall not prohibit the naming, renaming or designation of a facility or property after a living individual who donates a significant portion of the cost of such facility or property. Further, this rule shall not prohibit the naming, renaming or designation of a road, facility or property after a living individual who has made a direct, significant lifetime contribution to this community, provided:<section prefix='(i)'>That the naming, renaming or designation is approved by three-fifths vote of the Board members present;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>That the naming, renaming or designation is not for any elected municipal, county, state or federal official currently serving or having served in any elected office within the last five years; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>That the naming, renaming or designation of a road, facility or property in a particular commission district is limited to two times during any calendar year.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Special provisions for employees who give their lives in the line of duty. The County Manager shall present the Board of County Commissioners with a resolution proposing the naming of an appropriate public right-of-way or portion thereof in honor of any Miami-Dade County employee who gives his or her life in the line of duty. Such resolution shall be considered at public hearing and may be adopted by the Board upon a favorable vote of a majority of the commissioners present.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Commission Auditor shall complete background research, reviewing public records and other sources of information, in print, on the internet, or through other means of communication, that are publicly available, on any person, organization, place or thing that is the subject of a naming, renaming or codesignation item or an item approving the codesignation of state or municipal roads, and shall prepare a report detailing the findings of said research prior to the Commission meeting during which the item is scheduled to be considered. The Clerk of the Board shall place the Commission Auditor's report on the commission agenda as a supplement to the related agenda item.</section></section><section><section prefix='(a)'>All requests for fee reductions and waivers for the use of Vizcaya Museum and Gardens must be submitted to the board for review at a public hearing before the full Commission. Following the public hearing any such fee reductions and waivers will require a two-thirds () majority vote of the board members present. This Rule does not apply when Vizcaya Museum and Gardens' budget is fully reimbursed from another County fund for such fee reduction or waiver. The following criteria shall govern the grant of a fee waiver or reduction:<section prefix='(1)'>Fee waivers and reductions shall be granted only to major cultural, diplomatic, international, military, or other events or conferences involving heads-of-state or other similar individuals that will enhance the visibility of the County as a place to live, work, visit, or invest.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No fee waivers or reductions shall be granted for events whose purpose is, in whole or in part, to raise funds.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Fee waivers and reductions shall be granted only to not-for-profit or governmental organizations, and not to private individuals or for-profit organizations.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Fee waivers and reductions may be granted at the discretion of the Board to an organization more than once every two years, but the Board recognizes that repeat events should generally not be based on recurrent complimentary use of this fragile facility.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Organizations that are offered fee waivers and reductions shall comply with all Vizcaya Museum and Gardens facility rental rules and regulations and shall sign and be bound by the facility rental agreement, except for the provisions regarding rental fee payment and deposit.</section><section prefix='(6)'>All direct costs that result from the organization's event shall be payable by the organization directly to Vizcaya Museum and Gardens, including but not limited to tent or equipment rental, hire of police and cleanup crew, and costs of any damages or cleanup by County staff or outside vendors, unless the resolution granting the fee waiver and reduction states that the County will pay such costs to Vizcaya Museum and Gardens.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Organizations requesting a fee waiver or reduction should first attempt to find other public or private ways to fund the Vizcaya fee.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding the previous paragraph (a), the County Manager shall be permitted to:<section prefix='(1)'>Administratively reduce fees four (4) times during any calendar year and waive fees two (2) times during any calendar year for the use of Vizcaya Museum and Gardens for any nonfundraising events provided that those events are either diplomatic activities or events that benefit the entire citizenry of Miami-Dade County, and annually report the reductions and waiver to the Commission; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Waive fees for events sponsored by organizations which provide volunteer services to Vizcaya Museum and Gardens or raise funds and provide support for the maintenance of, and improvements to, Vizcaya Museum and Gardens.</section></section></section><section></section><section>All proposed expenditures from Seaport Promotional Funds over five thousand dollars ($5,000.00), other than those adopted as part of the County's annual budget ordinance, shall require a written recommendation from the County Manager together with a two-thirds () vote of the entire membership of the Board.</section><section></section><section>Whenever a Commissioner proposes a resolution, ordinance or other action of the Board that would result in a decrease in revenues, the proposal from the Commissioner must specifically designate an equal or greater reduction in expenditures or identify a project or service of equal or greater costs to be eliminated.</section><section>Whenever a Commissioner proposes an increase in expenditures above the adopted budget level, such Commissioner must concurrently propose additional revenue appropriate to fund the increased expense or an expenditure reduction equal to or greater than the amount of proposed new expense.</section><section>No final action affecting the adopted budget shall be taken if any member of the County Commission requests a recommendation from the County Manager pertaining to a budget adjustment proposed by a County Commissioner. The County Manager's recommendation shall be presented at the next regularly scheduled meeting of the County Commission.</section><section></section><section><section prefix='(1)'>The County shall hold six public meetings regarding any resolution calling an election on a proposed Home Rule Charter amendment. The Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall schedule public meetings on any such resolution proposed by the Board following the Chairperson's assignment of the items to committee or following any waiver of the committee requirement. Such public meetings shall be held prior to committee review or adoption of such resolution, if committee review is waived or not required.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the Clerk of the Circuit Court approves an initiative petition to amend the Home Rule Charter as to form, the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee shall make County-owned public facilities such as public libraries or park facilities available to the initiative petition proposers, at no cost, so that six public meetings can be conducted regarding the proposed initiative. Such meetings shall be scheduled within 60 days after the date the Clerk approves the initiative as to form.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The public meetings required in this section shall be conducted by county staff and shall be for the purpose of soliciting community input about the proposed charter amendments. Members of the public, County officials, County staff, and initiative petition proposers, if any, may be heard at such meetings.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All public meetings required hereby shall be held at locations and times which are accessible and convenient to the majority of residents in Miami-Dade County and allow for maximum participation by geographic and ethnic communities within Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All public meetings shall be appropriately advertised, including use of print advertisements in newspapers of general circulation and community based periodicals.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The provisions of this section shall be construed as directory only and failure to comply with the provisions hereof shall not affect the validity of any resolution, action of the Board, the election scheduled on any proposed charter amendment, or the timing of any initiative petition.</section></section><section></section><section>The Board shall place no more than three (3) County questions on any general election ballot that includes a presidential election.</section><section>For purposes of this rule, "County questions" shall mean straw ballot questions, commissioner-sponsored proposed amendments to the Home Rule Charter and any other questions related to the County that are proposed by the Board. This subsection shall not apply to amendments to the Home Rule Charter proposed by initiatory petition pursuant to of the Home Rule Charter. Once the Board has voted to place three (3) County questions on any general election ballot that includes a presidential election, each additional County question may be placed on such a ballot only with an affirmative vote of two-thirds () of those commissioners present.</section><section><section prefix='(a)'>Prior to entering upon the duties of the office, each newly elected or re-elected County Commissioner shall take the oath of office as set forth in Article II, Section 5(b) of the Florida Constitution or as otherwise required by law. Each Commissioner shall, at his or her option, either:<section prefix='1.'>Verbally take the oath of office; or</section><section prefix='2.'>Execute a written oath of office as set forth in substantially the form attached to this ordinance or as otherwise required by law.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The oath of office under either paragraphs (a)(1) or (a)(2) above shall be administered by a person authorized to administer the oath of office pursuant to Florida law. Such person shall sign an acknowledgement of administration of the oath of office as set forth in substantially the form attached to this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Clerk of the Board shall retain in the public records each executed written oath of office and each executed acknowledgement of administration of the oath of office.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Nothing contained in this section shall prevent the Board of County Commissioners from holding an installation ceremony for County Commissioners. At the installation ceremony, Commissioners may take a ceremonial oath of office which shall be administered at each Commissioner's option, in one of the two following ways:<section prefix='1.'>The Clerk or other official administering the oath shall state the oath of office in its entirety as set forth in Article II, Section 5(b) of the Florida Constitution or as otherwise required by law, as follows:<section>Do you (Commissioner's name) solemnly swear (or affirm) that you will support, protect, and defend the Constitution and Government of the United States and of the State of Florida; that you are duly qualified to hold office under the Constitution of the state; and that you will well and faithfully perform the duties of County Commissioner on which you are now about to enter. So help you God?</section><section>After the Clerk or other official has stated the oath in its entirety, the Commissioner shall then say "I do;" or</section></section><section prefix='2.'>The Commissioner shall repeat after the Clerk or other official administering the oath of office the oath as set forth in Article II, Section 5(b) of the Florida Constitution or as otherwise required by law.</section></section></section><section></section><section>Whenever the Commission deems it necessary or desirable that the Commission shall be represented at meetings, conferences or other occasions involving other governmental entities, agencies, officials or groups or nongovernmental organizations, or departments, agencies or officials of the County government, the Presiding Officer may designate members of the Commission to represent the Commission at such meetings, conferences or other occasions, with the consent of the designee. A majority of the board then present may disapprove any such appointment. Such representatives shall have no power to act for or on behalf of the Commission, or to make any commitment or binding obligation on behalf of the Commission or the County. Such representatives shall report in writing to the Commission with regard to such meeting, conference or other occasion.</section><section></section><section>If a procedural rule of this board is not complied with by either the Presiding Officer or the parliamentarian, then the validity of the underlying substantive ordinance, resolution, motion or other action shall in no way be affected thereby, and the failure of compliance with said procedural rule shall not be the basis for any person or party to challenge any ordinance, resolution or other action of this board.</section><section>PART 10. MAYORAL APPOINTMENT OFCOUNTY MANAGER AND OF DEPARTMENT DIRECTORS OF THE ADMINISTRATIVEDEPARTMENTS OF THE COUNTY, ANDCOMMISSION DISAPPROVAL</section><section></section><section>The authority and powers provided to the Mayor and the Commission under Sections C and D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter shall be exercised exclusively in accordance with the terms and conditions of this rule.<section prefix='(a)'>The Mayor shall utilize the form provided herein to appoint the County Manager or a department director of an administrative department of the County. The Mayor shall personally sign a copy of the form in the place so provided and shall indicate with specificity the position, name, and qualifications of the person appointed. The form shall be as follows:<section>OFFICE OF THE MAYORMIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA</section><section></section><section>MAYORAL APPOINTMENT</section><section></section><section>To: Honorable Chairperson and Members Board of County Commissioners Miami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>From: [Signature of Mayor]MayorMiami-Dade County, Florida</section><section>Pursuant to the authority vested in me under the provisions of Sections C and D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, I hereby appoint:</section><section>[insert name of person appointed]</section><section>to the position of:</section><section>[insert position to which the person is appointed].</section><section>The person's qualifications for this position are as follows:</section><section>A copy of the person's resume shall be attached.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The completed form, together with the resume, shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board on or before 4:30 p.m. on the date of appointment. The Clerk's official date and time recorder stamp on the completed form shall conclusively determine date and time of submission of the form to the Clerk.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Clerk shall place appointments by the Mayor, together with the completed form and resume on the next regularly scheduled Commission agenda under the mayoral reports section of the agenda for Commission consideration.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notwithstanding any other rule of the Commission, appointments made by the Mayor shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Not be subject to the "4-day rule" as provided in Rule 5.05(c);</section><section prefix='(2)'>Not be deferred to a future meeting;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Not require committee review;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Not be subject to a motion to reconsider, except at the same meeting; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Not require publication or public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>The Mayor shall make every effort to have the nominee attend the Commission meeting at which the appointment is presented. Commissioners may ask such questions as they deem appropriate at that time.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any Commissioner may move to disapprove a mayoral appointment made subject to this rule. A motion to disapprove a mayoral appointment shall be stated as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>"I move that the Mayor's appointment of [insert name of person appointed by the Mayor] as [insert the position to which such person was appointed by the Mayor] be disapproved."</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>If a two-thirds () majority of those Commissioners then in office vote in favor of the motion as stated in subsection (f) above, the appointment shall be deemed disapproved; otherwise, the appointment shall be deemed effective.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The provisions of this rule shall not be waived under Rule 7.01(n).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-135,  1, 2, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 02-215,  1, 10-22-02)</history></law>