<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00095' order_by='00095' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXVII. AFRICAN-AMERICAN TOURIST SITE TASK FORCE BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1052</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership, appointment and term office.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000744</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1052. Membership, appointment and term office.<section prefix='(a)'>The Task Force Board shall be composed of twenty-three (23) voting members, appointed as described below. Each member may designate a single alternate to serve and vote on his or her behalf. Members shall serve without compensation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Task Force Board shall be appointed by the Board with representatives from the following:<section prefix='(1)'>One (1) representative of each member of the Board of County Commissioners for a total of thirteen (13) representatives, to be chosen initially from the membership of the original African-American Tourist Site Task Force.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The County Manager of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Two (2) representatives from the Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce.</section><section prefix='(4)'>One (1) representative from the Miami-Dade County Public Schools.</section><section prefix='(5)'>One (1) representative from the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Two (2) representatives from the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau.</section><section prefix='(7)'>One (1) representative from the Beacon Council.</section><section prefix='(8)'>One (1) representative from the Tools for Change.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Mayor or City Manager of the City of Miami.</section></section><section>Vacancies on the Task Force Board shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community, and the segments of the community necessary to achieving the goals of the Task Force Board.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All voting members shall serve terms of three (3) years each.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No member, with the exception of ex officio members, shall be permitted to serve more that two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by two-thirds () vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners. Members may be removed in accordance with provisions of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Board of County Commissioners may, from time to time, appoint ex officio non-voting members, by resolution or motion.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Each member shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-169, ยง 1, 11-12-96)</history></law>