<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00096' order_by='00096' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXVIII. COMMISSION ON ETHICS AND PUBLIC TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1071</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization of the Ethics Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000754</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1071. Organization of the Ethics Commission.<section>The Ethics Commission shall elect one (1) of its voting members as chairperson who shall serve a term of two (2) years. No chairperson shall be permitted to serve two (2) consecutive terms.</section><section>The Ethics Commission shall hold regular, meetings in accordance with the by-laws of the Ethics Commission and the Ethics Commission may hold such other meetings as it deems necessary. Except as provided in, all meetings of the Ethics Commission shall be public and written minutes of the proceedings thereof shall be maintained by the County Commission. All actions taken at the meetings of the Ethics Commission shall be promptly and properly recorded. Copies of all minutes, resolutions, decisions or advisory opinions of the Ethics Commission shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Ethics Commission.</section><section>The Ethics Commission shall make, adopt and amend by-laws, rules of procedure which are consistent with the provisions of this ordinance and rules and regulations for the Ethics Commission's governance. The Ethics Commission shall be empowered to appoint an Executive Director and to remove such appointee at will. The Executive Director shall be a member of the Florida Bar in good standing. The Ethics Commission shall utilize a competitive selection process when selecting an Executive Director. The Ethics Commission shall fix the Executive Director's salary. The Executive Director shall be exempt from the classified service.</section><section>The Executive Director shall be empowered to appoint, remove, and suspend employees or agents of the Ethics Commission, to fix their compensation, and to adopt personnel and management policies,</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-105, ยง 1(6), 7-8-97)</history></law>