<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-10.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Competitive bidding requirement for all County bond transactions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000123</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-10.6. Competitive bidding requirement for all County bond transactions.<section prefix='(1)'>Definitions. In addition to words and terms defined within the context of this section, the following words and terms shall mean:<section prefix='(a)'>Capital before haircut means "Net Capital before haircuts on securities positions" as shown in item 3640 of each underwriting firm's focus report filed with the SEC periodically or any equivalent measure of capital established by the SEC from time to time.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Eligible amount means an underwriting firm's capital before haircut multiplied by fifteen (15), or any equivalent measure of eligibility established by the SEC from time to time.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Focus report means the monthly focus report filed by underwriting firms with the SEC or any successor report required by the SEC from time to time.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Pre-sale allocation means the bonds allocated to an underwriting firm in accordance with Sections 10(d) through 10(h) of this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Minority firm means an underwriting firm that is fifty-one (51) percent, or more, owned and controlled by blacks, females, Hispanics, or any combination of each.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Locally headquartered firm means an underwriting firm that maintains its corporate headquarters in Miami-Dade County or Broward County.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Sale of bonds. All general obligation, special obligation and revenue bonds, certificates of participation, notes and other similar obligations of the County (collectively, the "Bonds") shall be sold at public sale by competitive bid at such place or places as the Board shall determine.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Waiver of competitive sale. The provisions of Section (2) may be waived:<section prefix='(a)'>Upon both the written recommendation of the County Manager and the County's financial advisor responsible for the transaction in question, and by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Board that a waiver is in the best interest of the County, provided the written recommendation of the County Manager sets forth specific findings as to the reasons a negotiated sale is recommended; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>By an affirmative vote of two-thirds () of the entire membership of the Board, provided the Board makes specific findings as to the reasons a negotiated sale is in the best interest of the County.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Manager's Finance Committee.<section prefix='(a)'>The Manager's Finance Committee ("MFC") is established and shall be comprised of a representative of the County Manager's Office, the Water and Sewer Department, the Aviation Department, the Department of Solid Waste Management, the Seaport Department, Transit Department, and the Office of Strategic Business Management; and two (2) members from the public sector and one (1) member from the private sector to be selected by the County Manager, all of whom shall be familiar with corporate or municipal public finance. The representative of the County Manager's Office shall serve as voting Co-Chairperson and the Finance Director shall serve as a non-voting Co-Chairperson.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Attorney's Office shall serve as staff counsel to the MFC. The County's Financial Advisors shall serve in an advisory capacity pursuant to the terms of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A majority of the voting members present shall constitute a quorum for purposes of transacting business.</section><section prefix='(d)'>It shall be the responsibility of the MFC to assign the underwriting firms to a particular negotiated transaction in accordance with the terms of this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The MFC shall make recommendations to the County Manager whether a particular transaction has merit.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, codified in Section 2-11.1 of the County Code, shall be applicable to the members of the MFC.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Selection of underwriting firms pursuant to RFQ.<section prefix='(a)'>The County Manager shall issue a Request for Qualifications ("RFQ") for the selection of underwriting firms to serve as members of the County's underwriting pool (the "pool") on all negotiated transactions, prior to each pool term. All underwriting firms in the pool may serve as Senior Manager, Co-Senior Manager or Co-Manager in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No underwriting firm shall be a member of the pool if such underwriting firm is serving as one (1) of the financial advisors to the County.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Underwriting pool.<section prefix='(a)'>A pool shall be in existence for a five-year period, commencing on the effective date of the Board's approval of that pool (the "term"). A pool may be established by resolution after a RFQ proposal process is complete.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The pool shall consist of two (2) divisions of underwriting firms (the "Division" or "Divisions") categorized by their capital before haircut and their ability to senior manage. They are:<section prefix='(1)'>Division 1: (Transactions equal to seventy-five million dollars ($75,000,000.00) or less). Division 1 shall consist of underwriting firms which demonstrate the ability to senior manage transactions with an aggregate principal amount between three million seven hundred fifty thousand dollars ($3,750,000.00) and seventy-five million dollars ($75,000,000.00) based on a minimum capital before haircut equal to two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000.00) and a maximum capital before haircut equal to five million dollars ($5,000,000.00). However, underwriting firms with an average capital before haircut greater than five million dollars ($5,000,000.00) but less than ten million dollars ($10,000,000.00) (aa) may also elect to be included in Division 1 when such underwriting firm responds to the RFQ, or (bb) may elect to remain in Division 1 pursuant to the terms of Section 8(e). With the exception of unsolicited proposals which is governed by Section 13, in no event shall an underwriting firm in Division 1 senior manager a transaction with an aggregate principal amount greater than seventy-five million dollars ($75,000,000.00).</section><section prefix='(2)'>Division 2: (Transactions equal to seventy-five million one dollars ($75,000,001.00) and above) shall consist of underwriting firms which demonstrate the ability to senior manage a transaction of at least seventy-five million one dollars ($75,000,001.00) based on a minimum capital before haircut equal to five million dollars ($5,000,000.00).</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The aggregate total number of underwriting firms selected in the pool shall not exceed thirty (30) firms.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Each underwriting firm shall notify the County of an increase or decrease in its capital before haircut, as reported in its most recent Focus Report, if such increase or decrease would result in a change to the underwriting firm's Division classification ("material change") assuming such material change would continue for a period of six (6) consecutive months. Failure by the underwriting firm to notify the County in writing within ten (10) business days from the date of the Focus Report which reports the material change shall result in automatic removal from the pool.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the average capital before haircut of an underwriting firm in Division 1 is greater than five million dollars ($5,000,000.00) but less than ten million dollars ($10,000,000.00) for a period of six (6) consecutive months and is at least five million dollars ($5,000,000.00) as reported in the sixth month, the MFC shall transfer such underwriting firm to Division 2 upon written request by the underwriting firm. Any underwriting firm in Division 1 with an average capital before haircut that exceeds ten million dollars ($10,000,000.00) for a period of six (6) consecutive months shall be automatically transferred to Division 2 by the MFC; provided, however, that any underwriting firm which elected to be included in Division 1 at such time the underwriting firm responded to the RFQ, as described in Section 8(b), shall remain in Division 1 for twelve (12) months. Once transferred, an underwriting firm shall remain in Division 2 unless it is reclassified to Division 1 as provided in the next sentence. If the average capital before haircut of an underwriting firm in Division 2 decreases below five million dollars ($5,000,000.00) over a period of six (6) consecutive months, the MFC shall automatically transfer such underwriting firm to Division 1. If the average capital before haircut of an underwriting firm decreases below two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000.00) over a period of six (6) consecutive months, the MFC shall automatically remove the underwriting firm from the pool.</section><section prefix='(f)'>When an underwriting firm is transferred to another Division, its past pre-sale allocation shall be added to any pre-sale allocation allotted to such underwriting firm in its new Division. Similarly, the number of times an underwriting firm has served as Senior Manager shall be determined by adding the number of times it has served as Senior Manager in both Divisions. If an underwriting firm is moved to another Division and not all of the underwriting firms in that Division have served as Senior Manager (with the exception of unsolicited proposals), the underwriting firm shall be deemed to be the lowest rated underwriting firm for that Division.</section><section prefix='(g)'>If a vacancy occurs for any reason in the pool, there shall be no replacement for that vacancy during the remainder of the term.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Underwriting firms may be suspended or removed from the Pool upon the written recommendation of the MFC to the County Manager, who will then consider the MFC's recommendation before submitting his/her recommendation to the Board. The County Manager shall not be bound by the MFC's recommendation and may recommend to the Board the suspension or removal of an underwriting firm from the Pool without a recommendation from the MFC. Final decisions reside with the Board, which may also suspend or remove an underwriting firm without a recommendation from the MFC or the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The MFC, County Manager or the Board shall consider, among other factors, the following in evaluating whether an underwriting firm shall be suspended or removed from the Underwriting Pool:<section prefix='(1)'>Any investigation whether threatened, pending or resolved by any Federal or state authority, including the State of Florida, concerning an underwriting firm's public finance related activities, particularly any Miami-Dade transactions, as evidenced by receipt of a Wells Letter or notice of a Wells Letter received by the firm with respect to a Federal investigation and/or receipt or notice of an investigation from any state, including the State of Florida; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any civil or criminal litigation involving the firm or any of its principals relating to activities as underwriters.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>An underwriting firm shall be automatically removed from the Underwriting Pool if the underwriting firm:<section prefix='(1)'>Ceases operations due to bankruptcy; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Terminates underwriting operation activities.</section></section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Sale on a negotiated basis. Whenever the competitive bid process has been waived pursuant to the provisions of Section (3) of this section, the transaction being proposed may be sold on a negotiated basis to the underwriting firms assigned in the manner described in Section 10.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Assignment of underwriting firms to particular bond transaction.<section prefix='(a)'>Until the initial pool is established pursuant to the terms of this section, the MFC shall continue to make assignments on negotiated transactions pursuant to the provisions of Subsections (e)(2) through (6) and (10), and Subsections (f)(1) through (6) of Section 2-10.6 of the County Code in the same manner as if such provisions were still in effect.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The underwriting firms selected to the pool may serve as Senior Manager, Co-Senior Manager and Co-Manager on a rotating basis as determined by the MFC pursuant to the terms of this section. When determining the rotation, the MFC shall first consider the number of times an underwriting firm has served as Senior Manager. With the exception of unsolicited proposals, the MFC shall first select the highest rated underwriting firm for the applicable Division as Senior Manager, then the next highest rated underwriting firm for the applicable Division and so on, until all underwriting firms in each Division have served at least once as Senior Manager, provided, however, that in each case, the MFC shall also consider the criteria (excluding past pre-sale allocation of bonds) described in Subsection (c) below. In the event that two (2) or more underwriting firms which are the next highest rated have the same rating, the MFC shall select among such underwriting firms by alphabetical order. After each member of a Division has served one (1) time as Senior Manager (excluding unsolicited proposals), the MFC shall assign underwriting firms to the Senior Manager position in accordance with the criteria described in Subsection (c) below.<section>In the event an underwriting firm declines to serve in any capacity when appointed, the underwriting firm shall be credited with the pre-sale allocation and, if applicable, Senior Manager designation, in the same manner as if it had accepted the assignment.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to past pre-sale allocation of bonds, eligible amount and the number of times served as Senior Manager, the MFC shall also consider current assignments, overall workload, prior performance or nonperformance, any conflict of interest for such firm or any employee of such firm, any event which would militate against the selection of the underwriting firm pursuant to operation of this section, whether the assignment to a particular underwriting firm will cause the County to incur higher interest rates on the bonds to be sold, any information it receives pursuant to Section 10(i) and other like factors when determining the rotation of the underwriting firms. Conditioned upon meeting the other provisions of this Section 10, in each negotiated transaction, the MFC shall assign such transaction in a manner so that a minimum of thirty-five (35) percent of the total pre-sale allocation for the transaction is assigned to minority firms and/or locally headquartered firms.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Transactions with an aggregate principal amount equal to or less than seventy-five million dollars ($75,000,000.00) shall be assigned to one (1) Senior Manager (@45%), two (2) Co-Senior Managers (@20%) and three (3) Co-Managers (@5%) all selected from Division 1, subject in each case to Section 10(j) below. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if the members of the MFC by a majority vote and upon the written recommendation of the County's financial advisor assigned to the transaction, find the transaction to be too large, too complicated or the underwriting firms in Division 1 lack the experience, expertise or adequate sales force or sales capability to sell the bonds without causing the County to incur higher interest rates, the MFC shall assign the Senior Manager position (@45%) to the next eligible underwriting firm in Division 2.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Transactions with an aggregate principal amount equal to seventy-five million one dollars ($75,000,001.00) and up to and including one hundred fifty million ($150,000,000.00) shall be assigned to one (1) Senior Manager (@39%) selected from Division 2, one (1) Co-Senior Manager (@12%) selected from Division 2, two (2) Co-Senior Managers (@12%) selected from Division 1 and five (5) Co-Managers (@5%) selected from Division 1, subject in each case to Section (8)(j) below.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Transactions with an aggregate principal amount equal to one hundred fifty million one dollars ($150,000,001.00) and up to and including three hundred million dollars ($300,000,000.00) shall be assigned to one (1) Senior Manager (@33%) selected from Division 2, two (2) Co-Senior Managers (@8%) selected from Division 2, two (2) Co-Senior Managers (@8%) selected from Division 1 and seven (7) Co-Managers (@5%) selected from Division 1, subject in each case to Section (8)(j) below.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Transactions with an aggregate principal amount equal to three hundred million one dollars ($300,000,001.00) or more shall be assigned to one (1) Senior Manager (@32%) selected from Division 2, two (2) Co-Senior Managers (@8%) selected from Division 2, two (2) Co-Senior Managers (@8%) selected from Division 1 and nine (9) Co-Managers (@4%) selected from Division 1, subject in each case to Section (8)(j) below.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The bonds shall be allocated among the underwriting firms assigned pursuant to Sections (8)(d), (8)(e), (8)(f) and (8)(g) as shown in the chart below:</section></section><section></section><section> </section><section>*<section prefix='(i)'>Prior to the MFC's assignment of underwriting firms to a transaction, each underwriting firm eligible for such assignment shall respond to any request by the MFC for information material to the selection of that underwriting firm. When making an assignment, the MFC shall consider the information received from each underwriting firm and from any other source which may militate against the assignment to an underwriting firm. On the last day of each six (6) month period during the term, every member of the pool shall forward copies of their Focus Reports for each month during the six (6) month period to the Finance Director. Failure to forward such Focus Reports and any other requested material shall subject such underwriting firm to removal from the pool.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The MFC shall not select an underwriting firm as Senior Manager and no underwriting firm shall accept the assignment as Senior Manager to a bond transaction if the underwriting firm's eligible amount is not sufficient to underwrite the entire transaction. In addition, no underwriting firm shall be allocated bonds in excess of its eligible amount. If a firm's eligible amount is less than the allocation due to such firm according to the table above, the difference shall be allocated pro rata among the Co-Senior Managers.</section><section prefix='(k)'>If there are not enough eligible firms in a particular Division to complete an assignment, the MFC shall have the discretion to assign an underwriting firm from the other Division.</section><section prefix='(l)'>The MFC shall forward its recommendation for assignments on negotiated transactions to the County Manager who will then consider the MFC's recommendation prior to advancing his/her recommendation to the Board. The County Manager shall not be bound by the MFC's recommendation except that all recommendations must be consistent with the selection criteria outlined in this section. Final underwriter selection resides with the Board in accordance with Section (9) of this section.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>Award resolution. All Bonds sold to an underwriting firm in the pool must be accomplished pursuant to a resolution of the Board. The Board reserves the right to remove an underwriting firm, suspend an underwriting firm or to exercise its sole discretion and not award a particular transaction to an underwriting firm.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Post-sale review. After completion of each transaction, the participating underwriting firms shall be subject to post-sale review by the Finance Director and the County's financial advisor assigned to the matter. The criteria to be reviewed shall include, among other things, breakdown of Bonds sold at retail or to institutions, responsiveness and cooperation of individuals assigned to each aspect of the transaction, perspective concerning agreed compensation and results achieved when compared with similar credits in the same market. The MFC may, based on one (1) or more such reviews, submit a report to the Board recommending removal of any one (1) or more underwriting firms.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Unsolicited proposals.<section prefix='(a)'>It is contemplated that underwriting firms will continually monitor the County's capital needs and market opportunities and develop unsolicited proposals in order to increase the likelihood for a negotiated transaction. In the event an unsolicited proposal results in a negotiated transaction within a reasonable time of its submission, the underwriting firm that submitted the unsolicited proposal, whether a member of the underwriting pool or not, shall serve as Senior Manager, provided the underwriting firm has an eligible amount sufficient to underwrite the transaction. If the underwriting firm does not have an eligible amount sufficient to underwrite the transaction, the underwriting firm shall serve as Co-Senior Manager and shall be allocated bonds equal to its eligible amount and the difference between its eligible amount and its pre-sale allocation shall be allocated among the other members in accordance with Section (8)(j) above. Such assignment shall be made by the MFC regardless of past pre-sale allocation of bonds and the number of times such underwriting firm has served as Senior Manager.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A meritorious unsolicited proposal, must be an innovative approach to: solving a County financial problem; improving the way in which the County gains access to short or long term capital funds; or identifying new sources of security to support County debt obligations. Matters which should be routinely monitored by the County's financial advisors such as debt which should be refunded for interest cost savings will not qualify. In addition, interest rate swap recommendations will not ipso facto qualify as meritorious unsolicited proposals. An unsolicited proposal deemed meritorious by the financial advisors shall be presented to the MFC for consideration. Upon a majority vote of the MFC in favor of the unsolicited proposal, the MFC shall proceed with the selection of underwriting firms in accordance with the terms of this section.</section></section><section prefix='(12)'>Exceptions. The provisions of this section do not apply to the issuance of bonds by the Miami-Dade County Educational Facilities Authority; the Miami-Dade County Health Facilities Authority; the Housing Finance Authority of Miami-Dade County, Florida and the Miami-Dade County Industrial Development Authority.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-73, §§ 2—14, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 04-202, § 1, 11-30-04)</history></law>