<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00096' order_by='00096' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXVIII. COMMISSION ON ETHICS AND PUBLIC TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1072</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties of the Ethics Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000755</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1072. Powers and duties of the Ethics Commission.<section prefix='(a)'>The Ethics Commission shall be authorized to exercise such powers and shall be required to perform such duties as are hereinafter provided. The Ethics Commission shall be empowered to review, interpret, render advisory opinions and letters of instruction and enforce the County and municipal:<section prefix='(1)'>Code of Ethics Ordinances;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Conflict of Interest Ordinances;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Lobbyist Registration and Reporting Ordinances; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Ethical Campaign Practices Ordinances.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Ethics Commission shall be empowered to review, interpret and render advisory opinions regarding the applicability of the Citizens' Bill of Rights as provided in Section 2-1074</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Ethics Commission shall from time to time review County and municipal Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinances, Lobbyist Registration and Reporting Ordinances, Ethical Campaign Practices Ordinances, the Citizens' Bill of Rights and applicable state and federal statutes relating to ethics in government and shall report annually to the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Ethics Commission shall prepare and make available to any person a copy of ordinances within the Ethics Commission's jurisdiction and the Citizens' Bill of Rights.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The County Commission shall by resolution set a reasonable filing fee to be paid by any person filing a complaint as provided in Section 2-1074. The Ethics Commission may waive the filing fee when a complainant is indigent.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Ethics Commission shall be empowered to appoint and remove the Inspector General and exercise those powers as provided in Section 2-1076</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-105, ยง 1(7), 7-8-97; Ord. No. 97-215, ยง 1, 12-16-97; Ord. No. 98-94, ยง 2, 7-7-98)</history></law>