<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-10.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Administrative guidelines for community development block grant funds.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000121</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-10.5. Administrative guidelines for community development block grant funds.<section prefix='(a)'>The following requirements apply to those funds which the County receives under the Community Development Act of 1974 as amended for fiscal year 1982 and any other year thereafter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Office of Community and Economic Development (hereinafter "the Office") shall continue to prepare an annual community development plan in which it shall specify which projects it intends to fund, which areas will be affected, and the manner in which low and moderate income families will benefit from these projects. In addition to any plan and certifications which may be required by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, the community development plan shall contain an antidisplacement strategy which anticipates the degree of displacement created by community development activities and specifies measures the Office will undertake to alleviate these consequences.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Miami-Dade County Citizen Participation Plan adopted July 1981, is hereby incorporated by reference and attached as Exhibit A.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All plans and reports relating to the Community Development Program shall be on file at the Office and available to the public during regular working hours.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To ensure that community development funds benefit low and moderate income people, the total program benefit funded by community development block grants shall provide at least seventy-five (75) percent of its benefits to low and moderate income persons. "Low and moderate income" shall be defined as eighty (80) percent or less than the median income for the standard metropolitan statistical area of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Community development funds used for economic development projects must generate substantial long-term employment for low and moderate income people. In order to assure compliance with this purpose:<section prefix='(1)'>All proposals for the expenditure of community development funds on economic development projects shall include:<section prefix='a.'>An estimate of the number of new, permanent jobs to be created by each project.</section><section prefix='b.'>An estimated ratio for each project of new, permanent jobs created to public funds received.</section><section prefix='c.'>An estimated percentage for each project of new, permanent jobs employing low and moderate income people.</section><section prefix='d.'>A detailed implementation plan describing the mechanisms by which these targets shall be attained.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>All approved projects shall be monitored by the office for compliance with the implementation and attainment of employment targets. If, in the determination of the Office, the project Managers are not adequately adhering to the implementation plan, or otherwise not making a reasonable effort to meet the employment targets, the County shall withhold or terminate funding of the project.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No less than seventy-five (75) percent of program year funds allocated to economic development projects shall be expended on projects in low and moderate income neighborhoods.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>No more than twenty (20) percent of the total federal community development block grant budget for each project year shall be spent for local administration of this program.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The provisions of this section shall be construed as directory only, and failure to comply with the provisions hereof shall not affect the validity of any acts taken pursuant to this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 82-16, ยง 1, 3-16-82)</history></law>