<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-107</section_number>
<catch_line>Planning Advisory Board—Established; composition; compensation of members; new member orientation; annual orientation workshop.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000289</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-107. Planning Advisory Board—Established; composition; compensation of members; new member orientation; annual orientation workshop.<section prefix='(a)'>A Planning Advisory Board is hereby established. This Board shall consist of:<section prefix='(1)'>Seventeen (17) voting members appointed by the County Commission. Each County Commissioner shall nominate one (1) member. The remaining four (4) members, each of whom shall be a professional in architecture, landscape architecture, urban design, urban planning, real estate or a similar field, shall be at-large appointments. Nominations for the at-large appointments shall be submitted to the Chair of the Board of County Commissioners to be voted on by the Board. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The following nonvoting members:<section prefix='a.'>A representative appointed by the School Board of Miami-Dade County, who may attend those meetings at which the Board considers an application to amend the comprehensive plan that would, if approved, increase residential density on the property that is the subject of the application.</section><section prefix='b.'>A representative appointed by the commanding officer of the Homestead Air Reserve Base, who may attend those meetings at which the Board considers an application to amend the comprehensive plan that, if approved, would affect the intensity, density, or use of the land adjacent to or in close proximity to the military installation.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>New members of the Planning Advisory Board appointed to the Board after the effective date of this ordinance shall attend a New Member Orientation Seminar conducted by the Department of Planning and Zoning and the County Attorney's Office. The seminar shall include, but shall not be limited to, a review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, incorporation and annexation issues, and a review of applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Planning Advisory Board members.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Planning Advisory Board members shall attend an Annual Planning Advisory Board Workshop organized and conducted by the Department of Planning and Zoning and the County Attorney's Office. The Workshop shall include, but shall not be limited to, a review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, incorporation and annexation issues, and a review of applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Planning Advisory Board members.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-8, § 14.03, 8-30-57; Ord. No. 59-2, § 1, 1-20-59; Ord. No. 64-39, § 10, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 73-20, § 1, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 81-53, § 1, 5-5-81; Ord. No. 94-119, § 1, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 05-90, § 1, 5-3-05; Ord. No. 05-188, § 2, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 07-146, § 1, 10-2-07)</history></law>