<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00096' order_by='00096' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXVIII. COMMISSION ON ETHICS AND PUBLIC TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1073</section_number>
<catch_line>Financial support for the Ethics Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000756</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1073. Financial support for the Ethics Commission.<section>The Ethics Commission shall establish a fiscal year which coincides with that of Miami-Dade County, and the County shall provide the Ethics Commission with financial support pursuant to the official county budget. The Ethics Commission shall timely submit to the Board of County Commissioners an Ethics Commission budget request pertaining to operating and capital expenditures, which request shall not be implemented until approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The Ethics Commission budget request shall be prepared on official county budget forms in a format prescribed by the County Manager, shall be reviewed in a manner similar to that in which of other County departments are reviewed, and shall be incorporated in the proposed budget and timely submitted to the County Commission each year. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to prohibit the Ethics Commission from submitting to the County Commission supplemental budget requests which, if approved by the Commission, shall constitute amendments to the county budget. In addition to budgetary appropriations made by Miami-Dade County, the Ethics Commission may accept grants, contributions or appropriations from the federal government, state government, any municipality within Miami-Dade County, or any academic institution or nonprofit entity which has not entered into a contract or transacted business with the County. The Ethics Commission may accept grants, contributions or appropriations from an academic institution or nonprofit entity which has entered into a contract or transacted business with the County if the County Commission by resolution approves the grant, contribution, or appropriation. No other grants, contributions or appropriations may be accepted by the Ethics Commission.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-105, ยง 1(8), 7-8-97; Ord. No. 01-23, ยง 1, 1-23-01)</history></law>