<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XIVA. WATER SUPPLY FOR FIRE SUPPRESSION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-103.21</section_number>
<catch_line>Required fire flow; consumption.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000281</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-103.21. Required fire flow; consumption.<section prefix='(A)'>Required fire flow. The required fire flow is the rate of flow needed for firefighting purposes to confine a major fire to the buildings within a block or other contiguous group. The determination of this flow depends upon the size, construction, occupancy, and exposure of buildings within and surrounding the block or group of buildings, and upon the existence of automatic sprinkler protection. The minimum required fire flow in the various land use zone classifications shall be as listed in Table I.</section><section>A required fire flow shall be determined at appropriate locations in each district or section of the County. The minimum fire flow requirement is five hundred (500) gallons per minute (gpm) in residential areas and the maximum for a single fire is twelve thousand (12,000) gpm in principal business districts. Where local conditions indicate that consideration must be given to possible simultaneous fires, an additional two thousand (2,000) to eight thousand (8,000) gpm will be required. The required minimum duration for fire flow shall be as listed in Table II. These required fire flow rates shall be required in addition to the water flow rates necessary to supply the needs of average daily consumption.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Consumption. The average daily consumption is the average of the total amount of water used each day during a one-year period. This average, considered as a rate for a twenty-four-hour period, is the average daily consumption rate. The maximum daily consumption is the maximum total amount used during any twenty-four-hour period (in determining this figure, records for at least the past three (3) years should be used, but high consumption that will not occur again due to changes in the system or that was caused by unusual operations, such as refilling of a reservoir after cleaning, should not be considered). This maximum considered as a rate over a twenty-four-hour period, is the maximum daily consumption rate; it is the average rate of consumption on the maximum day.</section><section>When available, the actual consumption shall be used. When no record of the maximum daily consumption is available, it shall be estimated on the basis of consumption in other communities of similar character and climate, but such estimates shall be at least fifty (50) percent greater than the average daily consumption in such other communities. The consumption rate to be used shall be the total maximum daily consumption rate that passes through the pumps, filters, mains, or other facilities being considered.</section><section>TABLE I</section><section>REQUIRED FIRE FLOWS BY ZONINGCLASSIFICATION<section>Each fire hydrant shall be able to deliver its required fire flow with a loss of not more than 2.5 psi in the hydrant and a total loss of not more than 5.0 psi between the street main and the outlet.</section><section>Those municipalities whose zoning classifications differ from that of Miami-Dade County shall adapt Table I fire flows to their zoning classifications and shall submit same to the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department within sixty (60) days from the adoption of this ordinance.</section></section><section>In the event that a zoning classification is changed by a zoning resolution of the Miami-Dade County Commission or by court order which would increase the fire flow requirement, the public utility shall have one (1) year from the date of said zoning resolution or court order to deliver the required gallons per minute at 20 psi residual and to increase the flow to each fire hydrant.</section><section>TABLE II</section><section>REQUIRED DURATION FOR FIRE FLOW</section><section prefix='(C)'>All new buildings and all existing buildings being altered to increase the area or height shall have available the required number of fire hydrants as specified in the Public Works Manual D-8, connected to a public water supply which meets the fire flow requirements specified in Table I hereof except in the following instances:<section prefix='(1)'>Exemptions:<section prefix='(a)'>All duplexes and single-family detached homes not requiring water main extensions for domestic purposes. For purposes of this section, water main extensions shall mean the extension of a water supply system by installation and construction of a new water main, six (6) inches in diameter or larger, as required by the appropriate regulatory authorities or utilities.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All single-family residential structures on lots in excess of one-half acre in size, including but not limited to the zoning classifications of EU-1, EU-2, EU-M, EU-S, and EU-1C, where a public water supply is not available.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Additions to existing buildings and accessory buildings not exceeding twenty-five (25) percent of the square footage of existing structures, but in no event greater than five thousand (5,000) square feet. Furthermore, additions to existing buildings or accessory buildings, less than two thousand (2,000) square feet, shall be exempt from the terms of Section 2-103.21(C).</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Neighborhood shopping centers with buildings totaling an area of less than one hundred thousand (100,000) square feet with no building under one (1) roof of more than ten thousand (10,000) square feet, with no building exceeding two (2) stories in height, and with at least twenty-five-foot separations between buildings, shall meet fire flow requirements of at least one thousand two hundred fifty (1,250) gallons per minute.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Individual, industrial or commercial buildings or structures not part of a neighborhood shopping center or industrial park and less than five thousand (5,000) square feet in area and with low or ordinary hazard content shall meet a fire flow requirement of at least seven hundred fifty (750) gallons per minute.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In the event the rate of fire flow required under the terms of this section is not available from the water supply utility serving the property at the time of application for a building permit and none of the exemptions or qualifications noted in Section 2-103.21(C)(1) through (3) apply, then the following interim criteria will govern the issuance of building permits:<section prefix='(a)'>Properties classified as having low hazard contents and not exceeding two (2) stories in height will be required to provide a minimum of fifty (50) percent of the flow rate described in Table I of this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Properties classified as having ordinary hazard contents and not exceeding two (2) stories in height will be required to provide a minimum of sixty (60) percent of the flow rate described in Table I of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Properties classified as having low or ordinary hazard contents and having more than two (2) stories but not exceeding five (5) stories in height will be required to provide a minimum of seventy (70) percent of the flow rate described in Table I of this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Properties classified as having high hazard contents and not exceeding one (1) story in height will be required to provide a minimum of seventy (70) percent of the flow rate described in Table I of this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Properties classified as having high hazard contents and exceeding one (1) story in height will be required to provide one hundred (100) percent of the flow rate described in Table I of this section.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All properties in excess of five (5) stories in height will be required to provide one hundred (100) percent of the flow rate described in Table I.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Property classifications of hazard of content (low, ordinary and high) when utilized in this section shall be defined as set out in Section 401 of the South Florida Building Code.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>In all cases of new construction where less than the flow rate described in Table I of this section is permitted pursuant to the provisions of Section 2-103.21(C)(4), engineering and construction of new facilities to meet the total fire flow requirements as described in Table I of this section will be provided so that at the time the water utility serving the property is capable of providing full fire flow, the properties receiving said flow will be capable of utilizing the full fire flow provided by the utility.</section><section prefix='(6)'>In all cases wherein the interim criteria of Section 2-103.21(C)(4) are utilized, no less than five hundred (500) gallons per minute fire flow shall be permitted for any type of improved property and all fire flow tests will be calculated with a minimum of twenty (20) psi residual pressure remaining in the water main.</section><section prefix='(7)'>In the event the minimum fire flow requirements set out in this section cannot be met by the water supply utility servicing said property, then the applicant for a building permit shall be required to supplement those flows through an on-site or readily available system meeting the minimum fire flow requirements of this section and meeting with the approval of the Fire Department having jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(8)'>In the event that the required fire flow is not available to supply an applicant for a certificate of occupancy but it is determined by the Fire Department having jurisdiction that system improvements are in process and/or are imminent so that the applicant will be able to meet the fire flow requirements, then the Fire Department having jurisdiction may extend the time to meet the requirements of this section for an initial interim period not to exceed ninety (90) days and may authorize temporary certificates of occupancy based thereon. A bond sufficient to assure completion of the required system improvements in order to meet the fire flow requirements shall be posted by the applicant with the appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction. The amount of the bond shall be determined by the Fire Department having jurisdiction and shall be equivalent to one hundred ten (110) percent of the cost to complete the fire flow improvements.</section><section prefix='(9)'>The location and number and sizes of the fire hydrants and fire hydrant branches shall be designated by the Fire Department having jurisdiction and in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Section D-8, Water Supply.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Unobstructed access to fire hydrants or on-site private systems shall be provided and maintained to accommodate firefighting apparatus.</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Distribution systems. The supply mains shall be of adequate size and have properly arranged connections to the arterial mains which shall extend throughout the system and have numerous connections to the secondary feeders that supply the minor distribution.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Main Sizes. The minor distribution branches or systems supplying residential districts shall consist of mains at least six (6) inches in size arranged so that they form a closed loop in all areas of the distribution system. Where long unsupported length of pipe are necessary, eight-inch or larger mains shall be used. In new construction, eight-inch or larger pipe shall be used where dead ends and a poor system pattern are likely to exist for a considerable period or where the layout of the streets is not well suited to producing a closed-loop system. The use of dead-ended six-inch and smaller mains to provide fire protection shall not be permitted.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Pressure. Sufficient pressures shall be provided within the system to maintain twenty (20) psi residual pressure while providing required fire flows. In those cases where system supply design and hydrant locations are capable of meeting full domestic, commercial and fire flow demands, residual pressures of ten (10) psi will be permitted.</section><section prefix='(G)'>No person shall place or keep any post, fence, vegetation growth, trash or other material near any fire hydrant that would prevent such hydrant from being immediately seen or in any manner deter or hinder the Fire Department from gaining immediate access to a fire hydrant.</section><section prefix='(H)'>No person shall use or operate any fire hydrant or other valve on any fire system intended for use by the Fire Department for fire suppression purposes except for the purpose of extinguishing fires, unless such person secures written prior approval from the Fire Department and the public utility concerned.</section><section prefix='(I)'>No person shall remove, tamper with, or otherwise disturb any fire hydrant or firefighting appliance except for the purpose of extinguishing fires, firefighting training, or making necessary repairs without first obtaining written approval by the Fire Department.<section prefix='(J)'>(1)Prior to issuance of any building permit, approval of the building plans shall be obtained from the Fire Department having jurisdiction in accordance with the requirements set out in Section 2-103.21(C).<section prefix='(2)'>Approval or disapproval of fire suppression systems and fire flow requirements set out in Section 2-103.21(C) for the purpose of obtaining a certificate of occupancy shall be accomplished by the Fire Department having jurisdiction within two (2) weeks after receiving a written request for same by the applicant for the certificate. Such approval or disapproval shall be given in writing.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A schedule of fees to cover the cost of processing building permits, certificates of occupancy, and other services for compliance with this article shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager for the Miami-Dade County Fire Department and shall be effective upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners. Municipal fire departments having jurisdiction to enforce this article may adopt the County fee schedule or may establish a fee schedule for the particular municipality. No permit or certificate of occupancy shall be issued and no services shall be rendered until the appropriate fee, if any, is paid.</section></section></section><section prefix='(K)'>All public utilities as defined in Chapter 32 of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall submit to the Miami-Dade County Fire Department a detailed preliminary engineering study outlining the projected costs to said public utility in order to conform their systems to the provisions of this ordinance. The study shall further provide for an analysis as to the time period in which conformity to this article can be accomplished. Said reports shall be submitted by October 31, 1975.</section><section prefix='(L)'>Temporary Fire Flow Operating Permits.<section prefix='(1)'>Intent. It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners to provide a procedure whereby public water supply utilities, as defined herein, may continue to operate their facilities, even though they cannot meet the requirements for fire flow pressures and water quantities by December 31, 1977. However, it is not the intent of the Board to grant such temporary fire flow operating permit unless the utility seeking same can affirmatively show a bona fide good faith effort being made to comply with the provisions hereof as soon as is reasonably possible. The Board recognizes the difficulty in complying with the terms of this section but also recognizes the overwhelming public need for adequate fire protection to all citizens of Miami-Dade County in as expeditious a manner as good faith efforts will allow.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Applications. All water supply utilities subject to the terms of this section that have not or cannot comply with the provisions of subsections (A), (B), (D), or (F) hereof, on or before December 31, 1977, shall apply within six (6) months of the date hereof for a temporary fire flow operating permit. Said application shall be made to and on forms supplied by the Miami-Dade County Fire Department, Division of Technical Services, Fire Engineering and Water Supply Services Section, or its successor entity, division, department, or section (hereinafter referred to as Department). Said application shall contain such information as the Department requires. The Department may require the applicant to submit any additional information reasonably necessary, and may refuse to grant a permit until such time as the information is furnished and evaluated.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Grounds for permit issuance. The Department may either grant, deny, or grant the permit subject to conditions set forth within it and/or as attached to the permit. No temporary permit shall be granted by the Department unless it is affirmatively shown and the Department finds that:<section prefix='(a)'>The applicant is not in compliance with subsections (A), (B), (D), or (F) of this section; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>The applicant is either constructing, installing, or placing in operation, or has submitted plans and reasonable schedules for constructing, installing or placing in operation approved facilities to increase and meet the fire flow requirements of this section; or the applicant has or is negotiating a contract, within a reasonable time period, which would allow the applicant to receive an increased supply of water and/or water pressure within a reasonable period of time so as to comply within the terms of this section; or, the applicant is actively engaged or engaging in financial planning efforts directed specifically towards compliance with this section and with a reasonable time schedule set out for completion and implementation of said financial planning; or, the applicant is actively pursuing implementation of financial planning in a bona fide attempt to receive funds to comply with this section either through, but not limited to, utility rate relief, fire flow surcharges, federal, State or local grant applications, loan applications, special purpose taxing districts, ad valorem tax increases or otherwise; or, that the applicant has or will, within reasonable time limits, file applications with regulatory agencies to permit the construction of facilities designed to accomplish the purposes of this section; or, such other active bona fide and good faith actions on behalf of the applicant as are directed to an expeditious implementation of the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>There is no present, reasonable or alternative means of compliance with this section without the granting of the subject permit; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>The denial of a temporary operating fire flow permit would work an extreme hardship upon the applicant; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>The granting of a temporary operating fire flow permit will be in the public interest; or</section><section prefix='(f)'>The grant of such a permit will not significantly endanger the public health, safety or welfare.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Permit issuance. Any permit issued hereunder shall be on a form prescribed by the Department which shall indicate on its face or as an attachment the conditions of the grant of said permit. Said permit shall be granted for a period of time not to exceed five (5) years in duration depending upon the reasonable time schedules for compliance set by the applicant and approved by the Department. Any permit granted for a period in excess of one (1) year shall automatically include a requirement for a yearly status report by the applicant on the progress that has been made in meeting the conditions set out within the permit. Any permit issued for a period of one (1) year or less will automatically include a provision for such a report every six (6) months, or such lesser period of time as the Department deems reasonable and necessary to accomplish the purposes of this section.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Permit revocation. The Department may revoke the temporary operating fire flow permit issued hereunder upon finding that the applicant has failed to meet the conditions of the permit or that the applicant has not shown a bona fide good faith effort to comply with the terms of this section. In the event the Department determines that the permit should be revoked, it shall notify the applicant of its intent to revoke and the grounds therefor. The applicant may, within fifteen (15) days of receipt of said notice, invoke the appeal provisions of this section towards the notice of intent to revoke permit issued by the Department.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Permit renewal. Temporary operating fire flow permits may be renewed upon proper application by the affected utility utilizing the same criteria affecting original permit issuance. In addition, the Department shall also consider compliance with original permit conditions in determining whether the permit shall be renewed. Applications for permit renewal shall be made at least sixty (60) days prior to the expiration date of the existing permit.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Appeals from actions of the Department. The provisions of Section 2-103.23 shall govern appeals by any person or applicant from any decision of the Department made pursuant to this subsection.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Enforcement. The provisions of this section and enforcement of the conditions of a temporary operating fire flow permit may be enforced by the Department in the following manner:<section prefix='(a)'>The Department, by and through its enforcement agent for the implementation of the fire flow ordinance, may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to establish liability and to recover damages for any injury to persons, realty or personalty that occur as a result of violation of this subsection or in violation of any conditions contained within a temporary operating fire flow permit.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department by and through its enforcement agent for the implementation of the fire flow ordinance, may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty for each violation of this subsection in an amount of not more than five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) per offense. However, the court may receive evidence in mitigation. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Department, by and through its enforcement agent for the implementation of the fire flow ordinance, may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek injunctive relief to enforce compliance with this subsection or any condition of a temporary operating fire flow permit issued hereunder in order to prevent and mandatorily enjoin the applicant to perform the duties, responsibilities and conditions to said permit and subsection.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The enforcement remedies set out hereinabove shall be in addition and supplemental to the remedies and penalties continued within Section 1-5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, and each day a violation of the provisions of this subsection or of the conditions of a permit issued pursuant hereto shall [continue shall] constitute a separate offense for purposes of this subsection.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-96, § 2, 12-3-74; Ord. No. 75-26, § 1, 4-16-75; Ord. No. 75-64, § 1, 7-16-75; Ord. No. 75-89, § 1, 10-15-75; Ord. No. 75-104, §§ 1, 2, 11-18-75; Ord. No. 78-6, § 1, 2-7-78; Ord. No. 80-42, § 1, 5-20-80)</history></law>