<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-10.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Joint purchases by County and quasi-governmental entities surcharges.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000115</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-10.1. Joint purchases by County and quasi-governmental entities surcharges.<section prefix='(A)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>County Manager shall refer to the County Manager or his designee.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Joint purchase provision shall refer to a provision in County contract documents that County purchases shall be available to any quasi-governmental entity at the County contract price.</section><section prefix='(3)'>County purchases shall refer to the County's purchase of commodities, services or both by competitive bidding procedures.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Quasi-governmental entity shall refer to any municipality or not-for-profit organization located in the State of Florida.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Joint purchases.<section prefix='(1)'>The County may include a Joint Purchase Provision in its contract documents for County purchases.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any quasi-governmental entity utilizing a Joint Purchase Provision shall be exempt from competitive bid requirements otherwise applicable for that particular purchase.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Surcharges. In order to fund the costs of the County's procurement function, the County Manager is authorized to impose a surcharge on the purchase by a Quasi-Governmental Entity utilizing a Joint Purchase Provision. The contracts which shall be affected, the amount of the surcharge as a percentage of purchase price, and the method of collection shall be established by administrative order. The surcharges shall be deposited directly to the General Services Administration but shall be subject to appropriation as deemed necessary by the County Manager.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-41, § 1, 9-15-64; Ord. No. 98-43, §§ 1, 2, 4-21-98)</history></law>