<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-108.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Responsibilities aslocal planning agency.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000291</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-108.1. Same—Responsibilities aslocal planning agency.<section>Pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 163, Part II, Florida Statutes, the Planning Advisory Board shall serve as the local planning agency (LPA) fulfilling the following specific responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>Hold at least one (1) public hearing with due public notice on the proposed comprehensive plan, plan element or portion thereof or proposed amendment thereto, and on proposed plan evaluation and appraisal reports prepared by the Department of Planning and Zoning;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Review the proposed comprehensive plan, plan element or portion thereof or proposed amendments thereto, and the Department of Planning and Zoning's recommendations, reports on proposed amendments, and proposed plan evaluation and appraisal reports prepared by the Department of Planning and Zoning pursuant to Section 2-116, and make final recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners prior to Commission action on transmittal to the State land planning agency or final action on such proposals or reports;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Complete the preparation of evaluation and appraisal reports for submission to the Board of County Commissioners and the State land planning agency pursuant to Section 163.3191(4), Florida Statutes; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>Conduct all meetings as public meetings with records properly maintained and available to the public.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-17, § 2, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>