<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00095' order_by='00095' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXVII. AFRICAN-AMERICAN TOURIST SITE TASK FORCE BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1054</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and functions of the Task Force Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000746</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1054. Powers and functions of the Task Force Board.<section>The members shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting or relating to the designation, development and implementation of the Site.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners an annual budget and plan for use of the federal grant and other funds allocated to carry out plans for the Site.</section><section prefix='(c)'>To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners the allocations of funds to public agencies, the award of contracts and grants to organizations, entities and agencies, including independent not-for-profit corporations organized under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To review the Site recommendations on a regular basis and at least annually to assure that the Site's implementation is achieving Site goals and addressing the needs of the Community.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To evaluate performance and recommend to the Board of County Commissioners any needed amendments or modifications.</section><section prefix='(f)'>To submit annually of the Board of County Commissioners a report summarizing and evaluating the performance of all programs and activities in the Site Selection, including the timetable for performance. The report shall include an audit and accounting, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, of all funds received and expended.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-169, ยง 1, 11-12-96)</history></law>