<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-105.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Responsibility for preparation of Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000286</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-105.1. Same—Responsibility for preparation of Comprehensive Development Master Plan.<section>Pursuant to Section 4.07, Charter of Miami-Dade County, and Section 163.3174(4)(a), Florida Statutes, the Director of Planning and Zoning, with the support of the Department, shall have the responsibility to prepare the comprehensive plan and all elements thereof, and any proposed amendments which, in his discretion, warrant initiation for public hearing and consideration by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director shall also have the responsibility to make recommendations to the Planning Advisory Board in its capacity as the local planning agency as provided in, and to the Board of County Commissioners on proposed comprehensive plan amendments and on the evaluation and appraisal report (EAR) prepared pursuant to. The Director shall also have the responsibility to monitor and oversee the effectiveness and status of the comprehensive plan including the timely preparation of proposed periodic evaluation and appraisal reports required by Section 163.3191, Florida Statutes. Any such proposed comprehensive plans, elements, or portions thereof or proposed amendments thereto, and proposed evaluation and appraisal reports shall be subject to duly noticed public hearings and to recommendations by the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency, and shall be presented to the Board of County Commissioners for their consideration. The Director shall work in close coordination with the County Manager in directing the Department in the exercise of these responsibilities.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-17, § 2, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>