<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-109</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Terms of office; vacancies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000292</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-109. Same—Terms of office; vacancies.<section prefix='(a)'>The terms of office of the members of the Planning Advisory Board shall end December 31, 1994 for members nominated by the County Commissioners representing Commission Districts 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 and 12 and shall end December 31, 1996, for members nominated by the County Commissioners representing Commission Districts 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11 and 13, with appointments thereafter for terms of four (4) years each. The membership of each appointee expires when the Commissioner who nominated that member leaves office. The four at-large members shall serve terms of two (2) years each. Each member shall hold office until his or her successor has been duly appointed and qualified. Any member of the Planning Advisory Board may be removed from office at any time by two-thirds vote of the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A member's position shall become vacant when:<section prefix='(1)'>The member is absent from three (3) consecutive meetings, regardless of reason, provided that absences from emergency meetings or specially called meetings shall not count toward the attendance requirement;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The member's term expires; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>The member resigns or is removed.</section></section><section>Any vacancy occurring during the unexpired term of office of any member of the Planning Advisory Board shall be filled for the unexpired term by the County Commission within thirty (30) days after the vacancy occurs.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-8, § 14.05, 8-30-57; Ord. No. 59-2, § 1, 1-20-59; Ord. No. 94-119, § 1, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 05-188, § 3, 11-3-05)</history></law>