<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XIV. PUBLIC WORKS DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-103.15</section_number>
<catch_line>Signs in public right-of-way; prohibition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000276</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-103.15. Signs in public right-of-way; prohibition.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall erect any sign, as described above [Section 2-103.14], within the right-of-way limits of any County maintained road within the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County or any County maintained road within the municipal limits of any municipality in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Traffic signs which have been approved by the Director of the Public Works Department are exempt from this section of the Code. Such exempted signs shall not contain any commercial advertisement.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Director of the Public Works Department has the authority to direct removal of any sign in violation of paragraph (a) as provided herein:<section prefix='(1)'>If a sign is located on or within the right-of-way of a County maintained road in violation of paragraph (a) the Director shall have the authority to remove and dispose of the sign.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Director may require the owner or benefactor and/or erector of the sign to immediately remove the sign and repair any damage caused by the placement of the sign including the replacement of any tree damaged or destroyed by the placement of the sign.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>In addition to any other remedy available by law or ordinance, enforcement against the owner or benefactor and/or erector of the sign shall be as outlined in Chapter 8CC (Code Enforcement). It shall be unlawful for any person to erect any sign, as described below, within the limits of any County maintained right-of-way:<section prefix='(1)'>Illegal sign in the right-of-way affixed to a tree in such a manner as to penetrate or injure a tree. For purposes of this section the definition of sign shall include any writing or graffiti which is directly applied to a tree.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Illegal signs in the right-of-way equal to or less than 22 inches by 28 inches overall secured by any non-adhesive means including but not limited to a stake, metal rod, rope, nails, thumb tacks, bricks, or boulders in the right-of-way.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Illegal signs in the right-of-way equal to or less than 22 inches by 28 inches overall secured with any adhesive type of material including but not limited to material such as tape, glue, duct tape or paste.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Illegal signs in the right-of-way of a size greater than 22 inches by 28 inches overall regardless of sign material or method of posting or attachment.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Illegal banners, pennants, or streamers in the right-of-way.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Information contained on any sign including names, addresses or phone numbers of person benefitting from the sign shall be sufficient evidence of ownership and/or beneficial interest for purpose of the enforcement of this Section 2-103.15. It is provided, however, that a person charged with violation of this section may rebut such evidence by demonstrating the following:<section prefix='(1)'>that the person charged with violation of this section gave prior, clear and express instruction regarding the specific lawful location or locations at which the sign or signs should have been placed. Such evidence may include written documentation establishing the prior instruction regarding the intended location, identification and form of placement of the specific sign or signs.</section><section prefix='(2)'>that the sign or signs that are the subject of the charge were in fact properly and lawfully placed in accordance with the person's instruction but were moved to an unlawful location without the person's permission or authorization. Such documentation may include but is not limited to an index of signs and site maps of their assigned locations, photographs of the proper placement of the sign or signs in accordance with the person's instructions, or police information reports of missing signs identifying the original location of the sign or signs and a description of the size and design.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>The provisions of paragraph (a) above do not apply to bus benches or transit shelters, or advertising on bus benches and transit shelters, on the right-of-way of any County road, which bus benches or transit shelters have been erected for the comfort or convenience of the general public, provided written authorization has been secured from Miami-Dade County pursuant to Chapter 21, Article XII (Public and Bus Passenger Benches and Shelters), Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The provisions of paragraph (a) above do not apply to advertising placed upon waste disposal receptacles of less than one hundred ten (110) gallons in capacity erected or placed on the right-of-way of any County road, provided written authorization has been secured from the Director of the Public Works Department.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The provisions of paragraph (a) above do not apply to the Miami-Dade County program that solicits and collects donations for the County's homeless programs by and through County owned and operated Homeless Trust donation meters; provided, however, written authorization for the number, location and placement of the Homeless Trust donation meters has first been secured from the Director of the Public Works Department.</section><section prefix='(i)'>All retail stores which sell pre-printed information signs, including but not limited to signs advertising garage sales, and signs indicating that real property is for lease or sale shall post at their cashier(s) or checkout counter(s) a sign in English, Spanish and Creole that advises the customer that the placing of the foregoing type of sign in the public right-of-way is illegal and can subject a person placing such sign in a public right-of-way to a fine of up to five hundred dollars ($500.00) per violation; provided, however, first time violators shall receive a warning rather than a fine in any dollar amount.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-56, § 1, 9-1-87; Ord. No. 96-61, § 1, 5-7-96; Ord. No. 99-114, § 1, 9-9-99; Ord. No. 01-154, § 1, 9-25-01; Ord. No. 03-115, § 1, 5-6-03; Ord. No. 03-179, § 1, 7-22-03; Ord. No. 10-07, § 1, 1-21-10)</history></law>