<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-105</section_number>
<catch_line>Director—Duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000285</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-105. Director—Duties.<section>Under the supervision of the Manager and with the advice of the Planning Advisory Board, the Director shall among other things:<section prefix='(a)'>Conduct studies of County population, land use, facilities, resources, and needs and other factors which influence the County's development and on the basis of such studies prepare official and other maps and reports.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Prepare for review and public hearing by the Planning Advisory Board, and for adoption by the Commission, zoning, subdivision and related regulations for the unincorporated areas of the County and minimum standards governing zoning, subdivision, and related regulations for the municipalities.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Prepare recommendations to effectuate the master plan and to coordinate the County's proposed capital improvements with the master plan.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Review the municipal systems of planning, zoning, subdivision, and related regulations and make recommendations thereon with a view to coordinating such municipal systems with one another and with those of the County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Upon request of the Commission to the Manager conduct special surveys and studies and make reports thereon.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Promote public understanding of and interest in the master plan and community development.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Examine and approve all proposed plats and proposed local area developments.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Provide for public hearings before the Planning Advisory Board.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Have the right to enter upon any land and make examinations and surveys, and place and maintain necessary monuments and markers.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Call upon any municipal or County official to appear before the Planning Advisory Board within a reasonable length of time and to bring with him such records or information as may be requested pertaining to any matter pending before the Planning Advisory Board.</section><section prefix='(k)'>To enter into an "essentially built out" agreement with a developer and the state land planning agency where it has been finally determined that a development of regional impact ("DRI") is "essentially built out", in accordance with the procedures set forth in Section 33-303.1. Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended, and Section 380.06(15)(g)(3), Florida Statutes, as amended.</section></section><section>The Department of Planning and Zoning shall be responsible for the enforcement of the Planning and Zoning laws of the County, in accordance with the provisions of this Code, including but not limited to Sections, and 33-39.21, and shall perform such other duties and functions as the County Commission may prescribe.</section><section>The Department is authorized to charge and collect fees and furnish copies of plans, permits, and other department records to the public provided that a schedule of the type and amount of fees to be charged is first filed with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with the provisions of of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-8, § 14.02, 8-30-57; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-123, § 1, 9-21-99; Ord. No. 00-31, § 1, 2-24-00)</history></law>