<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XIV. PUBLIC WORKS DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-100</section_number>
<catch_line>Functions, powers and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000261</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-100. Functions, powers and duties.<section>The Public Works Department shall perform the following functions:<section prefix='(a)'>Plan, design, construct and maintain all arterial and other roads, bridges, tunnels, canals and related facilities in the unincorporated area of the County, as well as such other arterial and other roads, bridges, tunnels, canals and related facilities situated partially or entirely within the incorporated areas of the County, which are from time to time designated by the Manager as County arterial, or other roads, bridges, tunnels, canals or related facilities.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Develop plans and make recommendations for the establishment, merger, and abolishment of special purpose districts within which may be provided beach erosion control, water, streets, sidewalks, street lighting, sewage collection and disposal, drainage, and other essential facilities and services, and at the direction of the Commission construct, maintain, provide and administer such facilities and services.</section><section prefix='(c)'>With the cooperation of the Department of Planning and Zoning, establish and enforce minimum standards for the approval of platting or replatting of any land in the County.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Promulgate, establish and enforce minimum standards for public works construction by the publication of a public works manual. The public works manual, which shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission, shall be the official guide and standards for public works construction in Miami-Dade County, Florida. These standards shall be applicable within the unincorporated area and all incorporated areas. Variances from these standards may be granted by the Public Works Department Director where such variance will not nullify the intent and purpose of the standards to provide uniform construction requirements for the protection and safety of the general public.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Control, abate and eliminate mosquitoes and other noxious insects throughout the County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Dispose of solid waste collected throughout the County including the incorporated areas and adopt and enforce such rates and regulations as are approved by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Provide and enforce a uniform Countywide motor vehicle inspection system.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Administer lot clearing and abandoned vehicle programs.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Perform all functions previously performed by the County surveyor.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Perform any other functions reasonably necessary to, or reasonably related to, the performance of the functions hereafter designated by administrative order of the Manager.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Review plans, issue permits and inspection of paving and drainage on public right-of-way and private property in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-2, § 5.02, 8-16-57; Ord. No. 58-25, §§ 1, 2, 7-1-58; Ord. No. 68-70, § 2, 11-19-68; Ord. No. 72-60, § 1, 9-19-72; Ord. No. 78-69, §§ 1, 2, 10-17-78; Ord. No. 88-12, § 1, 3-1-88; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>