<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XIV. PUBLIC WORKS DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-103.16</section_number>
<catch_line>Articles in the public right-of-way.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000277</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-103.16. Articles in the public right-of-way.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions. For the purposes of this section:<section prefix='(1)'>Storage bin shall mean any container used for the collection, storage or distribution of personal property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Vehicle shall mean functioning automobiles, trucks, buses or trailers.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Trees shall be defined as in Section 19-3 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Public right-of-way shall mean rights-of-way in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Article shall mean any personal property, including but not limited to storage bins, and trees, except newsracks and vehicles temporarily parked in the public right-of-way.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Unless otherwise authorized by law, no person, corporation, partnership, association or other legal entity shall place any article in the public right-of-way without first having obtained a permit from the Public Works Department; provided, however, the United States, federal agencies and their contractors, the State of Florida and State agencies, in the execution of federal or State projects are exempted from the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Issuance of permit. The Department of Public Works shall have the authority to issue permits for the placement of articles in the public right-of-way in accordance with standards established in the Official Manual of the Public Works Department. In establishing standards for the placement of articles in the public right-of-way, the department shall take into consideration:<section prefix='(1)'>Pedestrian and driving safety and convenience;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Public and property safety during hurricane conditions;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Access for the use and maintenance of poles, traffic signs or signals, hydrants, and access to locations used for public transportation purposes;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Uniformity in the treatment of similar articles;</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Permit application process. Applicants for permits to place articles in the public right-of-way shall file with the Public Works Director a written application in a form prepared by the Public Works Department. If the application meets the standards set forth in the Public Works Department Manual, a permit shall be issued upon payment of the fee set forth in an administrative order. If a permit is denied, the applicant shall be notified within five (5) working days of the department's receipt of the completed application. The applicant shall be advised of the specific cause of the denial.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Public Works Department shall charge and collect permit fees at rates established by separate administrative order which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. All such fees will be used solely to defray administrative expenses incurred pursuant to this section. Any applicant who, after paying a permit fee, chooses not to place the article for which the permit was obtained in the public right-of-way shall be entitled to a refund and the permit shall be cancelled. If a permit is denied, the applicant shall be notified within five (5) working days of the department's receipt of the completed application. The applicant shall be advised of the specific cause of the denial.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Existing articles in the public right-of-way. Owners of trees and precast concrete traffic buttons existing in the public right-of-way at the time this ordinance is adopted shall not be required to obtain permits under this section but shall be required to comply with all other standards set forth in the Public Works Department Manual. Owners of other articles in the public right-of-way at the time this section is adopted shall have ninety (90) days from the date this section becomes applicable to such article within which to obtain the permit or permits required by this section.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Director of the Public Works Department shall have the authority to order the removal of any article from the public right-of-way which does not comply with this section or is otherwise in violation of the law.</section><section prefix='(h)'>In addition to any other remedy available by law or ordinance, enforcement against a person, firm, corporation or benefactor who places an article in the public right-of-way or fails to remove an article from the public right-of-way in violation of this section shall be as provided in Chapter 8CC of the Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-198, ยง 1, 11-7-95; Ord. No. 96-37, ยง 1, 2-20-96; Ord. No. 06-178, ยง 1, 12-5-06)</history></law>