<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00093' order_by='00093' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXV. FEDERAL ENTERPRISE COMMUNITY COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1025</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and functions of the Council.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000730</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1025. Powers and functions of the Council.<section>The members shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board with respect to all issues affecting or relating to the implementation of the Plan.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To recommend to the Board, in accordance with the Plan, an annual budget and plan for use of the federal grant and other funds allocated to carry out the Plan.</section><section prefix='(c)'>To recommend to the Board, in accordance with the Plan, the allocation of funds to public agencies, the award of contracts and grants to organizations, entities and agencies, including independent 501(c)(3) corporations.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To review the Plan on a regular basis and at least annually to assure that the Plan's implementation is achieving Plan goals and addressing the needs of the Enterprise Community.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To evaluate performance and recommend to the Board any needed amendments or modifications.</section><section prefix='(f)'>To submit annually to the Board of County Commissioners and the City Commissions of Miami, Florida City and Homestead, a report summarizing and evaluating the performance of all programs and activities in the Strategic Plan during the previous fiscal year, including the timetable for performance. The report shall include an audit and accounting, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, of all funds received and expended.</section><section prefix='(g)'>To monitor, review and evaluate Miami-Dade County's economic links to the Enterprise Community, including the airport and seaport and medical complex and the direct benefit to the residents of the Enterprise Community.</section><section prefix='(h)'>To submit reports required by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section><section prefix='(i)'>To monitor, review and evaluate the effectiveness of the Enterprise Community Center in its delivery of services including increasing access to capital, targeted technical assistance for businesses, job development and training.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-87, ยง 5, 6-4-96)</history></law>