<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Automatic suspension of County official charged with commission of a felony.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000131</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.3. Automatic suspension of County official charged with commission of a felony.<section>Whenever any person serving as an appointive official of the government of Miami-Dade County, including any member of a County board or agency created and appointed by the County Commission, has been charged with committing a felony under the laws of the State of Florida or the United States by indictment or information, such person shall be immediately suspended from office. Such suspension shall continue in effect until the charges shall have been finally disposed of or adjudicated by acquittal or dismissal. During the period of suspension, such person shall be disqualified from performing any of the duties and functions of his County office or position and from acting in any capacity for or on behalf of the County government. In the event such person is convicted of the charges, he or she shall be disqualified from holding any office or position under the County government. In the event such person is found not guilty of the charges, he or she may be reinstated to office by affirmative action of the official or entity responsible for making appointments to the position from which the person was suspended. During the period of such suspension, the office or position may be filled by temporary appointment for the remainder of the unexpired term or until reinstatement of the suspended official or officer, whichever is the sooner occurrence. The provisions of this section shall not be applicable to County officials holding an elective office.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-217, ยง 1, 10-24-02)</history></law>