<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00100' order_by='00100' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXII. RONALD REAGAN EQUESTRIAN CENTER COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1150</section_number>
<catch_line>Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center Council.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000788</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1150. Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center Council.<section prefix='A.'>Creation of the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center Council. There is hereby created and established the Ronald Reagan Park Equestrian Center Council (the "Council") for the purpose of providing guidance on programming and use of the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center and to report to the Board of County Commissioners the status and progress of programming and use of the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center.</section><section prefix='B.'>Authority and Mission of the Council:<section prefix='1.'>The Council shall assist with promoting the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center internationally and secure major events for this magnificent venue in order to generate revenues for the Miami-Dade County Park, Recreation, and Open Spaces Department or its successor department ("Parks Department").</section><section prefix='2.'>The Council shall have the authority to make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners. The Council shall provide an annual report, either oral or written, to the Board of County Commissioners embodying its recommendations.</section><section prefix='3.'>The Council shall have the authority to make recommendations to the Parks Department regarding programming and maximizing the use of the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center. The Council shall also provide technical and practical advice to the Parks Department regarding the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center's operations.</section><section prefix='4.'>The Council shall provide a citizens' review of the County's annual operating budget for the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center and make its budgetary recommendations to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='5.'>The Council may provide recommendations to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners concerning the reinvestment of a share of the revenues derived from the Ronald Reagan Equestrian Center for maintaining and operating the Center, as well as concerning ways to market the center as a venue for future revenue generating activities.</section><section prefix='6.'>The Council shall have no power or authority to bind Miami-Dade County to any policies, or to incur any financial obligations or to create any liability on the part of the County. The actions and recommendations of the Council are advisory only and shall not be binding upon the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor or the Parks Department.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Council Membership. The composition and representative membership of the Council shall be as follows:<section prefix='1.'>Three (3) members shall be representatives from the Miami-Dade Horse Council;</section><section prefix='2.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the Florida Paso Fino Association;</section><section prefix='3.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the Foundation for the Pure Spanish Horse;</section><section prefix='4.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the Hipico Nicaraguence Miami U.S.A.;</section><section prefix='5.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the South Florida Horse Show Association;</section><section prefix='6.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the South Florida Trail Riders Association;</section><section prefix='7.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the Southeastern Peruvian Horse Club;</section><section prefix='8.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the Miami-Dade Farm Bureau;</section><section prefix='9.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau;</section><section prefix='10.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the "Team Roping" equestrian sport;</section><section prefix='11.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the "Team Penning" equestrian sport;</section><section prefix='12.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from a cattle association;</section><section prefix='13.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the cattle ranching industry;</section><section prefix='14.'>One (1) member shall be a representative with expertise in tropical fruit crops horticulture or horticulture research;</section><section prefix='15.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the veterinary medicine industry specializing in large animals;</section><section prefix='16.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the farming/growers community;</section><section prefix='17.'>One (1) member shall be a representative of the horse breeding industry;</section><section prefix='18.'>One (1) member shall be a representative from the "Hunters or Jumpers" equestrian sport.</section><section prefix='19.'>Three (3) members shall be representatives from the equestrian or large animal trades business, supply or equipment business, transportation business, international trade business or animal genetics business.</section></section><section prefix='D.'>Qualifications of Council Members. Council Members shall be of high moral character and have demonstrated business experience and acumen in the professional category under which they are appointed.</section><section prefix='E.'>Appointment of Council Members. The Parks Department shall contact each of the entities referenced in subsection (C)(1) through (9) above, and shall request that each entity submit the name of at least one (1) interested and eligible nominee. The Parks Department shall also review the credentials of any person interested in serving as a Council Member who meets any of the criteria outlined in subsection (C)(9) through (19). The Parks Department shall submit their nominations for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='F.'>Election and Term of Office. Council Members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners shall serve a two-year term and may be reappointed by the Board of County Commissioners for subsequent terms. Council Members shall serve until the earlier of: (i) unsuccessful reappointment by the Board of County Commissioners; (ii) removal by a majority vote of the Council; or (iii) resignation from the Council. Any Council vacancies arising due to a Council Member's term expiring, removal, resignation, or otherwise shall be filled as follows: the Council shall review the credentials of any person interested in serving as a Council Member and the Council shall submit their nomination for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='G.'>Removal. Any Council Members may be removed from the Council with or without cause at any time by the vote of a majority of the Council Members present at a special meeting of the Council called for that purpose.</section><section prefix='H.'>Compensation. Members of the Council shall serve without compensation, salary or remuneration of any nature, but the County Commission may provide in the annual County budget sufficient funds for the reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by the Council in performance of its duties and functions.</section><section prefix='I.'>Organization of the Council:<section prefix='1.'>Meetings. The Council shall adopt a schedule of regular meetings. Council meetings shall be held at least quarterly pursuant to notice and at such times and places as the Council shall determine. Seven (7) members of the Council shall constitute a quorum. Special meetings of the Council may be called by the written request of five (5) members. All meetings of the Council shall be duly noticed to the public and written minutes shall be maintained.</section><section prefix='2.'>Applicability of County Rules and Procedures. The Council shall at all times operate under Florida open government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws, and public records laws, and shall be governed by all State and County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended.</section><section prefix='3.'>Attendance Requirement. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, any Council Member shall be automatically removed if, in a given fiscal year: (i) he or she is absent from three (3) Council meetings, consecutive or otherwise, without an acceptable excuse; or (ii) whether excused or not, he or she misses two-thirds () of the Council's meetings in a given fiscal year. A member shall be deemed absent from a meeting when he or she is not present at the meeting at least seventy-five (75) percent of the time. An "acceptable excuse" is defined as an absence for medical reasons, business reasons, personal reasons, or any other reason, which a majority of the Council Members present at a meeting deem appropriate. By a two-thirds () vote of the Council Members present at a meeting, the provisions of this subsection (I)(3) may be waived.</section><section prefix='4.'>Staff and Facility Support. The Park and Recreation Department shall provide such staff to support the Council as may be necessary to accomplish its purpose. The Park and Recreation Department may provide such facilities as the Council deems necessary to accomplish its purpose.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-83, ยง 1, 10-2-12)</history></law>