<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. BRANCH OFFICES OF COUNTY AUTO TAG AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-119</section_number>
<catch_line>Occupational license, approval by County Manager, prerequisites to operation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000331</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-119. Occupational license, approval by County Manager, prerequisites to operation.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person, firm, partnership, professional association or corporation operating a branch auto tag agency office and performing the functions thereof pursuant to law must have (1) authorization from the County Manager, pursuant to the provisions of this article and (2) a valid, current occupational license pursuant to this article. This section shall apply to branch auto tag agency offices in existence prior to July 1, 1994, as well as any office established subsequent thereto; provided, however, that only those branch auto tag agency offices authorized for the first time after July 1, 1994, shall be subject to the bid provisions of Section 2-120.1(a).</section><section prefix='(b)'>It is unlawful for any person, firm, partnership or corporation not authorized to operate a branch auto tag agency office pursuant to this article to advertise, name its business, or otherwise hold itself out in such a way as to represent itself as an official state or county office or agent with respect to performing the functions of an auto tag agency. The penalties for violation of this subsection are set forth in Section 2-127(a).</section><section prefix='(c)'>Automobile and/or truck dealers which are properly licensed by the State of Florida and which are in good standing with the Florida Division of Motor Vehicles may operate a Limited Branch Office solely for the purpose of issuing a vehicle registration renewal, permanent license plat, and/or title transfer only in the course of a sale or lease of a vehicle by said dealer. Prior to issuing a vehicle registration renewal, permanent license plate, and/or title transfer, the automobile and/or truck dealer must:<section prefix='(1)'>Enter into a written agreement with a currently licensed and existing branch auto tag agency, which agreement shall contain, but not be limited to, the proper procedures for issuance of auto tags and decal inventory through the Electronic Filing System. This written agreement shall be approved by and on file with the Tax Collector.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Enter into an agreement with a Valid Certified Service Provider to obtain approved software applications which will enable the dealer (Limited Branch Office) to comply properly with this article and the program standards for the Electronic Filing System as established by the Florida Tax Collectors, Inc.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Obtain written authorization from the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-135, ยง 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, ยง 1, 6-17-97)</history></law>