<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-114.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Modification of vested development.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000301</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-114.4. Modification of vested development.<section prefix='(a)'>Purpose and persons eligible to apply. An owner of property which is the subject of (1) a current, valid vested rights determination, (2) a pending application relating thereto pursuant to Sections 2-114.1, 2-114.2, or 2-114.3 of the Code, or (3) a development order approving a development of regional impact subject to the provisions of Section 163.3167(8), Florida Statutes, may file an application for modification of vested development pursuant to this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Application. An application form to accomplish the purposes of this section shall be prescribed by the Chairman of the DIC Executive Council. Such form shall require sworn information relevant and material to a determination of modification of vested development, including but not limited to:<section prefix='(1)'>A statement of the applicant establishing either the issuance of a prior final vested rights determination or a pending application pursuant to Sections 2-114.1, 2-114.2, or 2-114.3 of the Code;</section><section prefix='(2)'>A detailed description of the existing or pending vested rights determination for the particular development in question, including the period of time for which the applicant claims rights are vested and any and all conditions and limitations applicable to the asserted existing or pending application for vested right to develop;</section><section prefix='(3)'>A detailed description of the proposed change to the vested development;</section><section prefix='(4)'>A detailed comparison of the impacts on governmental facilities and services for which the CDMP establishes level of service standards, for both the vested development and the proposed modified development;</section><section prefix='(5)'>A detailed comparison of the vested development with the proposed modified development pertaining to impacts upon the environment; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>A complete itemization of governmental approvals (e.g. permits and resolutions) encompassed by the vested development as compared with those encompassed by the proposed modified development.</section></section><section>In addition to all items otherwise required by the Chairman, the applicant shall attach: (1) copies of any applicable development permits and development orders; and (2) any other documents which either support or negate the relief sought by the applicant.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Standards. A development which is the subject of a current valid vested rights determination or reaffirmation pursuant to Sections 2-114.1, 2-114.2, or 2-114.3 of the Code may be modified without the loss of vested rights upon an affirmative finding that:<section prefix='(1)'>The proposed modified development shall not generate increased impacts on any governmental facilities or services for which the CDMP establishes level or service standards, when compared with the vested development; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The proposed modified development shall not generate increased impacts on the environment when compared to the vested project.</section></section><section>If both of the foregoing standards are met, the proposed modified development may incorporate a land use not previously approved for the vested project, provided that such land use does not exceed either fifteen (15) percent of the acreage of the vested project or fifteen (15) percent of the gross floor area for the vested project, and further provided that this ordinance shall not entitle the applicant or the development to alternate or additional land use approvals, including but not limited to (i) zoning actions as defined by(1) of the Code, or (ii) a use in conflict with the land use element of the CDMP.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notice; review of application; appeal. The requirements of Section 2-114.2(e) relating to notice, and Section 2-114.2(f) relating to review of the application, shall be applicable to proceedings under this section and shall be in addition to the provisions of this section. Unless otherwise specifically provided herein or required as a matter of practicality, all standards, procedures, and requirements of Sections 2-114, 2-114.1, and 2-114.2 of the Code shall be applicable to applications and proceedings under this section and shall be in addition to the provisions hereof.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Effect of modification of vested development. If an affirmative DIC Executive Council recommendation pertaining to modification of vested development becomes a final determination, then the particular provisions of the CDMP or the County land development regulations specified in the final determination shall not limit or modify the right of the applicant to complete the particular modified development in question. A final determination of modification of vested development, however, shall not limit the applicability of any other provisions of the CDMP or any other ordinances, rules, regulations and requirements of Miami-Dade County. Nor shall the determination of modification of vested development entitle the applicant to the issuance of any development resolution or permit not specified in the final determination. The existence of a final determination of a modification of vested development shall not have any relevance to an application for any such development permit or development resolution other than to provide evidence that the development specified in said determination is subject to vested rights in relation to CDMP provisions or land development regulations specified in the determination.</section><section>An applicant who has obtained a determination regarding a modified project shall not be required to commence development of the modified project, and may elect to commence, continue or complete the vested project. However, if the modified development is commenced, the development plan for the original vested development shall stand abandoned together with any determination or reaffirmation of vested rights pertaining thereto.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-76, ยง 3, 7-24-90)</history></law>