<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00102' order_by='00102' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXIV. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY CITIZENS' TRANSPORTATION OVERSIGHT COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1162</section_number>
<catch_line>Composition and appointment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000792</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1162. Composition and appointment.<section>The Oversight Committee shall consist of sixteen (16) members. Thirteen (13) members shall be selected by the Board of County Commissioners from a slate of candidates submitted by a nominating committee as provided in(a). The additional three (3) members shall be appointed as provided in(b).<section prefix='(a)'>Nominating Committee. Thirteen (13) members of the Oversight Committee shall be appointed in the manner set forth in this subsection. A nominating committee ("Nominating Committee") comprised of at least twenty-two (22) members shall be appointed as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>The Mayor of Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Chief Judge of the Eleventh Judicial Circuit shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Mayor of each municipality with a population of 50,000 or more residents shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Executive Director of the Miami-Dade League of Cities shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce ("Greater Miami Chamber") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the Chairperson of the Greater Miami Chamber or one (1) of its members;</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Camara de Comercio Latina de los Estados Unidos ("CAMACOL") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the President of CAMACOL or one (1) of its members;</section><section prefix='(7)'>The North Dade Regional Chamber of Commerce ("North Dade Chamber") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the Chairperson of the North Dade Chamber or one (1) of its members;</section><section prefix='(8)'>The Chamber South shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the Chairperson of Chamber South or one (1) of its members;</section><section prefix='(9)'>The Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee who shall be the President of the Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce or one (1) of its members;</section><section prefix='(10)'>The President of Florida International University or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(11)'>The President of Miami-Dade Community College or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(12)'>The President of the Trust for Public Land or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(13)'>The Chairperson of the United Way or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(14)'>The Chairperson of the Champion Our Children Initiative or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(15)'>The Chairperson of the Cultural Affairs Council or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(16)'>The Chairperson of the Greater Miami Visitors and Convention Bureau or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(17)'>The Chairperson of the Urban Economic Revitalization Task Force or his or her designee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee;</section><section prefix='(18)'>The Chairperson of the Citizen's Transportation Advisory Committee shall serve as a member of the Nominating Committee; and</section><section prefix='(19)'>The Hialeah Chamber of Commerce & Industries ("Hialeah Chamber") or the Hialeah-Miami Springs Northwest Dade Area Chamber of Commerce ("Hialeah-Miami Springs Chamber") shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee. The Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution determine whether the Hialeah Chamber or the Hialeah-Miami Springs Chamber shall appoint one (1) member of the Nominating Committee.</section><section>The Nominating Committee shall submit a slate of four (4) candidates from each Commission District to the Board of County Commissioners for selection. The Board must select from the slate submitted by the Nominating Committee; however, the Board may request additional nominations.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Additional members. In addition to the thirteen (13) members of the Oversight Committee appointed pursuant to Subsection (a), the following persons shall serve on the Oversight Committee:<section prefix='(1)'>The Chairperson of the Miami-Dade County Commission on Ethics and Public Trust shall serve as a member of the Oversight Committee;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Chairperson of the Alliance for Ethical Government shall serve as a member of the Oversight Committee; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>One (1) member of the Efficiency and Competition Commission shall serve as a member of the Oversight Committee. Said member shall be appointed by the Mayor of Miami-Dade County and shall not be an elected official.</section></section></section><section>Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties. The provisions of which provide that no member of a county board shall become a candidate for elective political office during his or her term shall not apply to members of the Nominating Committee appointed pursuant to(a)(3).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-87, ยง 1, 7-27-99)</history></law>