<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00099' order_by='00099' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXI. VIZCAYA GARDENS AND MUSEUM TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1116</section_number>
<catch_line>Requirements for complete transition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000779</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1116. Requirements for complete transition.<section>The additional powers and responsibilities shall be exercised by the Trust beyond those described for the initial transition period upon the following being produced and approved by the Board of the County commissioners:<section prefix='1.'>A Transitional Plan setting forth the manner in which management of personnel, property and other resources are to be assumed by the Trust from the Park and Recreation Department.</section><section prefix='2.'>Negotiated agreements with all support groups clearly reflecting roles and responsibilities of each in relation to the Trust, including how private fund raising is to be optimized and coordinated with other funding for the benefit of the facilities. Such private fund raising shall conform with the national Standards of Philanthropy established by the National Charities Information Bureau, including the requirement that no less than sixty (60) percent of annual expenses from privately generated funds be dedicated to program activities. The fund raising shall also follow Standards for Charitable Solicitations established by the Council for Better Business Bureaus.</section><section prefix='3.'>By-laws, rules, regulations governing all of the Trust's contemplated activity.</section><section prefix='4.'>Updated mission statement as required by Section 4, Paragraph I of this agreement.</section><section prefix='5.'>Recommended standards of operations, including restoration, preservation and maintenance of the facilities.</section><section prefix='6.'>Audited financial statements for all finances relating to activities supporting the facilities and which are not reflected in the County financial statements.</section><section prefix='7.'>A report of decision-making and business activity indicating the Trusts' demonstrated ability to assume management responsibility of the facilities.</section><section prefix='8.'>A report from the County Manager attesting to compliance with this article and recommendation to proceed with the October 1, 2000 transition.</section></section><section>The above requirements shall be met no later than March 30, 2000. It shall be at the sole discretion of the Board of County Commissioners to determine, at any time, whether to proceed with the complete transition.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-112, ยง 6, 7-21-98)</history></law>