<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-114.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Reaffirmation of vested rights.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000300</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-114.3. Reaffirmation of vested rights.<section prefix='(a)'>Requirements to invoke. In lieu of the procedures set forth in Section 2-114.2 of the Code, a property owner shall be entitled to utilize the reaffirmation procedures of this section when (1) there has been a previous determination of vested rights pursuant to Sections 2-114.1 through 2-114.4 of the Code; (2) all "zoning action" (as defined in Section 33-302 of the Code) required for the development sought to be vested was in existence at the time of the previous vested rights determination or was obtained pursuant to the vested rights determination; and (3) subsequent to the prior vested rights determination, the development has received:<section prefix='(1)'>A Class IV permit within one hundred twenty (120) days; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>A building permit within one hundred twenty (120) days; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Approval of a tentative plat within ninety (90) days, approval of a final plat within an additional one hundred eighty (180) days thereafter, and a building permit within an additional ninety (90) days thereafter.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Application. An application form to accomplish the purposes of this section shall be prescribed by the Chairman of the DIC Executive Council. The form shall require information relevant and material to a determination of reaffirmation of vested rights, including but not limited to:<section prefix='(1)'>A detailed description of the particular development in question;</section><section prefix='(2)'>A complete itemization of each development permit in question;</section><section prefix='(3)'>A sworn statement by the applicant establishing issuance of the prior vested rights determination and the fulfillment of one (1) or more of the three (3) conditions described in subsection (a). The sworn statement shall have attached a copy of the prior vested rights determination and documentation establishing the extent of compliance with the conditions of that determination. The applicant shall submit with his application a letter of intent explaining the basis of his claim for reaffirmation of vested rights.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Procedure. Except as otherwise specified all standards, procedures, requirements and definitions of Sections 2-114, 2-114.1, and 2-114.2 shall be applicable to applications and proceedings under this section. An application for reaffirming of vested rights shall be filed with the DIC Coordinator. The DIC Coordinator shall verify the correctness of the application and sworn statement and shall give a notice to all County departments affected by the application. The DIC Coordinator shall, within thirty (30) days after receiving a complete application, forward a recommendation to the Chairman of the DIC Executive Council. Except as otherwise provided herein, the DIC Executive Council shall conduct its review in accordance with the standards and procedures of Sections 2-114.1, and 2-114.2. If the Chairman finds that the aforementioned conditions have been met he shall issue a reaffirmation that the prior determination of vested rights still remains in effect. This reaffirmation shall describe, with particularity, the development in question as well as any and all development permits which are vested. If the Chairman finds such conditions have not been met, he shall issue a denial of reaffirmation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Appeal. Within fourteen (14) days after the issuance of a reaffirmation of vested rights or a denial of reaffirmation, an appeal of that determination to the Board of County Commissioners may be filed pursuant to Sections 33-312 and 33-313 of the Code. The requirement to exhaust remedies, as prescribed by Section 33-316 of the Code, shall apply to the approval or denial of reaffirmation of vested rights.</section><section>Such County Commission hearing shall be after notice in accordance with of the Code, which section incorporates the notice provisions of Sections(c), (d), (e), and (f) of the Code. The Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a de novo hearing and, by resolution, issue a final vested rights reaffirmation determination pursuant to the procedures of of the Code. Judicial review shall be pursuant to of the Code.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Filing period. Any application for reaffirmation of vested rights pursuant to this section, shall be filed with the DIC Coordinator within sixty (60) days after (a) the expiration of the original determination or a reaffirmation or modification of vested rights, or (b) the applicant's failure to meet a specific timetable identified in the previous vested rights determination, reaffirmation, or modification.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-76, ยง 2, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, ยง 1, 9-4-96)</history></law>