<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.14.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Film and Entertainment Advisory Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000144</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.14.1. Film and Entertainment Advisory Board.<section prefix='(a)'>Board created. There is hereby created the Film and Entertainment Advisory Board.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Purpose. The purpose of the Board is to advise and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners and the Mayor on all matters pertaining to the film and entertainment related industries and to support and advance the interests and resources of the film and entertainment industry in Miami-Dade County for the purposes of economic and professional development; education and national and international awareness of Miami-Dade County. The Board is intended to operate as a focal point for these industries in Miami-Dade County. The Board is to provide a point of reference for the public and the County government for collection, input and dissemination of information related to these relationships with other government agencies to enhance and support the film and entertainment industries in Miami-Dade County. No decision of the Board shall be binding upon the Board of County Commissioners or the Mayor.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Membership and terms of office.<section prefix='(1)'>Membership. The Board shall consist of seventeen (17) members. Each County Commissioner and the Mayor shall appoint one (1) Board member. Additionally, one (1) Board member shall be appointed by a majority vote of the entire Board of County commissioners, and one (1) Board member shall be appointed by the League of Cities. One (1) additional Board member, who is a representative consumer of the film and entertainment industry shall be appointed by a majority vote of the entire Board of County Commissioners. Board members shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed for actual authorized expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Qualifications. Each of the members shall be individuals who have substantial knowledge and personal involvement in the film and entertainment industries. Board members should represent the following components of the industry: film, television, still photography, commercial production, music, new media. The one member selected by the Board of County Commissioners shall represent the consumers of the film and entertainment industry. All members shall satisfy the qualifications for membership set out in Section 2-11.38 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Terms. Each Board member shall be appointed to a term which shall end concurrently with the last day of the term of the Mayor or County Commissioner or other appointing authority who appointed the Board member, as provided in Section 2-38.2 of this code. The Board member appointed by the Board of County Commissioners and the Board member appointed by the League of Cities shall each serve four-year terms. If a vacancy occurs prior to the expiration of the Board member's term, the County Commissioner who appointed that member shall appoint a new member to fill the balance of the term.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Removal. Failure by any Board member to maintain the qualifications for membership set out in Section 2-11.38, failure to maintain the attendance requirements of Section 2-11.39, or a violation of the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be grounds for removal from the Board.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Procedure.<section prefix='(1)'>Chair. The Board shall have a Chairperson elected by a majority of the Board members.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Meetings. The Board shall meet at the call of the Chairperson, but in no event shall it meet less than once every three (3) months. A quorum shall consist of seven (7) members. The Board may appoint committees of at least two (2) Board members, and may include as committee members individuals who are not Board members. All actions by committees are advisory, and are not binding upon the Board, the County Manager, or the County Commission. All meetings of the Board and its committees shall comply with all requirements of the Florida "Government in the Sunshine" Law, Chapter 119, Florida Statutes, as it may be amended from time to time.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Powers. The Board shall have the power to invite individuals to address it, to hold public hearings, workshops and seminars. The Board shall have the power to solicit private sponsors for networking events which is a legitimate purpose for the Board subject to the County's Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance codified at Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Any funds contributed for such purpose shall be paid into a trust fund administered by the County Finance Department which shall be named the Film and Entertainment Advisory Board Trust Fund which shall be used to fund activities authorized by the Code with the majority vote of the Board. Other than authorized expenditures from the Film and Entertainment Advisory Board Trust Fund, the Board cannot commit itself or the County to any expenditure of funds without the specific approval of the Board of County Commissioners, or of the County Manager, under circumstances when the Board of County Commissioners has delegated that authority to him or her.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Staff. The Mayor shall provide to the Board adequate staff and support services to enable it to carry out its purposes, subject to the budget approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Reports. The Board shall submit a written report annually to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners detailing its activities during the past year and outlining its contemplated activities for the ensuing year. Additionally, such report shall specifically set forth the names and addresses of any private sponsors that contribute money or in-kind goods or services to any Board activity and the amounts of such in-kind or cash contributions made by such sponsors to any Board activity and an accounting of the funds deposited and paid out from the Film and Entertainment Advisory Board Trust Fund.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-108, § 1, 10-1-91; Ord. No. 94-8, §§ 1, 2, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 99-110, § 1, 9-9-99; Ord. No. 00-140, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 07-167, § 1, 11-6-07)</history></law>