<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-116.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Area planning reports—Board of County Commission Action.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000325</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-116.7. Area planning reports—Board of County Commission Action.<section>Following the action by the Planning Advisory Board pursuant to above, the Department shall: a) prepare its recommendations on the proposed area planning report including proposed implementation actions; and b) transmit the area planning report and the resolution of the Planning Advisory Board, together with the recommendations of the Department, through the County Manager to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>Upon receipt of the proposed area planning report and recommendations of the Department and recommendations, if any, of the planning advisory board, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing on the proposed area planning report. An advertisement of such public hearing, including the meeting time and place and a map depicting the area being studied and the purpose of the hearing shall be published in the newspaper of largest general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than seven (7) days prior to the public hearing.</section><section>At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution:<section prefix='(1)'>Accept or accept with modification, the proposed area planning report including proposed implementing actions,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Resubmit the proposed area planning report to the Department of Planning and Zoning for further consideration and for revision, or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Reject the proposed area planning report in its entirety.</section></section><section>The acceptance of an area planning report shall be by resolution and shall henceforth be referred to as the accepted area planning report.</section><section>The above actions shall in no way prejudge or predetermine the actions of the Board of County Commissioners on any amendments to the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan or other implementation actions proposed in the report that may be subsequently heard and acted upon by the Commission. Acceptance of proposed implementation actions shall be solely for the purpose of considering such actions at an appropriate future time.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-46, § 1, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>