<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00099' order_by='00099' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXI. VIZCAYA GARDENS AND MUSEUM TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1118</section_number>
<catch_line>Executive Director.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000781</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1118. Executive Director.<section prefix='(a)'>Autonomy Within Park and Recreation Department. The Director of Vizcaya Museum and Gardens shall, for the transition period, report directly to the Director of the Park and Recreation Department. In recognition of the unique status and special needs of Vizcaya, the Vizcaya Director shall be afforded the maximum degree of management autonomy within the departmental structure without compromising necessary command and control requirements. Among other matters, the Executive Director shall have the authority and responsibility to alert the County Manager to any matter necessary and essential to protect the accreditation of the Vizcaya Museum and Gardens or to comply with this article. After October 1, 2000, upon meeting the transition requirements of Section 6, the Director of Vizcaya shall report directly to the Trust.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Authority and Responsibilities. Within the confines of reasonable departmental command and control requirements, the Executive Director is authorized to conduct and manage the day-to-day operations of Vizcaya Museum and Gardens, including but not limited to:<section prefix='1.'>Maintain the property, collections, and exhibits;</section><section prefix='2.'>Manage all publications and educational programs;</section><section prefix='3.'>Administer all sales programs;</section><section prefix='4.'>Coordinate all membership, volunteer and support groups and programs;</section><section prefix='5.'>Counsel, hire, terminate, and supervise all staff and employees pursuant to Miami-Dade County personnel rules;</section><section prefix='6.'>Serve as Executive Director of the Trust;</section><section prefix='7.'>Prepare and present the annual budget for the Vizcaya Museum and Gardens to the Park and Recreation Department, the County Manager and the Board of County Commissioners, subject to the advice and recommendation of the Trust;</section><section prefix='8.'>File on behalf of Miami-Dade County all reports, applications, and documentation necessary to secure and maintain the accreditation of Vizcaya Museum and Gardens in accordance with County procedures;</section><section prefix='9.'>Apply for and in conjunction with departmental management, serve as fiscal manager of gifts and grants for Vizcaya, in accordance with County procedures;</section><section prefix='10.'>Ensure appropriate publicity and marketing;</section><section prefix='11.'>Implement policy as established by the Board of County Commissioners and the Trust; and undertake such other activities which will further the mission of the Vizcaya Museum and Gardens within the confines of adopted budgets and operating rules and regulations and through appropriate chains of command.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Removal and Appointment. The Director of the Park and Recreation Department, with the approval of the County Manager, shall have the authority to remove the Executive Director. After October 1, 1999, the Director of the Park and Recreation Department, with the approval of the County Manager and the Trust, shall have the authority to remove the Director. After October 1, 2000, upon meeting the transition requirements of Section 1116, the Trust shall have the authority to remove the Director with the concurrence of the County Manger. When a vacancy occurs, the vacancy shall be filled using the following process. No earlier than twenty (20) days and not later than forty-five (45) days from the occurrence of a vacancy, the Trust and the Director of the Park and Recreation Department shall submit the name or names of suitable candidates either jointly or individually to the County Manager, who may appoint from the list, or reject the list and request names of additional candidates. It is the intent that candidates shall be offered by the Trust and department on the basis of a competitive recruitment relying on the requisite level of appropriate experience and training. After October 1, 2000, upon meeting the transition requirements of Section 6, the Trust shall have the power to hire the Executive Director with the concurrence of the County Manager. Prior to October 1, 1999, any interim vacancy shall be filled by the Director of Park and Recreation. After October 1, 1999, any interim vacancy shall be filled by the Director of Park and Recreation, with the approval of the Trust. After October 1, 2000, any interim vacancy shall be filled by the Trust with the concurrence of the County Manager.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-112, ยง 8, 7-21-98)</history></law>