<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-115.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Agricultural Land Use Plan—Findings and legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000308</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-115.6. Agricultural Land Use Plan—Findings and legislative intent.<section>The foregoing declarations and findings are found to be true and are hereby adopted as the legislative intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and are made a part hereof. The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares and finds that it is essential to encourage and protect agriculture as a viable economic use of Miami-Dade County's land. This Board declares and finds that the agricultural land use plan provides a comprehensive framework to guide future planning, land use, and land development decisions in a manner that will minimize the adverse effects of continuing urban growth on Miami-Dade County's farmland; will help maintain a supply of land for a diversity of viable agricultural uses; will protect and enhance agriculture as a resource of economic, social and environmental importance to Miami-Dade County; will help maintain an adequate supply of land for urban uses; and will provide for continuing urban growth. It is the purpose and intent of this Board to protect the health, safety, and welfare of the present and future inhabitants of Miami-Dade County through implementation of the "final proposals" of the "Agricultural Land Use Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida," dated March 1983.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 83-24, § 1, 5-3-83)</history></law>