<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE IB. STANDARDS FOR CREATION AND REVIEW OF BOARDS GENERALLY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.38.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Term of office.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000168</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.38.2. Term of office.<section prefix='(a)'>The terms of office of the members of each board shall be staggered.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No board member shall serve more than eight (8) consecutive years on any one (1) board. The provisions of this section shall not apply to current board members. Nothing set forth in this subsection above shall prohibit any individual from being reappointed to a County board after a hiatus of two (2) years. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Board of County Commissioners may, by a resolution adopted by a two-thirds () vote of members present, waive the restriction that a particular member of a board may not serve more than eight (8) consecutive years on that board or any other term limit applicable to a particular board member.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Additionally, notwithstanding any other provision of the Code or of any resolution, the term of every board member nominated by a Commissioner shall automatically expire when:<section prefix='(1)'>The nominating Commissioner leaves office; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>The nominating Commissioner's term of office expires.</section></section><section>The provisions of this subsection shall be applicable to the terms of County Commissioners which expired in October 1998, and thereafter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-136, § 6, 12-16-80; Ord. No. 93-104, §§ 5, 7, 10-19-93; Ord. No. 93-114, §§ 6, 8, 10-21-93; Ord. No. 99-04, § 1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 10-06, § 1, 1-21-10)</history></law>