<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-116.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Area planning reports—Implementation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000326</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-116.8. Area planning reports—Implementation.<section>Following acceptance of an area planning report by the Board of County Commissioners, the Department of Planning and Zoning shall within one (1) year make official requests for the various implementing actions proposed in the report, except that 1) proposed amendments to the Urban Development Boundary of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be initiated at the next filing opportunity authorized by(2) Code of Miami-Dade County, and 2) proposed zoning changes that require prior amendments to the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be filed no later than three (3) months following the enactment of such plan amendments.</section><section>Within five (5) years after County Commission acceptance of an initial or amended area planning report, the Department of Planning and Zoning shall review the subject area planning report and prepare and provide to the Board of County Commissioners a written evaluation presenting: 1) an assessment of the success or failure in accomplishing the purposes of the subject area planning report and in implementing the recommendations contained in the report, and of the continuing applicability of the report to conditions and circumstances within, and in the vicinity of the area; and 2) any need for amendment or rescission of the report as may be warranted by any changes to such conditions and circumstances.</section><section>After receipt of the evaluation, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing on the evaluation. An advertisement of such public hearing, including the meeting time and place and a map depicting the area covered by the area planning report being evaluated and the purpose of the hearing shall be published in the newspaper of largest general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than seven (7) days prior to the public hearing.</section><section>At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Board of County Commissioners shall by resolution:<section prefix='(1)'>Accept or accept with modification, the area planning report evaluation including any need for amendment or rescission,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Resubmit the area planning report evaluation to the Department of Planning and Zoning for further consideration and for revision, or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Reject the area planning report evaluation in its entirety.</section></section><section>Following acceptance or acceptance with modification of an area planning report evaluation by the Board of County Commissioners, the Department of Planning and Zoning shall petition the County Manager for amendment or rescission of the area planning report pursuant to if a need therefor has been identified in the accepted evaluation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-46, § 1, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>