<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-115.13</section_number>
<catch_line>Citizens' Advisory Committee for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study; intent and purpose; establishment; membership; qualifications; appointment; term; duties; staff support.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000315</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-115.13. Citizens' Advisory Committee for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study; intent and purpose; establishment; membership; qualifications; appointment; term; duties; staff support.<section prefix='(1)'>Legislative intent and purpose.<section prefix='(a)'>It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County to establish a broad-based Citizens' Advisory Committee (the CAC) for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study (the Study) pursuant to policy established in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP). The purposes of the CAC and duties of its members shall be:<section prefix='(i)'>To serve as a two-way conduit of information between consultants retained to assist in the study and community interests represented by the CAC members;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>To advise the consultants and assigned County, South Florida Water Management District, and U.S. Army Corps of Engineers staff as to those views represented by the CAC members;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>To suggest information sources to the consultants; and</section><section prefix='(iv)'>To review and comment on the consultants' draft and all deliverables, including recommendations on polices, programs, and strategies.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Citizens' Advisory Committee for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study.<section prefix='(a)'>There is hereby established an advisory board to be known as the Citizens' Advisory Committee (CAC) for the Agriculture and Rural Area Study. The CAC shall be composed of sixteen (16) members appointed as follows: one representative from the row crop industry, to be recommended by the Miami-Dade County Farm Bureau; one representative from the lime and avocado industry, to be recommended by the Florida Lime and Avocado Growers Association; one representative from the tree crop industry, to be recommended by Tropical Fruit Growers of South Florida; two representatives from the nursery industry, to be recommended by the Florida Nurseryman and Growers Association; one agribusiness representative, to be recommended from the Florida Fertilizer and Agri-Chemical Association; one agri-banking representative, recommended from a bank in South Dade with significant involvement in commercial/banking aspects of the agricultural industry; one representative from and recommended by the Homestead/Florida City Chamber of Commerce; one representative from and recommended by the Redland Citizen's Association; one representative of farm labor recommended by the Coalition of Florida Farmworkers Organizations; one representative of the aquaculture industry, recommended by the South Florida Aquaculture Association; one representative of the agricultural land leasing real estate industry, to be recommended by the Agricultural Practices Study Advisory Board; one representative from and recommended by the Redland Conservancy; one representative from and recommended by the National Audubon Society; one representative from and recommended by Sierra Club; and one representative from and to be recommended by the Miami-Dade County Agri-Council.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each member shall be appointed by the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners to serve until submission of the study to the Board of County Commissioners or until replaced by the County Manager with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. Except for the provision prohibiting membership on two County boards, appointments and activities of the CAC shall otherwise comply with the requirements of Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. At its first meeting, the CAC shall elect a Chair and Vice-Chair. It is the Chair's responsibility to chair all meetings and to issue an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with Section 2-11.37(a), Code of Miami-Dade County. A simple majority of the CAC members shall constitute a quorum and a simple majority of a quorum of the CAC shall be required for the passage of any motion. The CAC shall automatically sunset upon the completion of the Study.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County Manager shall assign appropriate staff. Designated staff shall prepare necessary meeting materials and advertisements, arrange meeting locations, and undertake other responsibilities associated with staffing the CAC.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-136, ยง 1, 10-3-00)</history></law>