<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00099' order_by='00099' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXI. VIZCAYA GARDENS AND MUSEUM TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1117</section_number>
<catch_line>Budget and finances.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000780</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1117. Budget and finances.<section prefix='1.'>The Vizcaya Museum and Gardens shall be operated as a proprietary fund. Separate accounts shall be established by the County that will allow for the segregated collection, deposit, maintenance and disbursement of funds derived from the operation of Vizcaya Museum and Gardens. It is intended that funds in such established accounts shall be used for the purpose of supporting the designated facilities, however, nothing shall prevent the use of funds for reimbursement of departmental and county indirect costs in support of the facilities consistent with generally accepted accounting principles as validated by the County's independent external auditor and for Vizcaya Museum and Gardens related activities.</section><section prefix='2.'>The budget for Vizcaya Museum and Gardens shall be prepared by the Director of Vizcaya with the advice and recommendation of the Trust on official county budget forms in a format prescribed by the County Manager, and, for the transition period, shall be incorporated into the proposed budget of the Park and Recreation Department submitted to the County Manager. In the event any changes to the budget recommended by the Trust are made by any department or the County Manager, the County Manager, with the advice and recommendation of the Trust, shall ensure that the recommendations of the Trust are reported to the County Commission. Effective October 1, 2000, upon meeting the transition requirements of Section 6, the Trust shall prepare the budget for Vizcaya in accordance with this paragraph, but it shall be submitted directly to the County Manager. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to prohibit the Trust from submitting to the County Commission supplemental budget requests which, if approved by the Commission, shall constitute amendments to the official county budget.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-112, ยง 1, 7-21-98)</history></law>