<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-116.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Amendment procedure for Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000317</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-116.1. Amendment procedure for Comprehensive Development Master Plan.<section prefix='(1)'>Scope of eligibility.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person or organization, including the federal government, the State of Florida, Miami-Dade County, any municipality in Miami-Dade County and any of their agencies, authorities and departments may request the initiation of the amendatory process provided below.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the applicant has an ownership interest in any real property covered by an application to amend the land use element of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, such interest shall be disclosed in the same manner as required of zoning applicants in Section 33-304 of the Miami-Dade County Code. If the applicant is acting as agent or attorney for a principal, the principal's interest shall be disclosed in the same manner as required of zoning applicants in Section 33-304 of the Miami-Dade County Code. This subsection (b) shall not apply to governmental applicants.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Application. Except as specifically provided below for applications pursuant to a compliance agreement, pursuant to a State statutory requirement, or pursuant to a concurrently requested development of regional impact (DRI) development order or change to an existing DRI development order, or for applications relating to reuse of military bases pursuant to Chapter 288, F.S., any request for amendments, modifications, additions or changes to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be submitted to the Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or successor agency (hereinafter referred to as "the Department") during the period between May 1 and May 31 inclusive (hereinafter "May period"), and during the period between November 1 and November 30 inclusive (hereinafter "November period"), in each year only in accordance with the following provisions:<section prefix='(a)'>Applications requesting amendment to the Urban Development Boundary (UDB) or to the Urban Expansion Area (UEA) boundary depicted on the Land Use Plan map, or to the land use classification of land located outside of said Urban Development Boundary may be filed only during the May period in odd-numbered years. The Director of the Department may also file applications requesting amendments to the UDB, UEA or to the land use classification of land located outside of said UDB for processing during either the May or November period following the adoption of an evaluation and appraisal report, provided that the amendments proposed in said applications are suggested in the adopted evaluation and appraisal report.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All requests shall be made by filing an application in a form and containing the information prescribed by the Director of the Department. Applicants seeking to have their requests considered to be small-scale amendment applications, as provided in Section 163.3187, F.S., and eligible for processing in accordance with the procedures provided herein for final action, shall clearly state such request in the application. Small-scale amendment applications shall not be eligible to request amendments to modify or expand the UDB or UEA. All proposed plan amendment applications not requested for adoption as small-scale amendment applications, and all requested small-scale amendment applications which are not adopted but which are transmitted to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies for review and comment are hereby defined as standard expedited amendment applications. Applications which are deemed by the Department to be unclear or incomplete may be supplemented no later than the seventh (7th) business day following notice from the Department that the application filed is deficient.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners may, by resolution or ordinance, at any time initiate a request to amend, modify, add to or change the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, or may, by resolution or motion, authorize or direct the County Mayor to utilize the optional procedure provided in Section 288.975, F.S., and Section 2-116.1(5)(b), herein, to amend the CDMP to enable military base reuse. Except for requests by the Board of County Commissioners to amend the Comprehensive Development Master Plan in the case of a compliance agreement as provided in Section 163.3187(5). F.S., in the case of a State statutory requirement, in the case of an application necessary to authorize a Development of Regional Impact initiated by the County, in the case of an application for a small-scale amendment pursuant to Section 163.3187, F.S., in the case of an application relating to military base reuse, prepared pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., or unless otherwise provided by said resolution or ordinance, the content, activities, and time periods herein provided, as quantified by number of days, shall be substantially applicable to such a request from the date of the adoption of the resolution or ordinance. Said resolution or ordinance shall direct the County Mayor to include the special application for review and action along with May period or November period applications as provided herein or that the special application shall be reviewed and action shall be taken on a special schedule prescribed in the resolution or ordinance. In no instance shall the filing or authorization of applications by the Board of County Commissioners for processing on a special schedule result in adoption of more than two (2) Comprehensive Development Master Plan amendments in any calendar year except in the case of a concurrent approval of a Development of Regional Impact as provided in Section 380.06(6)(b), F.S., approval of a small-scale amendment as provided in Section 163.3187, F.S., a compliance agreement as provided in Section 163.3187(1)(e), F.S., or utilization of the optional CDMP amendment procedure for military base reuse as provided in Section 288.975, F.S.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In the event that the Board of County Commissioners has entered into a compliance agreement pursuant to Section 163.3184(6), F.S., requiring the filing of an application to amend, modify, add to or change the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall file an application pursuant to the terms of the approved settlement agreement in accordance with the content, activities and time periods provided by the terms of the compliance agreement and by the resolution approving such agreement and in accordance with the procedures provided in Section 163.3184(6), F.S.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Procedure upon application; Director of Regulatory and Economic Resources, Community Councils, Planning Advisory Board (PAB), and Board of County Commissioners; or applications pursuant to a compliance agreement.<section prefix='(a)'>Upon receipt of an application for amendment, modification, addition or change to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, the Director of the Department shall consult with other County personnel, departments or agencies, a municipality or County having jurisdiction over or adjacent to the area in question as he deems necessary to evaluate the proposed application. Each application may be deemed by the Board of County Commissioners to include similarly situated or adjoining property which could be affected by the adoption of the request in whole or in part, except that no such determination by the Board of County Commissioners shall cause a requested small-scale amendment to exceed the conditions for such amendments enumerated in Section 163.3187(1)(e), F.S.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director of the Department shall prepare an applications report listing all applications received, including small-scale amendment applications and staff applications, including the nature of the application and the reasons stated for requesting the proposed amendment, modification, addition or change. The report shall also itemize proposals suggested and under evaluation by the Department staff; however, this initial identification of staff proposals shall not preclude further staff proposals. Such staff proposals, except those initiated in direct response to the written comments submitted by the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., shall be finalized no later than the advertised notice of the public hearing to be conducted by the Community Councils pursuant to Section 2-116.1(3)(e), Code of Miami-Dade County. Further staff proposals initiated in direct response to the written comments submitted by the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies shall be finalized no later than two weeks prior to the date of the Board of County Commissioners final public hearing pursuant to Section 2-116.1(4)(b), Code of Miami-Dade County. The Department and the local planning agency are authorized to recommend, and the Board of County Commissioners is authorized to adopt, CDMP amendments with changes to include, (a) similarly situated or adjoining property which could be affected by the adoption of a request, (b) staff proposals in whole or in part as provided in this section, (c) changes within the scope of the applications and staff proposals, or (d) changes to ensure internal consistency among plan elements, applications or staff proposals.<section>On or before June 21st following the filing of May period applications and December 21st following the filing of November period applications, the applications report shall be submitted to the Planning Advisory Board and directly impacted Community Councils as determined by the Director of the Department and shall be available to the public at the same time. Any small-scale application may be withdrawn by written notice by the applicant filed with the Director on or before the deadline established in paragraph (3)(f) for formulation of recommendations by the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency, and any standard or transmitted application may be withdrawn by written notice by the applicant filed with the Director on or before the deadline for formulation of final recommendations by the Department. After these dates a withdrawal may be authorized only by affirmative vote of the Board of County Commissioners. However, in no instance shall a filing fee be refunded unless timely request for withdrawal and refund is filed in accordance with paragraph (8), herein.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>For the purposes of preparing the initial recommendations of the Department, the Director shall request an evaluation from all county departments and agencies responsible for supplying and maintaining infrastructure and services relevant to the CDMP as determined by the Director. Such departments and agencies shall respond with a written evaluation of the estimated incremental and cumulative impact on Miami-Dade County for bringing such infrastructure and services to the area as well as the costs of annually operating and maintaining such infrastructure and services. The evaluation shall estimate the extent to which the costs of the required infrastructure and services will be borne by the described property or will require general taxpayer support, and an estimate of the amount of such support. The Director shall also request a similar report from non-County authorities and agencies which may be affected by a proposed land use change including but not limited to the Metropolitan Planning Organization, Miami-Dade County Public School District, and the South Florida Water Management District. The Director shall consider responses received in writing by any person or organization, on or before the tenth (10th) day in July following the filing of May period applications and on or before the tenth (10th) day of January following the filing of November period applications. The Director shall also consider and evaluate the information presented at any public workshops which are held in accordance with this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>On or before the twenty-fifth (25th) day in August following the filing of May period applications and the twenty-fifth (25th) day of February following the filing of November period applications, the Department shall issue its initial recommendations on the applications. The initial recommendations of the Department shall refer to each application specifically or as combined with other similar applications and shall consider all comments, information and recommendations received in accordance with paragraph (c) above. The initial recommendations of the Department are not necessarily limited to specific applications but may deal with any aspect of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.<section prefix='(1)'>The proposed future land use plan map designation of the subject property; the boundary of the subject property and its location in relation to the surrounding street and thoroughfare network shall be shown on (a) map(s);</section><section prefix='(2)'>The land use designations of the subject property and abutting properties currently designated on the future land use plan map shall be shown on (a) map(s);</section><section prefix='(3)'>The size of the subject property in acres or fractions thereof shall be indicated;</section><section prefix='(4)'>A description of the availability of, and the demand on, the following public facilities shall be included: sanitary sewer, solid waste, drainage, potable water, traffic circulation and recreation, as appropriate, and any others deemed appropriate by the Director; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>Information regarding the compatibility of the proposed land use amendments with the objectives and policies of the land use element and those of other affected elements.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Each Community Council may at its option conduct one (1) public hearing per amendment cycle to address proposed CDMP amendment applications, or portions thereof that would directly impact the Council's area as determined by the Director of the Department. All Community Council hearings on CDMP amendment applications shall occur either during September following the filing of May period applications or during March following the filing of November period applications. Upon conclusion of a public hearing addressing CDMP amendment applications, the Community Council may, at its option, make recommendations to the Planning Advisory Board and the Board of County Commissioners on the applications. Recommendations may address the decisions to be made by the Board of County Commissioners regarding transmittal of the applicable applications to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies for review and comment, and regarding ultimate adoption, adoption with change, or denial of the applicable applications. Public hearings of Community Councils shall be advertised in the manner provided in the "Requirements for the Conduct of Community Council's Non-Zoning Business" adopted by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, A decision by any Community Council not to conduct a public hearing or not to adopt recommendations within the time frame established in this paragraph shall not preclude the Planning Advisory Board acting as the Local Planning Agency, or the Board of County Commissioners, from conducting public hearings or taking actions required by this section. In the event that the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance or resolution authorizes or requests a committee, board, council or similar entity to review proposed CDMP amendment applications, such reviews shall also occur during September following the filing of May period applications and during March following the filing of November period applications.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency shall hold one (1) public hearing in October following the filing of May period applications and in April following the filing of November period applications. Such public hearings shall be preceded by a notice of the time, place and purpose of such hearing published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than ten (10) days prior to the date of the hearing. In the event that the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency determines it to be necessary or desirable, it may continue the hearing to one (1) or more additional dates during the same month in which the hearing commenced. No additional public notice shall be required for the continued hearing, provided that the date and time are announced at the hearing being continued. The purpose of the public hearing shall be to receive public comments and to address the amendment applications, the initial recommendations of the Department, and the questions of, (1) the adoption of requested small-scale amendment applications, (2) transmittal of the standard expedited applications, and (3) transmittal of the State coordinated review applications. and any small-scale amendment applications not recommended for adoption to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies for review pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., and (4) subsequent approval of transmitted applications, by the Board of County Commissioners. At the conclusion of each public hearing conducted pursuant to this paragraph, the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency shall issue recommendations regarding adoption of any small-scale amendment requests, recommendations regarding transmittal by the Board of County Commissioners, to State agencies for review pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., of the expedited standard amendment applications. State coordinated review applications and any small-scale amendment applications not recommended for adoption, and recommendations regarding subsequent final action by the Board of County Commissioners on the transmitted plan amendment(s).</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall hold one public hearing during November following the filing of May period applications and during May following the filing of November period applications. Hearing(s) held pursuant to this paragraph shall be advertised in accordance with Section 163.3184(11)(b), F.S., and shall be held on a weekday not less than ten (10) days after the day that the advertisement is published. At these hearings the Department shall present to the Board the listing of applications filed pursuant to Section 2-116.1(3)(b), Code of Miami-Dade County, and the Board shall consider the adoption or adoption with change of any requested small-scale amendments, the transmittal of the expedited standard amendment applications and the transmittal of the State coordinated review amendment applications to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies and any requested small-scale amendments not adopted. If any requested small-scale amendments will be considered for adoption at a public hearing conducted pursuant to this paragraph, the Department shall, prior to said hearing, submit to the Board of County Commissioners an ordinance for first reading providing for Commission action on said small-scale amendments. The action to adopt any small-scale amendment to the CDMP shall be by ordinance enacted only upon vote of the majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds () of members present, but not less than seven affirmative votes. The transmittal action shall be taken by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. The decision to transmit shall be by affirmative vote of not less than a majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Following the adoption of the resolution pertaining to transmittal, the Board may consider the approval on first reading of one (1) or more ordinances to subsequently take final action on the transmitted applications. The Board of County Commissioners hereby authorizes and directs the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee to transmit all documents and information required by Sections 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S., following the hearing, on behalf of the Board.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The Department shall evaluate all of the information received at the transmittal hearing or within thirty (30) days after action by Board of County Commissioners addressing transmittal of the applications and may present final recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Procedures for final actions after transmittal to state review agencies. After the County Mayor or his designee transmits the applications instructed by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to foregoing paragraph 3(g), subsequent County actions shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall conduct one (1) or more advertised public hearings not later than forty-five (45) days after receipt of comments from the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies, unless a greater time period is deemed necessary by the Director. At such hearing(s) the Board of County Commissioners shall take final action to adopt, adopt with changes or not adopt each of the applications. Any changes must be within the scope of the applications filed and the proposals made pursuant to, and as authorized by, Sections 2-116.1(2)(a), (b), (c), and (d), and (3)(a) and (b), Code of Miami-Dade County, or within the scope of the written comments submitted by the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(6)(3) and (4), F.S. The deadline established in this paragraph may be extended by sixty (60) days where all pending plan amendments are proposed to implement an adopted evaluation and appraisal report of the CDMP.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All public hearings conducted by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to foregoing paragraph (4)(a) to take final action on applications to amend the CDMP shall be advertised in the manner required by Section 163.3184(11), F.S. All such hearings shall be held on a weekday approximately ten (10) days after the date that the advertisement is published. All amendments, modifications, additions or changes to the comprehensive development master plan shall be by ordinance enacted only upon vote of the majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office, except that any decision to include any additional land within the Urban Development Boundary, or to redesignate to an urban use any land located outside the UDB shall require a vote of two-thirds () of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds () of members present, but not less than seven affirmative votes. Findings, if any, made by the Board of County Commissioners which are not included in the ordinance adopting plan amendments and which provided the basis for adoption or determination not to adopt shall be transmitted to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies with the adopted amendments. In addition, the Department shall prepare for transmittal a statement in support of the Commission's actions indicating the relationship, if any, of the changes not previously reviewed by the State Land Planning Agency and other reviewing agencies to the comments submitted by said agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S. The County Mayor or the Mayor's designee is hereby authorized and directed to transmit, on behalf of the Board, the adopted amendments, adopting ordinance and all other necessary information and documents required by Section 163.3184(3)(c)2. and (4), F.S. Copies of adopted proposals shall be transmitted by the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee to said agency after adoption pursuant to Section 163.3184(3) and (4), F.S.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Applications filed pursuant to a compliance agreement, concurrent approval of a Development of Regional Impact (DRI), or to enable reuse of a military base designated for closure or closed by the Federal Government. Notwithstanding other requirements of this subsection, any application filed pursuant to a compliance agreement as provided in Section 163.3184(6), F.S., shall be subject only to the procedural requirements for such applications found in Section 163.3184, F.S., and to the procedural requirements of the resolution or other action of the Board of County Commissioners approving the filing of such application. Applications which are subject to concurrent approval of, or change to, a development of regional impact development order shall be subject only to the procedural requirements for such applications provided in Section 380.06(6)(b), F.S., and in Section 2-116.1(5)(a)(1) through (7), herein.<section prefix='(a)'>Procedure for amendment concurrently with Development of Regional Impact Development Order, Applications related to a proposed development of regional impact (DRI) including requests for approval of a substantial deviation from an approved DRI, may be filed at times other than May and November as provided by Section 380.06(6)(b), F.S., in instances where a CDMP amendment would be necessitated by the DRI approval sought. Such applications shall be processed in accordance with the following provisions:<section prefix='(1)'>Whenever an applicant for a DRI development order seeks a related amendment to the CDMP, the applicant must inform the Director of the Department of the amendment requested by filing an application in the form prescribed by the Director pursuant to this section. The application must be accompanied by a copy of the letter submitted to the regional planning council applying for DRI development approval, the data and analysis and any other information specified at the preapplication conference with the regional planning council staff, or its successor agency, upon which the County can determine whether or not to transmit the proposed CDMP amendment pursuant to Section 163.3184(4), F.S. The application filing date is hereby deemed to be the later of the dates on which the Director of the Department receives a completed CDMP amendment application, or the date on which the Director receives notification from the regional planning council or its successor agency that the application for development approval is sufficient,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where an application directly impacts a Community Council as determined by the Director of the Department, the subject Community Council shall be provided with an opportunity to conduct a public hearing and issue recommendations on the application in the manner set forth in paragraph 2-116.1(3)(e), herein; provided, however, such hearing and review shall take place within twenty (20) days after an application is filed pursuant to this paragraph and before the public hearing conducted by the Local Planning Agency. The Planning Advisory Board acting as the Local Planning Agency (LPA) shall conduct a public hearing to address the application not later than thirty (30) days after an application is filed pursuant to this paragraph. This public hearing shall be noticed in accordance with the notice provisions contained in Section 2-116.1(3)(f), herein. At the conclusion of the public hearing, the LPA shall issue the following to the Board of County Commissioners: (1) recommendations regarding transmittal of the application by the Board of County Commissioners to the State review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184(3), F.S.; and (2) recommendations regarding subsequent final action by the Board of County Commissioners on the plan amendment(s) being proposed for transmittal to the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Not later than sixty (60) days after the filing of an application pursuant to this paragraph, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing and make a determination on the transmittal of the application pursuant to Section 163.3184(4), F.S. The public hearing shall be advertised once not later than thirty (30) days after the filing of the application in the manner required by Section 163.3184(11), F.S., for the advertisement of public hearings at which the Board of County Commissioners will consider the transmittal of proposed plan amendments. The transmittal actions of the Board of County Commissioners and the transmittal by the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall occur in the manner prescribed in Section 2-116.1(3)(g), herein, for transmittal of applications filed during May and November CDMP amendment filing periods.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall take final action on the application filed pursuant to this paragraph at the same public hearing as it acts upon the application for approval of or the proposed change to, the DRI development order. However, the Board of County Commissioners shall take action separately on the application for development approval or the proposed change and on the CDMP amendment. This public hearing shall occur no sooner than thirty (30) days and no later than sixty (60) days after receipt of the response from the State Land Planning Agency and other review agencies pursuant to Section 163.3184, F.S. This public hearing to consider amending the CDMP shall be advertised in the manner prescribed in Section 163.3184(11), F.S., for the advertisement of public hearings at which the Board of County Commissioners will consider adoption of CDMP amendments.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Board of County Commissioners actions to transmit, adopt, or adopt with changes any application filed pursuant to this paragraph shall be by affirmative vote of not less than a majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office, except that any decision to include any additional land within the Urban Development Boundary, or to redesignate to urban use any land outside the Urban Development Boundary, or to modify the Urban Expansion Area boundary shall require the affirmative vote of two-thirds () of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds () of members present but not less than seven affirmative votes.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The deadlines established in paragraphs 2-116.1(5)(a)(2) through (4), above, may be extended only at the written request of the applicant received by the Director of the Department prior to the earliest of the dates that the Department submits public hearing advertisements for newspaper publication or mails hearing notices to neighboring property owners. After this date, such written requests may be approved only by motion by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Procedure for amendments implementing military base reuse plans, pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S. Notwithstanding other requirements of this section, applications requesting amendments to the CDMP, to enable base reuse activities authorized by a base reuse plan approved by record of decision issued by the military branch having jurisdiction over a military base which has been closed or which is designated for closure or realignment, may be filed and approved in accordance with the optional procedures provided in Section 288.975, F.S., and in Section 2-116.1(5)(b) through (5)(b)(12), herein, if authorized by the Board of County Commissioners or County Mayor as provided in paragraph (5)(b)(1). CDMP amendments necessary to initially adopt the military base reuse plan pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., shall be exempt from the limitation on frequency of plan amendments contained in Section 2-116.1(2), herein.<section prefix='(1)'>Any decision by Miami-Dade County to use the optional procedure established in Section 288.975, F.S., shall be made by motion or resolution by the Board of County Commissioners. Such decisions shall be made not less than seven (7) days prior to the deadline established in Section 288.975(3), F.S., for issuing notice of intent to the State Land Planning Agency of the County's intent to use the optional procedure provided in Section 288.975, F.S. If a decision is made to use the optional procedure, the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall, within the time frame established in Section 288.975(3), F.S., notify the State Land Planning Agency in writing; by hand delivery or return receipt requested, of the County's intent to use the optional provisions of Section 288.975, F.S. The Board of County Commissioners or County Mayor may designate a County agency to have principal responsibility to manage the facility or County portion thereof (hereinafter the base management agency). Any written notice issued by the Miami-Dade County Aviation Department to the State Land Planning Agency prior to the effective date of this provision indicating Miami-Dade County's intent to use the optional procedures provided in Section 288.975, F.S,, is hereby deemed sufficient and approved.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whenever Miami-Dade County shall be the host local government as defined in Section 288.975(2)(d), F.S., (a) the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or successor agency shall coordinate all CDMP amendment activities in close consultation with, and with the assistance of, the designated base management agency, if any, and (b) the Department, or the Aviation Department solely in the case of Homestead Air Reserve Base, shall request the State Land Planning Agency to coordinate a presubmission workshop in Miami- Dade County pursuant to Section 288.975(8), F.S. The Department and base management agency shall be the Miami-Dade County agencies with which the State Land Planning Agency shall coordinate the workshop, and the County shall request the State Land Planning Agency to invite all Miami-Dade County agencies represented on the Miami-Dade County Developmental Impact Committee (DIC) to attend.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Application to amend the CDMP shall be filed with the Department in a form prescribed by the Director pursuant to Section 2-116.1(2)(b), herein, and shall contain all information required by Section 288.975(4)(a) through (4)(e), F.S., and all information necessary to ensure consistency as required by Section 288.975(7), F.S. If all information data and analysis required by Section 288.975, F.S., Chapter 163, Part 2, F.S. and administrative rules adopted thereunder, are not submitted with the application initially submitted, the initial application shall contain a scope of work and schedule for production of all such supporting information, deemed necessary by the Director, for submission on a date specified by the Director which will ensure timely submittal to, and analysis by, the Department and review by the Planning Advisory Board, but not later than the last day of the ninth month following issuance of notice pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(1), herein. Applications shall be deemed by the Director to be complete upon his confirmation that the application content and supporting information, data, and analyses reasonably respond to the requirements of laws referenced herein. Completion of an application shall not preclude the preparation or submittal of additional information, data, or analyses by the applicant or Department, or recommendations by the Department for submittal of additional information.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Upon receipt of an application, the Director may distribute the application to the Director of the MPO Secretariat and to other County agencies he deems necessary for review and comment on aspects of the application which pertain to matters under the jurisdiction of the agency and which are within the scope of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Any such requested comments shall be returned to the Director by the director of the requested agency or his designee on a date specified by the Director in his request.</section><section prefix='(4.5)'>Not later than seventy (70) days prior to the due date for transmittal of a proposed plan pursuant to Section 288.975(9), F.S., the Director shall submit to the Planning Advisory Board, acting as the Local Planning Agency (LPA), and any Community Council(s) directly impacted by the application as determined by the Director of the Department, the complete application along with supporting information, data and analyses or summaries thereof. The Director shall submit the Department's initial recommendations on the application not less than ten (10) days before the respective public hearing(s) conducted pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(5) and (6), herein. In formulating its initial recommendations, the Department shall consider the supporting information submitted by the applicant, government agencies, and timely public comments. The initial recommendations shall reflect consideration of the factors and information noted in Section 2-116.1(3)(d), herein. The Director's recommendations may suggest changes to the application as filed, may address subsequent adoption of the application with or without changes, may recommend production of additional supporting analyses or information, and may recommend an alternative schedule for submission of the application to state review agencies if changes to the application or production of addition information is recommended.</section><section prefix='(5)'>At least six (6) weeks before the date scheduled for the Board of County Commissioners public hearing to be conducted pursuant to Section 2- 116.1(5)(b)(7), herein, the Community Council(s) directly impacted, as determined by the Director, by an application filed pursuant to this section may at its option conduct a public hearing and issue recommendations addressing the proposed amendments. The public hearing shall occur in the manner set forth in paragraph 2-116.1(3)(e), herein; provided, however, such hearing and review shall occur during the period provided in this paragraph, and before the hearing conducted by the Local Planning Agency.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA shall conduct one (1) public hearing at least three (3) weeks before the date scheduled for the Board of County Commissioners public hearing to be conducted pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(7), herein, and approximately ten (10) days after publication of an advertisement in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. If it finds it necessary, the LPA may continue the public hearing once to a date not later than three (3) weeks prior to the date scheduled for the Board of County Commissioners hearing. No additional public notice shall be required for the continued hearing provided that the date and time are announced at the hearing being continued. The purpose of the public hearing shall be to receive public comments on the CDMP amendment proposals contained in the application and to address the initial recommendations of the Department, the questions of transmittal of the amendment proposals to State agencies for review pursuant to Section 288.975(9)(a), F.S., and subsequent adoption of the proposed amendments by the Board of County Commissioners, or if justified and necessary in accordance with Section 288.975(9), F.S., a request for an extension of the deadline for transmitting the proposed amendments to the State review agencies. At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA shall issue recommendations regarding transmittal of the amendment proposals to the State for review, and recommendations regarding subsequent final action by the Board of County Commissioners to adopt, adopt with changes, or not adopt the proposed amendments contained in the application, or if necessary to comply with Section 288.975, F.S., to recommend that the Commission request an extension of the deadline for submission.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall hold one (1) public hearing not later than fifty (50) weeks after the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee submits notice to the State Land Planning Agency of Miami-Dade County's intent to use the optional provisions of Section 288.975, F.S. The hearing held pursuant to this paragraph shall be advertised in accordance with Section 163.3184(11), F.S., and shall be held on a weekday approximately ten (10) days after the day that the advertisement is published. At this hearing the Board shall consider transmitting to the State agencies listed in Section 288.975(8), F.S., (hereinafter State review agencies) a copy of the amendments proposed pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., or petitioning the secretary of the State Land Planning Agency for an extension of the deadline if justified and necessary, in conformance with Section 288.975(9)(b), F.S. The transmittal action shall be taken by approving on first reading an ordinance to take final action on the proposed amendments. The Board of County Commissioners shall take final action after future public hearing to occur after State review agencies have received the transmitted proposed amendments and had opportunity to review and comment. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Section, petition for extension of the deadline may be approved by motion approved by majority of a quorum of the Board of County Commissioners in attendance at any meeting of the Board of justified and necessary in conformance with Section 288.975(9)(b), F.S, The County Mayor or the Mayor's designee is authorized and directed to transmit to the state review agencies the amendments authorized by approval at first reading along with all supporting information required by Section 288.975 and Chapter 163, Part 2, F.S., and pertinent administrative rules adopted pursuant thereto. Transmittal shall occur by hand delivery, or certified or express mail service, with return receipt, not later than ten (10) days after approval of transmittal by the Board of County Commissioners, and the transmittal letter shall specify that all State review agencies shall return comments directly to the Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or successor agency as the County's coordinator of the CDMP amendment process. Not more than five (5) days after transmittal of the proposed plan amendments to the State, the Department shall cause the commencement of the State review period to be advertised in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County with invitation for public comments to be submitted to the Department within sixty (60) days after publication of this advertisement. Miami-Dade County shall consider all comments received not later than sixty (60) days after publication of this advertisement. If a listed State review agency has not provided comments within seventy (70) days after transmittal, the Director may determine that comments have not been timely provided and that no objection has been issued by that agency and he may proceed to schedule the activities listed in following paragraphs (8) through (12), herein.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Not later than fourteen (14) days after the Department receives comments from all State review agencies or the Director determines that no additional comments are timely as provided in foregoing paragraph (7), the Department, in consultation with the base management agency and any other agencies deemed appropriate by the Director shall issue to the LPA revised recommendations for the Board of County Commissioners to adopt, adopt with changes, or not adopt the proposed amendments.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Not later than thirty (30) days after the Department determines that it has received all timely comments from the listed State review agencies, the Planning Advisory Board acting as the LPA shall conduct a duly noticed public hearing. The purpose of the public hearing shall be to receive public comments on the proposed amendments, on the initial recommendation of the LPA issued prior to transmittal, on any comments received from State review agencies, on the current recommendations of the Department, and on the questions of adoption by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., and to formulate its revised recommendations. In the event that the LPA determines it to be necessary, it may continue the hearing to a date not later than thirty-five (35) days after the Department has received timely comments from the listed State review agencies. No additional public notice shall be required for the continued public hearing, if any, provided that the date and time are announced at the hearing being continued. At the conclusion of the public hearing the Planning Advisory Board acting as the local planning agency shall deliberate and formulate final recommendations. The Department may also modify its previous recommendations. If the Local Planning Agency has issued recommendations prior to transmittal, failure by the Local Planning Agency to timely conduct a public hearing or issue recommendations pursuant to this paragraph shall not preclude the Board of County Commissioners from conducting a public hearing and taking final action pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(b)(10), herein.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Not later than sixty (60) days after the Department has received timely comments from all of the State review agencies, the Board of County Commissioners shall conduct a public hearing and shall take final action to adopt, adopt with changes or not to adopt the proposed amendments. Any such changes must be within the scope of the application filed and the proposals made pursuant to, and as authorized by, Section 2-116.1, Code of Miami-Dade County, or within the scope of the written comments received from the State review agencies or other affected persons pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S. The public hearing conducted by the Board of County Commissioners to take final action on the proposed amendments to the CDMP shall be advertised in the manner required by Section 163.3184(11), F.S. The hearing shall be held on a weekday approximately ten (10) days after the date that the advertisement is published. All amendments, modifications, additions or changes to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall be by ordinance enacted only upon vote of the majority of the total membership of the County Commission then in office, except that any decision to include any additional land within the Urban Development Boundary (UDB), or to redesignate land outside the UDB to an urban use, or to include or exclude any land within the Urban Expansion Area boundary, shall require a vote of two-thirds () of the total membership of the County Commission then in office. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, any decision to make amendments, modifications, additions, or changes to a declaration of restrictive covenants that was accepted in connection with a prior application to amend the CDMP shall require a vote of two-thirds () of members present, but not less than seven affirmative votes.<section prefix='(b)'>Whenever the sixty-day period prescribed in the preceding paragraph is waived pursuant to Florida Statutes, the time for the taking of final action upon a proposed amendment implementing a military base reuse plan shall be extended through and including one hundred seventy-nine (179) days after the sixty-day period prescribed by the preceding subsection 2-116.1(5)(b)(10)(a). It is the express intent of this subsection to permit, inter alia, further consideration of an application, even after "final action" under subsection (10)(a). In the event that a hearing under subsection (10)(a) is concluded and a further hearing on the merits is held under this subsection (10)(b), all advertising and other requirements of subsection (10)(a) shall separately apply to such further public hearing. It is provided, however, that once a public hearing is advertised, the same may be recessed without the requirement of further advertisement if the date, time and place of the continuation of the hearing are announced during the hearing at the time the matter is recessed.</section></section><section prefix='(11)'>Within ten (10) days after adoption of CDMP amendments, the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall forward a copy of the adopted amendments to any affected local government and regional and State agencies that submitted comments on the proposed plan amendments. In addition the Department shall publish notice in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County indicating how and where a copy of the Plan amendments may be obtained or inspected. The County Mayor and County Attorney, in consultation with the Director of the Department and the director of the base management agency, are hereby authorized and instructed to resolve any challenge or dispute which may resolve any challenge or dispute which may arise pursuant to Section 288.975(12), F.S. Miami-Dade County shall utilize the procedures established in Section 288.975(12) through (12)(d), F.S., to resolve any such challenge.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Not later than one hundred thirty-five (135) days following adoption of the base reuse CDMP amendments by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 288.975, F.S., and resolution of any petitions filed pertaining to the amendments, the County Mayor, in consultation with the Directors of the Department, base management agency, and other affected County agencies, shall submit for first reading by the Board of County Commissioners any ordinances necessary to create or amend Miami-Dade County's land development regulations necessary to fully implement the CDMP amendments adopted pursuant to Section 12-116.1(5)(b), herein.</section></section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Optional Public Workshops. At any time prior to final action by the Board of County Commissioners, the Board of County Commissioners, Planning Advisory Board or Department may conduct public workshops in addition to the public hearings required by this Section. Any such public workshop shall be advertised in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least once seven (7) to fourteen (14) days prior to the date of the workshop.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Consideration of economic reports, appraisals, etc. No economic reports or studies, real estate appraisals or reports, and/or written reports of consultants or other experts shall be considered as evidence by either the Planning Advisory Board, the Department, or the Board of County Commissioners during their consideration of final action on the amendments unless filed with the Director not later than thirty (30) days after the Board of County Commissioners takes action to transmit the subject proposed application(s) to the State review agencies. Submittal of such reports after this date is hereby authorized only to respond to comments submitted after this date by the State Land Planning Agency or its successor or delegates. This deadline may be waived to permit the submission of such materials addressing matters other than the comments of the State Land Planning Agency only after an affirmative vote of the Board of County Commissioners which may approve such submittal of material upon a demonstration by any interested party that an injustice will occur.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Schedule of fees. All fees charged for filing, processing and evaluating applications requesting amendments to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan by the Department are established by separate administrative order which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. In approving the administrative order, the Board shall consider the cost to the county in processing amendments to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Fees will be returned to any applicant who requests an application withdrawal on or before the fifth work day following the deadlines established in this section for filing applications, or the actual date of filing of an application pursuant to Section 2-116.1(5)(a)(1), herein. After these dates no fees shall be returned to any applicant withdrawing their application without express approval by the Board of County Commissioners. Such administrative order shall also provide that a portion of the fee will be returned to the applicant for any application which is not eligible for adoption as a small-scale amendment application and which is denied transmittal by the Board of County Commissioners to the State Land Planning Agency or its successor or designees pursuant to paragraph 2-116.1(3)(g) of this section.</section><section prefix='(9)'>No applicant or applicant's representative seeking a recommendation for approval or approval of an amendment to the land use map shall be permitted to argue or represent to the Board of County Commissioners or other recommending County board that the property which is the subject of the application will be put to a specific use or uses or to exclude a use or uses authorized by the proposed land use designation, unless the applicant has submitted a restrictive covenant committing to such representation which has been submitted to the Director and has received approval as to form. This subsection shall not apply, however, if a CDMP amendment is being reviewed concurrently with an application seeking approval or modification of a Development of Regional Impact ("DRI") development order, if the proposed DRI development order application incorporates an Application for Development Approval ("ADA") or Notification of Proposed Change ("NOPC") with the express restrictions limiting development in the same manner as represented by the applicant in the CDMP amendment process.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Adjustment of dates. Regarding all dates and time computations contained in this section, except those pertaining to advertising dates, when the last day of a time period falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or official County holiday, that time period will be expanded to include the following business day.</section><section prefix='(11)'>All references in this Section to Florida Statutes shall also refer to any amendments thereto and successor legislation or rules.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The foregoing procedure shall be the exclusive procedure for amending all elements of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP); however, annual updates to the capital improvements element schedule of improvements shall not be deemed to be amendments to the CDMP and may be made by ordinance of the Board of County Commissioners without regard to foregoing subsections (1) through (7).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-4,  3, 1-20-76; Ord. No. 76-95,  2, 10-19-76; Ord. No. 78-48,  2, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 78-49,  1, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 78-50,  1, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 78-85,  1, 11-21-78; Ord. No. 86-97,  2, 12-16-86; Ord. No. 88-18,  2, 4-5-88; Ord. No. 89-24,  2, 4-4-89; Ord. No. 89-66,  3, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 89-121,  1, 12-5-89; Ord. No. 90-2,  2, 1-16-90; Ord. No. 90-19,  1, 3-6-90; Ord. No. 90-111,  1, 9-25-90; Ord. No. 90-135,  1, 12-4-90; Ord. No. 92-17,  3, 3-17-92; Ord. No. 92-120,  1, 10-13-92; Ord. No. 93-23,  2, 3-30-93; Ord. No. 93-131,  2, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-69,  1, 4-18-95; Ord. No. 95-96,  1, 6-6-95; Ord. No. 95-215,  1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-104,  1, 7-2-96; Ord. No. 97-150,  1, 9-9-97; Ord. No. 98-125,  1, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 98-143,  11, 9-18-98; Ord. No. 99-30,  1, 3-18-99; Ord. No. 00-50,  1, 4-11-00; Ord. No. 01-163,  1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 03-40,  1, 3-11-03; Ord. No. 08-52,  1, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 10-10,  1, 2-2-10; Ord. No. 12-81,  1, 10-2-12; Ord. No. 13-25,  2, 3-5-13)</history></law>