<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-115.12</section_number>
<catch_line>Advisory committee for the South Miami-Dade Watershed Plan;</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000314</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-115.12. Advisory committee for the South Miami-Dade Watershed Plan;<section prefix='(1)'>Legislative intent and purpose.<section prefix='(a)'>It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County to establish a broad-based Advisory Committee (the Committee) to participate in the formulation of the South Dade Watershed Plan (the Watershed Plan) to be prepared pursuant to policy established in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP). The purposes of the Committee and duties of its members shall be as follows:<section prefix='(i)'>To serve as a conduit of information between project supervisors, consultants retained to prepare the Watershed Plan, and community interests represented by the Committee members;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>To advise the consultants and assigned County, South Florida Water Management District, and Regional Planning Council staff as to the views of the Committee members and represented community interests;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>To inform the membership of represented interest organizations as to the purpose of the watershed planning project, status of planning activities, findings and proposals, and bases thereof;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>To suggest information sources to the consultants; and</section><section prefix='(v)'>To review and comment on the proposed scope of work and subsequent consultant drafts and deliverables;</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>South Miami-Dade Watershed Plan Advisory Committee.<section prefix='(a)'>There is hereby established an advisory committee to be known as the South Miami-Dade Watershed Plan Advisory Committee. The Committee shall be comprised of voting and nonvoting members as follows:<section prefix='(i)'>Voting members shall be representatives of the Miami-Dade Agri-Council, the Miami-Dade County Agricultural Practices Study Advisory Board, the Miami-Dade County Farm Bureau, the Potato Grower Exchange, the Miami-Dade County Chapter of the Florida Nurserymen and Grower's Association, the Florida Lime & Avocado Committee, the Tropical Everglades Visitor Association, the Homestead-Florida City Chamber of Commerce, Chamber South, the Florida Engineering Society, a citizens' organization active in the combined geographic area of Community Councils 11 and 12, a citizens' organization active in the combined geographic area of Community Councils 13 and 15, the Redland Citizens' Association as the citizens' organization active in the area of Community Council 14, one building industry organization, the National Audubon Society, the Tropical Audubon Society, the Sierra Club Miami Group, Biscayne National Park, Everglades National Park, the cities of Homestead and Florida City, one member from the community at large appointed by the County Manager to serve as Chairperson and two at large members recommended by the Chairperson.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Non-voting members shall be representatives of the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning, the Miami-Dade Department of Environmental Resources Management, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, the South Florida Water Management District, the South Florida Regional Planning Council, and the Florida Department of Environmental Protection.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Each member shall be appointed by the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners to serve until the Board of County Commissioners takes final action on the proposed Watershed Plan, or until replaced by the County Manager with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. The provision in Section 2-11.38 of this Code prohibiting simultaneous membership on more than one County board shall not apply to those members of the Miami-Dade County Agricultural Practices Study Advisory Board, the Floodplain Management Task Force, the Redland Area Municipal Advisory Committee, and the Biscayne National Park Buffer Development Review Committee who are appointed to the Committee. Appointments and activities of the Committee shall otherwise comply with the requirements of Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The County Manager shall appoint the Chair. It is the Chair's responsibility to chair all meetings and to issue an annual report to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with Section 2-11.37(a). Code of Miami-Dade County. A simple majority of the Committee members shall constitute a quorum, and a two-thirds majority of a quorum of the Committee shall be required for the passage of any motion. The Committee may establish other procedures and protocols regarding attendance, alternate attendees, and voting. The Committee shall automatically sunset upon adoption of the Plan.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County Manager shall assign appropriate staff to assist the Committee in accomplishing its purpose, including the following: prepare necessary meeting materials and notices; arrange meeting locations; prepare meeting summaries; and transmit communications between the Committee, project consultants, and participating agencies.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-37, ยง 1, 3-21-00; Ord. No. 01-97, ยง 1, 5-24-01; Ord. No. 01-200, ยง 1, 12-4-01; Ord. No. 04-62, ยง 1, 3-16-04)</history></law>