<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IC. INDEPENDENT REVIEW PANEL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.51</section_number>
<catch_line>Physical facilities and staff.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000184</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.51. Physical facilities and staff.<section prefix='(a)'>Office space, etc.; auditorium. The County shall provide the Panel with appropriately located office space and auditorium facilities together with necessary office supplies, equipment and furnishings.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Executive Director. The Board of County Commissioners shall appoint an Executive Director from 3 nominees provided by the Independent Review Panel. The Independent Review Panel shall utilize a competitive selection process when selecting nominees for Executive Director. The Executive Director shall only be removed by the Independent Review Panel. Such removal shall be for good cause upon a majority vote. The Independent Review Panel shall establish the rate of remuneration of the Executive Director in conjunction, concurrence and consensus with the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Staff. The Executive Director may hire and administer the necessary staff, subject to budgetary allocation by the Board.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Legal counsel. The County Attorney shall provide the Panel with necessary legal counsel.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Research, investigative personnel. The Panel may request the Board to provide such other fact-finding and research personnel as it may determine are necessary from time to time.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-8, § 10, 2-19-80; Ord. No. 81-44, § 3, 4-21-81; Ord. No. 83-19, § 1, 4-19-83; Ord. No. 83-42, § 1, 6-21-83; Ord. No. 97-86, § 5, 6-5-97; Ord. No. 97-130, § 1, 7-22-97; Ord. No. 06-31, § 1, 3-7-06)</history></law>