<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-113</section_number>
<catch_line>Adoption of Comprehensive Development Master Plan—Findings of fact; declarations of policy; purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000295</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-113. Adoption of Comprehensive Development Master Plan—Findings of fact; declarations of policy; purpose.<section>The Board of County Commissioners for Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares and finds that uncoordinated use of lands within the County threatens the orderly development, the environment of the County, and the health, safety, order, convenience, prosperity and welfare of the people of this County. The Board of County Commissioners, recognizing that man depends on his biological and physical surroundings for food, shelter, and other needs, and for cultural enrichment as well; in recognizing further the profound impact of man's activity on the interrelations of all components of the natural environment, particularly the profound influences of population growth, high-density urbanization, industrial expansion, resource utilization and exploitation, and new and expanding technological advances; and recognizing further the critical importance of restoring and maintaining environmental quality to the overall welfare and development of man, declares that it is the continuing policy of Miami-Dade County, Florida, in cooperation with federal, State, regional and local governments, and other concerned public and private organizations, to use all reasonable means and measures to:<section prefix='(a)'>Foster and promote the general welfare;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Create and maintain conditions under which man and nature can exist in productive harmony; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Fill the social, economic and other requirements of the present and future generations of citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>Accordingly, it is the purpose of this Commission in adopting the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan to declare a County policy which will [encourage productive and enjoyable harmony between man and his environment, to promote reasonable efforts which will] prevent or eliminate unreasonable or unnecessary damage to the environment and the biosphere, to stimulate the health and welfare of man, and to enrich the understanding of the ecological systems and natural resources important to the County, the State and the nation. It is the purpose and intent of this plan to assure for all people of Miami-Dade County safe, healthful, productive and aesthetically and culturally pleasing surroundings; to attain the widest range of beneficial uses of the environment without unreasonable degradation, risk to the health or safety, or other undesirable and unintended consequences; to preserve important historic, cultural and natural aspects of our national heritage; to maintain, wherever possible, environment which supports diversity and variety of individual choice; to achieve a balance between population and natural and man-made resources which will permit the high standards of living and a wide sharing of life's amenities, and to enhance the quality of renewal resources and approach the maximum attainable recycling of depletable resources. Accordingly, this Commission hereby recognizes that each person has a fundamental and inalienable right to a healthful environment, and that each person has a responsibility to contribute to the preservation and enhancement of the environment. The Commission further adopts the goals and objectives of the Local Government Comprehensive Planning and Land Development Regulation Act, Chapter 163, Part II, § 163.3161 et seq., Florida Statutes (1987), and dedicates its decision-making function in furtherance of the express intent of said act.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-22, § 2, 3-31-75; Ord. No. 79-63, § 3, 7-11-79; Ord. No. 88-110, § 3, 11-29-88)</history></law>