<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE IB. STANDARDS FOR CREATION AND REVIEW OF BOARDS GENERALLY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.40</section_number>
<catch_line>"Sunset" review of boards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000173</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.40. "Sunset" review of boards.<section>Commencing with calendar year 2001 the initial board program category shall be reviewed and every year thereafter in the following manner:<section prefix='(a)'>By February 1, 2001 and by February 1 each year thereafter, each board's chairperson shall submit a report, approved by the board, to the County Manager setting forth the following information concerning the board:<section prefix='(1)'>Whether the board is serving the purpose for which it was created.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whether the board is serving current community needs.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A list of the board's major accomplishments.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Whether there is any other board, either public or private, which would better serve the function of the board.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Whether the ordinance creating the board should be amended to better enable the board to serve the purpose for which it was created.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Whether the board's membership requirements should be modified.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The cost, both direct and indirect, of maintaining the board.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Whether the County board is meeting performance measures developed to determine their effectiveness in achieving stated goals.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>By March 15, 2001 and by March 15, each year thereafter, the County Manager shall deliver to the Board of County Commissioners the report submitted by the chairperson of each board, pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, together with the recommendation or comments that the County Manager submits.</section><section prefix='(c)'>By April 15, 2001 and by April 15 each year thereafter, the chairperson shall make an oral presentation to the Board of County Commissioners should it be the desire of the Board. Said presentation shall be based upon the report set forth in subsection (a) above. The Board of County Commissioners shall evaluate the chairperson's report, the County Manager's recommendations and any other information it deems relevant to determine whether the board shall continue in its present form.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall determine whether to abolish, continue, consolidate or modify the board.</section><section prefix='(e)'>At the conclusion of this review process, affected County departments must follow up on the Board of County Commissioners' action and, if necessary, prepare the appropriate legislation to abolish, consolidate or modify a board if it is not continued in its present form.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The following board categories shall be reviewed in the following years and every other year thereafter:<section prefix='(i)'>2001: Policy Formulation, General Government, Internal Support, Culture and Recreation, and Physical Environment</section><section prefix='(ii)'>2002: Protection of People and Property, Transportation, and Health and Human Services</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>All existing and newly created boards shall be administratively placed in the appropriate program category under subsection (g) above.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Any proposed Miami-Dade County ordinance or resolution creating a board must be accompanied by a report from the County Manager's Office setting forth the following information concerning the board:<section prefix='(1)'>Whether there is a need for the proposed board.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whether the purpose of the proposed board could be accomplished in any other manner.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The cost both direct and indirect of creating and maintaining such a board.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A clear statement of the mission, desired outcomes and strategies for accomplishing such outcomes, and performance measures to assess whether such outcomes are being achieved. Such outcomes specified shall be measurable, concrete and specific.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A date when the ordinance creating the board shall be repealed, contingent upon the completion of a review by the County Manager and the Board of County Commissioners prior to said repeal date, to determine its effectiveness in achieving stated goals and to revise or modify program components for the full achievement of said goals. No board shall be created whose date for repeal is greater than five (5) years from the effective date of the enacting ordinance.</section></section><section prefix='(j)'>Any and all boards created pursuant to state or federal law shall be exempt from the requirements of Sec. 2-11.40</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-136, ยง 8, 12-16-80; Ord. No. 95-93, ยง 1, 6-6-95; Ord. No. 98-113, ยง 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 01-20, ยง 1, 1-23-01)</history></law>