<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00099' order_by='00099' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXI. VIZCAYA GARDENS AND MUSEUM TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1115</section_number>
<catch_line>Scheduled expanded scope of Trust authority.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000778</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1115. Scheduled expanded scope of Trust authority.<section>Subject to meeting the requirements set forth in Section 6, after October 1, 2000, the Trust shall have the following additional powers:<section prefix='1.'>Power to act. The Trust shall be empowered to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to contract and be contracted with, and to have an official seal and alter the same. This provision shall not be construed to in any way affect the laws relating to governmental immunity.</section><section prefix='2.'>Contracts. Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, the Trust as agent and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County, shall be authorized to act for Miami-Dade County in the performance and enforcement of all contracts pertaining to the Trust and designated facilities and existing on the effective date of this chapter, and shall additionally be empowered to negotiate and execute, subsequent to the effective date of this chapter, such contracts as are properly within the powers and duties of the Trust subject to the following limitations:<section prefix='a.'>The Trust shall not, without prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, enter into or amend any contract which shall require the expenditure of funds in excess of the amounts appropriated in the contractual services category of the section of the County budget pertaining to the operation of the Trust.</section><section prefix='b.'>The Trust shall not, without prior approval of the County Commission, enter into or alter any contract the effect of which is to change substantially policies established by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='c.'>The Trust shall not be authorized to enter into a contract with any labor union or other organization representing employees without first having obtained the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. The County Manager through the County labor relations officer and the County personnel department shall be responsible for the negotiation of labor agreements with organizations representing Trust employees; however, the Trust and the Director shall be authorized to participate in such negotiations.</section><section prefix='d.'>The Trust shall comply with the formal bid requirements of Section 4.03(D) of the Charter of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, and for such purpose the term "Board" as used in Section 4.03(D) shall be construed to be the "Trust" and the term "Manager" shall be construed to be "the Director."</section><section prefix='e.'>For all construction contracts, the Trust shall comply with the provisions of Article 11 of Chapter 10 of the County Code and the administrative procedures adopted pursuant to said section.</section><section prefix='f.'>For all purchases of commodities and services, the Trust shall comply with the provisions of Section 2-8.2 of the County code and the administrative procedures adopted pursuant to said section.</section><section prefix='g.'>It is specifically provided that contracts and amendments thereto executed by the Trust or other obligations incurred by the Trust, shall not be binding upon Miami-Dade County. In the event that the Trust is abolished, obligations of the Trust shall only be enforceable against Miami-Dade County to the extent that such obligations would have been enforceable with regard to business income which would have come into the possession of the Trust had the Trust not been abolished.</section><section prefix='h.'>If the Trust intends to procure goods or services from an entity other than Miami-Dade County, the Trust must also solicit offers from Miami-Dade County. The Trust shall annually present a written report to the Board of County Commissioners that details the date, amounts, and circumstances of each such contract and explains why the offer from Miami-Dade County was not accepted.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Property. The Trust shall, subject to prior approval of the County Commission be authorized to purchase or otherwise obtain real property, the title to which shall be vested in Miami-Dade County and the possession and operating control of which shall be held in trust for Miami-Dade County under the provisions of this chapter.</section><section>The Trust shall not be authorized to sell, convey, mortgage, or otherwise impair or encumber the title to real property.</section><section>The Trust shall not, without having previously obtained the approval of the Commission, destroy, replace, or abandon real property. The Trust shall be authorized to maintain and repair designated facilities and may alter, modify, or make additions to such facilities whenever such changes are necessary for the proper operation and maintenance of such facilities. The Trust may buy and sell personal property provided, however, such personal property that constitutes part of the museum collection of the Trust may be sold only with the concurrence of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-112, ยง 5, 7-21-98)</history></law>