<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.18</section_number>
<catch_line>Performance based program review proposal.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000148</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.18. Performance based program review proposal.<section prefix='(a)'>The County Manager shall develop a schedule and apply performance based program review principles in reviewing the programs of each County department and agency, including all trusts and entities falling under the jurisdiction of Miami-Dade County government, at least once every eight years, commencing with the Fiscal Year 2004-2005 Budget Cycle. As used herein, "performance based program review principles" may include, among others, the following: (1) a review as to whether the program is in conformance with the strategic plans, business plans, and adopted budgetary priorities; (2) zero-based budgeting concepts; (3) application of program workload measures, program efficiency measures, program effectiveness measures, program outcome measures and cost-benefit analysis; and (4) an analysis of the customer or client base served by the program and delivery of service alternatives.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Manager shall develop a plan for such performance based program reviews and submit a report regarding that plan for consideration by the Budget and Finance Committee by May 15, 2003. That plan shall include a grouping of all County departments, trusts, and agencies so that approximately one-eighth of the entities are thoroughly reviewed annually and so the cycle will subject each entity to a performance based program review every eight years. The plan shall require that all performance based program reviews be performed in coordination with the Office of the Commission Auditor.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For each department, trust, and agency required to conduct a performance based program review, the County Manager shall present his or her findings, analysis, and reports to the Budget and Finance Committee before the Proposed Budget is submitted. When any trust is reviewed under the performance based program review, the trust board shall be responsible for reviewing its programs under the same principles and shall present its findings, analysis and reports to the County Manager for review at last six weeks prior to the presentation to the Budget and Finance Committee. The trust board shall present its findings, analysis and reports to the Budget and Finance Committee at the same meeting at which the County Manager presents his or her findings, analysis, and reports regarding that trust.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-65, §§ 1—3, 4-8-03)</history></law>