<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.14</section_number>
<catch_line>Film production on publicly-owned or controlled property.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000143</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.14. Film production on publicly-owned or controlled property.<section>The purpose of this section shall be to provide for the coordination of film production on publicly-owned or controlled property to serve the public interest.</section><section prefix='(a)'>Definitions. The following terms shall have the meanings ascribed to them below for the purposes of this section:<section>Still, live or motion picture production whether made on or by film, electronic tape, or any other electronic device used to produce theatrical motion pictures, television entertainment motion pictures, industrial motion pictures, television commercials, or print media.</section><section>Those municipalities located within Miami-Dade County which have executed interlocal agreements with Miami-Dade County with regard to the coordination of film permitting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Film permits.<section prefix='(1)'>Required. No person shall film within a publicly-owned site, facility or right-of-way within the participating incorporated or unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County without first obtaining a permit. Within the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, the County Manager shall establish the criteria and procedures to be followed for film permits. Within the participating incorporated areas, the municipality having jurisdiction shall establish the criteria and procedures to be followed for film permits through interlocal agreement with Miami-Dade County. Permits shall be authorized by the governmental body having jurisdiction over the public site.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Exceptions. Nothing in this section shall require any permit from:<section prefix='(i)'>Individuals filming or video taping only for their own personal or family use.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Employees of print or electronic news media when filming on-going news events. This exception shall not apply to simulations or re-enactments orchestrated by print or electronic news media.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Students and faculty filming exclusively for educational purposes.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Permit application. The permit application shall (i) identify the applicant; (ii) demonstrate the public liability insurance provided by the applicant in the amount established by the governmental body having jurisdiction; (iii) identify the number and type of locations to be utilized for filming and the agencies to provide assistance. Each participating municipality may establish additional permit requirements.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Procedures. Procedures for the collection of required fees and reimbursements, if any, shall be established through administrative orders in connection with County locations and through interlocal agreements in connection with participating municipal locations.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Permit criteria. The permit shall be granted unless the County Manager's designee finds that the proposed film production:<section prefix='(i)'>Unduly impedes governmental business or public access; or</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Conflicts with previously scheduled activities; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Imperils public safety; or</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Violates the provisions of applicable interlocal agreement.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Appeals. Any person aggrieved by the terms of a permit issued by the County, by the decision not to issue a permit or by a revocation of a permit issued by the County may, within ten (10) days of the decision, appeal to the County Manager, whose decision will be final.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Authority of County Manager. The County Manager shall designate an individual who shall be authorized to facilitate and coordinate the use of publicly-owned sites within the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County for the filming and production of film projects. In this regard the Manager's designee shall be responsible for:<section prefix='(1)'>Negotiating interlocal agreements with municipalities to provide that the County may issue municipal film permits on behalf of the participating municipality, which shall conform to the requirements of all applicable municipal ordinances and written regulations, and shall set out the procedures by which the County shall facilitate film production within the municipality.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Establishing by administrative order the criteria for film permits issued with regard to sites owned or controlled by the County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Issuing, denying or revoking permits pursuant to this section, administrative order or interlocal agreements.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Coordinating proposed film production schedules to minimize conflicts and to monitor compliance with applicable rules and regulations of the County and of the participating municipalities, and coordinating with the police and fire departments having jurisdiction to determine those services reasonably necessary to protect the life, safety and welfare of the public, as well as property.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Facilitating execution of appropriate permits for the provision of special police, fire or other public services as may be required. In connection with these arrangements, the County may collect all necessary fees and deposits on behalf of the County and participating municipalities and shall remit municipal fees collected in accordance with the interlocal agreement with the participating municipality. Municipal fees shall be determined by each participating municipality.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Supporting public programs and private initiatives that enhance Miami-Dade County as a location for film production and post-production facilities.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Developing and disseminating a comprehensive listing of all related available resources including but not limited to companies dealing with film production to assist in the expansion and enhancement of the film production industry and related industries in Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-112, § 6, 12-21-76; Ord. No. 91-50, §§ 1, 2, 5-7-91)</history></law>