<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-116.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Area planning reports—Initiation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000321</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-116.3. Area planning reports—Initiation.<section>The Board of County Commissioners, an individual, a group or an entity, including the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning, may petition the County Manager for the preparation of an area planning report. The County Manager shall direct the Department of Planning and Zoning to review petitions from entities other than the Department of Planning and Zoning, meeting with the petitioner(s) as needed, and within sixty (60) days to recommend to him whether the requested area planning report should be prepared and, if so, the issues, objectives, boundaries, approach, schedule, and magnitude of staff resources required and available for the preparation of the requested area planning report. A Department of Planning and Zoning petition for an area planning report shall contain the same type of information as does its recommendation to the County Manager on a petition by another entity.</section><section>Upon receipt of a Department of Planning and Zoning petition for an area planning report or the Department of Planning and Zoning's recommendation regarding a petition submitted by another entity, the County Manager shall transmit such petition or recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners, together with the County Manager's recommendation as to whether the requested area planning report should be prepared. After consideration of the petition for the preparation of the area planning report and the recommendation of the County Manager, the Board of County Commissioners shall either deny the petition or by resolution direct the County Manager to direct the preparation of an area planning report by the Department of Planning and Zoning. Such resolution shall set forth the objectives, boundaries, approach, schedule and magnitude of staff resources to be used in the preparation of the area planning report. The boundaries of the area designated as the subject of an area planning report shall be described by reference to streets, highways or other geographic boundaries.</section><section>When the area planning reports procedure is utilized in conjunction with the building and zoning moratoria provisions of through, Code of Miami-Dade County, the time limitations therein contained shall govern the schedule for completion of the report established in the authorizing resolution. The County Manager shall have discretion as to whether or not to incorporate any or all of an area planning report into his report pursuant to Sections through of the Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-46, § 1, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>