<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00098' order_by='00098' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HIV/AIDS PARTNERSHIP</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1104</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000770</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1104. Powers and duties.<section>The Partnership shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>Establish methods for obtaining input on community needs and priorities which may include public meetings, conducting focus groups, and convening ad-hoc panels.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Develop a community-wide comprehensive plan for the Partnership and health services that is compatible with the State of Florida and the County's plan regarding the provision of health services to individuals with HIV/AIDS.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Establish prevention, housing, and care and treatment recommendations, including priorities.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Establish priorities for the allocation of Part A funds within the County, including how best to meet each such priority and individual factors that the County should consider in allocating funds under Part A of the Ryan White Program based on the:<section prefix='(1)'>Documented needs of the population affected by HIV/AIDS within the County;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Cost and outcome effectiveness of proposed strategies and interventions, to the extent that such data are reasonably available;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Priorities of the communities affected by HIV/AIDS for whom the services are intended; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Availability of other governmental and non-governmental resources.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Make recommendations for service priorities for the use of other funds, to the areas of greatest need, with equal weight and attention provided to HIV/AIDS prevention, health and supportive services, and housing, including but not limited to the use of the following funding sources:<section prefix='(1)'>Part B of the Ryan White Program.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS program.</section><section prefix='(3)'>State of Florida General Revenue Care and Treatment funding.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Other federal and state grants</section><section prefix='(5)'>Funding from municipalities interested in supporting implementation of the Partnership's Comprehensive Plan.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Private Foundation grants.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Private contributions.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor, and other governmental entities with respect to all issues affecting or relating to persons at risk of contracting the virus and persons living with the virus.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Participate in the development of the Statewide Coordinated Statement of Need initiated by the State of Florida's public health agency responsible for administering grants under the Ryan White Program.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Establish procedures within the Partnership's By-Laws for addressing grievances with respect to Part A funding and any other matter deemed appropriate by the Partnership, including but not limited to procedures for submitting grievances for Part A allocations that cannot be resolved by binding arbitration as required by the Ryan White Program. Grievance procedures developed by the Partnership shall be submitted for review and approval to the appropriate federal agency. Upon approval, these procedures shall become the sole dispute resolution mechanism and shall take precedence over all other County dispute resolution mechanisms, including but not limited to the County bid protest procedures.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Assess the efficiency of the administrative mechanism in rapidly allocating funds to the areas of greatest need with the County and, at the discretion of the Partnership, assess the effectiveness and quality, either directly or through contractual arrangements, of the services offered in meeting the identified needs.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Those powers and duties granted by the Ryan White Program, Healthy Communities 2010 Objectives, AIDS Housing Opportunity Act, and Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and State of Florida General Revenue Care and Treatment Allocations as presently exist or as may be amended.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-127, ยง 4, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 02-35, ยง 4, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 07-71, ยง 4, 6-5-07)</history></law>