<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00099' order_by='00099' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXI. VIZCAYA GARDENS AND MUSEUM TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1114</section_number>
<catch_line>Initial transitional scope of Trust authority.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000777</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1114. Initial transitional scope of Trust authority.<section>For the transition period commencing from the effective date of the ordinance from which this article derives to October 1, 2000, the powers of the Trust include the following:<section prefix='1.'>Prepare the Mission Statement for the Vizcaya Museum and Gardens. This Mission Statement shall meet AAM requirements and must address the purpose, function, membership, outreach, and aspirations of Vizcaya Museum and Gardens. It shall include short and long-term strategic plans for the operation, maintenance, interpretation, preservation and restoration in perpetuity of the Vizcaya Museum and Gardens, including the Farm Village, as a self-sustaining, AAM accredited museum of fine arts of national stature. Once approved by the Board of County Commissioners, the Mission statement will govern all actions by Miami-Dade County and its agents and employees concerning Vizcaya Museum and Gardens. The Trust may amend the Mission Statement from time to time, which shall be effective upon approval of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='2.'>Establish written schedules of rates, charges, and fees relating to Vizcaya, which shall be effective upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='3.'>Develop policies regarding Vizcaya Museum and Gardens which shall be binding on all Miami-Dade County departments, agents, users, and employees once approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The Trust shall develop policies governing and overseeing the management of:<section prefix='(a)'>The role of support groups, including recognition, affiliation with the Museum and Gardens, creation, dissolution, oversight, audit, reporting requirements, use of the Vizcaya Museum and Gardens name, use of facilities, and community outreach by support groups;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Membership programs;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Education programs;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Fee waivers and reductions;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Acceptance of gifts and grants;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Outreach programs for Miami-Dade County communities that have historically underutilized the Museum and Gardens;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Preparation for any accreditation and re-accreditation processes;</section><section prefix='(h)'>Exhibition policies;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Appropriate stewardship of the collection and their management.</section></section><section prefix='4.'>Negotiate and recommend contracts and agreements with support groups, which, upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners, shall govern the support groups. Such contracts shall include: the mission statement of the support group; standards to measure the accomplishments of the support group; terms and conditions for use and access to the Museum and Gardens; Miami-Dade County's and the Trust's authority to inspect and audit books and records of support groups; accounting and disposition of fund raising proceeds; reporting requirements; coordination of support group activities; and other related matters. The agreement with the support groups will address fund raising targets which will be based on the aggregate gross revenues of the support groups and contributions in kind by the Vizcaya Volunteer Guides. It is intended that the aggregate of such support group revenues and contributions in kind by the Volunteer Guides will be not less than five hundred fifty thousand dollars ($550,000) per year, including amounts in excess of five hundred fifty thousand dollars ($550,000) carried forward from year to year.</section><section prefix='5.'>Develop such additional appropriate plans and ordinance amendments for the transition of the operation of the Museum and Gardens to a public/private operating partnership similar to the structure of other successful cultural institutions owned by Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='6.'>Exercise its powers regarding the budget of the Museum and Gardens as outlined in this article.</section><section prefix='7.'>Advise the County Manager, Mayor, Board of County Commissioners, the Director of the Park and Recreation Department, and the Executive Director of Vizcaya on matters relating to the operation and management of the Museum and Gardens.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-112, ยง 4, 7-21-98)</history></law>