<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.13.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Payment of moving expenses for new employees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000142</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.13.1. Payment of moving expenses for new employees.<section prefix='(a)'>Reimbursement authorized. Miami-Dade County, in its sole discretion, may reimburse any new employee of Miami-Dade County for reasonable moving expenses incurred in relocating the employee and his family from any point to Miami-Dade County. Such reimbursement may be made only upon the express and affirmative finding by the County Manager that the payment of such moving expenses is a necessary condition to the employment of the new employee and that the new employee possesses such qualifications, expertise or experience which renders him particularly qualified to perform the duties for which he is being hired. It is the intent of this section that the principles of merit selection of new employees should be applied to insure that all new County employees are the best qualified persons to fill the available positions, and that such new employees should not be forced to make large personal sacrifices in the form of moving expenses in order to obtain employment with Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Approval procedure. Any department head desiring to hire a prospective employee, which employment will necessitate that employee moving to Miami-Dade County, shall secure prior approval from the County Manager before hiring such an employee or promising payment of moving expenses. The County Manager shall, by administrative order, provide the necessary approval and authorization forms for use by all County departments.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-48, ยง 1, 7-5-77)</history></law>