<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.8</section_number>
<catch_line>[Agency authorized to acquire real property.]</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000136</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.8. [Agency authorized to acquire real property.]<section prefix='(a)'>This Board hereby approves and authorizes execution by the County Manager of the Interlocal Cooperation Agreement between the County, the Agency and the City in substantially the form attached to the ordinance from which this section derives as Exhibit A and incorporated herein by this reference (the "Interlocal Agreement").</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Board hereby authorizes the Agency to exercise the right to acquire by condemnation any interest in real property, including a fee simple title thereto, which it deems necessary for, or in connection with, community redevelopment and related activities under the Act provided such exercise must be in accordance with the provisions of Section 163.375, Florida Statutes. The Agency may exercise the power of eminent domain in the manner provided in Chapters 73 and 74 of the Florida Statutes and acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto, or it may exercise the power of eminent domain in the manner now or which may be hereafter provided by any other statutory provision for the exercise of the power of eminent domain. Notwithstanding and prevailing over anything in this section to the contrary, the exercise of eminent domain power shall be limited as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>The power of eminent domain may be exercised upon only those parcels of land listed in Appendix B of the Plan, a copy of which Appendix B is attached hereto as Exhibit B and incorporated herein by this reference provided such properties are vacant or abandoned at the time of the filing of the condemnation action or with the mutual consent of the property owner and the Agency;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The power of eminent domain shall not be exercised if the effect of such condemnation is a reduction in the pool of affordable housing; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>The delegation of eminent domain power shall be effective for a five (5) year term commencing on the date of execution of the Interlocal Agreement, such that upon the lapse of such five (5) year period, the Agency shall no longer have the right to exercise the power of eminent domain.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-100, §§ 2, 3, 9-9-99)</history></law>