<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-114.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Administrative review of takings and vested rights claims.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000298</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-114.1. Administrative review of takings and vested rights claims.<section prefix='(a)'>Documentation of claim.<section prefix='(1)'>Any applicant alleging that the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, as applied to a particular development order or action, constitutes or would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights (taking or abrogation) and any person or entity claiming a potential taking or abrogation under Chapter 33 of this Code must affirmatively demonstrate the legal requisites of the claim by exhausting the administrative remedy provided in this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Claims of a taking or abrogation of vested rights are limited solely to extreme circumstances rising to the level of a potential denial of rights under the Constitutions of the United States and the State of Florida. The procedures provided herein for demonstrating such a taking or abrogation of vested rights are not intended to be utilized routinely or frivolously, but only in the extreme circumstances described above. The claimant or the attorney for the claimant shall exercise due diligence in the filing and argument of any sworn statement, notice of invoking administrative remedy or other claim for a taking or abrogation of vested rights. The signature of the claimant or the attorney for the claimant upon any document in connection with a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights shall constitute a certificate that the person signing has read the document and that to the best of his knowledge it is supported by good grounds and that it has not been presented solely for delay. The claimant and the attorney for the claimant shall have a continuing obligation throughout the proceedings to correct any statement or representation found to have been incorrect when made or which becomes incorrect by virtue of changed circumstances. If a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights is: (1) based upon facts that the claimant or the attorney for the claimant knew or should have known were not true; or (2) frivolous or filed solely for the purposes of delay, the appropriate County board or agency shall make such a finding and may pursue any remedy or impose any penalty provided by law or ordinance.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Developmental permit defined. For purposes of this section a "developmental permit" shall mean a developmental order or action which may be issued by an administrative official without the necessity of a hearing on the application for said developmental permit.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Developmental resolution defined. For purposes of this section, a "developmental resolution" shall mean a developmental order or action which requires the approval of a County board or agency after a hearing on the application for said developmental resolution prior to its issuance.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Sworn statement defined. For purpose of this section, "sworn statement" shall mean the sworn statement described in Section 2-114.1(a) together with all accompanying documents, witness lists, items and things supporting the applicant's claim and an administrative fee established by administrative order of the County Manager to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Invocation of administrative remedy.<section prefix='(1)'>Any developmental permit denied on the grounds of inconsistency with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan shall state in writing that the permit has been denied on such basis. Any applicant seeking to appeal the denial of a developmental permit on the grounds set forth in Section 2-114.1(a) shall file a notice of invoking administrative remedy with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator on a form prescribed by the Director within fifteen (15) days of the denial of said developmental permit. Any claimant contending that action upon a County application will result in a taking or abrogation of vested rights under Section 33-311 of this Code shall file a notice of invoking administrative remedy with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator on a form prescribed by the Director within thirty (30) days of receipt of the certified mail notice required by Section 33-311, provided the County Commission may extend the thirty-day filing period prescribed by this sentence upon a showing of good cause as provided by Section 33-311. The applicant shall file a complete sworn statement within ninety (90) working days of the filing of the notice of invoking administrative remedy. Failure to file the sworn statement within the time specified in this paragraph shall constitute an irrevocable waiver of claim.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any applicant alleging that the action of the Board of County Commissioners or a Community Zoning Appeals Board upon an application for a zoning action under Chapter 33 would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights shall file a complete sworn statement with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator not later than forty-five (45) days before the first hearing on the developmental resolution. No oral testimony or written reports or documents in support of any argument that the denial of the developmental resolution would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or would abrogate vested rights shall be considered as evidence at the public hearing unless the complete sworn statement has been timely filed pursuant to this paragraph; provided, however, that where an applicant has failed to timely file a sworn statement pursuant to this paragraph, the Board of County Commissioners, Environmental Quality Control Board, or any other board taking action on a developmental resolution may defer the hearing on an application for a developmental resolution to avoid a manifest injustice and to provide adequate time for review of the sworn statement by the Developmental Impact Committee or, in the event of an application initiated by a party other than the affected property owner, to provide adequate time for the property owner to invoke the administrative remedy and to adhere to the time schedules provided herein.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Review by Developmental Impact Committee and County Boards.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be the duty and responsibility of the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee to review all sworn statements timely filed with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator pursuant to this section. The Developmental Impact Committee shall have the authority to request additional information from the applicant.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee finds that a denial of a developmental permit would result in a temporary or permanent taking or abrogation of vested rights, it shall reverse or modify said denial. Otherwise, the Executive Council shall affirm said denial. Within fourteen (14) days the applicant may appeal the decision of the Executive Council to the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 33-314 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, the Board of County Commissioners shall have jurisdiction to review conflicts between decisions of the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee regarding developmental permits made pursuant to this section and decisions of any other County board made pursuant to an appeal of an administrative decision.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee shall prepare a written recommendation to the appropriate County board regarding sworn statements filed in connection with an application for a developmental resolution. With the exception of County boards whose decisions are directly reviewable by an appellate court, the Board of County Commissioners shall have exclusive jurisdiction to consider and take action upon all applications for developmental resolutions for which the applicant has invoked the administrative remedy set forth in this section.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The appropriate County board may elect to first consider the primary application rather than concurrently conduct a hearing upon a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights. If the Board's determination is that the primary application should be denied in whole or in part, such determination shall not be a final decision but shall be subject to a further determination of a claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights. The Board may either hear directly the claim of taking or abrogation of vested rights, may defer consideration of the claim to a subsequent hearing, or may refer the same to the Executive Council of the Development Impact Committee for further review and recommendation prior to taking final action. If the Board shall finally determine that denial of the primary application would result in a taking or abrogation of vested rights, the Board shall grant appropriate relief which would avoid such result. Upon a determination by the Board that denial of the primary application would not effect a taking or abrogate vested rights, the preliminary determination to deny shall become final.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding any contrary provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, a developmental resolution adopted by any County board other than the Board of County Commissioners shall not be deemed to be a final order for any purpose where: (1) the administrative remedy of this section has been invoked; and (2) the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee has appealed said developmental resolution to the Board of County Commissioners. Said appeal shall be filed within fourteen (14) days of the date of the adoption of the developmental resolution.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Exhaustion of administrative remedies. A developmental order or action shall not be deemed a final order in any court or quasi-judicial proceeding challenging the denial of the developmental order or action as a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights unless the remedies set forth in this section have been exhausted.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-10, § 2, 2-21-89; Ord. No. 94-37, § 1, 3-3-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-198, § 1, 11-4-97; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>