<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. BRANCH OFFICES OF COUNTY AUTO TAG AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-119.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000332</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-119.1. Definitions.<section>For the purpose of this article the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(1)'>The term "applicant" shall refer to any person, firm, partnership or corporation which meets the requirements for placement in the eligibility pool described in Section 2-120. As set forth in Section 2-120(f), a designated person shall represent a corporate applicant.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The term "authorization" shall refer to the authority granted an operator by the County Manager in accordance with this article, and after compliance with all applicable requirements, to operate a branch auto tag agency office.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The term "Board" shall refer to the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The term "branch office" shall refer to a private business operating pursuant to the provisions of this article and on behalf of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency providing auto tag agency services to the public.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The term "corporate," when used in this ordinance, shall refer to and encompass, in addition to a corporation, any firm, partnership or other business entity other than a sole proprietorship.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The term "eligibility pool" shall refer to the pool established pursuant to Section 2-120 containing the names of applicants eligible to bid for award of authorizations to operate new branch offices and to otherwise acquire existing branch offices.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The term "operator" shall refer to any person, firm, partnership or corporation which is authorized to operate a branch auto tag agency or a Limited Branch Office and the name for which the authorization is granted. With respect to a branch auto tag agency, as set forth in Section 2-120(f), and subject to the requirements therein, a designated person shall represent a corporate operator.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The term "qualified employee" shall refer to a person who has satisfactorily passed a written examination given under the direction and supervision of the Tax Collector or his designees, which tests the person's knowledge of applicable laws, rules, regulations and procedures.</section><section prefix='(9)'>The term "automobile and/or truck dealer" shall refer to those entities properly licensed by the State of Florida to engage in the business of selling motor vehicles to the general public.</section><section prefix='(10)'>The term "Electronic Filing System" (EFS) shall refer to the system by which permanent auto tags are assigned and issued to buyers of cars or trucks when the transaction occurs at a licensed automobile and/or truck dealer with Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The term "limited branch office" shall refer to an automobile and/or truck dealer who is licensed by and is in good standing with the State of Florida, has been authorized by the Tax Collector, and has a current written agreement with a private branch auto tag agency, which agreement has been approved by and is on file with the Tax Collector, for the purpose of fulfilling obligations relating to the EFS. A limited branch office shall not mean and shall not be interpreted to mean a privately owned auto tag agency as described in this article.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The term "valid certified service provider" shall refer to a provider of software and other computer services to a limited branch office which has contracted with the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for the applicable access agreements, contracted with the Florida Tax Collectors, Inc. for compliance with the program standards of the EFS, and agreed with Miami-Dade County to adhere to appropriate local laws, standards, administrative orders, and other appropriate procedures.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-135, ยง 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, ยง 2, 6-17-97)</history></law>