<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE IB. STANDARDS FOR CREATION AND REVIEW OF BOARDS GENERALLY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.38</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership on boards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000166</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.38. Membership on boards.<section>All members of County boards shall be permanent residents and electors of Miami-Dade County unless the Board of County Commissioners, by a two-thirds vote of its membership, waives this requirement, and should have reputations for integrity and community service. In addition, all board members should have demonstrated an interest in the field, activity or sphere covered by the board. Each board shall include at least one (1) person whose livelihood does not depend on the area regulated, administered or dealt with by the board.</section><section>Unless the Board of County Commissioners by two-thirds () vote of its membership waives the residency requirement, any member of County boards who ceases to be a resident of Miami-Dade County during the term of his or her office shall immediately advise the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. Upon being advised by the Clerk of such circumstances, the Board of County Commissioners shall declare the position to be vacant and shall promptly fill the same pursuant to the provisions of.</section><section>The primary consideration in appointing board members shall be to provide the board with the needed technical, professional, financial, business or administrative expertise. The membership of each board should be representative of the community at large and should reflect the gender, racial, ethnic and cultural make-up of the community.</section><section>No person shall be eligible to serve on a County board if, at the time of appointment to the County board, the person has filed a lawsuit against the County that is pending at the time of appointment and that challenges a policy set by the Board of County Commissioners, unless the Board of County Commissioners by two-thirds () vote of its membership waives this requirement. No person sitting on a County board may file a lawsuit against the County that challenges a policy set by the Board of County Commissioners without relinquishing his or her seat on the County board unless the Board of County Commissioners by two-thirds () vote of its membership waives this requirement.</section><section>No member of any County board shall become a candidate for elective political office during his or her term. Should any member of a County board qualify as a candidate for elective political office, such qualification shall be deemed a tender of resignation from such board. No person shall serve on more than two (2) County boards simultaneously, unless the Commission has by unanimous vote approved the appointment after being advised of all other County board(s) upon which the person sits, provided, however, a person serving on any one of the following boards shall not serve on any other County board simultaneously except as provided by ordinance: Community Council; Community Zoning Appeals Board; Planning Advisory Board; Citizens' Independent Transportation Trust; Housing Finance Authority; Independent Review Panel; Industrial Development Authority; Health Facilities Authority; Educational Facilities Authority; Commission on Ethics and Public Trust; Environmental Quality Control Board; The Children's Trust; and the Public Health Trust. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a person is prohibited from serving on a County board where such service would violate federal or state law, the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter or county ordinance.</section><section>Any Commissioner who has nominated a citizen to a County board as that term is defined in of the Code of Miami-Dade County may at any time, with or without cause, request the Board of County Commissioners to remove said board member from his or her position on a County board and recommend a different person to fill the position.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-136, § 4, 12-16-80; Ord. No. 89-55, § 1, 6-20-89; Ord. No. 92-141, § 1, 11-17-92; Ord. No. 93-68, § 1, 7-15-93; Ord. No. 93-104, § 6, 10-19-93; Ord. No. 93-114, § 7, 10-21-93; Ord. No. 96-179, § 1, 12-3-96; Ord. No. 04-57, § 1, 3-16-04; Ord. No. 05-194, § 1, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 08-35, § 1, 3-18-08)</history></law>