<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00098' order_by='00098' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HIV/AIDS PARTNERSHIP</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1102</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership requirements; appointment of members; terms; removal.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000768</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1102. Membership requirements; appointment of members; terms; removal.<section prefix='(a)'>All members of the Partnership shall be permanent residents and electors of Miami-Dade County, unless the Board of County Commissioners, by a two-thirds vote of its membership, waives this requirement and shall have reputations for integrity and community service. Notwithstanding the qualified elector requirement stated herein, applicants for or members of the Partnership who are appointed to fill the seat of a former inmate of a local, state, or federal prison as described in Section 2-1102 (23) of this code shall be exempt from the qualified elector requirement set forth herein.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Partnership shall be composed of thirty-eight (38) voting members from the following categories of representatives:<section prefix='(1)'>Fifteen (15) member representatives of affected communities that include individuals with HIV disease, who are not affiliated or employed by a Part A funded provider and are recipients of Part A services, and historically underserved groups and subpopulations that reflect the demographics of the population within the eligible metropolitan area, and constitute;</section><section prefix='(2)'>One (1) Health care provider, which must represent a Federally Qualified Health Center;</section><section prefix='(3)'>One (1) Community based AIDS service organization;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Two (2) Housing, Homeless or Social Service providers;</section><section prefix='(5)'>One (1) Mental health provider;</section><section prefix='(6)'>One (1) Substance abuse provider;</section><section prefix='(7)'>One (1) HIV prevention provider;</section><section prefix='(8)'>One (1) Hospital or health care planning agency;</section><section prefix='(9)'>One (1) representative from agencies receiving grants under Part C of the Ryan White Program;</section><section prefix='(10)'>One (1) representative from agencies receiving grants under Part D of the Ryan White Program, or from organizations with a history of providing services to children, youth, and families if funded locally;</section><section prefix='(11)'>Four (4) grantee representatives of Other Federal HIV programs including Ryan White Program Part F and HOPWA, if funded locally;</section><section prefix='(12)'>One (1) Ryan White Program Part A local grantee;</section><section prefix='(13)'>One (1) State government/Ryan White Program Part B grantee representative;</section><section prefix='(14)'>One (1) State government/Medicaid Agency representative;</section><section prefix='(15)'>One (1) Local public health agency representative from the Miami-Dade County Health Department;</section><section prefix='(16)'>One (1) Miami-Dade County Public Schools representative;</section><section prefix='(17)'>One (1) Non-elected community leader who does not provide HIV related health care services subject to funding under Partnership programs;</section><section prefix='(18)'>One (1) former inmate of a local, state, or federal prison released from the custody of the penal system during the preceding three (3) years and had HIV disease as of the date of his release, or a representative of HIV+ incarcerated persons;</section><section prefix='(19)'>One (1) State of Florida General Revenue grantee representative;</section><section prefix='(20)'>One (1) representative of a federally recognized Indian tribe as represented in the population from the affected community;</section><section prefix='(21)'>One (1) representative co-infected with hepatitis B or C from the affected community.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Ex officio members shall be appointed in the same manner by which voting members are appointed, and at a minimum shall include ex officio members from the following categories of representatives:<section prefix='(1)'>One (1) representative from the Office of the Mayor;</section><section prefix='(2)'>One (1) representative from the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Three (3) representatives of the affected community who are not affiliated or employed by a Part A funded provider, and are recipients of Part A services shall also be appointed as alternates. Alternate members may be assigned as voting members of committees, but are non-voting members of the full Partnership except when the voting member appointed to that category of representatives is unable to serve, at which time an alternate member of the same category of representatives designated by the chairperson shall serve as voting member for the full Partnership.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Partnership shall maintain at all times a fair and open nominations process as written in its By-Laws which shall result in a recommended slate of candidates, including alternates, which is forwarded to the Mayor for his consideration. Members and alternates shall be appointed by the Mayor, who shall designate which category listed in subsections (a) and (b) above each member shall represent. Members shall be appointed in accordance with Sections 2-11.38 and 2-11.38.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Vacancies on the Partnership shall be filled in the same manner as above, except for affected community positions, which may be filled by an affected community alternate member appointed by the Partnership.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Appointment shall comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Composition of the Partnership shall reflect in its composition the demographics of the epidemic in Miami-Dade County with particular consideration given to disproportionately affected and historically underserved groups, subpopulations, and geographic areas in Miami-Dade County</section><section prefix='(2)'>Composition of the Partnership, including committee membership, shall strive to assure the following:<section prefix='(A)'>Parity, with each member having equal opportunity for input and participation as well as equal voice in voting and other decision making activities;</section><section prefix='(B)'>Inclusiveness, that all affected communities are represented and involved in a meaningful manner in the community planning process;</section><section prefix='(C)'>Representation, that members who represent a specific community truly reflect that community's values, norms and behaviors.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>No more than fifteen (15) individuals shall be appointed who personally provide, who represent entities that provide, or who otherwise possess a financial relationship with entities that provide HIV related services funded by Partnership programs.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No funded provider shall have more than one (1) representative or employee as a member, except as mandated by the legal requirements of Partnership programs.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>The term of office of members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.38.2 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Members shall be appointed to three (3) year terms, which shall end concurrent with the last day of the county's fiscal year, except that initially twelve (12) members shall be appointed to a one (1) year term and twelve (12) members appointed to a two (2) year term.</section><section prefix='(h)'>No member shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years except as required by law. Notwithstanding the term limit requirements set forth herein, members appointed to fill government or grantee seats are excepted from these requirements and shall serve as members of the Partnership for as long as they are designated by their respective agencies to serve in this capacity.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Attendance requirements for members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.39, except that five (5) absences, excused or unexcused, in any fiscal year shall also constitute grounds for removal and except absences that are due to Partnership business related travel are not counted against the total of five (5) absences. If a member appointed to represent a category listed in subsection (a) or (b) above loses such representative status, fails to maintain the qualifications for membership set forth in Section 2-11.38, fails to maintain attendance requirements, voluntarily resigns, or for other good cause is removed, the member shall forfeit membership on the Partnership.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Members shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary authorized expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties pursuant to policies and procedures published by the County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-127, ยง 2, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 02-35, ยง 2, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 07-71, ยง 2, 6-5-07)</history></law>