<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-116.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Area planning reports—Planning Advisory Board action.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000324</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-116.6. Area planning reports—Planning Advisory Board action.<section>Upon receipt of a proposed area planning report from the Department of Planning and Zoning, the Planning Advisory Board shall forthwith hold a public hearing thereon in the area or its vicinity, and invite the participation of interested persons, to consider the proposed area planning report including the actions proposed for its implementation. An advertisement of such public hearing, including the meeting time and place and a map depicting the area being studied and the purpose of the hearing shall be published in the newspaper of largest general circulation in Miami-Dade County not less than seven (7) days prior to the public hearing. Additionally, written courtesy notices of said public hearing, containing the time, place, description of area being studied, and a brief summary of the contents of the proposed area planning report shall be mailed to any individual or group representative who has made a written request to the Department of Planning and Zoning for such notice. Failure to mail or to receive such written notice shall not affect the validity of the public hearing or any other matter to which this ordinance pertains. Copies of the proposed area planning report shall be made available to the general public prior to and during the public hearing.</section><section>At the conclusion of the public hearing, the Planning Advisory Board shall take one (1) of the following actions:<section prefix='(a)'>By resolution make recommendation to the County Manager and Board of County Commissioners on the proposed area planning report, or state the reason(s) it is unable to make any recommendation,</section><section prefix='(b)'>Return the proposed area planning report to the Department of Planning and Zoning for further consideration and evaluation, to be followed by a further public hearing in accordance with this subsection, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Conduct another public hearing for the purpose of soliciting or suggesting revisions to the proposed area report. Such additional public hearing may either be announced at the conclusion of the previous public hearing or advertised and noticed in the manner provided in this section.</section></section><section>The above actions shall in no way prejudge or predetermine the actions of the Planning Advisory Board on any amendments to the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan or other implementation actions proposed in the report that may be subsequently heard and acted upon by the Planning Advisory Board.</section><section>The Planning Advisory Board shall complete its action on the area planning report within the schedule established by the Board of County Commissioners or obtain a time extension from the commission by resolution.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-46, § 1, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>