<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE IB. STANDARDS FOR CREATION AND REVIEW OF BOARDS GENERALLY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.37</section_number>
<catch_line>Creation of new boards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000165</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.37. Creation of new boards.<section prefix='(a)'>All County boards created after the effective date of this article shall be created only by ordinance. Such ordinance shall set forth the board's purpose, function, power, responsibility, jurisdiction, membership requirements and restrictions, terms and conditions of appointment to or removal from the board, and the specific staff support, if any, to be provided to the board. The ordinance shall also provide for an annual report, either oral or written, to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(b)'>After passage on first reading of an ordinance creating a new board and prior to the public hearing held on said ordinance, the County Manager shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners, a report setting forth the following information concerning the proposed new board:<section prefix='(1)'>Whether the establishment of the board will create sufficient betterment to the community to justify the Board of County Commissioners' delegation of a portion of its authority.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whether another board or agency, either public or private, which is already in existence could serve the same purpose.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The costs, both direct and indirect, of establishing and maintaining the board.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Whether the board is necessary to enable the County to obtain State or federal grants or other financing.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Whether the board should have bonding authority.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Whether the board should have final authority to enter into contracts and spend County funds, or whether its contracts and expenditures must be ratified by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Whether the creation of a new board is the best method of achieving the benefit desired.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The public hearing shall be held no earlier than six (6) weeks after passage on first reading of the ordinance creating said board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-136, ยง 3, 12-16-80)</history></law>