<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IC. INDEPENDENT REVIEW PANEL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.45</section_number>
<catch_line>Authority and powers generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000178</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.45. Authority and powers generally.<section prefix='(a)'>The Panel may hold public hearings, make factual determinations, draw conclusions, propose recommendations, and prepare interim and final reports on matters relating to serious complaints or grievances made against an employee, agency or instrumentality of Miami-Dade County. The Panel may also hold hearings, render findings of fact and conclusions of law and issue recommendations, as provided in Chapter 2, Article LXXI of the Code. The Panel shall have the authority and responsibility to determine whether complaints or grievances are sufficiently serious to institute a review process.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Panel may adopt, promulgate, amend and rescind such rules of procedure as may be necessary to exercise its authority; provided, however, that no rules shall conflict with the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Panel may demand, examine and duplicate public records and documents in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 119, Florida Statutes, as may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Panel may enter and inspect any premises under the jurisdiction or control of Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Panel may request any person, including the supervisor of the Internal Review Section of the Miami-Dade Police Department, to give sworn testimony or to produce documentary or other evidence.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Panel may conduct or participate in conferences, inquiries, meetings or studies.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Panel may request the County Attorney to render opinions relating to its duties, jurisdiction or power.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The Panel shall not interfere with any ongoing criminal investigation of the State Attorney.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-8, ยง 3, 2-19-80; Ord. No. 96-41, ยง 2, 3-5-96)</history></law>