<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-116.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Area planning reports—Legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000320</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-116.2. Area planning reports—Legislative intent.<section>It is the purpose of Sections through to provide a process for preparing and implementing "area planning reports" for portions of the unincorporated area which process shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(a)'>A procedure for initiating the preparation of growth management planning reports on an area basis;</section><section prefix='(b)'>A means of citizen participation in the preparation of area planning reports at a time reasonably convenient to the area residents, owners of property, members of homeowner associations or civic groups and other interested parties during the study process;</section><section prefix='(c)'>A method for preparing and periodically revising area planning reports that may be more detailed than the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan, and that may provide the basis for subsequent amendments to the master plan or for zoning district boundary changes and other suggested implementation actions; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>A procedure for Planning Advisory Board recommendation on area planning reports and acceptance of such reports by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A requirement for the Department of Planning and Zoning initiation of the implementation actions contained in accepted area planning reports.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-46, § 1, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98)</history></law>