<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00098' order_by='00098' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HIV/AIDS PARTNERSHIP</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1103</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000769</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1103. Organization.<section prefix='(a)'>The Partnership shall establish, adopt, and amend bylaws, rules, and regulations for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Partnership shall elect a chairperson and a chair-elect from among its members, who shall serve at the will of the Partnership. The chairperson and chair-elect shall not personally provide, represent entities that provide, or otherwise possess a financial relationship with entities that provide HIV related services funded by programs under the purview of the Partnership. The chairperson and chair-elect shall not be a representative of a grantee organization for any HIV/AIDS related program under the purview of the Partnership.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The chair-elect shall act as chairperson in the absence or inability of the chairperson.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Partnership shall have assistance from staff designated by the county manager and other governmental entities and legal representation from the county attorney's office. The staff shall maintain and keep the records of the Partnership; prepare, in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, resolutions or correspondences as the Partnership may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of the Partnership, subject to budgetary limitations.</section><section prefix='(e)'>In order to transact any business or to exercise any power vested in the Partnership, a quorum consisting of no less than thirteen (13) voting members shall be present.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All meetings of the Partnership shall be open to the public and shall be held only after adequate notice to the public. The records, reports, transcripts, minutes agenda and other documents which are made available to or prepared for or by the Partnership shall be available for public inspection and copying at a single location consistent with Chapter 119 of the Florida Statutes and the Federal Advisory Council Act.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Partnership shall not transact business or exercise its powers unless a majority of the quorum in attendance agrees to the activity. The chairperson, or five (5) Partnership members upon written request to the chairperson, may call for a special meeting.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The Partnership may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks, and may appoint as committee members individuals who are not Partnership members.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Each committee shall strive to maintain no less than one-third () membership by representatives of the affected community.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-127, ยง 3, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 02-35, ยง 3, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 07-71, ยง 2, 6-5-07)</history></law>