<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.24</section_number>
<catch_line>Disposition of unexpended omnibus reserve funds.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000154</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-11.24. Disposition of unexpended omnibus reserve funds.<section prefix='(1)'>All unexpended omnibus reserve funds at the end of each fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 1995-96, shall be earmarked in the Countywide General Fund Budget for the following fiscal year for the Countywide General Fund Reserve for State and Federal Funding Cuts. These funds shall only be for expenditure on social service, affordable housing, community and economic development programs. Additionally, these funds shall supplement and not supplant the funding included in the proposed operating budget designated for the Countywide General Fund Reserve for State and Federal Funding Cuts. The Board shall be duly notified of unexpended omnibus reserve funds and those funds shall be incorporated as an amendment to the Countywide General Fund Budget Ordinance.</section><section prefix='(2)'>These funds shall be subject to the provisions of the ordinance that regulates the Countywide General Fund Reserve for State and Federal Funding Cuts. Particularly, allocations from these funds must require a favorable recommendation from the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Housing, Community and Economic Development shall mean services such as but not limited to programs for the homeless, housing counseling, affordable housing, fair housing, community development corporations, community development programs, and economic development programs.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Social services shall mean services such as but not limited to employment training, drug and alcohol rehabilitation, drug prevention, mental health, meals programs, temporary shelter, child care, child development, acculturation, family support services or services that target specific communities such as but not limited to children, adolescents, elderly, disabled, mentally ill, indigent, migrant workers, immigrants, homeless, illiterate, substance abusers and domestic violence victims.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Unexpended omnibus reserve funds shall mean any funds which have not been allocated by September 30 of the fiscal year in which they were originally budgeted.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>This section shall repeal any actions by the Board of County Commissioners that are in conflict with this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(5)'>This section shall stand repealed two (2) years after its effective date.</section><section prefix='(6)'>This section [Ordinance No. 96-35] shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-35, §§ 1—3, 5—7, 2-20-96)</history></law>