<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-110</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Organization; meetings; quorum; rules; records of meetings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000293</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-110. Same—Organization; meetings; quorum; rules; records of meetings.<section>The Planning Advisory Board shall elect a Chairperson and such other officers as may be necessary from among its members to serve for a one (1) year term commencing March first. Elections shall be held in February of each year, and each officer shall serve until his or her successor is elected. The Director of Planning and Zoning shall be the executive director and secretary of the Planning Advisory Board. Such staff as may be necessary to assist and advise the Planning Advisory Board in the fulfillment of its duties shall be furnished by the Department of Planning and Zoning. All meetings of the Board shall be held in a public place and shall be open to the public. Six (6) members of the Board shall constitute a quorum, and, except as otherwise provided, decisions may be made by majority vote of the members present at a meeting at which a quorum is present. The Planning Advisory Board may prescribe other rules for the conduct of its affairs. The Chairperson, or in his or her absence, the Acting Chairperson, may administer oaths and compel the attendance of witnesses in the manner prescribed for the attendance of witnesses in the County Court. The Planning Advisory Board shall keep minutes of its proceedings and records of its other official actions, showing the vote of each member on each question. If a member is absent or fails to vote, the record shall indicate such fact. All records shall be filed immediately in the Department of Planning and Zoning office and shall be open to the inspection of the public.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-8, § 14.06, 8-30-57; Ord. No. 59-2, § 1, 1-20-59; Ord. No. 81-53, § 2, 5-5-81; Ord. No. 94-119, § 1, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 1, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 05-188, § 4, 11-3-05)</history></law>