<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='3'>ARTICLE XVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY EXPRESSWAY AUTHORITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-129</section_number>
<catch_line>Governing body; composition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000348</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-129. Governing body; composition.<section>The governing body of the Authority shall consist of thirteen (13) members, each of whom shall, except for the District Secretary of the Florida Department of Transportation, at all times during his or her term of office be a resident of Miami-Dade County. The governing body shall consist of:<section prefix='(a)'>Five (5) voting members appointed by the Governor.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Seven (7) voting members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners. Up to two (2) of the members so appointed may be elected officials residing in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Four (4) non-voting members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>The District Six Secretary of the Florida Department of Transportation shall serve as a voting member of the governing body.</section></section><section>The terms of the members shall be four (4) years each, except that the initial terms of the voting members shall be as follows: one (1) member appointed by the Governor shall serve a one (1) year term and two (2) members appointed by the Governor shall serve a two (2) year term; two (2) members appointed by the County Commission shall serve a three (3) year term and three (3) members appointed by the Commission shall serve a four (4) year term; and except that the initial terms of those persons who were non-voting members of the Authority prior to July 1, 1997 shall be: two (2) members shall serve a three (3) year term and two (2) members shall serve a four (4) year term. Upon the effective date of his or her appointment, or as soon as practicable thereafter, each appointed member shall enter upon his or her duties. A member shall hold office until his or her successor has been appointed and qualified. Any member of the Authority is eligible for reappointment. The Governor may remove any member of the governing body from office for misconduct, malfeasance, misfeasance, or nonfeasance in office. Members of the governing body shall receive from the Authority their travel and other expenses incurred in connection with the business of the Authority as provided in Section 112.061, Florida Statutes, but they may not draw salaries or other compensation from the Authority. Members of the governing body shall comply with the applicable financial disclosure requirements of Florida Statutes Sections 112.3145, 112.3148, and 112.3149, and the Code of Ethics for Public Officers and Employees at Florida Statutes Section 112.311, et seq.</section><section>All those persons initially appointed as non-voting members on the Board shall be converted to voting members, as of July 1, 1997, without any effect on their initial term of office. When the initial term of members who were non-voting member prior to July 1, 1997 expires, those members shall be replaced by two (2) Governor-appointed members and two (2) Board of County Commissioners-appointed members, until the governing body is comprised of seven (7) voting members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners and five (5) voting members appointed by the Governor.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-215, ยง 2, 12-13-95; Ord. No. 98-4, ยง 1, 1-13-98)</history></law>