<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. BRANCH OFFICES OF COUNTY AUTO TAG AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-125</section_number>
<catch_line>Compliance with applicable rules, regulations, required; supervision or revocation of agency authorization, review of suspension or revocation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000344</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-125. Compliance with applicable rules, regulations, required; supervision or revocation of agency authorization, review of suspension or revocation.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to complying with the laws, rules and regulations of the United States, Florida and Miami-Dade County, the operator of private branch agencies and limited branch offices shall fully comply with all rules and regulations of the Florida Division of Motor Vehicles, Florida Department of Revenue, the County Manager, and the Tax Collector.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Tax Collector shall have authority to prescribe rules and regulations relating to the operation of all branch offices and limited branch offices and standards of service.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Failure to comply with any applicable laws, rules or regulations of the United States, Florida and Miami-Dade County, including those promulgated by the County Manager and Tax Collector, shall constitute adequate and sufficient grounds for suspension or revocation by the County Manager of the operator's authorization. In the event of such action, the County Manager shall serve a notice of suspension or revocation upon the operator. Conditions of suspension or revocation may include, in the County Manager's discretion, immediate suspension of operations until such time as a review, if requested, is concluded. If three (3) violations of this ordinance which result in a letter of reprimand and/or suspension occur within an eighteen-month period, it will be grounds for revocation of authorization to operate the branch office. The Tax Collector may in his discretion continue branch office operations with his own personnel during the period in which a suspension is in effect or during which operations have been suspended pending review.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The operator may seek review by the Board of County Commissioners of the County Manager's notice of suspension or revocation by filing a written request for review with the clerk of the board within fifteen (15) days from the date of service of the County Manager's notice. If requested, said review shall be scheduled on the next available Board agenda. The operator shall have the right to present its position and all supporting evidence to the Board as part of the Board's review. Witnesses shall be sworn and the rules of evidence applicable to quasi-judicial proceedings shall govern. The Board shall hear and consider all facts material to the review and may affirm, modify or reverse the action taken. The decision of the Board shall be final unless overturned by a court of competent jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Nothing herein is to be deemed to vest in any third party the right to require the Tax Collector or the County Manager to take any course of action with respect to the activities of branch offices.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any violations by a limited branch office of this article and/or administrative orders shall constitute an irreparable injury and grounds for suspension or revocation of the privilege of utilizing the EFS system in Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-135, ยง 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, ยง 5, 6-17-97)</history></law>