<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00105' order_by='00105' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXVII. AIRCRAFT NOISE ABATEMENT TASK FORCE FOR OPA-LOCKA EXECUTIVE AIRPORT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1273</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000816</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1273. Membership.<section prefix='(a)'>Members. The Task Force shall consist of not fewer than seven (7) or more than nine (9) members, each of whom shall be appointed by the Mayor or designee. The Task Force is to be composed of members providing balanced representation from the communities impacted by aircraft noise at OPF, current and prospective tenants of OPF, and MDAD. The members of the Task Force shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County ("Code") and shall serve without compensation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Term. The members of the Task Force shall serve staggered terms of two (2) years each. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, no member shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive terms.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Vacancies. Vacancies in the membership of the Task Force shall be filled in the same manner by which the original Task Force members were appointed and shall be filled within 45 days.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Removal from Office. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, if any Task Force member is absent from two (2) consecutive Task Force meetings annually without an acceptable excuse, or from four (4) Task Force meetings annually without an acceptable excuse, the Task Force shall certify the same to the Mayor or designee.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Exemption from Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. Pursuant to the authority of Section 2-11.39.2 of the Code, the members of the Task Force are exempted from the application of the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance arising from Task Force membership.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-15, ยง 3, 2-5-08)</history></law>