<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. BRANCH OFFICES OF COUNTY AUTO TAG AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-120</section_number>
<catch_line>Eligibility to apply to operate a branch office; qualifications, examination of applicants; conditions for transfer of branch office; reporting responsibilities of applicants and operators.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000334</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-120. Eligibility to apply to operate a branch office; qualifications, examination of applicants; conditions for transfer of branch office; reporting responsibilities of applicants and operators.<section prefix='(a)'>Effective July 1, 1994, authorization for operation of a new branch office shall be awarded to the highest bidder. Only applicants in the eligibility pool established and maintained by the Tax Collector shall be eligible to bid. The eligibility list in existence as of the effective date of this ordinance shall expire July 1, 1994. However, applicants on said list can be placed in the eligibility pool by notifying the Tax Collector by certified mail no later than thirty (30) days from the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The eligibility pool shall contain only the names of applicants whose written applications have been approved, who have qualified by written examination and who have paid an application fee established by administrative order. A grade of seventy (70) in the written examination shall qualify the applicant for purposes of passing the examination and the names of those qualified shall appear in the eligibility pool. A qualified applicant shall remain eligible to bid for newly established branch offices or on those existing offices offered for sale provided that the Tax Collector is notified via certified mail every three (3) years that the applicant wishes to remain in the eligibility pool. The Tax Collector shall open the eligibility pool each October 1, or whenever he deems appropriate. An advertisement shall appear in a newspaper of daily circulation at least forty-five (45) days prior to the opening of any eligibility pool. The advertisement shall be in substantially the following form:<section>"Notice for acceptance of applications for authorizations to operate branch auto tag agency offices of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency in Miami-Dade County, Florida."</section><section>"Pursuant to the provisions of, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, notice is hereby given that applications will be accepted for eligibility to bid for an award of authorization to operate a new or existing branch auto tag agency of the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency. Application forms may be obtained from the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency, 140 West Flagler Street, Miami, beginning at . Completed applications may be filed with the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector at any time following the above time and date along with a application fee. All persons submitting a completed application prior to shall submit to a written examination to be given at on . An application list will be established based upon a qualifying score on the written examination. All future authorizations for new agencies will be offered to the highest bidder in the eligibility pool maintained by the Tax Collector. The sale or transfer of existing agencies will be allowable only to those applicants in said eligibility pool. No person shall be appointed to simultaneously operate more than one branch auto tag agency office. Only legal residents of the United States who reside in Miami-Dade County or corporations authorized to operate within the State of Florida shall be authorized to operate branch auto tag agency offices."</section></section><section>"MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA By "</section><section prefix='(c)'>As established by administrative order, a fee shall be paid to the County for the transfer by sale or gift of any authorization granted hereunder. The fee owed to the County will be paid in full upon consummation of the sale or transfer. No fee shall be paid for transfer by gift to family, as defined in Section 2-119.2(f)(1), or by testamentary devise pursuant to Section 2-119.2(f)(1).</section><section prefix='(d)'>At the time of application, each applicant shall provide complete information about any prior violation of any provision of this article, any prior charge or conviction of any felony or of any offense involving moral turpitude or the mishandling of funds or properties, the nature and extent of his business or professional experience, character, employment and business references and such other information as may be required by applicable law or that the Tax Collector may in his discretion deem appropriate.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Each applicant and operator is required to keep on file with the Tax Collector complete and current copies of all documents requested by the Tax Collector consistent with State and County disclosure requirements and necessary to the Tax Collector for implementation of this article, including the name of the designee required in subsection (f) of this section. The Tax Collector shall be notified of all changes to the applicant's or operator's corporate charter, officers and directors and of individuals having a financial interest in the branch agency. Additionally, a copy of any contract executed in the event of a transfer or sale of existing agency shall be submitted to the Tax Collector.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Corporate applicants and operators shall be represented by one qualified officer or employee who will be responsible for fulfilling all requirements of this article that pertain to applicants and operators. A person so designated can act only on behalf of one applicant or operator. In the event that the designated person's affiliation or employment with the applicant or operator ends, there must be designated within thirty (30) days a successor who must qualify by written examination as provided in subsection (b) herein.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Only legal residents of the United States who reside in Miami-Dade County or corporations authorized to operate within the State of Florida shall be authorized by the County to operate branch auto tag agency offices.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-135, § 2, 6-21-94)</history></law>