<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. BRANCH OFFICES OF COUNTY AUTO TAG AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-126</section_number>
<catch_line>Violations by operators and employees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000345</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-126. Violations by operators and employees.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person, whether as an individual or as an officer, manager, agent or employee of a private branch office or a limited branch office who shall receive or collect any money from any person upon the representation, promise or for the purpose of payment of any taxes or fees imposed on any motor vehicle or boat for which a fee, commission or any other compensation is collected or expected and who shall convert or embezzle said money to his/her own use or benefit or to the use or benefit of some person other than the taxpayer or who shall fail to pay over said money to the Tax Collector within the time prescribed by this article and applicable administrative orders or to the person paying same upon demand, shall be guilty of embezzlement and shall upon conviction be punished as if he/she had been guilty of larceny.</section><section prefix='(b)'>An operator shall not knowingly aid or abet any person or firm in an unlawful transaction relating to a motor vehicle, boat or any other vehicle. It shall be unlawful for any branch office or limited branch office to knowingly give false information to persons with whom it deals concerning official agency or limited branch office transactions.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Private auto tag agencies shall not conduct business in such a manner as to restrict the choice of certified service providers by a licensed branch office.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Certified service providers shall not conduct business in such a manner as to restrict the choice of private auto tag agencies by a licensed branch office.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Limited branch offices shall not conduct business in such a manner as to restrict the choice of certified service providers and/or private auto tag agencies by a licensed branch office.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Violations of any of the provisions of this section shall constitute an irreparable injury and grounds for suspension or revocation of authorization to operate the branch office or limited branch office.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-135, ยง 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 97-93, ยง 6, 6-17-97)</history></law>