<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00104' order_by='00104' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXVI. TARGETED JOBS INCENTIVE FUND PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1256</section_number>
<catch_line>Application process.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000808</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1256. Application process.<section>Through September 30, 2020, a company wishing to participate in the TJIF Program will submit an application to The Beacon Council. Upon request, a Company's confidentiality will be protected for any information regarding a project's location and/or expansion evaluation of any site in Florida in accordance with Sections 288.075 and 288.1066 of the Florida Statues.</section><section>The application will be approved by the Board of County Commissioners and all TJIF requirements shall be incorporated therein to ensure all parties comply with the requirements of this Ordinance. An application must be signed by an officer of the applying company.</section><section>At the time of application, The Beacon Council will confirm that the Company has provided information and/or documentation supporting the Company's consideration of other locations and that the requested TJIF incentive is required for the Company to choose Miami-Dade County as the location of its new operations or expansion. Any Company decisions committing the Company to a location in the County prior to the Board of County Commissioners approval of the TJIF application/agreement will render a Company ineligible to participate in the TJIF program. The County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee may waive this prior decision rule and forward the Company's application to the Board of County Commissioners for consideration upon the written request by the Company to preserve the inducement for a limited time period and the recommendation of The Beacon Council. However, the Board of County Commissioners retains the sole and absolute discretion to approve or deny the Company's application. This prior business decision rule waiver shall not be available to a Company that has already publicly disclosed the intent to locate or expand its operations in Miami-Dade County. Upon receipt and initial review, The Beacon Council shall contact the County to schedule application presentation to County staff as directed by the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee. Within 14 days of receipt of the Company's application, The Beacon Council shall prepare its recommendation on the application, including an economic impact analysis utilizing a professionally accepted econometric model such as Department of Commerce, BEA RIMS-II; Minnesota Implan Group, IMPLAN V.3; or REMI, Inc., REMI Model PI+. At the request of The Beacon Council or at the direction of the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee, the analysis and projections of economic and fiscal impacts may be performed by the Office of Economic Development and International Trade, or its successor department, using a professionally accepted econometric model such as those noted above. Each Board approved application shall serve as the written agreement between Miami-Dade County and the Company, and shall include all application requirements outlined in this Section and, at a minimum, specify:<section prefix='a.'>The total number of New Jobs to be created and that will be dedicated to the project, the Average Annual Wage of those jobs, and a time schedule or plan for when such jobs will be in place and active in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='b.'>The projected amount of Capital Investment on the project;</section><section prefix='c.'>The fiscal impact to the County;</section><section prefix='d.'>The timeframe of when the project will be completed and when the Capital Investment will appear on the County tax roll;</section><section prefix='e.'>The maximum amount of TJIF awards which the Company is eligible to receive on the project and the maximum amount of TJIF awards that the Company is eligible to receive for each fiscal year;</section><section prefix='f.'>That Miami-Dade County may review and verify the financial and personnel records of the Company and/or perform on-site visits to verify employment relating to the New Jobs, wages paid, and the Capital Investment indicated in the TJIF application/agreement, and ascertain whether the Company is in compliance with the terms of the application/agreement;</section><section prefix='g.'>The date (May 15) by which, in each fiscal year, the Company must file a claim to be considered to receive a TJIF award in the following County fiscal year;</section><section prefix='h.'>That compliance with the terms and conditions of the approved application/agreement is a condition precedent for the receipt of any TJIF award in a fiscal year and that the Company's failure to comply with the terms and conditions of the approved application/agreement results in the loss of eligibility for receipt of TJIF awards and the revocation by the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee of the certification of the Company as a TJIF eligible business;</section><section prefix='i.'>That payment of TJIF incentives are conditioned on and subject to specific annual appropriations by the Board sufficient to pay amounts under the approved application/agreement; and</section><section prefix='j.'>That the amount of the incentives received will be based on the incentive levels specified in Section 2-1258 of the County Code.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-98, ยง 7, 7-25-00; Ord. No. 02-251, ยง 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 11-08, ยง 1, 2-1-11)</history></law>