<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. BRANCH OFFICES OF COUNTY AUTO TAG AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-121</section_number>
<catch_line>Bond and insurance; amount, terms, conditions; computers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000339</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-121. Bond and insurance; amount, terms, conditions; computers.<section prefix='(a)'>Before being authorized or reauthorized, each potential or current operator shall give bond with good and sufficient sureties, or part cash collateral with the Tax Collector. The amount and type of said bond will be set forth in Administrative Order 4-83. Such bond shall be conditioned upon the branch office and its officers, directors, agents and employees' faithful compliance with all laws, correctly accounting for all moneys coming into its hands, and using ordinary care in correctly informing persons with whom it deals concerning any taxes or fees levied against them or their property. Such bond shall be payable to the County for any damages suffered by the County by reason of any unlawful act, fraud, neglect or embezzlement by such branch office, its owners, employees, officers or agents. It is further provided that any person who shall be damaged by reason of any unlawful act, fraud, neglect or embezzlement of said branch office shall have as his sole recourse an action on said bond in his name against the principal and sureties thereon. In no event shall such person claiming to have been damaged have any right, remedy, action or course of action against the County or its agents or employees.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each branch office shall furnish evidence of liability insurance in an amount and type to be determined by the County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The bond and insurance shall be carried with solvent and responsible insurers authorized to transact business in the State of Florida. Such bond and insurance shall be subject to the approval of the County risk manager prior to acceptance by the Tax Collector. Failure of the operator to maintain the required bond and insurance shall result in suspension of all auto tag activities during the period when the bond and insurance are not in effect.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Computer equipment providing access to Division of Motor Vehicle (DMV) Florida Real Time Information System (FRTIS) will be supplied and maintained by DMV. Operators shall be required to execute a use agreement with the State and maintain such insurance thereon as required by the State. Failure to execute and comply with said agreement may result in the removal of the agency's computer equipment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-135, ยง 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 01-25, ยง 2, 2-13-01)</history></law>