<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00104' order_by='00104' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXVI. TARGETED JOBS INCENTIVE FUND PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1255</section_number>
<catch_line>Program requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000807</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1255. Program requirements.<section>Companies applying for TJIF incentives must be New-to-Market Companies or Expanding Businesses. Any company applying for TJIF incentives must pay all of its employees salaries that are no less than the Living Wage Rate as defined by of the Code of Miami-Dade County as adjusted annually by the Miami-Dade County Department of Small Business Development, or its successor department. Companies receiving TJIF incentives must pay all of its employees no less than the Living Wage Rate to remain eligible for the TJIF program. In addition, the New Jobs promised under the TJIF application/agreement must pay an estimated Average Annual Wage at least equal to the average private sector wage of the County or the statewide private sector average wage, in determining the Average Annual Wage, only New Jobs are to be included and wages for existing jobs shall be excluded from the calculation. The Board of County Commissioners at its discretion may waive the Average Annual Wage requirement upon receipt of a written request and justification from the Beacon Council and the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee.</section><section>New-to-Market or Expanding Businesses must create at least ten (10) New Jobs within three (3) years of starting operations or completing their Capital Investment commitment in Miami-Dade County, whichever is later, and maintain those new jobs for an additional three (3) years. County staff, as directed by the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee, must verify compliance with New Job creation and wage requirements as specified in the Board of County Commissioners approved TJIF application/agreement prior to any disbursement of a TJIF incentive. The Company must agree to furnish all documents necessary for staff to verify the Company's compliance with the New Job and salary requirements pursuant to the TJIF application/agreement.</section><section>The Company's Capital Investment must generate economic growth within Miami-Dade County and strengthen Miami-Dade County's tax base over the period for which the TJIF incentive is provided. The Capital Investment must be verified by County staff, as directed by the County Mayor or the County Mayor's designee, from a review of information available from the Company, the Tax Collector's records or any other sources prior to disbursement of a TJIF incentive award. The Company must furnish an independently audited financial accounting to verify the Capital Investment, when the County so requests, as provided in.</section><section>Where a Company is delinquent in paying its County taxes the County shall withhold Incentive funds until the Company is current on such taxes. Where a Company is more than one (1) year delinquent in paying such taxes, the Company's TJIF award shall be canceled and the Company shall be disqualified from participating in the TJIF program.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-98, ยง 6, 7-25-00; Ord. No. 02-251, ยง 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 05-193, ยง 2, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 11-08, ยง 1, 2-1-11)</history></law>