<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00104' order_by='00104' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXVI. TARGETED JOBS INCENTIVE FUND PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1252</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000804</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1252. Definitions.<section>As used in this article, unless the context otherwise requires:<section prefix='a.'>Average Annual Wage means the average of all wages and salaries in the State of Florida or Miami-Dade County, using the most currently available data as determined by the Florida Agency for Workforce Innovation.</section><section prefix='b.'>Capital Investment means the amount of money that a business spends on local taxable real and/or tangible personal property, which shall be limited to new construction, renovation of buildings and new equipment used in business operations as specified in the TJIF application/agreement.</section><section prefix='c.'>County Code means the Code of Ordinances of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='d.'>Company means a business, or employing unit, as defined in Section 443.036, Florida Statutes, which is registered with the Florida Agency for Workforce Innovation for unemployed compensation purposes; or a subcategory or subdivision of an employing unit which is accepted by the Agency for Workforce Innovation as a reporting unit.</section><section prefix='e.'>Designated Priority Area or Designated Priority Areas means the Empowerment Zone area as designated by the Board of County Commissioners by Resolution No. R-1028-98 as may be amended, Enterprise Zone areas as designated by the Board of County Commissioners by Ordinances Nos. 0-88-27 and 0-96-74 as well as Resolutions No. R-492-95 and No. R-913-08, as may be amended, Targeted Urban Areas designated by the Board of County Commissioners by Ordinance No. 97-33 as may be amended, Brownfields areas as designated by the Board of County Commissioners by Resolution R-767-99 as may be amended, and Community Development Block Grant eligible areas as designated by the Board of County Commissioners by Resolution No. 618-02 as may be amended.</section><section prefix='f.'>Expanding Business or Expanding Businesses means a commercial or industrial business, excluding residential development that increases operations on a site in Miami-Dade County co-located with a commercial or industrial operation owned by the same business or a site in Miami-Dade County to which the commercial or industrial operation will relocate or has relocated.</section><section prefix='g.'>Incentive or Incentives means the funds paid to a Company under this TJIF Program by the County.</section><section prefix='h.'>New Job or New Jobs means jobs created by a local Expanding Business or a New-to-Market Business which are being added to the Company's roster of employees and that did not exist within the last twelve (12) months prior to the date The Beacon Council submits the Company's application to the County.</section><section prefix='i.'>New-to-Market Business or New-to-Market Company is an entity that relocates to Miami-Dade County or is a start-up company setting up operations in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='j.'>South Florida means the region comprised of Miami-Dade, Broward, and Palm Beach counties.</section><section prefix='k.'>The Beacon Council means Miami-Dade County's official economic development partnership entity as designated by the Board of County Commissioners per Ordinance No. 87-38.</section><section prefix='l.'>TJIF Project or Project means the capital investment and the associated new jobs that are the basis of the application for a TJIF award.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-98, ยง 3, 7-25-00; Ord. No. 02-251, ยง 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 11-08, ยง 1, 2-1-11)</history></law>