<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. BRANCH OFFICES OF COUNTY AUTO TAG AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-122</section_number>
<catch_line>Grant, revocation of decal paper stock and/or tag consignment privileges; inventory of decals and/or tags.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000341</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-122. Grant, revocation of decal paper stock and/or tag consignment privileges; inventory of decals and/or tags.<section>Upon the issuance of the bond required by and the payment of the occupational license tax required by, each branch office may secure decal paper stock and/or tags from the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency.</section><section>Each branch office may be granted decal paper stock and/or tag distribution privileges at quantities for automobiles and vessels and classes to be determined by the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency. The Tax Collector shall prescribe rules and regulations upon which the distribution privileges are predicated.</section><section>All reports shall be accompanied by remittances in full and reports for tags sold shall be returned to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency on the basis of first in-first out, according to each series.</section><section>Each branch office shall furnish the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency with a letter setting forth the names and signatures of that branch office's qualified employees who can receive and sign for decal paper stock, tags and other accountable items.</section><section>The failure of any operator or its employees or agents to comply with any rules, regulations or the provisions of this article shall constitute adequate and sufficient grounds for the revocation of prepayment and/or decal paper stock and/or tag distribution privileges in the discretion of the Tax Collector.</section><section>Each branch office shall, upon request of the Tax Collector or his representative, return all unused decal paper stock, tags, and other accountable documents, licenses and items supplied by the Tax Collector to the Miami-Dade County Auto Tag Agency for inventory purposes, and all decal paper stock, tags and other accountable documents, located within the branch office's place of business, shall be subject to physical inventory by the Tax Collector or his representative at any time.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-135, ยง 2, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 01-25, ยง 3, 2-13-01)</history></law>