<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00110' order_by='00110' level='3'>ARTICLE XCII. COMMUNITY IMAGE ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1336</section_number>
<catch_line>Function.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000850</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1336. Function.<section prefix='1.'>Submittal of Semi-annual Reports. The Advisory Board shall be responsible for providing two (2) reports per year for the duration of its existence, the first of which shall be submitted to the Board within three (3) months following the passage of this article or the first meeting of the Advisory Board, whichever is later. Each subsequent semi-annual report will be submitted within six (6) months following the submittal of the prior report, but provided that no more than two (2) reports need be presented to the Board of County Commissioners in one (1) year. For purposes of this article, a year shall be the 365 contiguous days following the submittal of the first Semi-annual report, regardless of whether those 365 days fall in a single calendar year.</section><section prefix='2.'>Contents of the Semi-annual Reports. The first semi-annual report in a given year shall contain the Advisory Board's prioritization of the Community Image Goals, as set forth in Section 2 (A), above, with the highest priority given to the Community Image Goal most necessary for the enhancement of tourism. This report will include an analysis detailing which County departments, if any, have an existing responsibility and budget allotment to undertake the Community Image Goal. The second semi-annual report will provide an action plan for each of the Goals, including which County departments should be responsible to undertake the proposed action(s). The second semi-annual report will detail the approximate budget required for each of the proposed actions, shall constitute the final Community Image plan to be submitted to the Board for consideration, and will contain the Advisory Committee's final action plan based on the priorities and budgets contained therein.</section><section prefix='3.'>The Advisory Board may promulgate rules consistent with this article for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities under this article. Any rules promulgated by the Advisory Board under this section shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for ratification.</section><section prefix='4.'>Implementation of the Community Image Plan. It shall be the responsibility of the County Manager to implement the elements of the plans that she or he, in her or his discretion, determines are in the best interest of the County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-164, ยง 2, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-31, ยง 1, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 03-215, ยง 2, 10-7-03)</history></law>