<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00107' order_by='00107' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXXIX. DIAL-A-LIFE PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1311</section_number>
<catch_line>Creation; operations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000831</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1311. Creation; operations.<section prefix='A.'>Creation of the Dial-A-Life Program. There is hereby created and established the Dial-A-Life Program for the purpose of collecting cellular and/or mobile telephones and distributing them to eligible members of the Miami-Dade County community for purpose of providing them access to emergency "911" services.</section><section prefix='B.'>Dial-A-Life Program Operations.<section prefix='1.'>Collection from Public. The Dial-A-Life Program is to operate through the Miami-Dade Fire Rescue Department (the "Department"). The Department shall coordinate the distribution of collection bins provided by the Miami-Dade Solid Waste Department ("Solid Waste") in at least five (5) locations throughout Miami-Dade County for the purpose of collecting discarded cellular and/or mobile telephones from members of the Miami-Dade County community ("Donors"). The Department shall also be responsible for distributing information regarding the Dial-A-Life Program, and collecting any and all information and/or forms from Donors required by the Dial-A-Life Program Board, as provided in Section 2-1312, below. The Department will also distribute, if requested by Donors, receipts reflecting the approximate value of the donated cellular and/or mobile telephones.</section><section prefix='2.'>County Surplus Telephones. Notwithstanding anything in Administrative Order 8-2 or Section 2-11.2.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, the County may assign surplus mobile and/or cellular telephones with no commercial value to the Dial-A-Life Program for donation in accordance with the terms and conditions of this article; provided, however, that the Board of County Commissioners first make a finding by resolution that any surplus cellular and/or mobile telephones slated for donation through the Dial-A-Life Program are obsolete, or their continued use is uneconomical or inefficient, or that they no longer serve a useful function, and that they are without commercial value. All donation of County surplus mobile and/or cellular telephones shall be in accordance with Section 274.05 or 274.06 of the Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='3.'>Distribution to Eligible Recipients. The cellular and/or mobile telephones collected by the Department for the Dial-A-Life Program shall be distributed to persons whose household income is less than twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) per year and/or who are:<section prefix='(1)'>Living with a physical or mental disability;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Over the age of sixty-five (65);</section><section prefix='(3)'>Have children in the home who are at-risk or disabled; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Have been victims of domestic violence (collectively "Eligible Recipients").</section></section></section><section>The Dial-A-Life Program Board, as provided in below, shall establish all guidelines for the distribution of the telephones to Eligible Recipients, including, but not limited to those for: proof of income, proof of disability, and proof of domestic violence. No more than two (2) cellular and/or mobile telephones will be distributed to a household.</section><section prefix='C.'>Sunset. The provisions of this ordinance shall sunset on June 15, 2013, unless otherwise reenacted by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-115, ยง 1, 7-10-01; Ord. No. 02-40, ยง 1, 3-12-02; Ord. No. 07-180, ยง 1, 12-18-07; Ord. No. 13-65, ยง 1, 7-2-13)</history></law>