<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00110' order_by='00110' level='3'>ARTICLE XCII. COMMUNITY IMAGE ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1334</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000848</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1334. Purpose.<section>The Advisory Board shall be responsible for establishing the yearly Community Image plans, including budget and initiative priorities, based on the following Community Image 2000 Goals:<section prefix='(1)'>The proper maintenance of grass in and around our main roadways and transportation gateways;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The continued enhancement of our main roadways and transportation gateways through the replacement of unhealthy or damaged landscaping;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The enhancement of areas under overpasses and bridges;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The establishment of a standard color-scheme for bridge overpasses;</section><section prefix='(5)'>The proper maintenance around the Metrorail and Metromover system and the creation of exciting designs through lighting, painting, and cosmetic changes to the Metrorail and Metromover trains;</section><section prefix='(6)'>The elimination of litter and trash on our main roadways and transportation gateways;</section><section prefix='(7)'>The clearance of roadway intersections and emergency lanes of debris;</section><section prefix='(8)'>The enhancement of all roadways serving major tourist transportation terminals, such as the airport, seaport, and train station;</section><section prefix='(9)'>The enhancement of water retention areas near major roadways through the use of lighting and fountains.</section><section prefix='(10)'>The education of the community regarding the goals of the Advisory Board, especially roadway and transportation gateway beautification.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-164, ยง 2, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-31, ยง 1, 2-26-02)</history></law>