<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00110' order_by='00110' level='3'>ARTICLE XCII. COMMUNITY IMAGE ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1335</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization of the board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000849</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1335. Organization of the board.<section prefix='1.'>Membership. The Advisory Board shall be made up of the following members:<section prefix='a.'>A representative from Florida Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix='b.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade County Solid Waste Department;</section><section prefix='c.'>A representative member from Team Metro;</section><section prefix='d.'>A representative from each municipality located within Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='e.'>A representative from West Kendall;</section><section prefix='f.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department;</section><section prefix='g.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade Transit Agency;</section><section prefix='h.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade County Park and Recreation Department;</section><section prefix='i.'>A representative from the County Manager's Office;</section><section prefix='j.'>A Miami-Dade County Commissioner from each Commission District or his or her designee;</section><section prefix='k.'>A representative from the Expressway Authority;</section><section prefix='l.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade County Aviation Department;</section><section prefix='m.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade County Seaport;</section><section prefix='n.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade Planning & Zoning Department;</section><section prefix='o.'>A representative from the Metropolitan Planning Organization ("MPO");</section><section prefix='p.'>A representative from Miami-Dade County Public Schools;</section><section prefix='q.'>A representative from Transportation Aesthetics Review Committee ("TARC");</section><section prefix='r.'>A representative from the Citizen's Transportation Advisory Committee ("CTAC");</section><section prefix='s.'>A representative from the Homestead/Florida City Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix='t.'>A representative from the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix='u.'>A representative from the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau;</section><section prefix='v.'>A representative from the Downtown Development Authority;</section><section prefix='w.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade League of Cities;</section><section prefix='x.'>A representative from Amtrak;</section><section prefix='y.'>A representative from Tri-Rail.</section><section prefix='z.'>A representative on behalf of the media sector.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>Appointment of members. The County Manager shall contact each of the organizations, companies, and municipalities referenced in Section (1) above, and shall request that each of these organizations, companies, and municipalities submit the names of at least one (1) interested and eligible nominee. The nominee from West Kendall shall be selected by the Commissioner from District 11. These nominees shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners in the form of a report for approval and appointment to the Advisory Board.</section><section prefix='3.'>Meetings. The Advisory Board shall hold regular meetings, no less than six times per year, and such other meetings as it deems necessary. Ten (10) of the duly appointed and sitting members of the Advisory Board shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Advisory Board and all meetings shall be duly noticed to the public.</section><section prefix='4.'>Applicability of County Rules and Procedures. The Advisory Board shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='5.'>Attendance requirement. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, any Advisory Board member shall be automatically removed if, in a given fiscal year he or she is absent from more than 50% of the year's meetings. A member shall be deemed absent from a meeting when he or she is not present at the meeting at least seventy-five percent of the time. By a one-third () vote of the members present, the provisions of this section may be waived.</section><section prefix='6.'>Compensation. Members of the Advisory Board shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='7.'>Staff and Facility Support. The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide such staff support to the Advisory Board as may be necessary to accomplish its purpose. The County Manager will provide such facilities as the Advisory Board may deem necessary to accomplish its purposes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-164, ยง 2, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-31, ยง 1, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 03-215, ยง 1, 10-7-03)</history></law>