<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00116' order_by='00116' level='3'>ARTICLE XCVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY YOUTH CRIME TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1432</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000891</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1432. Membership.<section>The Task Force shall consist of the following appointments:<section prefix='(a)'>Mayor of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Two Members of the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Assistant County Manager for Public Safety;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Representative from the Miami-Dade County Legislative Delegation;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Director of Miami-Dade Police Department;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Coordinator, Neighborhood Resource Team, Miami-Dade Police Department;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Chief of the City of Miami Police Department;</section><section prefix='(h)'>Chief of Police for Miami-Dade Public Schools;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Superintendent of Miami-Dade Public Schools;</section><section prefix='(j)'>Chief of the Juvenile Division, State Attorney for Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(k)'>Chief of the Juvenile Division, Public Defender's Office of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(l)'>Juvenile Court Judge, 11th Judicial Circuit;</section><section prefix='(m)'>Deputy Division Director of Operations, Department of Children & Families;</section><section prefix='(n)'>Senior Juvenile Justice Manager, Florida State Department of Juvenile Justice, District XI;</section><section prefix='(o)'>Director Delinquency Prevention Services, Miami-Dade County Department of Human Services;</section><section prefix='(p)'>Director of Miami-Dade Juvenile Assessment Center;</section><section prefix='(q)'>Director of the Children's Services Council;</section><section prefix='(r)'>Director of Metro-Miami Action Plan (MMAP);</section><section prefix='(s)'>The President of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), Florida State Conference Branch;</section><section prefix='(t)'>Up to eleven (11) members who work for or serve on the board of directors of an organization that works with youth and/or crime prevention recommended by the County Manager and appointed by the Board of County Commissioners;</section></section><section>The appointments listed in(a) through (s) may be served by a designee. If the appointment is served by a designee that person serves in the full capacity of the appointment, with all its duties and responsibilities, and not as a proxy. The appointment of a designee by a Task Force member shall be in writing to the Clerk of the Board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-131, ยง 2, 7-23-02)</history></law>