<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='3'>ARTICLE XIX. Miami-Dade TRANSIT AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-145</section_number>
<catch_line>Created and established; administrative direction and supervision; functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000357</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-145. Created and established; administrative direction and supervision; functions.<section>The Miami-Dade Transit Agency is hereby created and established. The County Manager is hereby empowered and shall have the duty and responsibility to provide the administrative direction and supervision of the Miami-Dade Transit Agency, in accordance with policies adopted and promulgated by the Board of County Commissioners. The Miami-Dade Transit Agency shall perform the following functions:<section prefix='(a)'>Routes, schedules and operations. Develop and maintain a system of routes consonant with the needs of the riding public and extend, discontinue or adjust such routes based upon studies relating to population distribution, business activity, employment, origin and destination of trips, traffic conditions, load analyses, schedules, or other such factors which would show the practicability, feasibility or general public benefit of such changes; make and adjust schedules; carry on safety and training activities; maintain an information service; conduct passenger traffic route change and marketing studies; and market the services of the transit system.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Maintenance of the fleet. Maintain, repair or modify the rolling stock of the fleet including engines, electrical systems, air conditioning systems, bodies, chassis, painting, and other mechanical components; conduct a preventative maintenance program; and keep such equipment cost accounts and records as may be necessary to determine the life, effectiveness, or usefulness of the equipment.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Damage claims. Investigate, adjust, compromise, settle or defend all damage claims arising from operation of the system in accordance with the procedures established by the County Manager pursuant to Section 2-148 of this article.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Sale of advertising space. Promote the sale of advertising space in or on the buses, stations, shelters, or other suitable facilities of the system on a nondiscriminatory basis.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Providing public transportation services and facilities for the physically disabled. Such services and facilities, in addition to other services and facilities for the disabled, shall be provided through the purchase and operation of buses equipped with appropriate devices (specifically including wheelchair lifts) to facilitate transportation of the physically disabled. The anticipated capital and operating expenditures for each fiscal year shall be determined and budgeted by the Manager in accordance with established budgetary procedures. For the purposes of this subsection, "buses" are defined as buses with a maximum capacity of forty-five (45) passengers.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-92, ยง 1, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 76-76, ยง 1, 9-7-76)</history></law>