<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00117' order_by='00117' level='3'>ARTICLE XCIX. SOCIAL AND ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1444</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and Functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000901</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1444. Duties and Functions.<section>The Council shall be charged with the following duties, functions and responsibilities and will report biannually to the Economic Development and Housing Committee:<section prefix='a.'>To suggest and recommend to the Mayor and Commissioners of Miami-Dade County the appropriate short-run policies and measures to reactivate the economy of the County, with special attention to the needs of low income segments of the population;</section><section prefix='b.'>To actively participate in and coordinate the efforts for the conceptualization, formulation and implementation of a long-run strategy for the acceleration of the social and economic development of Miami-Dade County. The resulting socioeconomic plan should aim at the rapid increase in the per-capita income of the general population as well as at the diversification of the local economy and the substantial reduction in the prevailing rates of poverty in the County;</section><section prefix='c.'>To provide a forum and medium for governmental officers and community leaders to study and address the socioeconomic consequences of the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001;</section><section prefix='d.'>To make findings and recommendations on a quarterly basis to the Mayor of Miami-Dade County and the Board of County Commissioners regarding the necessary measures to ensure full recovery and future socioeconomic development.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-120, ยง 4, 7-9-02; Ord. No. 08-117, ยง 3, 10-7-08)</history></law>