<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00116' order_by='00116' level='3'>ARTICLE XCVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY YOUTH CRIME TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1434</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and Duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000893</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1434. Powers and Duties.<section prefix='(a)'>The Task Force shall have the following powers and duties:<section prefix='(1)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to matters of youth crime, youth weapons violence and youth crime prevention.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To study the problems of youth crime and youth weapons violence in Miami-Dade County and to analyze possible solutions to these problems with particular emphasis on studying crime prevention programs which have significantly reduced youth crime in other communities and cities.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To develop an overall countywide plan for the prevention of youth crime and youth weapons violence in Miami-Dade County in cooperation with other planning agencies and entities.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To submit a written report to the Board of County Commissioners with its countywide plan and recommendations to address youth crime and youth weapons violence.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To recommend guidelines and criteria to be included in competitive solicitation processes for the allocation of youth crime prevention funding, review any and all proposals submitted through such competitive solicitation process and provide recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners or the Alliance for Human Services for the award of such youth crime prevention funding.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Task Force is advisory only and shall not have the power or authority to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities to any policies, to incur any financial obligation or to create any liability, contractual or otherwise, on behalf of Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-131, ยง 4, 7-23-02)</history></law>