<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LAW DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Duties and functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000188</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-14. Same—Duties and functions.<section prefix='(a)'>The County Attorney shall be the attorney of record in all civil suits, actions and legal proceedings wherein the County, County Commission, Manager, departments, boards or County officials or employees are parties by virtue of their official positions or actions. He shall institute and prosecute all eminent domain proceedings and other civil suits, actions and legal proceedings authorized by the County Commission. He shall defend all civil suits, actions and legal proceedings brought against the County. The County Attorney shall not be required to represent any County official or employee in respect to their private or personal affairs or actions.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Attorney shall serve as legal adviser to the County Commission, Manager, department heads, County boards, and County officers. When requested, he shall render written legal opinions on matters relating to County government and the interpretation, construction and meaning of the constitutional amendment, charter, statutes, ordinances, resolutions and contracts affecting or pertaining to the County government, and such opinions shall be binding upon, and adhered to by all appointed County officials or employees, except in the performance of judicial or quasi-judicial powers of duties. Copies of all written opinions of law rendered by the County Attorney shall be furnished to the Chairman of the County Commission and the Manager.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County Attorney shall prepare, or review and approve as to form and legal sufficiency, all County ordinances, resolutions, deeds, contract documents and other legal instruments affecting or pertaining to the County, or in which the County is a party.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The County Attorney, or an Assistant County Attorney, shall attend and be present during all regular and special meetings of the County Commission. When requested, he shall attend meetings of special committees of the County Commission, and meetings of County boards.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The County Attorney shall represent the County and department heads in hearings or trials before the Personnel Advisory Board in appeals taken by County employees under the provisions of the Larger Counties Civil Service Act, codified herein as Article IV of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The County Attorney shall perform all duties and functions imposed by general or special laws upon County Attorneys; and he shall perform such other legal duties as may be assigned by the County Commission.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 70-91, § 1, 12-1-70)</history></law>