<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00121' order_by='00121' level='3'>ARTICLE CIII. THE CHILDREN'S TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1526</section_number>
<catch_line>Fiscal Responsibilities and Obligations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000932</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1526. Fiscal Responsibilities and Obligations.<section prefix='(a)'>The fiscal year of The Children's Trust shall be the same as that of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On or before July 1 of each year, The Children's Trust shall prepare a tentative annual written budget of its expected income and expenditures, including a contingency fund. The Trust shall, in addition, compute a proposed millage rate within the voter-approved cap necessary to fund the tentative budget and, prior to adopting a final budget, comply with the provisions of s. 200.065 of the Florida Statutes, relating to the method of fixing millage, and shall fix the final millage rate by resolution of The Trust. The adopted budget and final millage rate shall be certified and delivered to the Miami-Dade Board of County Commissioners as soon as possible following The Trust's adoption of the final budget and millage rate pursuant to chapter 200 of the Florida Statutes. Included in each certified budget shall be the millage rate, adopted by resolution of The Trust, necessary to be applied to raise the funds budgeted for The Trust's operations and expenditures. In no circumstances, however, shall The Trust levy millage in excess of the maximum approved by the voters and allowed under s. 125.901 of the Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The budget of The Trust so certified and delivered to the Board of County Commissioners shall not be subject to change or modification by the Board of County Commissioners or any other authority. Neither shall the Board of County Commissioners consider The Children's Trust funds to be a supplanting of County funds for children's services.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All tax money collected under this section, as soon after the collection thereof as is reasonably practicable, shall be paid directly to The Trust by the tax collector of the county, or the clerk of the circuit court if the clerk collects delinquent taxes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All moneys received by The Trust shall be deposited in qualified public depositories, as defined in s. 280.02 of the Florida Statutes, with separate and distinguishable accounts established specifically for The Trust and shall be withdrawn only by checks signed by the chair of The Trust and countersigned by either another member of the Trust or by the chief executive officer who shall be so authorized by the Trust.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Upon entering the duties of office, the chair and either another member of The Trust or the chief executive officer who signs its checks shall each give a surety bond in the sum of at least $1,000 for each $1 million or portion thereof of The Trust's annual budget, which bond shall be conditioned that each shall faithfully discharge the duties of his or her office. The premium on such bond may be paid by The Trust as part of the expense of The Trust. No other member of The Trust shall be required to give bond or other security.</section><section prefix='(g)'>No funds of The Trust shall be expended except by check as aforesaid, except expenditures from a petty cash account which shall not at any time exceed $100. All expenditures from petty cash shall be recorded on the books and records of The Trust. No funds of The Trust, excepting expenditures from petty cash, shall be expended without prior approval of The Trust, in addition to the budgeting thereof.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Within 10 days, exclusive of weekends and legal holidays, after the expiration of each quarter annual period, The Trust shall cause to be prepared and filed with the Board of County Commissioners a financial report which shall include the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The total expenditures of The Trust for the quarter annual period;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The total receipts of The Trust during the quarter annual period;</section><section prefix='(3)'>A statement of the funds The Trust has on hand, has invested, or has deposited with qualified public depositories at the end of the quarter annual period; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>The total administrative costs of The Trust for the quarter annual period.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>After or during the first year of operation of The Trust, the board of county commissioners, at its option, may fund in whole or in part the budget of The Trust from its own funds.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The Trust shall comply with all other statutory requirements of general application which relate to the filing of any financial reports or compliance reports required under part III of chapter 218 of the Florida Statutes, or any other report or documentation required by law, including the requirements of ss. 189.415, 189.417, and 189.418 of the Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The Trust shall comply with any other fiscal responsibilities or obligations that may from time to time be added to s. 125.901 of the Florida Statutes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-247, ยง 6, 12-3-02)</history></law>