<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00120' order_by='00120' level='3'>ARTICLE CII. JAY MALINA INTERNATIONAL TRADE CONSORTIUM OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1504</section_number>
<catch_line>Composition, qualifications, and appointment and tenure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000925</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1504. Composition, qualifications, and appointment and tenure.<section prefix='(a)'>Composition. The members of the Advisory Board shall be appointed as follows: The Mayor of Miami-Dade County shall appoint the Chairperson from among the members of the Board of County Commissioners, and the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint the Vice Chair who shall be a well-respected member of the business community. The Mayor shall also appoint three other members. Each member of the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint one member to the Advisory Board. The Chair of the Advisory Board shall appoint a member. In addition, the following organizations shall appoint one member to the Advisory Board: the Beacon Council, the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce, the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau, Enterprise Florida, Inc., the Latin Chamber of Commerce (CAMACOL), World Trade Center Miami, the Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce, the District Export Council, the Florida International Bankers Association, the Florida Custom Brokers and Forwarders Association and the Foundation for Democracy in Africa. The Directors of Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami shall each appoint a representative from their respective departments.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Qualifications. Each member of the Advisory Board shall be a United States citizen, a permanent resident, and duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, unless the Board of County Commissioners waives the permanent residency and qualified elector requirements by a two-thirds vote of its membership. Members who represent economic development organizations must be members of the Board of Directors of said organizations and not paid staff members with the exception of the appointees of Miami International Airport, Port of Miami, and Enterprise Florida, Inc. Advisory Board members who are representatives of, or who are employed by, any State or local governmental agency may not vote on matters affecting the governmental agency by whom they are employed or whom they represent. The provision of Section 2-11.38 of the Miami-Dade County Code providing that no person shall serve on more than one County board simultaneously, shall not apply to the members of the Advisory Board appointed since its inception.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Tenure. The members of the ITC Board that are serving on the ITC Board at the time of the adoption of this ordinance that: (1) were appointed by the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners or (2) that have appointments on the Advisory Board representing economic development agencies shall hereafter serve on the Advisory Board until the expiration of their terms as such terms were existing on the ITC Board and shall be eligible to be reappointed for additional two-year terms up to a maximum of eight years. Those remaining ITC Board members representing agencies not having appointments on the Advisory Board shall continue to serve for a period of one year from the adoption of this ordinance. Advisory Board appointees that are appointed after the adoption of this ordinance shall serve two-year staggered terms from the time of appointment and may be reappointed to three additional two-year terms at the conclusion of their first term for a maximum of eight years.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Compensation. Advisory Board members shall serve without compensation.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Removal. Board members may be removed by a majority vote of the BCC for cause. Additionally, Board members that have three (3) absences out of a possible four (4) Board meetings within any one fiscal year shall automatically be removed from the Board.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Vacancy. Upon any vacancy of the Advisory Board member, the appropriate appointing agency or authority shall fill the vacancy.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Organization. Members of the Board shall elect one of its members as Secretary and Treasurer, and such other officers as may [be] deemed to be necessary. The Chairperson, Vice Chairperson, the elected officers, the Chairs of standing Committees, and the representatives of Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami shall constitute the Executive Committee, and shall serve for a two-year term. The Executive Committee shall act on behalf of the Board when the Board is not meeting but its decisions are subject to ratification by the full Board at a later date. The Executive Committee shall provide all Board members with an advanced copy of the agenda of the Executive Committee meetings. There shall be a Sister Cities Committee to the Board and such other committees as the Chair of the Board determines are appropriate. The Chair of the Board shall appoint the members of the Sister Cities Committee and such other committees of the Board that the Chair of the Board establishes.</section><section prefix='(h)'>By-Laws. The Advisory Board shall make, adopt, and amend its own By-Laws and Rules.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Meetings, Quorum, Sunshine and public records. The Board shall hold regular meetings in accordance with its By-Laws. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in the Code of Miami-Dade County, quorum for Board meetings shall constitute one Board member more than 40% of the Board members that have been appointed. All meetings shall be public and in accordance with Section 286.011 of the Florida Statutes, the "Sunshine Law." In addition, the books and records of the Board shall be open to the public in the manner provided in Chapter 119 of the Florida Statutes, the "Public Records Act."</section><section prefix='(j)'>Applicability of conflict of interest and code of ethics ordinance. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida shall be applicable to Advisory Board members and members of the staff.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The County Attorney shall provide support to the Advisory Board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-60, ยง 10, 9-24-10; Ord. No. 12-31, ยง 1, 5-1-12)</history></law>