<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00121' order_by='00121' level='3'>ARTICLE CIII. THE CHILDREN'S TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1522</section_number>
<catch_line>Governing Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000928</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1522. Governing Board.<section prefix='(a)'>The governing board of The Children's Trust shall consist of the following thirty-three (33) members:<section prefix='(1)'>Superintendent of Miami-Dade Public Schools;</section><section prefix='(2)'>One (1) member who is a representative of Florida International University as appointed by the university president;</section><section prefix='(3)'>One (1) member who is a representative of Miami-Dade Community College as appointed by the college president;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Miami-Dade County Manager;</section><section prefix='(5)'>District XI Administrator, State of Florida Department of Children and Family Services or designee who is a member of the Senior Management Service or the Selected Exempt Service;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Director of Miami-Dade County Public Health Department or designee;</section><section prefix='(7)'>State Attorney for Miami-Dade County or designee;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Chief Judge of Juvenile Division of the Eleventh Circuit, or another juvenile judge designated by the Chief Judge, who shall sit as a voting member of the board on all matters except for the setting of ad valorem taxes;</section><section prefix='(9)'>One (1) member selected by the Board of the United Way of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(10)'>One (1) member who is a member of and is selected by the Greater Miami Chapter of the National Conference for Community and Justice;</section><section prefix='(11)'>One (1) member who is a member of and is selected by a coalition of the local chambers of commerce;</section><section prefix='(12)'>One (1) member who is a member of and is selected by the Miami-Dade County School Readiness Coalition;</section><section prefix='(13)'>One (1) member who is a representative of the United Teachers of Dade;</section><section prefix='(14)'>One (1) member who is a member of and is selected by the Alliance for Human Services;</section><section prefix='(15)'>One (1) member who is a member of and is selected by the Miami-Dade Council of Parent-Teacher Association/Parent-Teacher-Student Association;</section><section prefix='(16)'>One (1) member who is a youth selected by the Miami-Dade Student Government Association;</section><section prefix='(17)'>One (1) member of the School Board of Miami-Dade County as appointed by the Chair of the School Board;</section><section prefix='(18)'>Mayor of Miami-Dade County or designee;</section><section prefix='(19)'>One (1) member of the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners, as appointed by the Commission Chair;</section><section prefix='(20)'>One (1) member of the State of Florida Legislature who represents residents of Miami-Dade County, as appointed by the chair of the Miami-Dade legislative delegation;</section><section prefix='(21)'>One (1) elected official representing the residents of a municipality located within Miami-Dade County, as appointed by the League of Cities;</section><section prefix='(22)'>Circuit Manager, State of Florida Department of Juvenile Justice or designee;</section><section prefix='(23)'>Four (4) members-at-large, as appointed by a majority of the sitting members of The Children's Trust;</section><section prefix='(24)'>Seven (7) members appointed by the Governor of the State of Florida in accordance with provisions set forth below.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Members Appointed by Governor.<section prefix='(1)'>Criteria. Members who are appointed by the Governor: a) must have resided within Miami-Dade County during the previous twenty-four (24) months; and b) must be representative of the geographic and demographic diversity of the population of Miami-Dade County, to the extent reasonably possible.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Selection Process. The Miami-Dade Board of County Commissioners, after soliciting recommendations from the public, shall submit to the governor the names of at least three (3) persons for each vacancy occurring among the seven (7) members appointed by the governor. The governor shall make his appointments to The Trust from the candidates recommended by the Board of County Commissioners. The governor shall make his appointments within forty-five (45) days of receipt of the Board of County Commissioners recommendations or request a new list of candidates. The governor's appointments shall serve four-year terms, except that the length of the terms of the initial appointees shall be adjusted to stagger the terms.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Removal/Resignation. The governor may remove a member for cause or upon the written petition of The Children's Trust. If any member appointed by the governor resigns, dies or is removed from office, the vacancy shall as soon as practicable be filled by the governor using the same method as the original appointment. The newly appointed member shall serve the remaining term of the person who resigns, dies or is removed from office.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-247, ยง 2, 12-3-02)</history></law>