<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00120' order_by='00120' level='3'>ARTICLE CII. JAY MALINA INTERNATIONAL TRADE CONSORTIUM OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1501</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000922</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1501. Purpose and duties.<section>The Office of Economic Development and International Trade (hereinafter referred to as "The Office") shall promote Miami-Dade County as a Global Gateway and enhance access to economic development opportunities. It shall be authorized to exercise such powers and to perform such duties as are hereinafter provided:<section prefix='(a)'>Advocate and support the development of Miami-Dade County as a premiere hemispheric platform for two-way trade.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Promote Miami-Dade County as a Global Gateway both locally and abroad by developing and expanding trade opportunities with Africa, Asia, Europe, and the Western Hemisphere.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Liaise with trade offices and chambers of commerce.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Establish and maintain a database of local businesses involved in international trade to foster import and export opportunities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Recommend trade policy.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Cultivate relations with Miami-Dade County's Sister Cities.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Coordinate and integrate Miami-Dade County's various economic development initiatives in pursuit of the County's strategic economic development goals.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Conduct economic and demographic research and other evaluative studies; and issue periodic analysis, reports, information, and/or recommendations that support the development of economic policies.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Improve access to economic development opportunities through the Targeted Job Incentive Fund (TJIF) and Qualified Target Industry (QTI) Programs.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Staff and support the International Trade Consortium and the Dr. Antonio Jorge Social and Economic Development Council for Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Administer the ITC Trust Fund Account, which shall hereafter be named the OEDIT Trust Fund Account, the Trade Mission Center of the Americas, Inc. funds, and the Miami-Dade County Sister Cities Program including its trust funds, pursuant to previously authorized resolutions. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary including any directive in Resolution R-1169-06, the OEDIT Trust Fund Account shall be administered by the Office.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Represent and advocate Miami-Dade County's economic development and international trade interests at the local, state and federal level.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Accept, receive, and expend public and private monies, gifts, fees, revenues and donations in addition to County funds.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Coordinate and act as a proactive liaison between the County and the Consular Corps of Miami.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Submit an annual report to the Mayor and Board of County Commissioners detailing the Office's activities, goals, outcomes, and statement of all its accounts.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Perform any other such functions reasonably related to the execution of the Office's functions and responsibilities.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-60, ยง 10, 9-24-10; Ord. No. 12-31, ยง 1, 5-1-12)</history></law>