<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='3'>ARTICLE XIX. Miami-Dade TRANSIT AGENCY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-150</section_number>
<catch_line>Fixing and changing fares, service, rates or charges.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000362</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-150. Fixing and changing fares, service, rates or charges.<section prefix='(a)'>Except as provided in Section 2-150(c), the County Commission shall have the authority to make service changes and fix all fares, rates or charges for the use of the transit system, provided however, that those fares, rates or charges in force on the effective date of this article shall continue in full force and effect until changed or modified by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Approved by County Commission after public hearing. The County Manager may recommend the following changes or modifications to service, fares, rates or charges, which changes may be adopted by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners after a public hearing:<section prefix='1.'>Any fare, rate or charge for transit service or for service ancillary to transit;</section><section prefix='2.'>Any change in service of twenty-five (25) percent or more of the number of route miles of a route;</section><section prefix='3.'>If, in a fiscal year, the cumulative changes on a route add up to twenty-five (25) percent or more change in the number of route miles of a route;</section><section prefix='4.'>A change in the interval between peak period transit services on a route of more than ten (10) minutes;</section><section prefix='5.'>A change in the interval between off-peak period transit services on a route of more than thirty (30) minutes; or</section><section prefix='6.'>A new transit service is established or an existing service is abolished.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Approved by County Manager. The following transit fare or service changes may be approved administratively by the County Manager, or his or her designee, and shall not require a public hearing:<section prefix='1.'>Institution of reduced or free promotional fares for up to one hundred and eighty (180) days;</section><section prefix='2.'>Service changes which are seasonal in nature;</section><section prefix='3.'>During an emergency for a period up to one hundred eighty (180) days;</section><section prefix='4.'>When the designation of a route (i.e., route name, number or letter) is changed;</section><section prefix='5.'>Institution of experimental service changes or demonstration routes/service changes for the duration of the experiment or demonstration;</section><section prefix='6.'>Any scheduling or service change which does not require a public hearing as described in Section 2-150(b).</section></section><section>The Agency shall provide public notice of such passenger fare and service changes in such a manner as to inform the public thereof.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The County Manager or his designee is delegated the authority to change service or modify or waive fares, rates or charges for special events not to exceed sixty (60) days. These short-term program changes, modifications or waivers will be exempt from public hearing requirements.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-92, ยง 1, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 84-91, ยง 1, 12-4-84; Ord. No. 98-162, ยง 1, 11-5-98)</history></law>