<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00121' order_by='00121' level='3'>ARTICLE CIII. THE CHILDREN'S TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1524</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000930</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1524. Powers.<section>The governing board of The Trust shall have all of the following powers and functions:<section prefix='(a)'>To provide and maintain, in Miami-Dade County, such health, development, safety, prevention, early intervention, enrichment, family empowerment, parenting and advocacy services for children as The Trust determines are needed for the general welfare of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(b)'>To provide such other services for children as the Trust determines are needed for the general welfare of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(c)'>To allocate and provide funds for other agencies in Miami-Dade County that are operated for the benefit of children, provided they are not under the exclusive jurisdiction of the public school system;</section><section prefix='(d)'>To seek grants from state, federal and local agencies and to accept grants and donations from public and private sources;</section><section prefix='(e)'>To collect information and statistical data and to conduct research that will help the Trust and Miami-Dade County meet the needs of children in the county;</section><section prefix='(f)'>To consult and coordinate with other agencies dedicated to the welfare of children so as to avoid whenever possible overlap and duplication of services;</section><section prefix='(g)'>To lease or buy such real estate, equipment, and personal property and to construct such buildings as are needed to execute the foregoing powers and functions, provided that no such purchases shall be made or building done unless paid for with cash on hand or secured by funds deposited in financial institutions. Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to authorize The Trust to issue bonds of any nature, nor shall The Trust have the power to require the imposition of any bond by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(h)'>To employ, pay and provide benefits for part-time or full-time personnel needed to execute the foregoing powers and functions; and</section><section prefix='(i)'>Any other powers and functions which may from time to time be added to Section 125.901 of the Florida Statutes.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-247, ยง 4, 12-3-02)</history></law>