<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00125' order_by='00125' level='3'>ARTICLE CVII. MIAMI-DADE SPORTS COMMISSION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1604</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and Duties of the Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000977</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1604. Powers and Duties of the Commission.<section>The Commission, acting through its governing body, shall have the following powers, duties, function and responsibilities.<section prefix='(a)'>To attract quality sporting events to Miami-Dade County in cooperation with the County's Parks Department that will result in economic benefit to Miami-Dade County through tourism activity and improve the quality of life of its citizens and showcase the Miami-Dade County area and its many athletic facilities to a local, national and international audience.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To form an independent 501(c)(3) corporation which will raise private funds to assist needy local adult and youth amateur athletic organizations and to assist the Commission.</section><section prefix='(c)'>To solicit membership from local corporations and business entities and to establish an advisory board consisting of those individuals or corporate representatives who become members of the Commission.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To establish membership fees and incentives programs.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to contract and be contracted with, and to have an official seal. This provision shall not be construed to in any way affect the laws relating to governmental immunity. The contractual powers of the Commission shall be subject to the following limitation:<section>It is specifically provided that contracts and any related amendments executed by the Commission, or other obligations incurred by the Commission, shall not be binding upon Miami-Dade County. In the event that the Commission shall be revoked, obligations of the Commission shall only be enforceable against Miami-Dade County to the extent that such obligations would have been enforceable with regard to personal property which was in the possession of the Commission and with regard to business income which would have come in the possession of the Commission had the Commission not been revoked.</section><section>The Commission shall comply with the formal bid requirements of Section 4.03D of the charter of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, and for such purpose the term "Board" as used in Section 4.03D shall be construed to be "The Metropolitan Dade County Sports Commission" and the term "Manager" shall be construed to be "Chief Executive Officer of the Authority."</section><section>For all contracts involving the purchase of goods or services (including construction), the Commission shall comply with the provisions of of the County Code and the administrative procedures pursuant to that subsection (f) to purchase or otherwise obtain title in its own name to personal property and shall be authorized to sell or otherwise lawfully dispose of personal property. Subject to prior approval by the Board of County Commissioners, the Commission shall have the authority to purchase real property and to sell, convey, mortgage or otherwise impair or encumber the title to real property. The Commission shall be authorized to lease real property either as lessee or lessor for any number of years and upon any terms and conditions. The leasing of any real property shall be in accordance with the requirements of Section 125.35, Florida Statutes.</section><section>Subject to prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, the Commission shall not destroy, replace, or abandon real property. The Commission shall be authorized to maintain and repair its facilities and may alter, modify, or make additions to its facilities whenever such changes are necessary for the proper operation and maintenance of such facilities.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>To appoint, remove, and suspend employees or agents of the Commission including an Executive Director, to fix their compensation, and to adopt personnel and management policies. Initially, the Commission may use County employees to serve as its staff. The Commission shall assure employees a process of appeal with regard to disciplinary or other official action.</section><section prefix='(h)'>To submit annually to the Board of County Commissioners, a report summarizing and evaluating all programs and activities undertaken by the Commission during that previous fiscal year.</section><section prefix='(i)'>To accept gifts of money, services, or real or personal property. All gifts shall be held pursuant to the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(j)'>To cooperate and contract with any governmental agency or instrumentality, federal, state, county, or municipal.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The Commission shall comply with all laws and regulations of the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County, including but not limited to the laws relating to the expenditure of funds and the keeping of records.</section><section prefix='(l)'>To establish a not-for-profit corporation under the laws of Florida to assume the duties and responsibilities of the Commission.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-71, ยง 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 06-109, ยง 3, 7-6-06)</history></law>