<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00128' order_by='00128' level='3'>ARTICLE CX. BEACON LAKES COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1673</section_number>
<catch_line>District regulations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001022</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1673. District regulations.<section>This article shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board. It is provided, however, that this article shall not become effective, in whole or in part, unless on or before 5:00 p.m. on the 10th day after the date of enactment, a proposed Interlocal Agreement has been submitted and received by the County Manager, in a form acceptable to the County Attorney, and executed by each member of the Board of Supervisor designates named in Section 4 of the ordinance from which this article derives, having provisions in substantially the following form:<section prefix='(a)'>Except upon the prior written consent of Miami-Dade County, which shall not be unreasonably withheld, the District shall not apply for or use grants or loans of money or other property from the United States, the State of Florida, any other unit of local government in Florida, or any other person or entity (except in connection with any financings of the District, and any loans made to the District by the developers, their affiliates and/or lenders in connection with the land development orders for property that is the subject of the Petition approved hereby, as they may be amended from time to time) for any District purpose. Any and all such requests by the District for authorization to apply for or use such grants or loans shall be made to Miami-Dade County, which shall have the sole discretion to decide whether to allow application for any such loans or grants. Should the County apply for any such loans or grants on behalf of the District, the District shall pay all costs to the County in connection with any such applications;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Department shall provide all water and wastewater service to the District and all lands within the District boundaries.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall, to the best of its ability, fully utilize economic development enhancement resource agencies and programs designed to involve small and minority businesses in the development and expansion of permanent job opportunities within the District. The proposed Interlocal Agreement containing this provisions shall contain examples of such agencies and programs. The Beacon Lakes Community Development District will attempt to access the range of job skills available in the region and promote greater labor force enhancement. At a minimum, the Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall encourage all landowners in the District to provide potential commercial tenants with information about employment and training agencies that maintain a database of trained/skilled workers to consider in meeting the District's employment needs.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall adopt and utilize specific measures designed to involve small and minority businesses in the development and expansion of permanent job opportunities. Such measures shall be in substantially the forms employed by Miami-Dade County, specifically, the Miami-Dade County Community Small Business Enterprise Program; the Black, Women and Hispanic Enterprise Programs; fair subcontracting measures; nondiscrimination in bidding and contracting measures; and prompt payment measures.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall provide for the election of a member to its Board of Supervisors who is deemed by the Board of County Commissioners to represent the voice of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In addition to notice required under Section 190.048, Florida Statutes, the Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall provide a separate notice to each prospective purchaser of residential property in the District, prior to execution of any contract for sale, describing the type and amount of all projected taxes and assessments on the property in the District, including a good-faith estimate of the taxes and assessments on the individual parcel being considered for prospective purchase.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Beacon Lakes Community Development District shall adopt and utilize measures providing for employment of welfare recipients by entities contracting with the District. Such measures shall be in substantially the form of Miami-Dade County Resolution R-1206-97, as the same shall be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The Beacon Lakes Community Development District agrees to apply for the creation of a multipurpose special taxing district to maintain the development's infrastructure such as roadways, storm drainage, water, sewer and landscape should the CDD be dissolved or fail to fulfill its maintenance obligations. Any and all plats of property within the CDD shall contain a conveyance clause to Miami-Dade County to be exercised at its discretion should the CDD be dissolved or fail to perform.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-105, ยง 15, 5-6-03)</history></law>