<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00125' order_by='00125' level='3'>ARTICLE CVII. MIAMI-DADE SPORTS COMMISSION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1603</section_number>
<catch_line>Governing Body.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000976</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1603. Governing Body.<section prefix='(a)'>Composition and appointment. The governing body of the Commission shall be a board of directors that consists of twelve (12) voting members from the following organizations and any additional members selected by the Executive Committee pursuant to (c) below:<section prefix='(1)'>The County Manager, Deputy County Manager, or Assistant County Manager;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Director of the Miami-Dade Parks Department;</section><section prefix='(3)'>A representative from the Miami-Dade League of Cities;</section><section prefix='(4)'>A representative who is involved in collegiate athletics from one of the local colleges or universities to be selected by the board of directors;</section><section prefix='(5)'>A representative from the Miami-Dade School Board;</section><section prefix='(6)'>A representative from the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau;</section><section prefix='(7)'>A representative from the Greater Miami and the Beaches Hotel Association;</section><section prefix='(8)'>A representative from The Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix='(9)'>A representative from The Orange Bowl Committee.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A member of the Board of County Commissioners to be appointed by the Chairman or Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners;</section><section prefix='(11)'>A member of the Board of County Commissioners to be appointed by the Chairman or Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners;</section><section prefix='(12)'>The Miami-Dade County Mayor or his designee.</section></section><section>Each organization shall appoint its representative to the board of directors. When making a selection, each organization shall consider that the voting members should reflect the gender, racial, ethnic or cultural make-up of the community.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Qualifications. Each member of the Commission shall be a United States citizen, a duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, and shall comply with the requirements of Chapter 2-11-38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Before taking any official action, each voting member shall take the prescribed oath of office. Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Executive Committee. The Executive Committee shall consist of the twelve (12) members of the Board of Directors appointed by the organizations listed in (a) above. The Executive Committee may, by majority vote, select and appoint up to thirty-four (34) additional voting members to the Board of Directors. The Executive Committee may expand its membership up to four (4) additional members selected from the Board of Directors. The Executive Committee, upon a majority vote, may veto any action taken by the Board of Directors. The twelve (12) members of the Board of Directors shall, by a majority vote, renew the up to thirty-four (34) Board members on an annual basis. The Chairperson shall be a member of the Board of County Commissioners appointed by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The members of the Commission who are the County Mayor or his designee or are members of the Board of County Commissioners shall serve terms of three (3) years each. No member who is a member of the Board of County Commissioners shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms of three (3) years each. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Board of County Commissioners may waive the term limits contained herein, in the manner prescribed in(b) of the Code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Vacancies. Each organization shall appoint a new representation within one month when its appointee resigns or is removed from the Commission.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Modified applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. The Metropolitan Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (the "Conflict of Interest Ordinance"), Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to the members of the Commission only in the manner and to the extent provided in the next sentence. It is declared to be the intent of the Commission, as expressed in this subsection, to provide that the Conflict of Interest Ordinance shall not operate to preclude individuals from serving as Commission members on the basis of interests relating to Miami-Dade County when such interests do not conflict with the Commission.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Organization and Procedure. The board of directors shall elect one (1) of its members as chairperson and one of its members as vice-chairperson whom shall both serve a term of two (2) years and such other officers as the board of directors may determine to be necessary.</section><section>The Commission shall create by-laws and shall hold regular meetings in accordance with those by-laws. The Commission may hold such other meetings, as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the board of directors shall constitute a quorum. All meetings of the Commission shall be public and the Commission shall maintain written minutes of all proceedings that shall be promptly prepared and recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Commission shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Commission.</section><section>The members of the Commission shall have the powers, duties, and responsibilities customarily vested in the board of directors of a private corporation, including the power to appoint a Chief Executive Officer and to remove such appointee and to make, adopt and amend rules and regulations that supplement its by-laws.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-71, § 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 04-28, § 1, 2-3-04; Ord. No. 06-109, § 2, 7-6-06; Ord. No. 09-07, § 1, 1-22-09; Ord. No. 12-50, § 1, 7-3-12)</history></law>