<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00125' order_by='00125' level='3'>ARTICLE CVII. MIAMI-DADE SPORTS COMMISSION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1605</section_number>
<catch_line>Financial support for the Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000978</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1605. Financial support for the Commission.<section>The Commission shall establish a fiscal year that coincides with that of Miami-Dade County, and the County Manager shall provide financial support to the Commission by including the amount of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000.00) in the official Miami-Dade County budget each year unless directed otherwise by the Board of County Commissioners. The amount provided to the Commission may be increased or decreased by the Board from time to time. The board of directors shall submit a requisition to the Finance Director in a form acceptable by the Finance Director for the dispersal of funds as needed. The Commission shall timely submit to the Board of County Commissioners a budget request pertaining to operating and capital expenditures for the succeeding fiscal year, which request shall not be implemented until approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The Commission budget request shall be prepared on official Miami-Dade County budget forms in a format prescribed by the County Manager, shall be reviewed in a manner similar to that in which requests of other county departments are reviewed, and shall be incorporated in the proposed budget and timely submitted to the Commission each year. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to prohibit the Commission from submitting to the Board of County Commissioners supplemental budget requests which, if approved by the Board of County Commissioners, shall constitute amendments to the official Miami-Dade County budget.<section prefix='(a)'>Borrowing of money. Subject to prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, the Commission shall have the authority to borrow money for any of its corporate purposes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>General financial provisions. The Commission shall have the authority to establish necessary banking accounts in its own name and to make cash disbursements. The Commission shall submit an annual financial report to the Board of County Commissioners no later than ninety (90) days from the close of such fiscal year. Miami-Dade County may require that an external auditor audit the Commission's annual financial statements.</section></section><section>The Commission Auditor of Miami-Dade County shall at all times have the right to audit all records of the Commission, and the external auditor of the Miami-Dade County, at the direction of the Board of County Commissioners, shall be empowered to audit all records of the Commission.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-71, ยง 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 06-109, ยง 4, 7-6-06)</history></law>