<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00137' order_by='00137' level='3'>ARTICLE CXVIII.5. GOVERNING FOR RESULTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1796</section_number>
<catch_line>Managerial Accountability and Performance, authority to make certain intradepartmental budget amendments, proscription on allowing departmental expenditures for any line item to exceed appropriations therefor, notification of possible deficiency and quarterly reporting required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001076</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1796. Managerial Accountability and Performance, authority to make certain intradepartmental budget amendments, proscription on allowing departmental expenditures for any line item to exceed appropriations therefor, notification of possible deficiency and quarterly reporting required.<section prefix='(a)'>Managers shall be held accountable for the achievement of performance objectives, as outlined in the strategic plan and departmental business plans, through performance evaluation and other appropriate managerial tools.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Management and staff shall employ progressive techniques to ensure continuous efficiency and effectiveness in County operations.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Managers and staff shall not allow the expenditures for any line item (as specified in Section 2-1795(b)) for their department or agency to exceed the total amount appropriated for such line item by the approved budgets providing revenues to that department or agency, as same may be administratively amended in accordance with subsection (d) below.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Mayor or his or her designee shall have the authority to make intradepartmental budget amendments that reallocate appropriations amongst a department's line item appropriations in each fund provided such reallocations do not cumulatively exceed ten percent of that fund's total appropriations to the department and, further provided that that fund's total appropriations to the department may not be changed. Reallocations amongst a fund's line item appropriations for expenditures in excess of ten percent of that fund's total appropriations to a department, or which reallocate line item appropriations from personnel services to any other line item, or which cause an increase in a fund's total appropriations to a department must be approved by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any department director, executive director or individual with the responsibility of budget development and monitoring who anticipates or has reason to believe that the annual budget of a department or agency may exceed the sum appropriated in the approved budget shall immediately provide written notification to the Budget Director. If verified, this information would then be forwarded to the Mayor, the County Commission, and Clerk of the Board.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Mayor or his or her designee shall present quarterly, except during the month of the Commission's summer recess, a written report on the status of the County's budget to the Commission Committee having oversight of the budget. At a minimum, this report should generally include, but not be limited to, the following information in a form acceptable to the Committee; fund summary, revenues by category and expenditure by major object, and revenues by category and expenditure by department, and the number and budgeted value of vacant positions.</section><section prefix='(g)'>In the case of those administrative departments of the County under the management of the Mayor, the Mayor and those assisting the Mayor in the management of such departments (including any responsible Deputy Mayor and the department directors) shall comply with the requirements of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-136, ยง 1, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 07-45, ยง 1, 3-6-07; Ord. No. 11-10, ยง 2, 3-1-11; Ord. No. 12-46, ยง 5, 7-3-12)</history></law>