<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00133' order_by='00133' level='3'>ARTICLE CXV. GUIDELINES FOR ACHIEVING MAXIMUM FEDERAL MATCHING FUNDING FOR HEALTH, SOCIAL AND HUMAN SERVICES PROGRAMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1754</section_number>
<catch_line>Responsibility of County Manager; Administrative Orders.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001044</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1754. Responsibility of County Manager; Administrative Orders.<section>The County Manager shall develop policies for the Federal Funds Maximization Program through an administrative order which shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(i)'>identification of federal matching fund opportunities and State programs available for maximizing federal matching funds;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>creation and maintenance of an inventory of all available local funds (including private funds to the extent provided by federal law) that may qualify as certified local funds pursuant to the Act and periodic review of this inventory;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>development and submittal of proposals that comply with the rules, regulations and other requirements promulgated by the State;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>seeking and monitoring State approval of the proposals, provided that the Commission shall approve all County proposals prior to their being submitted to the State;</section><section prefix='(v)'>implementation and monitoring of State-approved County programs which have been awarded revenue maximization funds;</section><section prefix='(vi)'>maintenance of the documentation, records, information and databases necessary to maximize federal matching funds in subsequent years; and</section><section prefix='(vii)'>submittal of quarterly reports to the Commission regarding the Federal Funds Maximization Program which shall include, but not be limited to, information on funds received and disbursed, problems encountered and recommendations.</section></section><section>Based upon the availability of State programs related to health services, the County Manager's first priority shall be to maximize federal matching funds for health services.</section><section>All entities, such as community-based organizations, other municipalities, special districts and instrumentalities of the County, that receive County funds for health, social or human services shall provide such documentation, records, information and data required by the County Manager to assist the County Manager in fulfilling his or her responsibilities hereunder.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-26, ยง 4, 2-3-04)</history></law>