<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00136' order_by='00136' level='3'>ARTICLE CXVIII. OFFICE OF INTERGOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1791</section_number>
<catch_line>Relationship to Mayor, Board, County Manager and County Attorney.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001071</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1791. Relationship to Mayor, Board, County Manager and County Attorney.<section prefix='1.'>The Mayor shall be the official spokesperson on behalf of the County for federal and state legislative issues that have been adopted by resolution and/or included in the legislative packages approved by the Board. The Mayor shall submit all legislative requests to the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs for inclusion in the federal and state legislative packages pursuant to the timetable set forth in Section 2-1789 and shall respond to requests for information and direction from the Office on a timely basis.</section><section prefix='2.'>The Board shall provide policy direction to the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs on legislative issues. Members of the Board shall submit all legislative requests for inclusion in the federal and state legislative packages pursuant to the timetable set forth in Section 2-1789 and shall respond to requests for information and direction from the Office on a timely basis. No member of the Board shall be precluded from speaking and lobbying on behalf of the County in support of the federal or state legislative issues that have been adopted by Board resolution and/or included in the federal and state legislative packages approved by the Board. The Chair or a member of the Board designated by the Chair shall serve as liaison to the County Manager on behalf of the Board in monitoring the Office.</section><section prefix='3.'>Notwithstanding that the Office shall report directly to the Board, the County Manager shall monitor and work closely with the Director of Intergovernmental Affairs to ensure that the policy direction of the Board is carried out. The County Manager's Office and all County departments shall respond to annual federal and state legislative requests to the Office pursuant to the timetable set forth in Section 2-1789. The County Manager and all County departments shall promptly respond to requests from the Office for information and review for fiscal and operational impact on departments.</section><section prefix='4.'>The County Attorney's Office shall provide legal support to the Office.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-219, ยง 11, 12-16-04)</history></law>