<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00132' order_by='00132' level='3'>ARTICLE CXIV. COMMUNITY REDEVELOPMENT REQUEST POLICY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1741</section_number>
<catch_line>Findings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001038</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1741. Findings.<section>This Board hereby finds that it is necessary to establish a policy by which the Board will consider requests from municipalities or community redevelopment agencies created by municipalities, for certain actions by the Board pursuant to the provisions of the Act or Interlocal Cooperation Agreement, including but not limited to: 1) creation of new tax increment districts within their municipal boundaries; 2) approval of amendments to an Interlocal Cooperation Agreement: 3) approval of an annual budget for expenditure of monies on deposit in the Trust Fund; 4) amendments to the redevelopment plan; and/or 5) any other matter that requires the approval of the Board. This Board hereby finds that it is in the best interest of the citizens of Miami-Dade County to require as a condition precedent to the Board's consideration of such municipal or agency requests that such municipality, in its sole discretion pursuant to ยง 163.387(2)(d)(1), F.S, exempt The Children's Trust, an independent special taxing district, from the provisions of Section 163.387(2)(a) for the term of collection of The Children's Trust ad valorem tax, including any extension of this ad valorem tax levy which is approved by the voters of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>However, if a municipality demonstrates to the reasonable satisfaction of the County that it is legally or contractually prohibited from exempting the Children's Trust in the manner required by this ordinance, then such municipality shall utilize any alternative method that results in the same or substantially the same benefit to the Children's Trust as if such municipality had exempted The Children's Trust. Any municipality that must use an alternative method shall be in compliance with this ordinance if such alternative method: (i) provides that the benefit accrues to The Children's Trust for the term of the collection of The Children's Trust ad valorem tax, including any extension of this ad valorem tax approved by the voters of Miami-Dade County; and (ii) is approved by the Board by resolution prior to the municipality's implementation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-210, ยง 2, 10-7-03)</history></law>