<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00137' order_by='00137' level='3'>ARTICLE CXVIII.5. GOVERNING FOR RESULTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1795</section_number>
<catch_line>Allocation of County Resources.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001075</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1795. Allocation of County Resources.<section prefix='(a)'>Each County department has the responsibility to prepare a proposed budget for review by the Mayor or his or her designee. The proposed budget shall identify the resources required to execute departmental activities, as outlined in the annual business plan, which conform to goals and priority outcomes in the County strategic plan.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Departmental budgets shall include, but not be limited to, the following components that shall be set forth in a line item format for each specific component and each particular department, office, division or other unit of County government:<section prefix='1.'>Proposed staffing levels;</section><section prefix='2.'>Proposed revenues and appropriations;</section><section prefix='3.'>Proposed adjustments to existing service levels; and</section><section prefix='4.'>Proposed new or increased fees.</section></section><section>Proposed departmental, office, division or other unit appropriations shall be set forth in a line item format for each specific component and shall be specified by the following line items:<section prefix='1.'>Personnel services;</section><section prefix='2.'>Court costs;</section><section prefix='3.'>Contractual services;</section><section prefix='4.'>Other operating Costs;</section><section prefix='5.'>Charges for county services;</section><section prefix='6.'>Distribution of funds in trust;</section><section prefix='7.'>Transfers out;</section><section prefix='8.'>Debt payments;</section><section prefix='9.'>Depreciation, amortizations and depletion;</section><section prefix='10.'>Capital; and</section><section prefix='11.'>Grants to outside organizations.</section></section><section>The line item format shall be used for all departments, offices, divisions or other units of government. Other formats, such as narrative, pie charts and graphs may also be used in addition to the line item format to supplement the line item format. In addition to the line items denoted above, a separate schedule containing the following specific expenditures for each department, office, division or other unit of County government shall be included: advertising, rent, security services, utilities, fuel, travel and registrations, temporary services and employee overtime.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The proposed budget shall clearly show the relationship between resources, departmental activities and the expected level of performance.</section><section prefix='(d)'>On an annual basis, the Mayor shall present the proposed budget, in a line item format, to the Board of County Commissioners for approval in accordance with the requirements of Section 5.03 of the Home Rule Charter and Section 2-1800. Other formats, such as narrative, pie charts and graphs may also be used in addition to the line item format to supplement the line item format and a separate schedule containing the following specific expenditures for each department, office, division or other unit of County government shall be included: advertising, rent, security services, utilities, fuel, travel and registrations, temporary services and employee overtime. The Commission Auditor shall work with the Office of Management and Budget (or its successor department) in the development of the proposed budget. Copies of the proposed budget referenced in Section 5.03(B) of the Home Rule Charter shall be made available to the Commission Auditor on the same date as such budget is presented by the Mayor or his or her designee to the Board of County Commissioners. The Commission Auditor shall then commence an in-depth review and analysis of such budget giving full consideration to the County Commission's adopted policy directives, including specifically, an in-depth review and analysis of the proposed budget of the Board of County Commissioners and all departments and divisions that report directly to the Board, including the County Attorney's Office, Office of the Inspector General, the Commission on Ethics and Public Trust and the Office of Commission Auditor and Legislative Analysis Division under the Board of County Commissioners' fund.</section><section>In addition to the foregoing, the Commission Auditor, in consultation with the Chair of the committee having jurisdiction over budgetary matters and the Mayor's designee from the Office of Management and Budget (or its successor department), shall prepare a separate budget for the Board of County Commissioners and all departments and divisions that report directly to the Board, including the County Attorney's Office, the Office of the Inspector General, the Commission on Ethics and Public Trust and the Office of Commission Auditor and Legislative Analysis Division under the Board of County Commissioners' fund.</section><section>Prior to the first meeting of the Committee of the Whole, the Commission Auditor shall present same to the Committee of the Whole. Between August 15th and the first budget hearing, a Committee of the Whole shall meet to review and discuss the Mayor's proposed budget and the Commission Auditor's proposed budgets for the Board of County Commissioners and all departments and divisions that report directly to the Board, including the County Attorney's Office, the Office of the Inspector General, the Commission on Ethics and Public Trust and the Office of Commission Auditor and Legislative Analysis Division under the Board of County Commissioners' fund, and the findings, results and recommendations of the Commission Auditor. Prior to the first meeting of the Committee of the Whole, the Commission Auditor shall provide to the Commission a report by department to reflect each line item set forth in. Such report shall be as of June 30th of the current fiscal year and shall include the prior fiscal year's budgeted and actual expenditures, the current year's budgeted expenditures and unaudited actual amounts as of June 30th, and the amounts included in the proposed budget. The report shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board and shall be posted on the County's website so it may be available to the general public. In addition, the County Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall post on the County's website the proposed budget in a line item format by program.</section><section>Each commission committee shall meet between the first meeting of the Committee of the Whole and the first budget hearing to review and discuss the Mayor's proposed line item budget for each administrative department within the committee's jurisdiction, and to forward any recommendations to the Board regarding such proposed budget. The Mayor or the Mayor's designee will present each departmental budget at the appropriate committee meeting and shall include as part of such presentation, at a minimum, the information required by. Each committee chair shall present any approved committee recommendations regarding the Mayor's proposed budget at the second Committee of the Whole.</section><section>Prior to the first budget hearing and after consultation with the Commission Chair and the Chair of the committee having jurisdiction over budgetary matters, the Commission Auditor, in cooperation with the Mayor or his/her designee, shall prepare and issue any recommended written changes to the Mayor's proposed budget and shall present same together with proposed budget amendments to the County Commission at the first budget hearing. A Committee of the Whole shall meet between the first and second budget hearings to discuss any proposed changes and recommendations which may result from the first budget hearing. At the second budget hearing, after consultation with the Chair of the Commission and the Chair of the committee having jurisdiction over budgetary matters and in cooperation with the Mayor or his/her designee, the Commission Auditor shall issue any final recommended written changes to the tentative budget and then present implementing amendments thereto to the County Commission.</section><section>In addition, the Commission Auditor shall review and analyze any midyear and year-end budget amendments proposed by the Mayor or his/her designee giving full consideration to the County Commission's policy directives. The Commission Auditor shall issue any final recommended written changes to the Mayor's proposed midyear and year-end budget amendments and present same to the County Commission prior to its consideration of such proposed budget amendments.</section><section>This subsection is not intended to be construed in any way as a limitation on the Mayor's right to participate in the budget process as set forth in the Home Rule Charter, including specifically the right to attend and be heard at the budget hearings to express a difference of opinion with the Commission Auditor's recommendations and proposed changes, or the Commission Auditor's proposed budgets for the Board of County Commissioners and all departments and divisions that report directly to the Board, including the County Attorney's Office, Office of the Inspector General, the Commission on Ethics and Public Trust and the Office of Commission Auditor and Legislative Analysis Division under the Board of County Commissioners' fund. The responsibilities assigned by this section to the Commission Auditor shall be deemed a permanent element of the Commission Auditor's annual work program for each ensuing fiscal year without need for further Commission approval.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Board shall adopt on an annual basis a five-year financial plan by September 30 of each year, reflecting as the base year, the current year's budget.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The County shall adopt budgets and develop its long and short-term financial and capital improvement plans containing estimates developed utilizing a professional revenue estimating process. Participants in the process shall include, but not be limited to: the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (or its successor department), or his/her designee; the Director of the Finance Department or his/her designee; and the Commission Auditor or his/her designee. If there is not unanimity amongst the participants as to what an estimate should be, each participant's estimate shall be presented to the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Commencing Fiscal Year 2012—13, prior to the Board's consideration of the resolution adopting its proposed millage rates for use in the preparation of the notice of proposed property taxes, a public hearing shall be held before a Committee of the Whole to discuss the proposed millage rates for the ensuing fiscal year, including, but not limited to, the impact of such proposed millage rates on funding for community-based organizations and the community.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-136, § 1, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 07-45, § 1, 3-6-07; Ord. No. 08-08, § 1, 1-10-08; Ord. No. 09-104, § 1, 11-17-09; Ord. No. 10-36, § 1, 6-3-10; Ord. No. 11-10, § 1, 3-1-11; Ord. No. 11-42, § 1, 7-7-11; Ord. No. 12-46, § 4, 7-3-12)</history></law>