<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00136' order_by='00136' level='3'>ARTICLE CXVIII. OFFICE OF INTERGOVERNMENTAL AFFAIRS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1787</section_number>
<catch_line>Functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001067</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1787. Functions.<section>The Office of the Intergovernmental Affairs shall perform the following functions within the scope of authority set forth in below:<section prefix='1.'>Coordinate the County's intergovernmental relations at the federal, state, and local levels.</section><section prefix='2.'>Manage the County's federal and state governmental representation and consulting services contracts and report issues relating to conflicts of interest as they pertain to contract lobbyists.</section><section prefix='3.'>Prepare annual federal and state legislative packages pursuant to Section 2-1789 below.</section><section prefix='4.'>Report to the Board on a timely basis and otherwise comply with the reporting requirements set forth in Section 2-1790 below.</section><section prefix='5.'>Coordinate meetings and facilitate relationships between the Board and the Miami-Dade County state and federal legislative delegations no less than once each quarter pursuant to Resolution No. 1060-93.</section><section prefix='6.'>On a continuing basis, advise the Board, Mayor, County Manager, and County Departments of the filing, progress and amendment of bills, appropriations, and legislative reports and projects that may affect the County.</section><section prefix='7.'>Raise, discuss and recommend any legislative action that may benefit the County given the current legislative trends and dynamics, including actions related to both substantive legislation and appropriations.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-219, ยง 7, 12-16-04)</history></law>