<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00026' order_by='00026' level='3'>ARTICLE XX. RAPID TRANSIT PROJECT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-171</section_number>
<catch_line>County Manager's authority to manage Stage I.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000367</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-171. County Manager's authority to manage Stage I.<section prefix='(a)'>Authority generally. The County Manager is hereby charged with the responsibilities of managing the design, development, construction and operation of Stage I of the Rapid Transit System. In order to carry out such responsibility, the County Manager shall have the following authority and may exercise such authority without necessity of further approval by the Board:<section prefix='(1)'>To file applications on behalf of Miami-Dade County for State and federal funds to be utilized for development and construction of the project.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To advertise contracts for competitive bids, issue bid documents including addenda thereto, receive and open bids, review bids, and issue notices to proceed after award.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To provide in the bid specifications and contract documents that the contract time and liquidated damages for failure to comply therewith may be extended and waived before or after the specified date for completion of the contract.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To provide in the bid specifications and contract documents that prime contractors submitting bids list thereon the names of all subcontractors that will be utilized on the contract.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To determine the validity of and negotiate and settle contractor claims[, and] to issue change orders and modifications within the general scope of the contract work in accordance with the contract's provisions. In no event shall the aggregate of claims settled, and changes or modifications made in a particular contract, exceed ten (10) percent of the original contract price without prior approval of the Board.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Enforce contract compliance with contract obligations.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Exercise the termination and suspension provisions of all or any portions of contracts.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Receive and review requests for partial or final payment, determine whether such requests meet the requirements of the contract and, if so, authorize appropriate payment.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Accept work or grant final acceptance in accordance with the terms of the applicable contract.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Delegation of authority. The County Manager may designate persons within the Office of Transit Agency to exercise the authority specified within subsection (a). Such persons may redelegate specific limited portions of such authority to specified members of the Kaiser Transit Group, the County's general architectural and engineering consultant for Stage I of the Rapid Transit System. Any delegation or redelegation of authority made pursuant to the provisions of this subsection (b) must be submitted in writing to and be approved by the Board as a condition of its becoming effective.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-76, ยง 2, 9-18-79)</history></law>