<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00138' order_by='00138' level='3'>ARTICLE CXIX. BUILDING BETTER COMMUNITIES CITIZENS' ADVISORY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1802</section_number>
<catch_line>Advisory Committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001083</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1802. Advisory Committee.<section prefix='(1)'>Membership and Appointment. The Advisory Committee shall be comprised of twenty-one (21) members. The Mayor shall appoint three (3) members, each Commissioner shall appoint one member and the remaining five (5) at-large members shall be selected by the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Qualifications. Each member shall be a resident of Miami-Dade County; shall possess an outstanding reputation for civic pride, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability; and shall have no financial interest, direct or indirect, in any of the programs or projects that are part of the Bond Program. The membership of the Advisory Committee should generally reflect the geographic, ethnic, racial and gender make-up of the County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Term. Mayoral appointed and District members of the Advisory Committee shall serve until the respective appointing authority, Mayor or Commissioner, leaves office, or until resignation, whichever occurs first. All such members may be reappointed or may continue to serve until resignation or their successors have been appointed.</section><section>The five (5) at-large members selected by the County Manager shall hold office for a term of five (5) years, or until resignation, whichever comes first and may be re-appointed for up to two (2) additional five (5) year terms.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Vacancies. The Mayor and each Commissioner shall appoint or re-appoint a member within forty-five (45) days of taking office or in the event of their appointee's resignation. All at-large member vacancies shall be filled by the County Manager within forty-five (45) days of the resignation of the member.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Modified applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (the "Conflict of Interest Ordinance"), Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to the members of the Advisory Committee only in the manner and to the extent provided in the next sentence. It is declared to be the intent of the Commission, as expressed in this subsection, to provide that the Conflict of Interest Ordinance shall not operate to preclude individuals from serving as Advisory Committee members on the basis of interests relating to Miami-Dade County when such interests do not conflict, directly or indirectly, with the Bond Program.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Organization and Procedure. The members shall elect a chairperson and a vice-chairperson and both shall serve a term of two (2) years. The members shall also elect other officers as the members determine to be necessary and such officers shall also serve a term of two (2) years.</section><section>The Advisory Committee shall hold regular meetings no less than four (4) times a year and such other meetings, as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the board of directors shall constitute a quorum. All meetings of the Advisory Committee shall be public and the Advisory Committee shall maintain written minutes of all proceedings that shall be promptly prepared and recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Advisory Committee shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Advisory Committee.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Compensation. Members of the Advisory Board shall serve without compensation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-70, ยง 1, 4-5-05)</history></law>