<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIA. HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-189</section_number>
<catch_line>Housing and Urban Development Advisory Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000375</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-189. Housing and Urban Development Advisory Board.<section>A Housing and Urban Development Advisory Board is created (hereinafter referred to as "the HUD Board"). The Director of Housing and Urban Development shall serve as Secretary to the Board.<section prefix='(a)'>Membership. The HUD Board shall consist of twenty-two (22) members, to be designated as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>The Board of County Commissioners will make thirteen (13) appointments to the HUD Board. Ten (10) of these appointees are to represent the following disciplines: Construction, property management, banking, legal and other appropriate disciplines. Three (3) additional appointees shall be residents of low income public housing projects, owned, leased or operated by Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Overall Tenant Advisory Council (OTAC) will make nine (9) appointments. Four (4) appointees shall be residents of low income public housing projects, owned, leased or operated by Miami-Dade County, Florida, and shall include at least one (1) elderly/handicapped public housing resident, one (1) Section-8 resident, and two (2) at-large residents of public housing. Five (5) additional appointees are to represent professionals or community leaders from the following disciplines: Education, social service, community based organizations, employment/training, government, legal, civic and religious organizations. One (1) of these five (5) appointees shall represent an organization or agency involved with the elderly.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Terms. Members of the HUD Board shall serve staggered terms of four (4) years each. Of the initial members, six (6) members shall serve an initial term of four (4) years, six (6) members shall serve an initial term of three (3) years, five (5) members shall serve an initial term of two (2) years and five (5) members shall serve an initial term of one (1) year as determined by the Director of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. Vacancies shall be filled by appointment to fill the unexpired terms and shall be designated by the Board responsible for making the initial appointment where the vacancy has occurred. Terms of office of members of the HUD Board, appointed by the Board of County Commissioners or OTAC, which would normally expire on or between the dates of January 1 through June 30, or July 1 through December 31 of the termination year, shall be deemed ended and expired as of March 31 or September 30 thereof respectively; and the position thereon vacated may be refilled by the County Commission or by OTAC.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Removal. Members may be removed by a majority of the HUD Board members for one (1) or more of the following reasons: (1) Three (3) consecutive unexcused absences from (a) Advisory Board (b) general and/or (c) committee meetings; (2) potential business conflict of interest; (3) consistent demonstration of incompetent or disruptive activities when carrying out Board duties.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Function. The HUD Board shall review and evaluate all major plans, programs and projects prepared by the Director of Housing and Urban Development and make recommendations for approval, disapproval or modification to the Board of County Commissioners and the Manager. The HUD Board shall advise the Director of Housing and Urban Development and make recommendations to the Manager and the Board of County Commissioners in matters relating to the management of property and materials, tenant services, budget and finance, formulation and enforcement of policies and procedures and their consistency with existing federal mandates and County administrative practices. The HUD Board shall promote public interest in and understanding of matters relating to urban renewal, housing and other urban development and redevelopment plans and consult with citizens to ascertain their duties and need for public housing, slum clearance, urban renewal and other programs designed to improve living conditions in Miami-Dade County. The HUD Board may initiate studies designed to improve the functioning of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 67-32, § 3, 4-25-67; Ord. No. 71-33, § 1, 4-13-71; Ord. No. 71-82, § 1, 10-5-71; Ord. No. 73-20, § 1, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 88-123, § 1, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 90-66, § 1, 7-10-90; Ord. No. 94-09, § 1, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-44, § 1, 3-7-95)</history></law>