<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00137' order_by='00137' level='3'>ARTICLE CXVIII.5. GOVERNING FOR RESULTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1800A</section_number>
<catch_line>Public Meetings Regarding New or Increased Taxes or Fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001081</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1800A. Public Meetings Regarding New or Increased Taxes or Fees.<section prefix='1.'>Six public meetings shall be conducted as provided herein throughout the County whenever the proposed budget or the proposed budget ordinances for the ensuing fiscal year provide for new taxes or fees or for increases in the rates of ad valorem taxes, local option sales and gasoline taxes, water and sewer rates, franchise fees, utility service taxes, garbage/trash collection fees, mass transit fares, impact fees, or County imposed auto registration fees. Such meetings shall be conducted by county staff to solicit community input about the proposed new or increased taxes or fees.</section><section prefix='2.'>The public meetings described herein are required only when a new fee or tax, or an increase in the rate of an existing fee or tax as enumerated in Paragraph 1 is proposed that will impact a majority of the residents of unincorporated Miami-Dade County. Such meetings shall be for the purpose of discussing revenue increase proposals as described herein and the purpose for which such revenues are being proposed only. Such meetings shall not constitute public budget hearings.</section><section prefix='3.'>The public meetings required hereby shall be held at locations and times which are accessible and convenient to the majority of residents in the County affected by the tax and which allow for maximum participation by the diverse population of the County.</section><section prefix='4.'>All public meetings required hereby shall take place during the period following the issuance of the proposed budget for the ensuing year and prior to the first public hearing on the proposed budget ordinances by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='5.'>The public meetings shall be appropriately advertised including use of print advertisements in newspapers of general circulation and community based periodicals, and to the extent practicable, direct mail to all registered property owners.</section><section prefix='6.'>This ordinance shall be construed as directory only, and failure to comply with the provisions hereof shall not affect the validity of any ordinance, resolution or action of this Board in whole or in part.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-45, ยง 1, 7-7-11)</history></law>