<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00138' order_by='00138' level='3'>ARTICLE CXIX. BUILDING BETTER COMMUNITIES CITIZENS' ADVISORY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1803</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties of the Advisory Committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001084</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1803. Duties of the Advisory Committee.<section>The Advisory Committee shall have the following duties, responsibilities, and functions.<section prefix='(1)'>To review and monitor performance and program achievements related to the Bond Program.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To periodically advise the Mayor, the County Commission and County Manager, and assist in informing the community regarding the Building Better Communities General Obligation Bond Program's accomplishments on projects as approved by the electorate on November 2, 2004.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To assist in the preparation of quarterly reports to the Mayor and the County Commission, and annual written report to the community describing the progress of the Building Better Communities General Obligation Bond Program. The Advisory Committee may also periodically provide advice, by either a written resolution or oral presentation, as may be requested by the County Commission, at regularly scheduled Commission meetings in accordance with the terms of this Ordinance.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To advise on the use of any surplus bond project funds or unspent allocations derived from those projects specifically identified in Resolution Numbers R-912-04, R-913-04, R-914-04, R-915-04, R-916-04, R-917-04, R-918-04, and R-919-04, and set forth in informational pamphlets and media releases distributed by the County to the public prior to said election.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To participate, along with County staff, in citizen outreach efforts relating to the Bond Program.</section><section prefix='(6)'>To promulgate rules consistent with this Ordinance for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities.</section><section prefix='(7)'>To comply with all laws and regulations of the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the laws relating to the keeping of records including the preservation of all audit rights.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Any member shall be automatically removed if, in a given calendar year; (i) he/she is absent from three (3) consecutive meetings or, (ii) he/she is absent from more than 50% of all the committee meetings held during a year. A member shall be deemed absent when he/she is not present at the meeting for at least 75% of its duration.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-70, ยง 1, 4-5-05)</history></law>