<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='3'>ARTICLE XXII. PUBLIC LIBRARY ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-199</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000393</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-199. Duties and functions.<section>The Public Library Advisory Board shall have the following duties, functions and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the County Commission in respect to all matters pertaining to Public Library and other cultural facilities, and to make periodic reports and recommendations in respect to such matters.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To make a continuing study of all existing Public Library facilities and services in this metropolitan area, and the future needs of this community in respect to Public Library facilities and services.</section><section prefix='(c)'>To formulate plans and programs for the coordination of the activities of all governmental entities, and nongovernmental agencies, relating to Library facilities and services.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To formulate comprehensive, feasible plans and programs for providing adequate Public Library facilities and services necessary to fulfill the present and future needs of this metropolitan area.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To devise means and methods by which existing and future Library facilities and services may be improved and more fully utilized to provide better service and availability to the general public.</section><section prefix='(f)'>To make a continuing study and periodic reports and recommendations for a sound, feasible program for financing the costs of improving existing Library facilities and services and providing additional Public Library facilities and services.</section><section prefix='(g)'>To review all laws, regulations and requirements governing Public Libraries and make recommendations concerning appropriate actions that may be taken to achieve the objective of providing adequate Public Library facilities and services for this metropolitan area, and to devise programs by which financial assistance from other governmental entities may be utilized to the fullest extent.</section><section prefix='(h)'>To perform and carry out such other duties and functions of an advisory nature as may be assigned to the Board by the County Commission.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-27, ยง 8, 7-2-63)</history></law>