<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00145' order_by='00145' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXVI. CLIMATE CHANGE ADVISORY TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1942</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; appointment, staggered terms and removal.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001137</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1942. Membership; appointment, staggered terms and removal.<section prefix='(a)'>The CCATF shall have twenty-five (25) members. Each member shall be a resident and elector of Miami-Dade County unless the Board of County Commissioners, by a two-thirds vote of its membership, waives this requirement.</section><section>Members should have reputations for integrity and community service and have demonstrated an interest in a field or activity related to global warming climate change.</section><section>The CCATF shall be composed of the following members:<section prefix='1)'>Harvey Ruvin, who as a former member of the Board of County Commissioners sponsored Resolution No. R-335-91 adopting the County's "Urban CO2 Reduction Plan" (hereinafter referred to as the "adopted plan") and has chaired its implementation since, and who continues his service to the community as the Miami-Dade County Clerk of Courts;</section><section prefix='2)'>One appointment for a member seat from each member of the Board of County Commissioners. In making the initial appointments preference should be given to those persons who have demonstrated a record of service by previous participation on the ad hoc committee on climate change adaptation chaired by Harvey Ruvin;</section><section prefix='3)'>The County Manager shall recommend to the Board of County Commissioners candidates for nine (9) members' seats from governmental agencies and educational institutions on the basis of technical expertise in areas that will facilitate the work of the CCATF.</section><section prefix='4)'>Two (2) appointments by the Mayor for two regular member seats.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The initial appointment of those members appointed by individual commissioners shall be for a term of three (3) years. Those members not appointed by individual commissioners shall serve an initial term of two (2) years. The successors to the initial two-year appointments shall be appointed for three (3) years.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Members may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-11.38 of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-113, ยง 2, 7-18-06)</history></law>