<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='3'>ARTICLE XXII. PUBLIC LIBRARY ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-195</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; vacancies; qualifications; term.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000389</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-195. Membership; vacancies; qualifications; term.<section prefix='(A)'>Membership. The Miami-Dade County Public Library Advisory Board shall consist of eleven (11) members appointed by the County Commission. Eight (8) members shall be residents of the Library Taxing District and three (3) members shall be residents of the City of Miami and members of the City of Miami's Library Board.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Vacancies.<section prefix='(1)'>Library taxing district members. In filling any vacancy the County Commission shall select the replacement board member from a list of three (3) candidates to be submitted by the remaining members of the Board; provided that the City Manager of the City of Miami Beach may recommend to the Library Board candidates for two (2) membership positions. In the event that none of the three (3) candidates suggested meets with commission approval, the Board shall submit another and entirely different list for commission consideration. This process shall continue until a replacement has been appointed.</section><section prefix='(2)'>City of Miami members (if City Library Board abolished). If the City of Miami's Library Board is abolished, then vacancies from among the aforesaid three (3) members who are residents of the City of Miami shall be filled as follows:<section prefix='a.'>The Board shall submit a list of three (3) candidates to the City Commission.</section><section prefix='b.'>The City Commission shall select one (1) of the candidates to submit to the County Commission; however, in the event that none of the three (3) candidates suggested meets with City Commission approval, the Board shall submit three (3) different names to the City Commission for its consideration.</section><section prefix='c.'>The County Commission shall appoint the suggested candidate to the Board; however, in the event that the candidate suggested does not meet with County Commission approval, the City Commission shall either submit one (1) of the remaining candidates to the County Commission or request three (3) different names from the Board.</section></section></section><section>This process shall continue until a replacement has been appointed.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Qualifications. Each member shall be a qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, and shall possess a reputation for civic pride, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability, and shall have demonstrated an active interest in Public Library facilities and services. As far as practicable, the membership of the Board shall be representative of the various interests of this metropolitan area in respect to geographic and economic factors.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Terms. The term of office of the membership shall be one (1) year for three (3) members, two (2) years for three (3) members and three (3) years for three (3) members; and effective October 1, 1986, the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint the tenth member to a two (2) year term and the eleventh member to a three (3) year term with appointments thereafter to be for a term of three (3) years for each of the eleven (11) members. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Board shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. Terms of office of members of the Board appointed by the Board of County Commissioners, which would normally expire on or between the dates of January 1 through June 30, or July 1 through December 31 of the termination year, shall be deemed ended and expired as of March 31 or September 30 thereof respectively; and the position thereon vacated may be refilled by the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to October 1, 1989, the Board of County Commissioners shall review the composition of the Public Library Advisory Board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-27, § 4, 7-2-63; Ord. No. 63-29, § 1, 7-16-63; Ord. No. 64-39, § 5, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 71-78, § 1, 9-22-71; Ord. No. 73-20, § 1, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 77-81, § 1, 11-15-77; Ord. No. 86-65, § 1, 9-16-86; Ord. No. 86-84, § 1, 10-28-86)</history></law>