<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00144' order_by='00144' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXV. TASK FORCE ON GOVERNMENTAL STRUCTURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1923</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001133</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1923. Duties and functions.<section>The Task Force shall:<section prefix='a)'>Develop criteria for identifying efficient and effective structures of local government in this country [county]. Such criteria may include: bond ratings; efficiency awards or recognitions; success in obtaining state or federal funds; as well as other criteria deemed by the members to be objective measures of an efficient and effective local government;</section><section prefix='b)'>Apply the criteria developed to evaluate the effectiveness and efficiency of the various structures of governance of the major metropolitan areas of this country [county]. This evaluation shall include local governments that vest procurement authority in elected officials, as well as those that vest such authority in appointed members of staff. The evaluation shall also include an analysis of jurisdictions that vest authority over air and seaports in elected officials, as well as in appointed officials;</section><section prefix='c)'>Review Commission agendas over the past five years and analyze those instances where the County Commission has rejected the County Manager's recommendation on a procurement matter, and identify the number thereof in relation to the total number of such recommendations and the percentage that such instances comprise of the total number of and total dollar value of all procurement recommendations submitted by the County Manager to the Commission during such period of time. The data gathered as a result of the foregoing shall be compiled and disseminated to the public by the County Communications Department;</section><section prefix='d)'>Conduct such public hearings as in the Task Force's opinion are sufficient to afford the members of the community the opportunity to provide their input. The Chair of the Task Force may, at his discretion, create a Citizens' Advisory Committee to assist the Task Force. The Chair of the Task Force shall appoint the members of the Citizens' Advisory Committee.</section><section prefix='e)'>At the conclusion of the public hearing process, the Task Force shall prepare written report for the County Commission's consideration that includes a summary of the Task Force's evaluation of the efficient and effective structures of local government studied and the opinions of constituents shared with the Task Force during the public hearing process. Such report shall be completed and submitted to the County Commission as soon as practicable, and in no event later than six (6) months after the effective date of this article. Upon such submission, the Task Force shall be dissolved.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-59, ยง 3, 5-9-06)</history></law>