<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00145' order_by='00145' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXVI. CLIMATE CHANGE ADVISORY TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1943</section_number>
<catch_line>Quorum; organization and procedures at meetings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001138</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-1943. Quorum; organization and procedures at meetings.<section prefix='(a)'>A quorum shall be a majority of the duly appointed and sitting members.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Harvey Ruvin shall serve as the initial chairperson for a three (3) year term. Thereafter, the chairperson shall be elected annually by a majority vote of the duly appointed membership.</section><section prefix='(c)'>At the initial meeting, the chairperson shall appoint another member to serve a one (1) year term as vice-chairperson, subject to approval by a majority vote of those members in attendance. Thereafter, the vice-chairperson shall be selected and approved annually in the same manner. The CCATF shall adopt rules of procedure for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The chairperson shall nominate and the CCATF shall appoint, by a majority vote of those members in attendance, a chairperson and members for such committees as the CCATF finds helpful to its mission. Each committee shall be chaired by a duly appointed member of the CCATF, however, the committee membership may include persons who are not members of the CCATF. A committee shall have no authority to act or speak on behalf of the CCATF. The CCATF may establish or eliminate committees at its discretion.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The CCATF shall hold not less than four (4) regular meetings each year.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-113, ยง 3, 7-18-06)</history></law>