<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='3'>ARTICLE XXII. PUBLIC LIBRARY ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-193</section_number>
<catch_line>Declaration of legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000387</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-193. Declaration of legislative intent.<section>It is the purpose and intent of the Board of County Commissioners, in enacting this article under and pursuant to the provisions of Section 4.08 of the Home Rule Charter, to create and establish an Advisory Board of official status composed of outstanding citizens with representative interests and geographical distribution, who are dedicated to the purposes of providing a feasible, adequate Public Library system for this entire metropolitan area in cooperation with all other governmental entities, and that will be in a position to furnish information, advice and counsel to the Board of County Commissioners in respect to the appropriate means and methods by which adequate Public Library facilities and services may be provided within the framework of the County government on a sound financial basis for the use and benefit of all residents and visitors of this metropolitan area, and to work towards the development and implementation of sound programs for public libraries through the mutual cooperation between the State, County and municipal governments and agencies and coordination with non-governmental organizations interested in library facilities and services. This article shall not be construed as delegating to such advisory board or its members any power or authority of a governmental, legislative or administrative nature, but as the establishment of an official instrumentality by which the Board of County Commissioners may obtain the benefit of accurate, comprehensive information, advice and counsel concerning all matters relating to public libraries and other cultural facilities and programs which may be necessary for appropriate action by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-27, ยง 2, 7-2-63)</history></law>