<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Designation of responsibility for custody and transportation by law enforcement agencies of persons believed to be mentally ill.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000073</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2.2. Designation of responsibility for custody and transportation by law enforcement agencies of persons believed to be mentally ill.<section prefix='(a)'>Pursuant to the authority of Section 394.463(2)(b), Florida Statutes, the Miami-Dade Police Department is designated as the law enforcement agency responsible to take custody of and transport persons in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County to the nearest receiving facility for involuntary examination pursuant to the provisions of Section 394.463(2)(a)(1) or (3), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Pursuant to the authority of Section 394.463(2)(b), Florida Statutes, each municipal law enforcement agency within Miami-Dade County is designated as the law enforcement agency responsible to take custody of and transport persons from within each respective municipality of Miami-Dade County to the nearest receiving facility for involuntary examination pursuant to the provisions of Section 394.463(2)(a)(1) or (3), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In the event that a municipality within Miami-Dade County has no law enforcement agency, then pursuant to Section 394.463(2)(b), Florida Statutes, the Miami-Dade Police Department is designated as the law enforcement agency responsible to take custody of and transport persons from such municipalities in Miami-Dade County which have no municipal law enforcement agency to the nearest receiving facility for involuntary examination pursuant to the provisions of Section 394.463(2)(a)(1) or (3), Florida Statutes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 86-40, ยง 1, 5-20-86)</history></law>