<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIII. COMMUNITY RELATIONS BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-205</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; qualifications; terms.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000397</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-205. Membership; qualifications; terms.<section>This Board shall consist of thirty (30) voting members. The membership of the Board shall be broadly representative of the various social, racial, religious, linguistic, cultural, economic, national origin and geographic groups comprising the population of this County. Each member shall be a resident of Miami-Dade County with an outstanding reputation for community pride, interest, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability and a documented commitment to intergroup relations.</section><section>Each Commissioner shall appoint a member to the Community Relations Board who is duly qualified under this ordinance and the criteria provided by a special nominating committee. The special nominating committee shall consist of: the Mayor or his designee, as chair; the County Manager; one person appointed by the Board of County Commissioners; and six past chairs of the Community Relations Board appointed by the Mayor. The special nominating committee will appoint thirteen duly qualified at-large members assuring diverse representation from among gender, ethnic and national origin groups. Four additional members shall serve by virtue of their election as chairpersons by the respective community advisory boards which are: Black Affairs Advisory Board, Hispanic Affairs Advisory Board, Asian-American Advisory Board and the Commission for Women. The advisory board chairpersons shall serve as voting members of the CRB during the period each holds that elected position. The remaining twenty-six (26) members of the Community Relations Board shall be appointed for an initial one year term.</section><section>Thereafter, the Community Relations Board shall consist of thirteen duly qualified members appointed by each Commissioner thirteen at-large members appointed by an ad hoc nominating committee designated by the CRB and four members elected as chairpersons by the community advisory boards.</section><section>After one year, the twenty-six appointed members will serve staggered terms chosen by lottery as follows: nine (9) members shall be appointed for terms expiring on the second anniversary of their appointment, nine (9) members shall be appointed for terms expiring on the third anniversary of their appointment, and eight (8) members shall be appointed for terms expiring on the fourth anniversary of their appointment. Subsequent appointments shall be for terms of three (3) years except that appointments to fill any vacancy shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term. Former chairpersons of the Board, who are not current members of the Board shall serve as ex officio members of the Board but shall not be entitled to vote on any matter before the Board and shall not be required to attend meetings of the Board. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in official duties, as may be determined and approved by the County Manager. The members of the Community Relations Board at the time of the passage of this ordinance shall continue to serve until such time as the reorganized Board is convened. The reorganized Community Relations Board shall be convened by the Mayor and Board of County Commissioners within 90 days of the passage of this ordinance. The Mayor shall serve as the convening chairperson until such time as the newly constituted Board shall select an executive committee.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-22, §§ 2, 3, 6-11-63; Ord. No. 67-38, § 1, 5-16-67; Ord. No. 69-44, § 1, 7-16-69; Ord. No. 73-20, § 1, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 73-71, § 1, 7-31-73; Ord. No. 77-30, § 1, 5-17-77; Ord. No. 00-115, § 1, 9-19-00; Ord. No. 02-30, § 1, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 03-86, § 1, 4-10-03)</history></law>