<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00155' order_by='00155' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXVI. COMPENSATION AND BENEFITS REVIEW COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2071</section_number>
<catch_line>Review committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001214</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2071. Review committee.<section prefix='(a)'>Membership. The Review Committee shall be comprised of nine (9) members.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Qualifications. Each member shall be a resident of Miami-Dade County; shall possess an outstanding reputation for civic pride, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability; and shall have no financial interest, direct or indirect, in the compensation paid to County employees. The membership of the Compensation and Benefits Review Committee should be representative of the community at large and should have a demonstrated expertise in human resources, organizational design, public management, or other related topics to be considered.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Term. Members of the Review Committee shall serve for a three-year term. All such members may be reappointed or may continue to serve until resignation or their successors have been appointed.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Appointment of Members. Members of the Review Committee shall be appointed by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners after having been selected by the Commission from persons nominated by a Nominating Council established and described herein. The Nominating Council, hereinafter known as the Compensation and Benefits Review Nominating Council, shall be comprised of the following five (5) voting members: three (3) County Commissioners, the Chair of the Social and Economic Development Council, and one representative of a County Collective Bargaining Union. The Members of the Nominating Council shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Board of County Commissioners, who shall designate a Chairperson of the Nominating Council. The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide appropriate staff support to the Council. The sole function of the Nominating Council shall be to solicit, screen, interview and recommend for appointment the best qualified candidate for each vacancy on the Compensation and Benefits Review Committee. All meetings of the Nominating Council shall be audio recorded and minutes of the proceedings shall be transcribed and maintained by the Clerk of the Board of the County Commission. The Nominating Council shall submit to the Commission a list of nominees containing a total number of names which is equal to one (1) nominee for each vacancy on the CBR Committee plus one (1) alternate nominee. The Commission shall select and appoint the voting members from the list of nominees submitted by the Nominating Council.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Modified Applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (the "Conflict of Interest Ordinance"), Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to the members of the Review Committee only in the manner and to the extent provided in the next sentence. It is declared to be the intent of the Commission, as expressed in this subsection, to provide that the Conflict of Interest Ordinance shall not operate to preclude individuals from serving as Review Committee members on the basis of interests relating to Miami-Dade County when such interests do not conflict, directly or indirectly, with their responsibilities on the Review Committee.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Organization and Procedure. The members of the Review Committee shall elect a chairperson and a vice-chairperson and both shall serve a term of three (3) years. The chairperson may organize the membership of the Review Committee as deemed necessary to conduct its business. The Review Committee shall hold regular meetings no less than four (4) times a year and such other meetings, as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the board of directors shall constitute a quorum. All meetings of the Review Committee shall be public and the Review Committee shall maintain written minutes of all proceedings that shall be promptly prepared and recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Review Committee shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Review Committee.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Compensation. Members of the Review Committee shall serve without compensation.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Any member shall be automatically removed if, in a given calendar year, (i) he/she is absent from three (3) consecutive meetings or, (ii) he/she is absent from more than 50% of all the committee meetings held during a year. A member shall be deemed absent when he/she is not present at the meeting for at least 75% of its duration.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-109, ยง 1(2), 12-1-09)</history></law>