<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00151' order_by='00151' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXII. COMMUNITY ACTION AGENCY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2044</section_number>
<catch_line>The board composition; petition process; interim board composition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001187</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2044. The board composition; petition process; interim board composition.<section prefix='(a)'>The Community Action Agency Board shall consist of forty-five (45) members as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Elected officials.<section prefix='a.'>Fifteen (15) members shall be the following elected officials:<section prefix='1.'>The Mayor of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='2.'>The thirteen (13) Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='3.'>The City of Miami Mayor;</section></section><section prefix='b.'>These elected officials may appoint a designee to serve on their behalf.</section><section prefix='c.'>If an elected official selects a designee to serve on the Community Action Agency Board, the elected official shall submit a letter on an annual basis advising the Community Action Agency Board of such designation.</section><section prefix='d.'>If the elected official leaves office or his/her term of office expires and such elected official had selected a designee to serve, such designee may continue to serve until the newly elected official takes his/her seat with the Community Action Agency Board or appoints his/her own designee.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Citizen participants. Sixteen (16) members shall be individuals who reside within sixteen (16) defined different target areas served by the Community Action Agency, are sufficiently representative of the individuals/families that reside within that specific target area and are selected through a democratic process developed by Miami-Dade County and delineated in the Community Action Agency's Board bylaws. No two (2) members shall reside in the same target area. However, in the event that the number of citizen participants exceeds the number of target areas, more than one citizen participant may reside in the same target area, provided that each target area has at least one representative. A target area shall mean a neighborhood of low income individuals and families served by the Community Action Agency.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Community interests and organizations.<section prefix='a.'>The remaining fourteen (14) members shall be representatives from the following: business; industry; labor; religious; law enforcement; social welfare; and education. Of the fourteen (14) members one shall be the Chair or his/her designee of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start Policy Council and one shall be the Chair or his/her designee of the County's Elderly Programs Committee of the Department of Human Services.</section><section prefix='b.'>There shall be a Nominating Committee, which will be convened by the County Manager, to select the initial twelve (12) members and fill any future vacancies. Such Nominating Committee shall consist of the Mayor of Miami-Dade County or his/her designee, the Chair of the Community Action Agency Board and the Chair of the Commission Committee of jurisdiction over the Community Action Agency or his/her designee. The Nominating Committee shall convene at least three (3) months prior to the scheduled vacancy of any position. The Chair of the Community Action Agency Board shall serve as the Chair of the Nominating Committee. The Nominating Committee shall solicit recommendations from the public to fill vacancies on the Community Action Agency Board by providing the public with notice of the availability of such position(s). The Nominating Committee shall review all recommendations and then submit a name for each vacancy plus an additional two (2) names to the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners shall make the appointments to the Community Action Agency Board from the candidates recommended by the Nominating Committee or request a new list of candidates for any of the vacant positions. In the event that the Board of County Commissioners requests additional candidates, the Nominating Committee will devise the process for developing said list.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Ex-officio members. The Board of County Commissioners may appoint ex-officio non-voting members, as recommended by the Community Action Agency Board. Such ex-officio members shall not count toward a quorum.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Petition process. The Community Action Agency Board, in order to comply with Community Services Block Grant funding requirements, shall establish a procedure in its bylaws to allow any individual living in a target area served by the Community Action Agency, a representative of individuals who reside in a target area served by the Community Action Agency or any community or religious organization, to petition for adequate representation on the Community Action Agency Board if they believe they are underrepresented.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Interim board composition. The Community Action Agency Board that exists at the time of the passage of this ordinance shall serve as the interim board for no more than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance, while the new Community Action Agency Board is convened.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-31, ยง 2, 5-5-09)</history></law>