<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIII. COMMUNITY RELATIONS BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-208</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000400</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-208. Duties and functions.<section>The primary mission of the Community Relations Board is to intervene and contain, as quickly as possible, community tensions.</section><section>The secondary mission of the Community Relations Board is to: work proactively to identify and relieve intergroup conflicts before crisis arise; to develop bridges of understanding, communication, and mutual respect; to develop and support local or city based Community Relations Boards throughout the County; and to assure that resources are in place to respond to community crisis.</section><section>The functions of the Board shall be:<section prefix='(a)'>To foster mutual understanding, tolerance, and respect among all economic, social, religious and ethnic groups in the County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To make studies in the field of human relations. The Board is vested with the power and authority and charged with the duty and responsibility.</section><section prefix='(c)'>To attempt to act as conciliator in controversies involving community relations.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To cooperate with federal, State and City agencies in developing harmonious community relations.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To cooperate in the development of educational programs dedicated to the improvement of community relations with, and to enlist the support of, civic leaders; civic, religious, veterans, labor, industrial, commercial and eleemosynary groups; and private agencies engaged in the inculcation of ideals of tolerance, mutual respect and understanding.</section><section prefix='(f)'>To serve as a quasi-autonomous body authorized to act independently to pursue strategies for the promotion of intergroup relations and to recommend to the Mayor, the Board of County Commissioners, and the County Manager such resolutions, ordinances and other causes of action as will aid in carrying out the purposes of this article.</section><section prefix='(g)'>To submit an annual report to the Mayor, the Board of County Commissioners and the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(h)'>To accept grants and donations on behalf of the County from foundations and others for the purpose of carrying out the above listed functions, subject to approval by the County Commission.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-22, ยง 5, 6-11-63; Ord. No. 00-115, ยง 1, 9-19-00)</history></law>