<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00157' order_by='00157' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXVIII. VOLUNTARY ENERGY EFFICIENCY AND RENEWABLE ENERGY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2079</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001222</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2079. Definitions.<section>means the County or any qualified firm selected by the County through a competitive process to administer the Energy Savings Program.</section><section>means a written agreement between the County and an Eligible Participant setting forth the terms and conditions of the Energy Savings Program.</section><section>means a contractor properly certified or registered pursuant to part I or part II of chapter 489, Florida Statutes.</section><section>means any residential or commercial Property owner who voluntarily participates in this Energy Savings Program and satisfies the eligibility requirements set forth below.</section><section>shall mean an energy audit performed by qualified energy auditor or a certified building energy rater approved by the County pursuant to.</section><section>means the Voluntary Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Program authorized by this Article.</section><section>means the notice that an Eligible Participant is required to provide to a purchaser of the Property prior to its sale.</section><section>means a property, residential or commercial, located within the boundaries of the County which is being improved pursuant to the Energy Savings Program.</section><section><section prefix='(1)'>Energy conservation and efficiency improvement, which is a measure to reduce consumption through conservation or a more efficient use of electricity, natural gas, propane or other forms of energy on the property, including, but not limited to, air sealing; installation of insulation; installation of energy-efficient heating, cooling, or ventilation systems; building modifications to increase the use of daylight; replacement of window(s); installation of energy controls or energy recovery systems; installation of electric vehicle charging equipment; and installation of efficient lighting equipment; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Renewable energy improvement, which is the installation of any system in which the electrical, mechanical, or thermal energy is produced from a method that uses one or more of the following fuels or energy sources: hydrogen, solar energy, geothermal energy, bioenergy, and wind energy; provided, such energy conservation and efficiency improvement and renewable energy improvement shall be made, and affixed, to an existing residential or commercial Property and not to new construction and shall not include a household appliance such as a washing machine or refrigerator that is not permanently fixed to real property.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-78, ยง 1(B), 11-4-10)</history></law>