<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00151' order_by='00151' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXII. COMMUNITY ACTION AGENCY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2047</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization, procedure and orientation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001190</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2047. Organization, procedure and orientation.<section prefix='(a)'>Bylaws. The Community Action Agency Board shall make and adopt bylaws for its guidance, operation, governance and maintenance, provided such bylaws, and any amendments thereto, are consistent with federal and state laws and county ordinances, rules, regulations, policies and procedures and have been approved for form and legal sufficiency by the County Attorney's Office.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Officers. Immediately after the members are appointed, including the fourteen (14) Community Interests members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners, the members of the Community Action Agency Board shall elect a chair, a vice-chair and other officers as designated in the bylaws. An interim chair, vice-chair and other officers may be elected to serve until such time as the fourteen (14) members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners have been selected. Officers shall be elected for a two-year term.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Committees. The Community Action Agency Board shall have an executive committee and a finance committee. Other committee(s) considered necessary to address the core mission of the Community Action Agency shall be designated in the bylaws. The bylaws shall also allow for the creation of ad hoc committees as necessary.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Meetings.<section prefix='(1)'>Meetings shall be conducted upon the call of the chairperson; however, the Community Action Agency Board shall meet on a regular basis as determined in the bylaws during the County's fiscal year.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All Community Action Agency Board meetings must be timely noticed at least seven (7) but not more than thirty (30) days prior to the meeting. Such notice shall be provided to the media and a copy shall be maintained at the Community Action Agency. However, if immediate action is necessary to address a matter of imminent harm to public health, safety and welfare, the Community Action Agency Board may schedule a meeting with no less than twenty-four (24) hours' notice.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Community Action Agency Board and such minutes shall be available for inspection by any interested person.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All meetings shall be open to the public.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Quorum. A quorum of the Community Action Agency Board shall be one-half (½) of the total number of members seated on the Community Action Agency Board plus one (1).</section><section prefix='(f)'>Inquiries and communications. All inquiries or communications from the Community Action Agency Board or any of its members to the Community Action Agency or to the County shall be made through the Chair of the Community Action Agency Board. Informal communications may be made freely from the Community Action Agency to the Community Action Agency Board members, pursuant to the Sunshine Laws.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Orientation. All new members of the Community Action Agency Board shall receive sufficient training and orientation to enable them to perform their duties.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-31, § 5, 5-5-09)</history></law>