<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00151' order_by='00151' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXII. COMMUNITY ACTION AGENCY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2048</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001191</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2048. Powers and duties.<section prefix='(a)'>The Community Action Agency Board shall have the following powers and duties with regard to the Community Services Block Grant funding and programs:<section prefix='(1)'>To advise the Board of County Commissioners regarding: the development, planning, implementation and evaluation of Community Service Block Grant programs and other programs administered by the Community Action Agency; issues and causes of poverty in Miami-Dade County; the reduction of such poverty; the revitalization of low income communities; and the empowerment of low income families and individuals to become self-sufficient;</section><section prefix='(2)'>To provide guidance and support to the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor and the County Manager in identifying and helping to reduce the causes of poverty in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(3)'>To assist in the identification of public and private resources at the local, state, and federal levels to promote self-sufficiency, family stability and community revitalization for economically disadvantaged persons;</section><section prefix='(4)'>To involve economically disadvantaged persons in developing and carrying out anti-poverty programs and encouraging their regular participation in the implementation of these programs;</section><section prefix='(5)'>To ensure the Community Action Agency is in compliance with all governing federal, state, county laws, regulations, policies and procedures, grant and contractual requirements;</section><section prefix='(6)'>To encourage and support coordination with other agencies dedicated to the eradication of poverty and the empowerment of the economically disadvantaged so as to avoid whenever possible overlap and duplication of services;</section><section prefix='(7)'>To approve and provide a Community Action Plan every two years, which shall serve as a written or oral report, to the Board of County Commissioners and the written report to the State of Florida. The Community Action Plan shall contain, but not be limited to, the following information:<section prefix='a.'>A community needs assessment update (including food needs);</section><section prefix='b.'>A description of the service delivery system targeted to low income individuals and families in the regions;</section><section prefix='c.'>A description of how linkages will be developed to fill identified gaps in services through information, referral, case management, and follow-up consultation;</section><section prefix='d.'>A description of how Community Service Block Grant funding will be coordinated with other public and private resources;</section><section prefix='e.'>A description of outcome measures to be used to monitor success in promoting self-sufficiency, family stability, and community revitalization and a description of the Community Action Agency's success in promoting these activities.</section><section prefix='f.'>A description of how the Community Action Plan interfaces with and is coordinated with Miami-Dade County's Strategic Plan;</section><section prefix='g.'>Any other information that the Community Action Agency is required to gather as a condition of receiving Community Service Block Grant funds from the State of Florida or the federal government; and</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>To perform any other duties or responsibilities that may from time to time be required as a condition of receiving Community Service Block Grant funds from the State of Florida or the federal government.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Community Action Agency Board shall have the following powers and duties with regard to Head Start/Early Head Start funding and programs:<section prefix='(1)'>To adopt practices that are consistent with federal regulations and that assure active, independent and informed governance of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program. Adoption of any such practices shall be documented as a report and presented to the Board of County Commissioners;</section><section prefix='(2)'>To fully participate in the development, planning and evaluation of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program as may be delineated more specifically in the CAA Board's bylaws;</section><section prefix='(3)'>To ensure compliance with all applicable Federal, State and County laws and regulations;</section><section prefix='(4)'>To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners for final approval the selection of service areas and delegate agencies, once any necessary Policy Council approval is attained and is consistent with County procurement policies and procedures;</section><section prefix='(5)'>To review, consistent with County procurement policies and procedures, contracts and agreements under one million dollars, which are necessary for the day-to-day operation of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program, including but not limited to, contracts with delegate agencies and ancillary service providers. The Community Action Agency Board shall review said contracts and agreements and send their recommendations to the Mayor or Mayor's designee for final review and approval. All other contracts and agreements shall be forwarded, with a recommendation from the Community Action Agency Board, to the Board of County Commissioners for final approval;</section><section prefix='(6)'>To establish procedures and criteria for recruitment, selection and enrollment of children;</section><section prefix='(7)'>To review and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners regarding all Head Start/Early Head Start program funding applications and amendments;</section><section prefix='(8)'>To establish procedures and guidelines for accessing and collecting information for review by the Board of County Commissioners as the governing body and the Policy Council regarding program planning, policies and Head Start/Early Head Start program operations. The CAA Board shall provide a quarterly report to the Board of County Commissioners ensuring that all planning, policies and Head Start/Early Head Start program operations are proceeding efficiently and according to the requirements of the Head Start Act. Additional reports outside of this quarterly reporting period shall be required to inform the Board of County Commissioners of issues and instances of exceptional importance that require immediate attention;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Consistent with the County's financial management structure, to: approve all major Head Start/Early Head Start financial expenditures; approve the Head Start/Early Head Start operating budget, prior to final approval by the Board of County Commissioners; oversee audit findings and other actions necessary to comply with applicable laws and regulations governing financial statements and accounting practices; review and approve the annual self-assessment and financial audit; review and approve the County's progress in carrying out the programmatic and fiscal provisions in the County's grant application, including implementation of corrective actions; and review results from federal monitoring, including appropriate follow-up activities;</section><section prefix='(10)'>To establish advisory committees to oversee key responsibilities related to program governance and improvement of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program if so approved by the Board of County Commissioners. If said advisory committee is approved by the Board of County Commissioners, the CAA Board shall contact the Office of Head Start and present information regarding the formation and purpose of the advisory committee;</section><section prefix='(11)'>To provide the following information to the Board of County Commissioners in an annual report:<section prefix='a.'>A list of approved delegate agencies and service areas;</section><section prefix='b.'>Procedures and criteria for recruiting, selecting and enrolling children in the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program;</section><section prefix='c.'>All approved contracts and agreements pursuant to subsection (b)(5);</section><section prefix='d.'>A copy of the annual report required by the Head Start Act.</section></section><section prefix='(12)'>All other powers and duties not specifically delegated hereunder shall remain with the Board of County Commissioners as the federally-recognized governing body of the County's Head Start/Early Head Start program with the legal and fiscal responsibility for administering and overseeing programs under the Head Start Act, including the safeguarding of federal funds.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>To perform any other duties that may from time to time be designated by the Board of County Commissioners through a resolution.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-31, ยง 6, 5-5-09)</history></law>