<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00147' order_by='00147' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY COMMUNITY PERIODICAL ADVERTISING PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2020</section_number>
<catch_line>Suspension and termination.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001161</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2020. Suspension and termination.<section prefix='(a)'>Suspension. The County may formally suspend a periodical for any period of time up to and including twelve months for any of the following reasons:<section prefix='(1)'>Failure to report changes in the information provided to the County within ten days of the change, when such change of information would not disqualify the periodical from participating in the program;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Failure to publish according to the schedule provided on two or three occasions in any six-month period;</section><section prefix='(3)'>On one occasion submitting an invoice for more than the guaranteed amount or when no insertion order was sent; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Single or accidental violations of the terms of this ordinance that County determines do not warrant termination.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Termination. The County may formally terminate a periodical for any period of time from one to three years for any of the following reasons:<section prefix='(1)'>Misrepresenting a material fact on the application that impacts the periodical's qualification for the program;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Failure to report changes in the information provided to the County within ten days of the change, when such change of information would disqualify the periodical from participating in the program;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Failure to publish according to the schedule provided on four or more occasions in any six-month period;</section><section prefix='(4)'>On two or more occasions, submitting an invoice for more than the guaranteed amount or when no insertion order was sent; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Other multiple or intentional violations of the terms of this ordinance.</section></section><section>A periodical that is formally terminated must reapply by submitting a new application after its termination is over.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-25, ยง 1, 4-3-12)</history></law>