<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00147' order_by='00147' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY COMMUNITY PERIODICAL ADVERTISING PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2021</section_number>
<catch_line>Departments required to purchase advertising through this program—Administrative matters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001162</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2021. Departments required to purchase advertising through this program—Administrative matters.<section>Community Periodical Advertising Expenditure. Each Department or County Entity that purchases print advertisements, will expend no less than one-half its discretionary print advertisement budget through this program. This requirement shall not apply to discretionary advertising or marketing that is designed to promote tourism or stimulate economic development by attracting consumers and businesses located outside of Miami-Dade County to do business within the County. As used in this section "discretionary print advertising" means all print advertisements, except those that are legally required to be published by ordinance, statute or law as a precondition to a County action or participation in a program. As part of each annual budget, the Mayor will provide the Board of County Commissioners a report that sets forth for each department the total budgeted print advertising dollars, the discretionary print advertising dollars, the print advertising dollars that are legally required to be published in newspapers of general circulation, and the non-print advertising dollars. If a specific amount for the program is established in the budget ordinance, the specific amount so established will control and the above provisions will not apply. Unless the budget ordinance indicates otherwise, moneys allocated in the budget for the program will be spent on the purchase of advertising and not on administrative expenses such as audits.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-25, § 1, 4-3-12)</history></law>