<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00152' order_by='00152' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXIII. MIAMI-DADE HOUSING CIVIL RIGHTS OVERSIGHT BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2055</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization, Procedure and Orientation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001198</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2055. Organization, Procedure and Orientation.<section prefix='(a)'>Bylaws. The Oversight Board shall make and adopt bylaws for its guidance, operation, governance and maintenance, provided such bylaws, and any amendments thereto, are consistent with federal and state laws and county ordinances, rules, regulations, policies and procedures and have been approved for form and legal sufficiency by the County Attorney's Office.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Officers. Immediately after the members are appointed, the members of the Oversight Board shall elect a chair, a vice chair and other officers as designated in the bylaws. Officers shall be elected for a two-year term.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Committees. The Oversight Board may establish through its bylaws such committees as it considers necessary to address the core mission of the Oversight Board. The bylaws shall also allow for the creation of ad hoc committees as necessary.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Meetings.<section prefix='(1)'>Meetings shall be conducted upon the call of the chairperson; however, the Oversight Board shall meet on a regular basis as determined in the bylaws during the County's fiscal year.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All Oversight Board meetings must be timely noticed at least seven (7) but not more than thirty (30) days prior to the meeting. Such notice shall be provided to the media and a copy shall be maintained at the Miami-Dade Commission on Human Rights. However, if immediate action is necessary to address a matter of imminent harm to public health, safety and welfare, the Oversight Board may schedule a meeting with no less than twenty-four (24) hours notice.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Oversight Board and such minutes shall be available for inspection by any interested person.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All meetings shall be open to the public.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Quorum. A quorum of the Oversight Board shall be one-half of the total number of members seated on the Oversight Board plus one.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Inquiries and Communications. All inquiries or communications from the Oversight Board or any of its members to the Miami-Dade Commission on Human Rights or to the County shall be made through the Chair of the Oversight Board, Informal communications may be made freely from the Miami-Dade Commission on Human Rights to the Oversight Board members, in a manner that is consistent with the Sunshine Law.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Orientation. All new members of the Oversight Board shall receive sufficient training and orientation to enable them to perform their duties.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-107, ยง 4, 12-1-09)</history></law>