<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00153' order_by='00153' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXIV. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY YOUTH COMMISSION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2062</section_number>
<catch_line>Commission Composition; Qualifications; Process for Nomination and Appointment; Exceptions to County Code; Term; Officers; Rules of Procedure; Staff Support.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001205</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2062. Commission Composition; Qualifications; Process for Nomination and Appointment; Exceptions to County Code; Term; Officers; Rules of Procedure; Staff Support.<section prefix='(a)'>The Youth Commission shall be composed of twenty-seven (27) youth who will serve as voting members of the Youth Commission.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each County Commissioner shall appoint two members of the Youth Commission. At least one of the students appointed by a County Commissioner shall be a Miami-Dade County public school student. One of the students appointed by a Commissioner may be a student attending a parochial or private school in the Commissioner's district. The members of the Youth Commission shall be between the ages of fifteen (15) to eighteen (18) years old at the time of appointment and be in the 10th, 11th, or 12th grade. To be qualified for appointment, such student shall have a minimum 2.0 grade point average and shall demonstrate a sincere interest and the motivation to work for the community and have a background in community-based activity.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each member of the County Commission shall receive the names of high school students from public, private and parochial high schools in his or her district. Such high schools shall be requested to forward the names and resumes of interested students for appointment to the Youth Commission to the office of the County Commissioner of the commission district in which the high school is located. The County Commissioner shall interview the nominated student and forward the name and the resume of the students appointed by the County Commissioner to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Mayor of Miami-Dade County, the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners, the County Manager, the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners and the Agenda Coordinator for the Board of County Commissioners shall each select a Miami-Dade Public School System student to be a nonvoting member of the Youth Commission. The Youth Commission member selected by each official shall meet the qualifications set forth in subparagraph (b) above. Each of these officials shall receive the names of high school students from the Miami-Dade County School Board. Each official or his or her designee shall interview the nominated student and forward the name and the resume of the student appointed by the official to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. These nonvoting members of the Youth Commission shall be exposed to and given the opportunity to learn the role of the official who appointed them as nonvoting members of the Youth Commission.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Miami-Dade County Public School student who is appointed to serve on the Miami-Dade County School Board shall be an ex officio voting member of the Youth Commission.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Notwithstanding Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, the members of the Youth Commission shall not be required to be an elector of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The term of office for each member shall be one (1) year. Members may be appointed for a subsequent one-year term; provided, that no member shall serve more than two (2) years as a member of the Youth Commission.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The Youth Commission members shall annually elect a voting member as chairperson and other officers it deems necessary from its voting membership.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The Youth Commission shall adopt its own rules and regulations, as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out its responsibilities, subject to the approval of the County Mayor or his or her designee.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The County Mayor shall designate staff support sufficient to carry out the purposes of this ordinance and provide facilities for meetings and other activities, as necessary. Programming for the Youth Commission shall be executed jointly and in coordination with the Teen Court and Violence Intervention Project programs,</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-05, ยง 3, 1-21-10)</history></law>