<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00154' order_by='00154' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXV. PERFORMANCE AND EFFICIENCY COMMISSION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2065</section_number>
<catch_line>Creation; Powers and Duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001208</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2065. Creation; Powers and Duties.<section>The Miami-Dade County Performance and Efficiency Commission is hereby created. The duties of the Miami-Dade Performance and Efficiency Commission shall be to:<section prefix='(a)'>Provide and obtain private and public sector input on the performance and efficiency of the operations of Miami-Dade County and prioritize recommended improvements;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Recommend cost-effectiveness measures and best business/management practices which will realize savings and improve service delivery, including, but not limited to, identifying opportunities for increased competition and efficiency, reorganizations, appropriate incentives such as performance pay and other gain sharing approaches, innovations in the building and permitting processes; and public-private price and performance competition projects which can be undertaken with county workers to ensure the highest potential value of services provided;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Recommend ways to explore and promote technology improvements as a means of achieving optimal operational effectiveness, as well as recommend ethics management and accountability measures for Miami-Dade County government;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Recommend management systems development, conduct project reviews and studies and participative management and employee recognition programs, public relations, and training and development programs;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Review the County's Strategic Plan and other administrative mechanisms to implement the County's Strategic Plan in order to accomplish the aims of this resolution; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>Monitor the implementation of recommended changes.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-43, ยง 1, 7-8-10)</history></law>