<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00157' order_by='00157' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXVIII. VOLUNTARY ENERGY EFFICIENCY AND RENEWABLE ENERGY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2081</section_number>
<catch_line>Application.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001224</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2081. Application.<section>An Eligible Participant shall submit a complete application to the Administrator for approval. A complete application shall include the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>Proof of ownership and location of the Property. Organizational documents if the Property owner is not on the title as an individual.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Documentation showing the structure or building, subject of the application, is an existing structure or building on the date of application.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A cost estimate for the installation of the Qualifying Improvements completed by a Contractor (including the name and license number of the Contractor). This estimate shall include all construction costs, equipment, permitting fees, recording fees for the assessment of liens, energy audit costs, and contingency fees. Estimated costs shall be reasonable for the scope of the proposed project and in relation to the property value.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Written documentation indicating that the Property owner meets all of the criteria set forth in Section 2-2080(3)—(7) above.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Statement that the Eligible Participant will agree to a non-ad valorem assessment being collected pursuant to Section 197.3632, Florida Statutes to secure any loans entered into by the Eligible Participant related to the Energy Savings Program.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Proof that notice was provided to any lender of the Eligible Participant's intent to enter into written agreement with the County with respect to the Energy Savings Program and in the event of a loan, the maximum principal amount to be financed and the maximum annual assessment necessary to repay that amount.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-78, § 1(D), 11-4-10)</history></law>