<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIII. COMMUNITY RELATIONS BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-206</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization; quorum; voting; rules of procedure; records of meetings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000398</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-206. Organization; quorum; voting; rules of procedure; records of meetings.<section>The members of the Board shall select and designate from its members a Chairperson, Vice-Chairperson, Secretary, and such other officers as may be deemed necessary, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board. Fifteen (15) members of the Board shall constitute a quorum, not withstanding. No action shall be taken except by a majority vote of those present at a duly constituted meeting of the Board; provided, however, an executive committee consisting of all officers and such other persons as the Chairperson may appoint from time to time is authorized to exercise all powers, duties and functions of the Board between Board meetings, any such action to be reported to the Board at its next meeting and the Board shall either ratify or rescind the action of the executive committee. The Board may adopt rules of procedure governing its meetings and actions on matters within its jurisdiction, not inconsistent with the provisions of this article, which rules of procedure shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. Copies of the minutes of all Board meetings shall be furnished to the Chairperson of the County Commission and the County Manager.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-22, § 3, 6-11-63; Ord. No. 64-10, § 1, 3-24-64; Ord. No. 67-38, § 2, 5-16-67; Ord. No. 68-2, § 1, 2-6-68; Ord. No. 00-115, § 1, 9-19-00; Ord. No. 03-86, § 2, 4-10-02)</history></law>