<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00155' order_by='00155' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXVI. COMPENSATION AND BENEFITS REVIEW COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2072</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties of the review committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001215</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2072. Duties of the review committee.<section>The Review Committee shall have the following duties, responsibilities, and functions.<section prefix='(a)'>To review and make recommendations concerning County personnel costs. The Review Committee shall conduct a comprehensive study of all employee compensation policies, and provide recommendations regarding salaries, wages and benefits. In making such recommendations, the Review Committee shall consider such factors as:<section prefix='(1)'>The current County pay structure as set forth in the adopted County Pay Plan.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The obligations and commitments adopted in the County's collective bargaining agreements.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The span-of-control ratios for managers and subordinates within the various service areas.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The preferences and desires of County employees as expressed through their collective bargaining representatives.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Comparison of the compensation paid to County employees with the compensation paid to employees of other public employers in the local area.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Comparison of the compensation paid to County employees with the compensation paid to private sector employees in the local area performing similar duties under similar conditions.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The County's fiscal condition and capacity to meet future personnel obligations.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The County's need to attract and retain qualified employees in order to provide efficient service to the public.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Policies governing the hiring of individuals separated pursuant to the Deferred Retirement Option Program.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Salary compression between supervisors and subordinates.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The County's classified civil service rules and other laws and rules designed to protect the rights of its employees.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Policies that govern continuing employment opportunities for civil service employees during periods of a reduction in force.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>To periodically advise the Mayor and the County Commission regarding the appropriate compensation policies to meet the needs of the County, its employees and the public.</section><section prefix='(c)'>To submit a report in May 2010 and an annual report in February of each year thereafter to the Mayor and the County Commission recommending the appropriate compensation policies for County employees.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To promulgate rules consistent with this Ordinance for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To comply with all laws and regulations of the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the laws relating to the keeping of records including the preservation of all audit rights.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-109, ยง 1(3), 12-1-09)</history></law>