<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00157' order_by='00157' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXVIII. VOLUNTARY ENERGY EFFICIENCY AND RENEWABLE ENERGY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2083</section_number>
<catch_line>Agreement terms.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001225</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2083. Agreement terms.<section>The County shall enter into a voluntary written agreement with each Eligible Participant. The written agreement shall provide, among other matters, for the following:<section prefix='(1)'>All work requiring a license under any applicable law to make a qualifying improvement shall be performed by a Contractor.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The source and amount of funding to be provided to the Eligible Participant.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The maximum limit of the financing for the Energy Savings Program shall not exceed 10 percent of the just value of the Property as determined by the County's Property Appraiser on the latest available tax roll unless:<section prefix='•'>A higher financing amount is consented to by the mortgage holder on the Property, if one exists; or</section><section prefix='•'>The Energy Audit demonstrates that the annual energy savings from the Qualified Improvement equals or exceeds the annual repayment amount of the non-ad valorem assessment.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Express voluntary consent by the Eligible Participant to accept the non-ad valorem assessment collection process pursuant to Section 197.3632, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The length of time for the Eligible Participant to repay the non-ad valorem assessment, provided, that it shall not exceed 20 years.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Eligible Participant shall be responsible for assuring the Qualifying Improvements are completed as reflected in the approved application documents. The Eligible Participant also consents to providing access to the Property to the County to verify that the Qualifying Improvements have been completed as proposed in the application.<section>At the time of a transfer of Property ownership except a transfer resulting from foreclosure, the past due balances of any non-ad valorem assessment under this Subsection shall be due for payment, but future payments shall continue as a lien on the property. At or before the execution of a contract for the sale and purchase of any property for which a non-ad valorem assessment for the Energy Savings Program has been levied and has an unpaid balance due, the seller shall give the prospective purchaser a Notice.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>The risks associated with participating in the Energy Savings Program shall be disclosed in the written Agreement, including risks related to the failure of the Eligible Participant to make payments and the risk of issuance of a tax certificate and loss of the property pursuant to Chapter 197, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The cost of an energy savings audit or the cost to complete an estimate of information on energy saving measures, estimated energy savings for each measure, estimated greenhouse gas reductions and estimated cost savings from the projects will be subject to reimbursement upon execution of the written agreement to accept the non-ad valorem assessment.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Description of the Qualifying Improvements, their cost, estimated completion date and estimated savings.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A copy of the Energy Audit shall be included as an Exhibit.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The Eligible Participant shall agree to apply any rebates provided by an entity other than the County, received for the Qualifying Improvements, towards the repayment of any non-ad valorem assessment.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The Eligible Participant shall provide all copies of final permits and inspections to the County upon completion of the Qualifying Improvements.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-78, § 1(E), 11-4-10)</history></law>