<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00150' order_by='00150' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXI. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT NEIGHBORHOOD RELATIONS COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2039</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001181</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2039. Membership.<section prefix='(a)'>NRC members. The NRC shall consist of nine (9) members representing the areas with the greatest potential for adverse impacts from MIA. Each member may designate a single alternate to participate and vote on his or her behalf. The members of the NRC shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County ("Code") and shall serve without compensation. Notwithstanding any provision in the Code to the contrary, the members shall be appointed in the following manner:<section prefix='(1)'>Two (2) members shall be residents of County Commission District 6, and shall be appointed by the County Commissioner of District 6;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Two (2) members shall be residents of County Commission District 12, and shall be appointed by the County Commissioner of District 12;</section><section prefix='(3)'>One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Miami, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Miami;</section><section prefix='(4)'>One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Miami Springs, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Miami Springs;</section><section prefix='(5)'>One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Doral, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Doral;</section><section prefix='(6)'>One (1) member shall be a resident of the City of Coral Gables, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the City of Coral Gables;</section><section prefix='(7)'>One (1) member shall be a resident of the Village of Virginia Gardens, and shall be nominated by the Mayor of the Village of Virginia Gardens.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Any member who ceases to meet the membership requirements set forth above shall immediately forfeit his or her office.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Term. In accordance with Section 2-11.38.2 of the Code, the members of the NRC shall serve staggered terms of three (3) years each. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, no member shall be permitted to serve more than eight (8) consecutive years. Members nominated by the County Commissioners representing Districts 6 and 12 shall serve an initial term of three (3) years. Members nominated by the Mayor of the City of Miami, the Mayor of the City of Miami Springs, the Mayor of the City of Doral, the Mayor of the City of Coral Gables, and the Mayor of the Village of Virginia Gardens shall serve an initial term of two (2) years.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Vacancies. Vacancies in the membership of the NRC shall be filled in the same manner by which the original NRC members were appointed and shall be filled within 45 days.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Removal from office. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, if any NRC member is absent from two (2) consecutive NRC meetings annually without an acceptable excuse, or from four (4) NRC meetings annually without an acceptable excuse, the NRC shall report the same to the County Commissioners of District 6 and 12.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-115, ยง 3, 10-7-08)</history></law>