<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00153' order_by='00153' level='3'>ARTICLE CXXXIV. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY YOUTH COMMISSION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2061</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and responsibilities of the Youth Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001204</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2061. Duties and responsibilities of the Youth Commission.<section>The Youth Commission shall have the following duties and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>Foster increased youth involvement in the affairs of County government;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Study problems and hold forums on issues, activities and concerns of youth in the County;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Comment upon existing or proposed legislation, ordinances, resolutions and policies that impact the youth in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Present methods to resolve youth-related conflicts between youth and between youth and adults;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Recommend the implementation of community programs to improve the lives of youth;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Monitor programs and policies that affect youth to ensure that they are achieving the intended results;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Work with other youth organizations in the County to collaborate on shared issues and interests;</section><section prefix='(h)'>Submit to the Mayor and Board of County Commissioners an annual report of the activities of the Commission in the month of May prior to the end of the regular school year;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Serve as the Violence Intervention Program representative for their respective school, as permitted by the Miami-Dade County Public School System;</section><section prefix='(j)'>Facilitate an annual Youth Summit in conjunction with the Juvenile Services Department and the South Florida Youth Advisory Board; and</section><section prefix='(k)'>Utilize social networking sites and/or technology to engage and inform the youth of their community of important County activities.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Participate in a workshop which will introduce the Youth Commission members to a County Commission agenda process, a mock county commission meeting, the role of the officials who appoint them and the County Attorney, at a minimum.</section><section prefix='(m)'>The member of the Youth Commission appointed by the Mayor shall be designated as a member of the South Florida Workforce Youth Advisory Council.</section></section><section>Additionally, each member of the Youth Commission is to meet with the official who appointed the Youth Commission member on a quarterly basis or at the discretion of the appointing official, as is mutually convenient for the Youth Commission member and appointing official to discuss teen and community issues of concern to them.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-05, ยง 2, 1-21-10)</history></law>