<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00165' order_by='00165' level='3'>ARTICLE CXLVI. SOUTH MUNICIPAL ADVISORY COMMITTEE A</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2141</section_number>
<catch_line>Created.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001270</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2141. Created.<section>The South Municipal Advisory Committee A (the "Committee") is hereby created as follows:<section prefix='A.'>Purposes.<section prefix='(1)'>To review the possible incorporation of the area known as South A, as shown with particularity on the attached maps incorporated herein by reference, all contained with County Commission District 9 (the "Study Area"). It is provided, however, that the Committee, as established herein, by majority vote of its members present, may expand the Study Area within the boundaries of District 9 and/or any adjacent commission district, provided that the commissioner of the district for the expanded area has filed a written consent with the Clerk of the Board agreeing to the study of the expanded area.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notwithstanding any provision of the Code or any ordinance to the contrary, the Committee may combine and consolidate with another municipal advisory committee created on the same date as the Committee, as long as the study area of the other municipal advisory committee is contiguous with the study area of this Committee.</section></section><section prefix='B.'>Duties and Responsibilities; Sunset.<section prefix='(1)'>The Committee shall prepare an advisory report that shall:<section prefix='a.'>Make findings of whether it is feasible or not to incorporate the Study Area; determine whether there is a desire to incorporate the Study Area; and propose a plan for the development of the Study Area as a viable municipality, as required by Section 20-29 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='b.'>Address any concerns of members of the Board of County Commissioners regarding incorporation of the area and the manner in which those concerns may be alleviated in the event the area studied by the Committee is incorporated as a new municipality; and</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The committee shall conduct no less than two duly advertised public hearings at which the residents of the area shall have the opportunity to express their views and concerns regarding the proposed incorporation of the Study Area.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Prior to the first public hearing, the committee shall become familiar with written materials concerning incorporation presented by the Office of Management and Budget.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The committee's responsibilities shall terminate upon submitting its report to the Board of County Commissioners or within twenty-four (24) months of the effective date of this article, whichever date is earlier.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Composition and appointment of members. The Committee shall consist of seven (7) members who are resident electors of the Study Area. The Commissioner for District 9, by filing a written memorandum to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, shall appoint the members of the committee.<section>Should the Study Area be expanded to include an area of an adjacent commission district which is contiguous to the study area, the commissioner of the expanded area shall be authorized to appoint one additional member to the Committee, so that the Committee shall consist of eight (8) members.</section><section>Should the Committee combine and consolidate with another municipal advisory committee as authorized by Paragraph A.(2) above, the membership of the consolidated committee shall be a number which totals the membership of each committee prior to consolidation.</section><section>If a vacancy occurs in the membership of the Committee, the commissioner who made the original appointment shall fill the vacancy by filing a written memorandum to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The members of the committee shall select officers from the membership as desirable or necessary.</section></section></section><section>The provisions of of the Code of Miami-Dade County that prohibit simultaneous board service on more than two County boards and membership on certain listed County boards and service on this Committee are waived; provided, however, no member of the Planning Advisory Board may be a member of this Committee.</section><section>The provisions of(A) of the Code of Miami-Dade County that prohibit the creation of a municipal advisory committee unless at least twenty-five (25) percent of the resident electors in the area to be studied consent in writing to the creation of a municipal advisory committee are hereby waived.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-77, §§ 1—3, 9-4-13)</history></law>