<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00160' order_by='00160' level='3'>ARTICLE CXLI. SCRAP METAL AND COPPER WIRE THEFT TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2108</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001250</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2108. Organization.<section prefix='(1)'>The Task Force may establish, adopt, and amend bylaws, rules, and regulations for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A chairperson and a vice chairperson shall be selected by the Task Force at its first meeting. The chairperson and vice chairperson shall serve at the will of the Task Force.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The vice chairperson shall act as chairperson in the absence or inability of the chairperson.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In order to transact any business or to exercise any power vested in the Task Force, a quorum consisting of a majority of those persons duly appointed to the Task Force shall be present, provided that at least one-half (½) of the full Task Force membership has been appointed.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Task Force may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks. Members of a committee may consist of members of the Task Force and/or other persons with specialized knowledge that would benefit the committee.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall supply such support staff to the Task Force as may be necessary to fulfill its purpose. The staff shall maintain and keep the records of the Task Force; prepare in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, or correspondence as the Task Force may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of the Task Force, subject to budgetary limitations.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The County Attorney's Office shall provide legal counsel, as needed, to the Task Force.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-76, § 3, 10-4-11)</history></law>