<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00163' order_by='00163' level='3'>ARTICLE CXLIV. WEST KENDALL (SECTION ONE) MUNICIPAL ADVISORY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2131</section_number>
<catch_line>Created.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001266</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2131. Created.<section>The West Kendall (Section One) Municipal Advisory Committee (the "Committee") is hereby created as follows.<section prefix='A.'>Purposes.<section prefix='(1)'>To review the possible incorporation of the area known as West Kendall (Section One) generally described by the following boundaries:<section>North:   Tamiami Trail</section><section>South:   SW 88th Street/North Kendall Drive East: Florida Turnpike</section><section>West:   The Everglades</section><section>But such study boundaries shall only include areas within District 11 (the "Study Area"). It is provided, however, that the Committee as established herein may expand or contract the Study Area within District 11, as long as the Commissioner of that district files a written consent with the Clerk of the Board agreeing to the study of any expanded area.</section></section></section><section prefix='B.'>Duties and Responsibilities; Sunset.<section prefix='(1)'>The committee shall prepare an advisory report that shall:<section prefix='a.'>Make findings of whether it is feasible or not to incorporate the Study Area; determine whether there is a desire to incorporate the Study Area; and propose a plan for the development of the Study Area as a viable municipality, as required by Section 20-29 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='b.'>Address any concerns of members of the Board of County Commissioners regarding incorporation of the area and the manner in which those concerns may be alleviated in the event the area studied by the Committee is incorporated as a new municipality.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The committee shall conduct no less than two duly advertised public hearings at which the residents of the area shall have the opportunity to express their views and concerns regarding the proposed incorporation of the West Kendall (Section One) area.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Prior to the first public hearing, the committee shall become familiar with written materials concerning incorporation as presented by the staff of the Office of Management and Budget.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The committee's responsibilities shall terminate upon submitting its report to the Board of County Commissioners or within twenty-four (24) months of the effective date of this article, whichever date is earlier.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Composition and appointment of members. The Committee shall consist of seven (7) members who are resident electors of the Study Area. Based on the percentage of current population in each Commission district within the Study Area as compared to the current population of the total Study Area, Commissioners, by filing a written memorandum to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, shall appoint the number of members as stated below:<section>District 11: 7 members</section><section>The district commissioner who previously made appointments to a seat shall fill any vacancy in that seat by filing a written memorandum to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The members of the committee shall select officers from the membership as desirable or necessary.</section></section></section><section>The provisions of of the Code of Miami-Dade County that prohibit simultaneous board service on more than two County boards and membership on certain listed County boards and service on this Committee are waived; provided, however, no member of the Planning Advisory Board may be a member of this Committee.</section><section>The provisions of(A) of the Code of Miami-Dade County that prohibit the creation of a municipal advisory committee unless at least twenty-five (25) percent of the resident electors in the area to be studied consent in writing to the creation of a municipal advisory committee are hereby waived.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 1370, §§ 1—3, 7-2-13)</history></law>