<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00159' order_by='00159' level='3'>ARTICLE CXL. MILITARY AFFAIRS BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2103</section_number>
<catch_line>Governing Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001245</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2103. Governing Board.<section prefix='(a)'>Composition and appointment. The Military Affairs Board shall consist of twenty-four (24) voting members appointed as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Each member of the Board of County Commissioners shall designate one (1) member who shall be approved by the County Commission; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Chairperson of the County Commission shall appoint one (1) member of the County Commission who shall be the Military Liaison of the County Commission; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Mayor of Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member of the Board; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>The command staff of Southern Command shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>The command staff at the United States Air Force Base in Homestead shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>The command staff at the United States Coast Guard District 7 shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(7)'>The command staff at the United States Army National Guard Reserve Station located in Miami shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(8)'>The command staff of the United States Navy and Marine Corps Reserves located in Hialeah shall appoint two (2) members: one (1) member representing the United States Navy; and one (1) member representing the United States Marine Corps; and</section><section prefix='(9)'>The Miami-Dade Defense Alliance shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(10)'>The Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(11)'>The Red Cross shall appoint one (1) member.</section></section><section>The Military Affairs Board shall also consist of the following non-voting members:<section prefix='(1)'>The Director of the Miami Veteran's Administration Healthcare System shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each Congressperson whose district includes a portion of Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Each United States Senator representing the State of Florida shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>The United States Attorney from the Southern District of Florida shall appoint one (1) member; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>The State Attorney for Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member.</section></section><section>When making a selection, each person or entity shall consider that the voting members should reflect the gender, racial ethnic or cultural make-up of the community.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Qualifications. Each member of the Commission shall (i) be a United States citizen, a duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County and (ii) shall comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Additionally, each member shall be a person who has previously served or is currently serving in the Armed Forces, or has an interest in military affairs. Before taking any official action, each voting member shall take the prescribed oath of office.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Term. Members of the Board shall serve terms of three (3) years each.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Vacancies. Each person or entity shall appoint a new representative within one month when its appointee resigns or is removed.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Applicability of Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (the "Conflict of Interest Ordinance"), Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be applicable to the members of the Board. It is declared to be the intent of the Commission, as expressed in this subsection, to provide that the Conflict of Interest Ordinance shall not operate to preclude individuals from serving as Board members on the basis of interests relating to Miami-Dade County when such interests do not conflict with the Board.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Organization and Procedure. The Chairperson of the Board shall be the Military Liaison of the County Commission selected by the Chairperson of the County Commission. The Board shall elect one (1) of its members as vice-chairperson and such other officers as the Board may determine to be necessary. The Board shall create by-laws and shall hold regular meetings in accordance with those by-laws. The Board may hold such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum. All meetings of the Board shall be public and the Board shall maintain written minutes of all proceedings that shall be promptly prepared and recorded. Copies of all minutes and resolutions of the Board shall be forwarded to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners no later than thirty (30) days subsequent to any meeting of the Board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-37, ยง 1, 5-15-12; Ord. No. 13-10, ยง 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>