<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00159' order_by='00159' level='3'>ARTICLE CXL. MILITARY AFFAIRS BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2102</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and Duties of Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001244</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2102. Powers and Duties of Board.<section>The Board shall have the following powers and duties:<section prefix='(a)'>Provide the Board of County Commissioners with recommendations regarding military affairs in Miami-Dade County involving the Marine Corps, Army, Navy, Air Force, National Guard and Coast Guard (collectively "Armed Forces") and active, reserve, retired, disabled and deceased military personnel in Miami-Dade County (collectively "military personnel"); and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Promote measures to enhance the quality of life for active, reserve, retired and disabled military personnel and their families, and families of deceased military personnel in Miami-Dade County; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Advocate on behalf of military personnel in Miami-Dade County regarding, among other matters: health care; housing; housing and business loans; pension benefits; education; employment; incarceration; reintegration; unemployment benefits; disability claims; vocational training; and insurance; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>Administer the medal of valor program created by Ordinance No. 10-29; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>Take steps to increase awareness and support for our military personnel from Miami-Dade County who are serving in the Armed Forces around the world; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>Interface with local Reserve Officer Training Corps ("ROTC") programs at both the high school and collegiate levels; and</section><section prefix='(g)'>Solicit input from and maintain a strong relationship with the United States Department of Defense, Department of Homeland Security, Department of Veterans Affairs, the Red Cross and any other entity which interacts with the Armed Forces regarding military affairs or military personnel regarding, among other things, military affairs impacting Miami-Dade County, military personnel in Miami-Dade County and ROTC; and</section><section prefix='(h)'>Coordinate Miami-Dade County's activities regarding Veteran's Day, Memorial Day and the 4th of July; and</section><section prefix='(i)'>Promote, attract and solicit military activities in Miami-Dade County from throughout the United States and within Miami-Dade County to the greatest extent feasible and strive to generate and further community support for the United States Armed Forces in the United States and abroad; and</section><section prefix='(j)'>Adopt an official seal; and</section><section prefix='(k)'>To submit annually to the Board of County Commissioners a report summarizing and evaluating all programs and activities undertaken by the Board during the previous fiscal year; and</section><section prefix='(l)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, accept and solicit gifts of money or services for the public purposes provided for in this article; and</section><section prefix='(m)'>Cooperate with any federal, state, county, or municipal government, agency or instrumentality; and</section><section prefix='(n)'>Create a standing committee relating to the Base Realignment and Closure process ("BRAC") charged with the following responsibilities and duties:<section prefix='(1)'>Working with other entities, such as federal and state agencies, to represent Miami-Dade County's interests by ensuring that local military bases remain open as part of the next BRAC round potentially scheduled for 2015; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Maximizing any opportunities for Miami-Dade County that may be realized from any potential realignment; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Minimizing any negative impacts to local communities; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Developing a comprehensive plan, approved by the Military Affairs Board, to be recommended to the Board of County Commissioners after evaluating infrastructure needs, land use needs, 21st century mission of the armed forces, and community support; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>Working with military bases in South Florida in order to put together a vision for the future and a relevance plan; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Providing advice and recommendations, approved by the Military Affairs Board, to the Board of County Commissioners regarding any actions it may take to further Miami-Dade County's interests with relation to any future BRAC round.</section></section><section prefix='(o)'>Expend funds for the purposes provided in this article. The Military Affairs Board shall only be authorized to expend funds deposited in the Military Affairs Trust Fund. The Mayor or his or her designee shall, on a monthly basis, provide the Military Affairs Board with an accounting of available funds. All expenditures of the Military Affairs Board shall be subject to a county audit.</section><section prefix='(p)'>To solicit and approve grant agreements for the public purposes provided for in this article. All funds received pursuant to a grant agreement shall be deposited in the Military Affairs Trust Fund. The Military Affairs Board shall only approve a grant agreement distributing funds to a third-party to the extent that funds are currently available in the Military Affairs Trust Fund.</section><section prefix='(q)'>To solicit and approve contracts for the public purposes provided for in this article, and only to the extent that funds are currently available in the Military Affairs Trust Fund. It is the intent of the County Commission that the Military Affairs Board be given the authority to enter into county contracts with the assistance of county staff subject to the limitations of this article. The contracting policies and procedures to be followed by the Military Affairs Board to give effect to this intent shall be set forth in an implementing order approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-37, ยง 1, 5-15-12; Ord. No. 13-10, ยง 1, 2-5-13)</history></law>