<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00160' order_by='00160' level='3'>ARTICLE CXLI. SCRAP METAL AND COPPER WIRE THEFT TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2107</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; Appointments; Vacancies; and Qualifications.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001249</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-2107. Membership; Appointments; Vacancies; and Qualifications.<section>The Task Force shall be comprised of twenty-six (26) members from the following categories of representatives:<section prefix='(1)'>One (1) member of the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners appointed by the Chair;</section><section prefix='(2)'>One (1) selected by each of the following municipalities:<section prefix='(a)'>City of Miami,</section><section prefix='(b)'>City of Hialeah,</section><section prefix='(c)'>City of Miami Gardens,</section><section prefix='(d)'>City of North Miami,</section><section prefix='(e)'>City of Miami Beach,</section><section prefix='(f)'>City of Medley, and</section><section prefix='(g)'>City of Homestead;</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>One (1) selected by the League of Cities;</section><section prefix='(4)'>One (1) from the Miami-Dade Office of the State Attorney selected by the Miami-Dade Office of the State Attorney;</section><section prefix='(5)'>One (1) selected by the Miami-Dade County Inspector General's Office;</section><section prefix='(6)'>One (1) from Florida Power & Light selected by Florida Power & Light;</section><section prefix='(7)'>One (1) from the Miami-Dade Schools Police Department selected by the Miami-Dade Schools Police Department; and</section><section prefix='(8)'>One (1) representative from each of the following County departments appointed by the Mayor or the Mayor's designee:<section prefix='(a)'>Miami-Dade County Police Department, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Miami-Dade County Public Works Department.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>The following representatives shall be appointed by majority vote of the Board of County Commissioners:<section prefix='(a)'>Six (6) representatives from the scrap metals industry each possessing at least five (5) years experience in the scrap metals industry; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Five (5) representatives from the community with an understanding of the impact of copper wire and scrap metal theft on neighborhoods.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Vacancies. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Qualifications of Members. Each member of the Task Force shall be a permanent resident and duly qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, unless the Board of County Commissioners waives this requirement by a two-thirds () vote of its membership. No applicant shall be selected for the Task Force if he or she has ever had in any jurisdiction any prior charge, indictment, citation, prosecution, plea of guilty or nolo contendere of a felony, misdemeanor, or ordinance violation, for larceny, theft, possession of or dealing in stolen goods or any crime related to scrap metal processors or junk dealers, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld. The members of the Task Force shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-76, ยง 2, 10-4-11; Ord. No. 12-79, ยง 1, 10-2-12)</history></law>