<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00034' order_by='00034' level='3'>ARTICLE XXV. CHILDREN'S SERVICES COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-236</section_number>
<catch_line>Council functions, responsibilities and restrictions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000413</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-236. Council functions, responsibilities and restrictions.<section prefix='(a)'>The Council shall have the following functions within the scope of its powers and shall exercise same subject to the direction of the Board of County Commissioners.<section prefix='(1)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to County government with respect to all issues within the Council's jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To encourage and facilitate coordination and cooperation with respect to programs and funding among those public and private agencies providing children's services within Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To formulate legislative, programmatic and funding agendas needed to address present and future needs of children in the community, including the identification and development of funding sources.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To provide legislative analysis and development at the local, State and federal levels.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To provide technical assistance as needed in the areas of concept development and grant writing.</section><section prefix='(6)'>To conduct research, compile information and maintain a comprehensive data base relating to children's programs, services and needs.</section><section prefix='(7)'>To monitor and evaluate existing children's services and give appropriate input with respect thereto.</section><section prefix='(8)'>To provide a forum for the discussion of issues relating to children.</section><section prefix='(9)'>To engage in advocacy activities on behalf of children.</section><section prefix='(10)'>To advise public and private sector organizations and agencies on issues relating to children, including recommending public policies relevant to children and families.</section><section prefix='(11)'>To network with other local governments to identify, increase and promote governmental and other funding for children's services programs.</section><section prefix='(12)'>To perform any other advisory functions assigned to the Council by the Commission.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Chairperson, or his or her designee, shall present to the Board of County Commissioners on an annual basis a written report describing the Council's activities. The Chairperson, or his or her designee, may also appear as needed before the Board to present any matters pertinent to the Council's concerns.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Council is advisory only and shall not have the power or authority to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies to any policies, to incur any financial obligation or to create any liability, contractual or otherwise, on the part of the County or any of its agencies.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Council members shall serve without compensation. The Board of County Commissioners may provide funds for appropriate and necessary expenses incurred by the Council or any of its members.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Council shall have the authority to accept gifts of money, services, or personal property. Subject to the prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, the Council may accept gifts of real property, the title of which shall be in Miami-Dade County. All gifts shall be held in a designated trust fund and used in the exercise of the Council's functions and responsibilities as outlined in this section. The trust fund shall be administered by the Department of Human Services, Office of Youth and Family Development and all expenditures of trust funds shall be approved by the Children's Services Council. Formal bid procedures and the requirements of Administrative Order 3-2 for the expenditure of trust funds for the purchase of goods and services associated with the programs and projects of the Children's Services Council are waived.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-50, ยง 1, 6-5-90; Ord. No. 92-36, ยง 1, 5-5-92; Ord. No. 96-75, ยง 1, 5-7-96)</history></law>