<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00034' order_by='00034' level='3'>ARTICLE XXV. CHILDREN'S SERVICES COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-233</section_number>
<catch_line>Composition and terms of membership.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000410</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-233. Composition and terms of membership.<section prefix='(a)'>The Council shall be composed of twenty-seven (27) members as follows: The Miami-Dade State Attorney; the Superintendent of Schools; the District Administrator of the State of Florida Department of Children and Families District XI; the Senior Juvenile Justice Manager of the State Department of Juvenile Justice, District XI; the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Health; the County Manager, seven (7) members, one (1) from each of the following organizations or agencies: A member of the Board of County Commissioners; a member of the Miami-Dade County School Board; a Judge assigned to the Juvenile Court Division of Florida's Eleventh Judicial Circuit; a member of the Miami-Dade Legislative Delegation; a representative of United Way; a representative from the Miami-Dade County PTA/PTSA; a representative from the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce; one (1) youth representative between the ages of fifteen (15) and twenty-two (22) years; and thirteen (13) members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No member appointed by the Board of County Commissioners or by a designated organization or agency shall serve more than three (3) consecutive and complete two-year terms. Of the initial Commission-appointed members, five (5) shall be appointed for two (2) years and four (4) shall be appointed for one (1) year. After the initial appointments, all terms shall be for two (2) years.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-50, § 1, 6-5-90; Ord. No. 90-108, § 1, 9-25-90; Ord. No. 95-83, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 97-54, § 1, 5-20-97; Ord. No. 99-40, § 1, 4-27-99)</history></law>