<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HEALTH FACILITIES AUTHORITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-263.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Refunding revenue bonds.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000446</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-263.4. Refunding revenue bonds.<section>The Authority is hereby authorized to provide for the issuance of revenue bonds for the purpose of refunding any of its revenue bonds then outstanding, including the payment of any redemption premium thereon and any interest accrued or to accrue to the earliest or subsequent date of redemption, purchase, or maturity of such revenue bonds. The proceeds of any such revenue bonds issued for the purpose of refunding outstanding revenue bonds may, in the discretion of the Authority, be applied to the purchase or retirement at maturity or redemption of such outstanding revenue bonds either on their earliest or any subsequent redemption date, or upon the purchase or at the maturity thereof, and may, pending such application, be placed in escrow to be applied to such purchase or retirement at maturity or redemption on such date as may be determined by the Authority. Any such escrowed proceeds, pending such use, may be invested and reinvested in direct obligations of the United States, in any obligations of which the principal and interest are unconditionally guaranteed by the United States, in certificates of deposit or time deposits secured by direct obligations of the United States, or in any obligations of which the principal and interest are unconditionally guaranteed by the United States, maturing at such time or times as shall be appropriate to assure the prompt payment, as to principal, interest, and redemption premium, if any, of the outstanding revenue bonds to be so refunded. The interest, income, and profits, if any, earned or realized on any such investment may also be applied to the payment of the outstanding revenue bonds to be so refunded. After the terms of the escrow have been fully satisfied and carried out, any balance of such proceeds and interest, income, and profits, if any, earned or realized on the investments thereof may be returned to the Authority for use by it in any lawful manner. All such revenue bonds issued for the purposes of refunding shall be subject to the provisions of this article in the same manner and to the same extent as other revenue bonds issued pursuant to this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-92, ยง 5(C), 10-16-79)</history></law>