<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HEALTH FACILITIES AUTHORITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-263.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Tax exemption; limitations on exemptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000448</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-263.6. Tax exemption; limitations on exemptions.<section>The exercise of the powers granted by this article will be in all respects for the benefit of the people of this County, for the increase of their commerce, welfare and prosperity, and for the improvement of their health and living conditions. Since the operation and maintenance of a project by a health facility will constitute the performance of an essential public function, neither the Authority nor a hospital institution shall be required to pay any taxes or assessments upon or with respect to a project or any property acquired by the Authority under the provisions of this article or upon the income therefrom, and any bonds issued under the provisions of this article, their transfer, and the income therefrom, including any profit made on the sale thereof, shall at all times be free from taxation of every kind by the State, Miami-Dade County, and municipalities and other political subdivisions in the State, except that such income shall be subject to the tax imposed pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 220, Florida Statutes. Nothing in this section shall be construed as exempting from taxation or assessments the leasehold interest of any health facility organized for profit. If any project or any part thereof shall be occupied or operated by any health facility organized for profit pursuant to any contract or lease with the Authority, the property interest created by such contract or lease shall be subject to taxation to the same extent as other privately owned property.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-92, ยง 7, 10-16-79)</history></law>