<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HEALTH FACILITIES AUTHORITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-263.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Administrative procedures for project evaluation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000443</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-263.1. Administrative procedures for project evaluation.<section>The Authority shall promulgate written administrative procedures, subject to final approval by the County Commission, that will be uniformly used to evaluate proposed projects. These administrative procedures shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Certificate of need; review by Health Council of South Florida, Inc. The Authority shall require a certificate of need for all new project applications as prescribed by Section 154.245, Florida Statutes, as said status may be amended from time to time, and in addition request a review and comment from the Health Council of South Florida, Inc., prior to acting on any applications for the issuance of revenue bonds for refinancing or refunding purposes. Comments received from the Health Council of South Florida, Inc., within thirty (30) days of request shall be considered by the Authority in making its decision on the application. If such comment has not been received thirty (30) days from the date of a formal written request, the Authority may act as though the application was favorably considered by the Health Council of South Florida, Inc.</section><section prefix='(2)'>[Reserved]</section><section prefix='(3)'>Service priorities. The guidelines shall include a priority for those institutions who currently provide or present a plan to provide services including, but not limited to:<section prefix='(a)'>Services rendered to patients eligible for all or partial County support in County-sponsored institutions; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Uncompensated services rendered under County/public health trust decentralization programs.</section><section>The services referred to in this paragraph shall be in addition to services mandated under the Hill-Burton program or other State or federally mandated programs.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Applicant expenses; review by County Manager or his designee. The applicant shall bear all costs and expenses incurred incident to the preparation of its application. The Authority shall provide for the timely review of each project by the County Manager in such a way as to minimize the expenditure of funds by the applicant should the review prove to be unfavorable. If the initial review is favorable, the applicant shall proceed with finalizing the bond issue for final approval by the Commission.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-92, § 6(A)—(C), (E), 10-16-79; Ord. No. 81-22, § 1, 3-3-81; Ord. No. 83-41, § 1, 6-21-83)</history></law>