<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='3'>ARTICLE XXX. COMMISSION FOR WOMEN</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-269</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and powers of the Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000455</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-269. Duties and powers of the Commission.<section>The Commission shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the County Commission, the County administration, the community, and all agencies and persons in Miami-Dade County, Florida, in respect to all matters pertaining to the status of women, including but not limited to discrimination against women, employment of women, education of women, establishment of day care centers in the community, and attitudes towards women in the community, and to make periodic reports and recommendations to these bodies in respect to such matters.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To make a continuing study of all existing County institutions, facilities and services, and programs dealing with women or affecting women, and consider the future needs of this metropolitan area in respect to such institutions, facilities, services and programs.</section><section prefix='(c)'>To serve as liaison between the County Commission and the County administration, and consult with representatives of said bodies from time to time as requested and necessary in order to carry out the Commission's duties and functions.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To make studies and have studies made of the problems of discrimination against women employees, increasing the availability of part-time employment for women, establishment of day care centers in the community, and attributable changes towards women in the community, and to formulate and recommend plans and programs for the coordination of the activities of all governmental entities and nongovernmental agencies dealing with these problems.</section><section prefix='(e)'>It is the express purpose of this Commission to serve as a medium for responsible persons to utilize and consult with in attempting to understand and solve the many complex problems involved with dealing with the status of women, and to make findings and recommendations to the County Commission and the County administration regarding such matters as are presented to the Commission.</section><section prefix='(f)'>To establish the Miami-Dade County Commission for Women Trust Fund (hereinafter referred to as "Trust Fund") in which will be placed all donations, contributions and funds received by the Commission for Women. The funds placed into the Trust Fund shall be used only to fund conferences, projects and special events which further the purposes of the Miami-Dade County Commission for Women.</section><section prefix='(g)'>To perform such other duties as may from time to time be assigned to it by resolution of the County Commission.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-11, ยง 6, 1-19-71; Ord. No. 92-85, ยง 1, 7-21-92; Ord. No. 92-121, ยง 1, 10-13-92; Ord. No. 99-35, ยง 4, 4-13-99)</history></law>