<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HEALTH FACILITIES AUTHORITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-261</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000440</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-261. Definitions.<section>The following terms, whenever used in this article, shall have the following meanings unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context:<section prefix='(a)'>Authority means the Miami-Dade County Health Facilities Authority.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Bonds or revenue bonds means revenue bonds of the Authority issued under the provisions of this article, including revenue refunding bonds, notwithstanding that the same may be secured by mortgage or the full faith and credit of a health facility.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Certificate of need means a written advisory statement issued by the [State] Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, having as its basis a written advisory statement issued by an areawide council and, where there is no council, by the [State] Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, evidencing community need for a new, converted, expanded, or otherwise significantly modified health facility.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Enabling act means Part III, Chapter 154, Florida Statutes, as maybe amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Health facility means any private corporation organized not for profit and authorized by law to provide hospital, adult congregate living or nursing home care services in accordance with Florida law.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Project means any structure, facility, machinery, equipment or other property suitable for use by a health facility in connection with its operations or proposed operations, including without limitation, real property therefor; a clinic, computer facility, dining hall, firefighting facility, fire prevention facility, food service and preparation facility, health-care facility, long-term care facility, hospital, interns' residence, laboratory, laundry, maintenance facility, nurses' residence, nursing home, nursing school, office, parking area, pharmacy, recreational facility, research facility, storage facility, utility, or X-ray facility, or any combination of the foregoing; and other structures or facilities related thereto or required or useful for health-care purposes, the conducting of research, or the operation of a health facility, including facilities or structures essential or convenient for the orderly conduct of such health facility and other similar items necessary or convenient for the operation of a particular facility or structure in the manner for which its use is intended. "Project" shall not include such items as fuel, supplies, or other items which are customarily deemed to result in a current operating charge.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Real property includes all lands, including buildings, structures, improvements, and fixtures thereon; any property of any nature appurtenant thereto or used in connection therewith; and every estate, interest, and right, legal or equitable, therein including any such interest for a term of years.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-92, ยง 2, 10-16-79; Ord. No. 89-132, ยง 1, 12-19-89)</history></law>