<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00044' order_by='00044' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXII. AVIATION DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-286.1</section_number>
<catch_line>County Manager's authority for retail activities at Miami International Airport.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000468</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-286.1. County Manager's authority for retail activities at Miami International Airport.<section prefix='(a)'>The County Manager shall implement retail activities (which shall be defined as including retail, food, and beverage products and services) at Miami International Airport envisioned in the Retail Concessions Master Plan, dated May 1995, as it may be administratively amended from time to time. Notwithstanding any other provisions of the Code, and notwithstanding any prior resolution or administrative order approved by the Board, including, but not limited to, Resolutions No. R. 1586-72 and 1587-72, and Administrative Orders No. 3-2, 3-4, and 3-16, the provisions of which resolutions and administrative orders are hereby waived, the County Manager shall have the following authority as to retail activities at the Airport:<section prefix='(1)'>Maintain close working relationships with the signatory air carriers at the Airport to obtain their input into the retail activities at the Airport, and execute amendments to airline agreements so as to permit negotiation of concessions at the Airport;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Issue invitations for bids, requests for qualifications, and requests for proposals for concessions, activities, services or goods related to retail activities at the Airport, provided, however, that to the extent permitted by state law and by contract, such invitations and requests in the discretion of the County Manager may be limited to retail or suppliers, including a single retailer or supplier, whom the County Manager determines will best meet the goals of the Retail Concessions Master Plan;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Enter into negotiations with a single retail concession provider, or competitive negotiations with two (2) or more retail concession providers, whom the County Manager in his discretion determines will best meet the goals of the Retail Concessions Master Plan. If the proposed concession will be exclusive, the County Manager is authorized to comply with all requirements of Section 125.012(17), Florida Statutes;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Negotiate and settle all claims arising out of the foregoing leases and concession agreements;</section><section prefix='(5)'>To the extent permitted by ordinance and other law, establish Disadvantaged Business Enterprise goals and set asides for concessions;</section><section prefix='(6)'>For any agreement with a concessionaire or tenant, authorize reimbursement or rental credit for construction and other costs for relocation of all or a portion of its premises, preparation of its premises for occupancy, and making changes or emergency repairs to the premises in any manner necessary or reasonably required to meet the requirements of the retail activities; provided that the concessionaire or tenant shall comply with the County's competitive bidding requirements, the essential requirements of Section 2-10.4, DBE contract measures, and any other directions provided by the County Manager;</section><section prefix='(7)'>For all the foregoing leases and concession agreements subject to Section 2-8.3 of the Code, waive the provisions of Section 2-8.3 to the extent provided in the solicitation documents;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Extend any concession, management agreement or agreement related to the retail activities on a month-to-month basis for so long as may be needed to avoid disruption of concession services to passengers, and</section><section prefix='(9)'>Delegate authority for execution of actions or authorizations permitted hereunder to the Aviation Director or his or her designee.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Manager may exempt from the County's classified service such Aviation Department employees as determined by the County Manager to be necessary or reasonably required for the efficient management or administration of retail activities at the Airport.</section><section prefix='(c)'>From the day on which any advertisement of a competitive contract is placed by the County Manager until the day the County Manager's notice of intent is filed with the Clerk, neither the bidder nor any one on its behalf shall have any contact with the County Manager, any County Commissioner, or any member of their staff, except for any person specifically designated by the County Manager in the contract documents or otherwise, or except in response to any inquiry or contact initiated by the County Manager.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-138, ยง 1, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 97-157, ยง 1, 9-23-97)</history></law>