<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. CULTURAL AFFAIRS COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-297</section_number>
<catch_line>Council meetings; public hearings; committees and advisors; reports; rules.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000476</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-297. Council meetings; public hearings; committees and advisors; reports; rules.<section prefix='(a)'>(1)All meetings shall be open to the public. Council meetings shall be held at least quarterly pursuant to notice and at such times and places as the Council shall determine. One-half of the Council membership, plus one (1), shall comprise a quorum for the transaction of business at Council meetings.<section prefix='(2)'>Continued and unexcused absence from Council meetings shall constitute cause for a member's removal from the Council, and replacement as provided for in subsection (b) of Section 2-293. Such action shall be taken only with approval of two-thirds of the remaining Council members.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Council shall hold at least one public hearing annually, pursuant to public notice specifying the date and place of hearing and the subjects to be considered, specifically for the purpose of making the Council's work known and investigating and assessing the needs and development of the arts and sciences in the County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Council may establish such working committees of Council members as it deems appropriate to carry out its purposes, objectives, duties and powers.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Council may convene such advisory panels and may consult with such advisors and experts as it deems necessary and appropriate for carrying out its objectives, duties and powers, and it shall initially establish and consult a professional advisory committee.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Council shall formulate and publish rules and regulations setting forth the criteria pursuant to which its financial aid is given, and such other rules regarding its activities as it deems appropriate.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Council shall annually file with the Board of County Commissioners a report summarizing its activities conducted during the preceding year and setting forth such recommendations, including recommendations with respect to present or proposed legislation, concerning State encouragement and support of the arts, as it considers appropriate. The Council's annual report, and such other reports as it deems appropriate, shall be made available to the public.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-34, ยง 7, 4-20-76)</history></law>