<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. CULTURAL AFFAIRS COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-291</section_number>
<catch_line>Miami-Dade County Cultural Affairs Council created; purpose; objectives.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000470</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-291. Miami-Dade County Cultural Affairs Council created; purpose; objectives.<section>There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County Cultural Affairs Council, hereinafter referred to as the Council, a part of the government of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for the purpose of developing, coordinating and promoting the performing and visual arts and the sciences, in Miami-Dade County, contracting for artistic services, performances, and exhibits, and developing physical facilities for the use of the arts and sciences, all for the enjoyment, education, cultural enrichment, and benefit of the citizens of Miami-Dade County. In furtherance of said purpose, the Council shall attempt to accomplish the following objectives:<section prefix='(1)'>Stimulate greater governmental and public awareness and appreciation of the importance of the arts and sciences to the people of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Encourage and implement greater and more efficient use of governmental and private resources for the development and support of the arts and sciences.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Encourage and implement opportunities for County residents to participate in artistic and scientific activities.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Promote the development of Miami-Dade County artists, scientists and institutions and community organizations sponsoring arts and science activities, and audiences.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Survey and assess the needs of the arts and sciences, and of the people of this County relating thereto and make such information promptly and regularly available to all interested agencies and persons upon request.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Support and implement the preservation and growth of the County's artistic and scientific resources.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Foster the development of a receptive climate for the arts and sciences to culturally enrich and benefit the citizens of Miami-Dade County in their daily lives, to make Miami-Dade County visits and vacations all the more appealing to the world and to attract to Miami-Dade County residency additional outstanding creators in the field of arts and sciences through appropriate programs of publicity, education, coordination and to sponsor activities such as the presentation of lectures and exhibitions and central compilation and dissemination of information on the progress of the arts and sciences in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Encourage and coordinate the artistic and scientific activities of other governmental agencies, including those concerned with the public educational system.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Provide Miami-Dade County cultural organizations with information and assistance.</section></section><section>The purposes and objectives provided by this section are hereby deemed to be public purposes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-34, ยง 1, 4-20-76; Ord. No. 87-34, ยง 1, 6-2-87)</history></law>