<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIB. CENTER FOR THE FINE ARTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-306</section_number>
<catch_line>Association; rights and obligations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000501</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-306. Association; rights and obligations.<section>The Association shall be responsible for funding all programming of the Center for the Fine Arts. The Board of County Commissioners may from time to time budget or grant funding support to the Association.<section prefix='(a)'>Admissions and charges. The Association may set and collect admissions rates and charges for entrance to the Center for the Fine Arts or any part thereof and may use the funds so collected as it may designate; provided, however, that at least one (1) day each week, admissions shall be free or on a voluntary donation basis and further provided, that the Board of County Commissioners shall approve the schedule of admissions charges as may be in effect from time to time.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Gift store. The Association shall have the exclusive right to sell merchandise inside the Center for the Fine Arts and to determine the identity and nature of items offered for sale. No partial assignment, concession, license, or sublease agreement for the gift shop may be entered into without the prior consent of the County regarding selection criteria and the identity of the assignee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Annual report. The Association shall report to the Board of County Commissioners, no less frequently than once each year, the Association budget and programming at the Center for the Fine Arts.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Books and records. The Association shall maintain books and records in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles. The Association shall furnish an audited accounting to the County within one hundred twenty (120) days after the close of each fiscal year. The County shall have the right to examine and to audit all Association books and records until three (3) years after such time as the Association may cease to exist.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-1, ยง 1, 1-20-87)</history></law>