<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00046' order_by='00046' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIA. SOUTH FLORIDA CULTURAL CONSORTIUM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-300.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000483</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-300.4. Powers.<section>The Consortium shall have the following powers which may be exercised without further approval of the governing body of any participating County:<section prefix='(a)'>To seek and accept in the name of the participating counties, federal, State, local or private gifts, grants, assistance, funds and bequests in the furtherance of its purposes;</section><section prefix='(b)'>To enter into contracts for commodities, goods and services, and into leases not exceeding one (1) year in duration and these contracts and leases shall bind the participating counties to the same extent as if entered into by those counties directly;</section><section prefix='(c)'>To expend or carry over budgeted sums to the succeeding fiscal year, provided that all expenditures and leases shall be in accordance with federal regulations, State law and the Miami-Dade County Charter, ordinances and procedures, and further provided that where Miami-Dade County ordinances and procedures require action by the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners, then action by the Consortium shall be required in lieu thereof, and where Miami-Dade County ordinances and procedures require action by the County Manager, then action by the Chair shall be required in lieu thereof;</section><section prefix='(d)'>To grant moneys in accordance with a formal program or programs which it shall develop; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>To acquire, operate, maintain, lease or sell any personal property subject to federal grant restrictions. At no time may the Consortium expend or commit more money in any fiscal year than it has received. The Consortium may sue and be sued in its own name; provided that each participating county shall bear an equal share of all liabilities incurred as a result of formal Consortium acts.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-26, ยง 1, 4-16-85)</history></law>