<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIB. CENTER FOR THE FINE ARTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-305</section_number>
<catch_line>Association.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000500</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-305. Association.<section prefix='(a)'>The Association, shall support the Center for the Fine Arts and shall foster community involvement in the Center for the Fine Arts' activities. The Association shall fund exhibitions and other programs at the Center for the Fine Arts for the advancement of public knowledge and appreciation of art and design. The Association shall actively interact with other components of the Miami-Dade Cultural Center to advance the cultural life and experience of the residents of and visitors to Miami-Dade County. With respect to the display of works and collections of art, the primary objective of the Association shall be the attraction to the Center of major art exhibitions loaned by other institutions and individuals. No permanent exhibition is contemplated. With respect to its other objectives, the Association shall conduct lectures, seminars and any other functions or operations appropriate for the dissemination of public knowledge and appreciation of art and shall promote the exchange of artists' aesthetic expressions, concepts and practices among the various academic, cultural, ethnic, religious and social groups within Miami-Dade County.</section><section>These objectives may be revised or restated by the Association trustees.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Neither the Board of Trustees nor any of its members shall direct the appointment of any person to, or his removal from, office by the Director or any of his subordinates. Except for the purpose of inquiry, the Board and its members shall deal with the Department employees solely through the Director, and neither the Board nor any of its members shall give orders to any Department employees either publicly or privately.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The bylaws of the Association shall provide that the Association shall hold the County and any individuals serving or employed by the County entirely harmless from and against any and all liabilities, damages, costs, expenses, causes of action, suits, claims, demands or judgments of any nature which arise from the negligent or deliberate acts or omissions of the Association, its officers, trustees, employees or agents; provided however, that this provision shall not apply to actions of or directed by any County employee.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Association is intended to reflect and be responsive to the cultural needs of the community. The Association should provide a broad source of community support for the Center for the Fine Arts, coordinating its private fund-raising activities and service of volunteers. To these ends, the bylaws and regulations of the Association shall encourage the membership of, and participation in the activities of the Association by, citizens of the diverse cultural, ethnic and artistic backgrounds in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Association shall establish a fiscal year which coincides with that of Miami-Dade County. Its budget in connection with the operations of the Center for the Fine Arts shall be balanced.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-1, ยง 1, 1-20-87)</history></law>