<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00049' order_by='00049' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIV. COMMISSION ON DISABILITY ISSUES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-316</section_number>
<catch_line>Prerogatives and powers of the Commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000508</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-316. Prerogatives and powers of the Commission.<section>The Commission shall have the following prerogatives and powers:<section prefix='(a)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners and, upon request, the County administration, the community, and all agencies and persons in Miami-Dade County, Florida, in respect to all matters pertaining to the status of persons with disabilities, including but not limited to discrimination against persons with disabilities, employment of persons with disabilities, vocational training for persons with disabilities, establishment of residential facilities in the community for persons with disabilities, transportation needs of persons with disabilities and attitudes towards persons with disabilities in the community, and to make reports and recommendations to these bodies in respect to such matters.</section><section prefix='(b)'>To serve as liaison between the Board of County Commissioners and persons with disabilities of the community, and to consult with representatives of said bodies from time to time as requested and necessary in order to carry out the Commission's functions.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When feasible and desirable, to institute studies and to have studies made of all existing County institutions, facilities, services and programs dealing with or affecting persons with disabilities, and to consider the future needs of Miami-Dade County in respect to such institutions, facilities, services and programs.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To institute studies and to have studies made in respect to, but not limited to, discrimination against persons with disabilities in employment, education, transportation, and architecture; the problems involving the establishment of a residential center for persons with disabilities; the treatment, recreational service and other facilities for persons with disabilities; and the problems of attitudinal barriers toward persons with disabilities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To formulate and recommend plans and programs for the coordination of the activities of all governmental entities and nongovernmental agencies dealing with problems of persons with disabilities.</section><section prefix='(f)'>To serve as a resource facility to persons with disabilities and to those interested in advancing the welfare of persons with disabilities.</section><section prefix='(g)'>To seek and accept appropriations or funds from interested persons and entities in order to carry out studies and activities for the advancement of persons with disabilities.</section><section prefix='(h)'>To perform any other activities as may from time to time be assigned to the Commission by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(i)'>To prepare and submit an annual report on the studies and activities of the Commission to the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-23, ยง 6, 4-19-77; Ord. No. 02-133, ยง 6, 7-23-02)</history></law>