<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00049' order_by='00049' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIV. COMMISSION ON DISABILITY ISSUES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-314</section_number>
<catch_line>Appointments and terms of office.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000506</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-314. Appointments and terms of office.<section>All appointments to the Commission shall be for a term which begins on the day of appointment and expires when the appointing Commissioner's term of office expires or the appointing Commissioner leaves office. A Commissioner who has appointed a Commission member may at any time, with or without cause, remove the member. A member of the Commission may be removed pursuant to the provisions of any general county ordinance relating to advisory boards or by the Board of County Commissioners when the member's absenteeism is generally excessive or the continued membership of the individual would be detrimental to the Commission on Disability Issues as determined by a majority of that Commission. The Commission on Disability Issues will make its determination by a formal motion and vote and the chairperson shall certify said vote to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners who shall place the matter on the next available agenda.</section><section>When any vacancy occurs on the Commission, the remaining members of the Commission shall recommend up to three (3) persons to the Commissioner responsible for recommending an appointment to that vacancy. That Commissioner shall either recommend to the Board of County Commissioners one of the individuals on the list or the commissioner shall request a new list of three (3) people either including or excluding, at the Commissioner's discretion, specific names from the original list. The Board of County Commissioners shall fill the vacancy from the names submitted.</section><section>Terms of office for CODI members shall run from the day of appointment by the Commission and expire when the appointing Commissioner's term of office expires or the appointing Commissioner leaves office. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, no member shall serve more than a cumulative total of eight (8) years on the Commission unless reappointed after a hiatus of two (2) years. If a seat remains vacant for more than thirty (30) days then any Commissioner may fill the vacancy. The positions vacated or expiring shall be filled by the Board of County Commissioners in the manner stated above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-23, ยง 4, 4-19-77; Ord. No. 79-90, ยง 3, 10-16-79; Ord. No. 94-04, ยง 4, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 02-133, ยง 4, 7-23-02)</history></law>