<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00053' order_by='00053' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI-DADE WATER AND SEWER DEPARTMENT AND ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-346</section_number>
<catch_line>Audit Review Committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000525</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-346. Audit Review Committee.<section prefix='(a)'>An Audit Review Committee is to be established composed of any or all of the following persons designated by the City of Miami: City Manager or designated representative; City Internal Auditor or designated representative; Director of Finance or designated representative; Public Works Director or designated representative; five (5) members of the public to be appointed by the City Commission.</section><section prefix='(b)'>This Committee will perform a review of the annual budget, finances and operation of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department to ensure that all Department funds remain segregated from the general funds of Miami-Dade County and that all proceeds received by the Department are used for the operation, maintenance and improvement of the water and sewer system of Miami-Dade County, including administrative overhead billed by other County departments.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The review will be performed within the months of April through June of each year.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The findings of the Committee shall be reported to both the City Manager and County Manager for presentation by each Manager to their respective Boards of Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department will provide to each member of the Audit Review Committee information normally furnished to bondholders, other interested parties and any other information as shall be requested by the Board relevant to the performance of the review.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Committee shall have such staff support from the Department as they may reasonably require to perform their responsibilities.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 86-8, §§ 1—6, 2-4-86)</history></law>