<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00054' order_by='00054' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVIII. IMPOSITION OF MORATORIUM ON EXECUTION OF WATER SUPPLY CONTRACTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-359</section_number>
<catch_line>Application to County Manager for issuance of administrative order; denial of order or failure of Manager to act on application; application to Board of County Commissioners; determination as to necessity of public hearing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000541</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-359. Application to County Manager for issuance of administrative order; denial of order or failure of Manager to act on application; application to Board of County Commissioners; determination as to necessity of public hearing.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person, as defined herein, shall be entitled to make written application to the County Manager for issuance of an administrative order provided for by Section 2-350 herein. Should such an application be made and denied by the County Manager or should the Manager fail to take action thereon within thirty (30) days, such person may make written application to the Board of County Commissioners for the issuance of a water contract moratorium by that Board. Such application to the Board shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, whose duty it shall be to place the matter before the Board of County Commissioners as soon as is reasonably practicable for the Board's determination as to whether a public hearing shall be called thereon. The County Manager shall be notified by the Clerk that the matter is to be considered by the Board. The word "person" as used in this section includes, but is not limited to, any individual, firm, corporation, governmental or private entity, including any County department, Board, agency or authority.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Should the Board determine that a public hearing should be held as to whether a water contract moratorium is appropriate, it shall call the same for the earliest practicable date and give reasonable notice thereof by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. Pending the public hearing, the Board may issue an order prohibiting the execution of water contracts in the affected area.</section><section>The procedure to be followed for the purposes of this section after the completion of the steps provided in Sections and above, is that set forth in Sections through of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-31, §§ 10, 11, 5-7-75; Ord. No. 83-92, § 4, 10-4-83)</history></law>