<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XLI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY TRAUMA ADVISORY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-392</section_number>
<catch_line>Terms and conditions of membership.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000558</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-392. Terms and conditions of membership.<section prefix='(a)'>The Committee shall be composed of twenty-nine (29) voting members appointed to staggered two-year terms pursuant to resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. Two (2) members shall be active in organizations that support the interests of consumers; and two (2) members shall be appointed as governmental representatives from Monroe County, Florida, such appointments to be the Project Director of the Upper Keys Health Care Taxing District and the Director of the Public Safety Division of Monroe County. Additionally, the Public Health Trust Trauma Committee and the Miami-Dade Fire Board shall each appoint one nonvoting ex officio member to the Miami-Dade County Trauma Advisory Committee. Each member shall serve a two-year term; provided, however, that of the initial Committee members, twelve (12) members shall be appointed for one-year terms. No member of the Committee shall be permitted to serve more than three (3) consecutive and complete terms. Section 2-11.38.2 of the Miami-Dade County Code shall govern terms of membership on the Committee.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Prior to the annual expiration date of members' terms, the County Manager shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners a recommended list of individuals to serve on the Committee, which said list may be augmented by individual County Commissioners. This list shall be in compliance with the requirements of Sections 2-11.38 and 2-11.38.1 of the Miami-Dade County. The list shall be broad-based and shall include a representative selection of individuals who have demonstrated familiarity with and interest in issues relating to the provision of trauma care. Each individual on the list shall have a reputation for integrity and service to the citizens of Miami-Dade County. In the event that the Board does not approve a sufficient number of recommendations from the list to fill available positions on the Committee, the County Manager shall provide the Board with additional recommendations until such time as all the available positions are filled. All vacancies occurring on the Committee shall be filled in the same manner either at the time of the annual appointment process or at a time specifically set by the Board.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any member of the Committee who fails to meet the requirements of Section 2-11.38 or 2-11.39 of the Miami-Dade County Code shall immediately forfeit membership on the Committee, unless said requirements are waived as provided. Any member of the Committee may be removed from office by two-thirds vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation. The Board of County Commissioners may provide funds for appropriate and necessary expenses incurred by the Committee or any of its members in the performance of Committee functions; provided, however, that no such funds will be expended without prior approval of the Board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-84, ยง 2, 9-6-88; Ord. No. 89-14, ยง 1, 3-7-89; Ord. No. 90-75, ยง 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 91-86, ยง 1, 7-23-91)</history></law>