<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='3'>ARTICLE XLII. TRANSPORTATION, INFRASTRUCTURE AND CONCURRENCY TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-395.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization of the Task Force; voting, quorum; conduct of meetings; compensation of members; staff support.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000563</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-395.2. Organization of the Task Force; voting, quorum; conduct of meetings; compensation of members; staff support.<section prefix='(a)'>The voting members of the Task Force, by majority vote, shall adopt a schedule of regular meetings. A majority of the voting members of the Task Force shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold meetings or take any action. No recommendation shall be forwarded nor any action taken unless first approved by a majority of a quorum attending a Task Force meeting. Special meetings of the Task Force may be called by the Chairperson or upon the written request of five (5) Task Force members. All meetings of the Task Force shall be public and written minutes shall be maintained. Each meeting of the Task Force shall be advertised, no less than seven (7) days in advance of any such meeting, in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. The public shall be invited to provide comment at each meeting concerning items on the official agenda for the meeting. Members of the Task Force shall serve without compensation, but the Board of County Commissioners may approve expenses or a budget for the reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by the Task Force in the performance of its duties.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Manager and County Attorney shall provide adequate clerical, administrative and technical personnel for the purpose of assisting the Task Force in the performance of its duties and functions, subject to budget limitations as fixed by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-34, ยง 2, 3-19-91)</history></law>