<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XLI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY TRAUMA ADVISORY COMMITTEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-394</section_number>
<catch_line>Functions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000560</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-394. Functions.<section prefix='(a)'>The Committee, in conjunction with the County Manager's office, shall advise the Board of County Commissioners and shall make recommendations with respect to establishment and implementation of Miami-Dade County's overall plans for the care of victims of trauma. The Committee's recommendations shall be in the areas of:<section prefix='(1)'>Coordination with all public and private entities and organizations which are concerned with provision of trauma care;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Formulation of legislative, programmatic and funding agendas needed to address present and future trauma care needs of the community;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Establishment of suggested administrative and medical policies and protocols to enhance the efficiency and quality of trauma care;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Overseeing the development of the State mandated trauma medical services plan;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Performance of any other advisory function assigned to the Committee by the Board.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Committee is advisory only and shall not have the power or authority to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies to any policies, to incur any financial obligation or to create any liability, contractual or otherwise, on the part of the County or any of its agencies.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Chairman, or his designee, shall present to the Board of County Commissioners on an annual basis a written report describing the Committee's activities. The Chairman, or his designee, may also appear as needed before the Board to present any matters pertinent to the Committee's concerns.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-84, ยง 4, 9-6-88)</history></law>