<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='3'>ARTICLE XLII. TRANSPORTATION, INFRASTRUCTURE AND CONCURRENCY TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-395.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000565</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-395.4. Duties and powers.<section prefix='(a)'>The Task Force shall advise the Board of County Commissioners on all matters pertaining to transportation facilities and services, as well as other public facilities and services, necessary for sound and orderly land development and infilling, with particular emphasis on matters pertaining to the formulation and coordination of public and private efforts to provide transportation facilities and services, as well as other public facilities and services, that will best enhance the quality of life for the County's present and future residents and visitors. The Task Force shall hold public hearings to elicit community input for the purpose of carrying out its duties. The Task Force shall make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners relative to:<section prefix='(1)'>Coordinating with public and private entities which are concerned with providing transportation facilities and other public facilities and services concurrent with the impacts of development and infilling necessitating those facilities and services;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Formulating referenda, as well as legislative, programmatic and funding plans and priorities, for addressing present and future transportation and other infrastructure component needs, including, without limitation, revenue streams, tax benefit districts, an expressway authority, as well as cost-saving operation and maintenance considerations and other cost-saving measures;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Reviewing compliance with State and regional laws, judicial decrees, administrative orders, rules and policies applicable to transportation, growth management and concurrency; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Performing any other advisory function in connection with transportation, infrastructure and growth management which may be assigned to the Task Force by any member of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Task Force is advisory only and shall not have the power to commit Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies to any policies, to incur any financial obligation, or to create any lability, contractual or otherwise, on the part of Miami-Dade County or any of its agencies.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Chairperson of the Task Force, or designee, shall deliver to the Board of County Commissioners:<section prefix='(1)'>A first interim written report no later than sixty (60) days after the effective date of this ordinance, presenting the preliminary findings and recommendations of the Task Force;</section><section prefix='(2)'>A second interim written report no later than one hundred and eighty (180) days after the effective date of this ordinance, presenting further findings and recommendations of the Task Force; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>A third interim written report within one (1) year of the effective date of this ordinance describing an implementation and action plan;</section><section prefix='(4)'>A final written report within two (2) years of the effective date of this ordinance, presenting an overview of the subject matter and commenting on the effectiveness of the implementation and action plan.</section></section><section>The Chairperson, or designee, may also appear as needed before the Board of County Commissioners to present any matters pertinent to the concerns of the Task Force. The interim reports and the final report may be accompanied by separate comments from the ex officio members of the Task Force concerning any of the findings and recommendations contained in such reports.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-34, ยง 2, 3-19-91)</history></law>