<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='3'>ARTICLE XLII. TRANSPORTATION, INFRASTRUCTURE AND CONCURRENCY TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-395.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Appointment of members; terms; qualifications for membership.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000562</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-395.1. Appointment of members; terms; qualifications for membership.<section prefix='(a)'>With the exception of not more than one member who shall represent the transit dependent or transit users, all members of the Task Force shall possess expertise in transportation (both public and private), engineering, banking, finance, urban planning, environmental protection, construction, trades, law or other disciplines related to designing, planning or funding of transportation facilities, other capital improvements and other infrastructure components necessary to meet the demands created by growth.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Task Force shall be composed of a maximum of eleven (11) voting members. Each member of the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint one (1) voting member; however each Commissioner may appoint an alternate who shall be entitled to participate and vote in the absence of the voting member.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Mayor may only appoint two (2) additional voting members to achieve a more representative ethnic balance of the community on the Task Force.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Mayor shall designate a Chairperson from the voting membership of the Task Force.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The voting members of the Transportation Planning Council of the Metropolitan Planning Organization for the Miami Urbanized Area, the Executive Director of the Metropolitan Planning Organization, the Executive Director of the South Florida Regional Planning Council and the County Manager shall be nonvoting, ex officio members of the Task Force. The ex officio members shall participate on the Task Force as resource members and may provide written comments pertaining to any recommendations adopted by the Task Force.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Task Force shall continue in existence for a term of two (2) years from the effective date of this ordinance, at which time the Task Force shall issue a final report and then be dissolved.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-34, ยง 2, 3-19-91)</history></law>