<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='3'>ARTICLE XLIV. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY ADDICTION SERVICES BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-422</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; qualifications; terms.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000574</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-422. Membership; qualifications; terms.<section prefix='(a)'>This Board shall consist of eighteen (18) members appointed by the County Commission in a manner set forth below. Each member of the Board shall be a resident and elector of Miami-Dade County and shall have an outstanding reputation for integrity, responsibility, and commitment to serving the community.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Nine (9) of the members shall be appointed from the public sector and nine (9) of the members shall be appointed from the private sector. In filling any "private sector" seat, the County Commission shall select from a list to be submitted by The Miami Coalition for a Drug-Free Community. The "public-sector" members appointed by the Board of County Commissioners shall include the following:<section prefix='(1)'>A State HRS administrator;</section><section prefix='(2)'>A representative of the State Attorney's Office;</section><section prefix='(3)'>A member of the Circuit Court of the 11th Judicial Circuit;</section><section prefix='(4)'>A representative from the Public Defender's Office;</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Superintendent of Schools, or the Superintendent's designee;</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Director of the Miami-Dade Department of Human Resources or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix='(7)'>The Director of Miami-Dade Police Department or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix='(8)'>The County Manager or the Manager's designee;</section><section prefix='(9)'>The Chief of Police of the City of Miami or the Chief's designee.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>All private sector members shall be appointed for terms of three (3) years. The public sector members shall be permanent appointments. Appointments to fill any vacancy of a private sector member shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Each member shall be eligible for reappointment and shall hold office until his or her successor is duly appointed and qualified.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If any member of the Board fails to attend three (3) consecutive meetings without due cause, the Chairperson shall certify the same to the County Commission, and such member shall then be deemed to have been removed and a vacancy created.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The members shall serve without compensation. The County Commission or other sources may provide funds for appropriate and necessary expenses incurred by the Board or any of its members in the performance of Board functions; provided, however, that no County funds will be expended without prior approval of the County Commission.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-144, ยง 2, 12-18-90; Ord. No. 92-93, ยง 1, 9-15-92)</history></law>