<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='3'>ARTICLE XLIV. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY ADDICTION SERVICES BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-424</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000576</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-424. Duties and powers.<section>The Board shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:<section prefix='(1)'>To assist in the establishment, operation and oversight of a central intake system providing twenty-four-hour access to addiction therapy.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners, the County Manager, and the community concerning substance abuse prevention and treatment services in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To make a continuous study and review of all existing substance abuse prevention and treatment services, both public and private, in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To make recommendations on the administration and distribution of monies directed to substance abuse prevention and treatment services from all sources.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To make recommendations on the administration and distribution of nondesignated trust funds held for substance abuse prevention and treatment services in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(6)'>To make recommendations on the coordination, organization, utilization, and implementation of substance abuse prevention and treatment services in Miami-Dade County as well as public education as to the addiction problems faced by Miami-Dade County and as to the substance abuse prevention and treatment services available to the County.</section><section prefix='(7)'>To work with the existing governmental providers of treatment and care as well as those providers in the private sector, and to make recommendations to these groups regarding the needs of Miami-Dade County for treatment programs and facilities.</section><section prefix='(8)'>To recommend to the Manager and the Board of County Commissioners such ordinances as will aid in carrying out the purposes of this article.</section><section prefix='(9)'>To submit an annual report to the Manager and the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(10)'>To accept grants and donations on behalf of the County from foundations and others for the purpose of carrying out the above listed functions, subject to approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(11)'>To perform such other duties as may from time to time be assigned to it by the Board of County Commissioners or that are reasonable, necessary or proper to the exercise of the powers and duties enumerated above.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-144, ยง 4, 12-18-90; Ord. No. 02-81, ยง 1, 5-21-02)</history></law>