<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='3'>ARTICLE XLVII. COMMISSION AUDITOR</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-473</section_number>
<catch_line>Auditor selection process.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000582</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-473. Auditor selection process.<section>The selection process shall be open and competitive and shall include, at a minimum, the following:<section prefix='1.'>Establishment of an Ad Hoc Auditor Screening Committee ("Auditor Screening Committee"), appointed by the Commission and responsible for the screening and preliminary interviewing of candidates. The Auditor Screening Committee shall be composed of five members appointed by the Commission and selected as follows:<section prefix='a.'>Two members, preferably certified public accountants, from either a private sector accounting firm or other governmental agency with experience in accounting and financial management operations.</section><section prefix='b.'>Two members from either private sector or non-profit organizations with executive experience and a background in program evaluation; and</section><section prefix='c.'>One member who is not an elected official.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>The Miami-Dade County Employee Relations Department shall advertise the availability of the position of Commission Auditor and shall provide the Auditor Screening Committee with a list of qualified candidates.</section><section prefix='3.'>The Auditor Screening Committee shall screen, interview and evaluate applicants for the position of Commission Auditor, and propose a slate of the top five candidates for the Commission's consideration. The Auditor Screening Committee shall be staffed by the Employee Relations Department.</section><section prefix='4.'>The Commission shall interview and select the Commission Auditor from the slate presented by the Auditor Screening Committee.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-2, ยง 3, 1-23-03)</history></law>