<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='3'>ARTICLE XLVII. COMMISSION AUDITOR</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-477</section_number>
<catch_line>Scope of Authority.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000586</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-477. Scope of Authority.<section>The Commission Auditor shall, to the extent provided for in the annual work program, perform the following functions and be charged with the following responsibilities on behalf of the Commission:<section prefix='1.'>To determine the extent to which legislative policies are being faithfully, efficiently and effectively implemented by the County Manager and County personnel;</section><section prefix='2.'>To determine whether County programs are achieving their desired objectives;</section><section prefix='3.'>To review both the administrative control and executive control systems as established by the County Manager and departmental personnel, and to determine whether such control systems are adequate and effective in accomplishing their objectives;</section><section prefix='4.'>To perform audits provided for in Section 2-476</section><section prefix='5.'>To give information to the Commission whenever required regarding any subject relating to the affairs of the County;</section><section prefix='6.'>To offer input throughout the budgetary process;</section><section prefix='7.'>To review the reasonableness of all revenue estimates included in the Mayor's and Manager's proposed budgets;</section><section prefix='8.'>To review all departmental budgets and perform an analysis of the Manager's and Mayor's proposed budgets and make recommendations to the Commission regarding adjustments to the proposed budgets;</section><section prefix='9.'>To prepare a budget for the County if requested by the Commission;</section><section prefix='10.'>To make periodic reports to the Commission which shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='a.'>To determine whether departments, agencies and entities of the County have complied with the fiscal and legislative policies of the Commission;</section><section prefix='b.'>To provide information on proposals that could adversely affect the County including, but not limited to, the County's credit rating;</section><section prefix='c.'>To report matters and make recommendations concerning the effectiveness and efficiency of programs and the operation of the County;</section><section prefix='d.'>To be empowered to take exception to improper specific expenditures incurred by any County department, agency or entity; and</section></section><section prefix='11.'>The Commission Auditor shall serve as a voting member of any competitive selection committee convened for the purpose of recommending an external auditor to the County Manager. The Commission Auditor shall also be apprised by the County Manager of the activities of the external auditor and may monitor the conduct of, and responses to, external financial statement audits, and the resolution of audit findings. The Commission Auditor shall also work toward the elimination of duplicative audit work through cooperation with state, federal and external auditors, and the Clerk of the Circuit and County Courts when the Clerk is performing as auditor under Article V, Section 16 of the Florida Constitution and general laws of the State of Florida.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-2, ยง 7, 1-23-03)</history></law>