<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='3'>ARTICLE XLVIII. MIAMI-DADE ECONOMIC ADVOCACY TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-505</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization; staff support.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000596</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-505. Organization; staff support.<section prefix='(a)'>Organization. The Board of Trustees shall organize after the members have qualified to serve and shall elect one of its voting members as Chairperson, one of its voting members as Vice-Chairperson and such other officers as the Board of Trustees may determine to be necessary. In addition, the Board of Trustees shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Employees. The Executive Director and all employees of the Trust shall be Miami-Dade County employees. The Board of Trustees shall submit the names of nominee(s) for the position of Executive Director to the County Manager. The Manager shall make a recommendation from the nominee(s) proposed by the Trust to the Board of County Commissioners for its approval. The Trust shall have the power to remove the Executive Director.</section><section>The Board of Trustees shall submit the names of nominee(s) for the position of Executive Director to the County Manager. The Manager shall make a recommendation from the nominee(s) proposed by the Trust to the Board of County Commissioners for its approval. The Trust shall have the power to remove the Executive Director.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Staff support. The County Attorney shall serve as Attorney for the Trust, the County Manager shall provide audit, budget and financial assistance to the Trust, and the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall be the Clerk and Secretary of the Trust.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall provide to the Trust fiscal review and oversight as well as programmatic focus and direction.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Trust shall present quarterly financial reports, including a current statement of all accounts, to the Commission Auditor and the County Manager. Copies of said reports shall be provided to the Board of County Commissioners. Said reports shall also include information concerning an assessment of the performance of each agency funded by the Trust as well as those program activities carried out directly by the Trust. In addition to these quarterly reports, the Trust shall submit annual reports to the County Manager and the Commission Auditor summarizing and evaluating all programs and activities undertaken by the Trust during the previous fiscal year. The annual report shall include an audit in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles of all funds received and expended by the Trust. The Trust shall not be able, however, to establish any bank accounts without the express approval of either the Board of County Commissioners or the County Manager; provided, however, that the Trust can establish an account for Miami-Dade Community Foundation monies to receive and expend non-County monies which the Trust receives. No County monies nor income from County accounts shall be deposited into external accounts. The Trust shall be subject to periodic reviews as deemed necessary by the County Mayor, the Board of County Commissioners, the Department of Audit and Management Services and the Office of Strategic Business Management. In the event that these reviews reveal management problems, as determined by the reviewing entity, then the County Mayor, after the approval of the Board of County Commissioners, may place the Trust on Management Watch. If the Trust is placed on Management Watch, the Mayor shall present a plan to the Board of County Commissioners which provides timelines for removal of the Trust from Management Watch. The Board of County Commissioners shall have the authority to remove the Trust from Management Watch.</section><section>The Trust, in addition to providing quarterly financial reports, shall submit to the Board an annual Report Card on the State of the Black Community in Miami-Dade County. The report card shall include information on factors such as, but not limited to, the unemployment rate, the rates of business ownership, graduation rates, and homeownership rates within Miami-Dade County's Black community. The report card shall be presented to the Board and to the community.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Subject to the Miami-Dade County budgetary process and the availability of funds, the County will include in its annual budget funds for administrative costs and additional funds for programmatic activities. Requests for administrative and programmatic funds are to be made in accordance with the procedures described in Section 2-506(i). The County Manager is directed to include his recommendation for administrative and programmatic funding for the Trust in the annual proposed budget.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-12, ยง 5, 2-18-92; Ord. No. 01-01, ยง 1, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 08-86, ยง 3, 7-1-08)</history></law>