<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='3'>ARTICLE XLVIII. MIAMI-DADE ECONOMIC ADVOCACY TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-506</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties of the Trust.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000597</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-506. Powers and duties of the Trust.<section>The Trust, acting through its governing body, shall be authorized to exercise such powers and shall be required to perform such duties as are hereinafter provided:<section prefix='(a)'>Every five (5) years, the Trust shall establish a five-year comprehensive plan (hereinafter "the plan"). The plan shall contain one-year goals and objectives, the completion of which shall be needed to accomplish the comprehensive plan. The first plan shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for approval.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Trust shall be empowered to expend administrative and programmatic resources to achieve each of its one-year goals and objectives as well as to accomplish and complete each five-year plan.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The Trust shall identify and develop a variety of alternative funding sources and shall seek and apply for State, federal and private grants, including but not limited from philanthropic and non-tax based sources.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Trust shall serve as an advocate for and providing of the economic conditions and economic development initiatives in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Trust shall submit to the Board an annual scorecard that reflects the performance of those entities, (both public and private) charged with and funded to improve conditions in blighted communities.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Trust shall conduct a disparity study that examines the present economic conditions of Blacks in Miami-Dade County. This study shall be conducted every ten (10) years and submitted to the Board.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Trust, as an agent and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County, shall be authorized to act for Miami-Dade County in the performance and enforcement of all contracts and, subsequent to the effective date of this chapter and subject to the limitations set forth below, shall additionally be empowered to negotiate and execute such contracts as are properly within the powers and duties of the Trust. However, the Trust shall not without the prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, enter into or amend any contract which shall require the expenditure of funds in excess of the amounts appropriated to the trust by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The Trust shall comply with the formal bid requirements of Section 4.03(D) of the Charter of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and for such purpose the term "board" as used in Section 4.03(D) shall be construed to be "board of trustees" and the term "manager" shall be construed to be executive director of the Trust.</section><section>For all construction contracts, the trust shall comply with the provisions of of the County Code and the administrative procedures adopted pursuant to said section.</section><section>For all purchases of commodities and services, the trust shall comply with the provisions of of the County Code and the administrative procedures adopted pursuant to said section.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The Trust's budget requests shall be prepared and submitted in the same manner as the budget for a County department and will be considered as part of the Miami-Dade County budget process. The Trust's budget requests shall be prepared in a format prescribed by the County Manager.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-12, ยง 6, 2-18-92; Ord. No. 93-12, ยง 1, 2-16-93; Ord. No. 01-01, ยง 1, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 09-70, ยง 4, 9-1-09)</history></law>