<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00065' order_by='00065' level='3'>ARTICLE XLIX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY INDIGENT HEALTH CARE TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-522</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; appointment; terms; removal.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000603</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-522. Membership; appointment; terms; removal.<section prefix='(a)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall, by resolution, appoint ten (10) members to the task force in a manner set forth below.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The membership shall consist of a community service agency representative and a representative from each of the following organizations:<section>Miami-Dade County Public Health Trust</section><section>Miami-Dade Legislative Delegation</section><section>Miami-Dade County Medical Association</section><section>South Florida Hospital Association</section><section>Primary Health Care Consortium</section><section>Health Council of South Florida</section><section>Miami-Dade League of Cities</section><section>Miami-Dade County Chapter of the National Medical Association</section><section>Miami-Dade County Bar Association</section></section><section>In addition, the County Commission shall appoint an alternate for each member who shall be empowered to vote in the absence of the representative.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Initial appointment and tenure. The ten (10) members and ten (10) alternates representative of the foregoing organizations, presently serving on the task force pursuant to Resolution Nos. 549-91 and 319-92, shall constitute the initial appointment. These members and alternates shall hold office until the task force expires pursuant to Section 2-525 below or until his or her successor is duly appointed and qualified.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Attendance requirements for members shall be in accordance with Section 2-11.39 of this Code. If a member appointed to represent a category listed in subsection (b) above loses such representative status, fails to maintain the qualifications for membership set forth in Section 2-11.38 of this Code, fails to maintain attendance requirements, voluntarily resigns, or for other good cause is removed, the member shall forfeit membership on the task force and the designated alternate shall replace that member and the County Commission shall appoint a new alternate.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The members shall serve without compensation. The County Commission or other sources may provide funds for appropriate and necessary expenses incurred by the task force or any of its members in performance of task force functions, provided that no County funds will be expended without prior approval of the County Commission.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-40, ยง 2, 5-19-92)</history></law>