<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00065' order_by='00065' level='3'>ARTICLE XLIX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY INDIGENT HEALTH CARE TASK FORCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-524</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties and powers of the task force.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000605</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-524. Duties and powers of the task force.<section>The task force shall have the following duties, functions, powers and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>The task force shall prepare recommendations to the County Commission addressing the following issues:<section prefix='(1)'>Reducing or limiting the liability exposure for registered volunteer health care providers that provide services to medically indigent patients whose treatment would otherwise be rendered by the Public Health Trust; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Developing a voucher system, reimbursement program or other financial arrangement that will allow private hospitals to recover the reasonable costs of rendering secondary level support services to those medically indigent patients that would otherwise be treated at Jackson Memorial Hospital. This program or arrangement would be available to registered volunteer physicians and other health care providers and staff physicians of the Public Health Trust.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The task force may review and comment on other indigent health care issues.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities set forth above, the task force may utilize a strategic planning process and shall meet with and receive input from other groups and agencies involved in health care planning.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The task force shall, on behalf of the above-referenced groups, present recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners regarding areas of indigent health care where the combined efforts of the public and private health care providers would be appropriate and cost effective.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-40, ยง 4, 5-19-92)</history></law>