<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='3'>ARTICLE LI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HIV HEALTH SERVICES PLANNING COUNCIL.</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-553</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000616</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-553. Organization.<section prefix='(a)'>The council shall elect a chairperson and vice-chairperson from among its members, who shall serve at the will of the council. The chairperson and vice-chairperson shall not personally provide or represent entities that provide HIV-related health care services subject to funding under the Ryan White Act. The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The vice-chairperson shall act as chairperson in the absence or inability of the chairperson.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The council shall have assistance from staff designated by the county manager and legal representation from the county attorney's office. The staff shall maintain and keep the records of the council; prepare, in cooperation with the chairperson, the agenda for each meeting; be responsible for the preparation of such reports, minutes, documents, resolutions or correspondence as the council may direct; and generally administer the business and affairs of the council, subject to budgetary limitations.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In order to transact any business or to exercise any power vested in the council, a quorum consisting of no less than thirteen (13) members shall be present.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The council shall not transact business or exercise its powers unless a majority of the quorum in attendance agrees to the activity. The chairperson or five (5) council members upon written request to the chairperson may call for a special meeting.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The council may appoint committees to accomplish its tasks, and may appoint as committee members individuals who are not council members.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-100, ยง 3, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 94-206, ยง 1, 11-1-94)</history></law>