<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00068' order_by='00068' level='3'>ARTICLE LII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON GROUND TRANSPORTATION REGULATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-582</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; organization; terms; rules.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000622</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-582. Membership; organization; terms; rules.<section>Committee members shall be appointed by resolution of the County Commission from among nominees recommended by the Community Affairs Committee and shall consist of the following:<section>One (1) member — who is a user of such ground transportation system;</section><section>One (1) member — who is a member of the private school bus industry;</section><section>One (1) member — who is a member or the non-emergency medical transportation industry;</section><section>One (1) member — who is a user of the Special Transportation Services (STS);</section><section>One (1) member — who is a member of the tourism industry;</section><section>One (1) member — who is the holder of a Miami-Dade County certificate of transportation to operate a passenger motor carrier;</section><section>One (1) member — who is a holder of a Miami-Dade County for-hire taxi license;</section><section>One (1) member — who is a holder of a Miami-Dade County for-hire limousine license;</section><section>One (1) member — who is a taxi driver who does not own or have any interest in a Miami-Dade County for-hire taxi license;</section><section>One (1) member — who is a representative of the Miami-Dade County League of Cities; and</section><section>One (1) member — who is a representative of a management company supplying services to taxis operated in Miami-Dade County; and</section><section>Four (4) members — each of whom has a background or a concern in ground transportation issues.</section></section><section>Committee members shall serve without compensation. The committee shall elect a chairperson and vice-chairperson from among its members. The committee shall have the power to develop and adopt rules to govern its internal procedures and operation.</section><section>The fifteen (15) members, including the chairperson and vice-chairperson, presently serving on the advisory committee pursuant to Resolution No. R.127-91 and appointment by the County Commission shall hold office until the committee is dissolved pursuant to herein or until his or her successor is duly appointed and qualified. The rules previously adopted by the committee shall continue to govern its internal procedures and operations until such time as the committee amends such rules.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-115, § 2, 10-13-92)</history></law>