<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAX REVIEW BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-69</section_number>
<catch_line>Election of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County; Establishing Qualifying Period and Fee and Residency Requirements; Commencement of Term; Compliance with the Ethical Campaign Requirements Ordinance; Restricting Corporate Campaign Contributions; Vacancy in Office.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000210</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-69. Election of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County; Establishing Qualifying Period and Fee and Residency Requirements; Commencement of Term; Compliance with the Ethical Campaign Requirements Ordinance; Restricting Corporate Campaign Contributions; Vacancy in Office.<section prefix='(a)'>The duties of the Property Appraiser, previously carried out under the supervision of the Mayor, are transferred to the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County, who shall be elected pursuant to Section 5.04 of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, effective upon the commencement of the term of office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Commencing with the general election held on November 4, 2008, the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be elected by a majority of the qualified electors voting at a countywide election held within Miami-Dade County, Florida. If no candidate receives a majority vote of qualified electors voting at the November 4, 2008 election, the Commission shall call a countywide runoff election to be held prior to January 1, 2009. Every four years thereafter, the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be elected at a countywide election by a majority of the qualified electors voting at such election held in conjunction with the Miami-Dade County state Primary election. If no candidate receives a majority of the votes cast, there will be a runoff election at the time of the general election following the state primary election between the two (2) candidates receiving the highest number of votes. Should a tie result, the outcome shall be determined by lot.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For the general election held on November 4, 2008, all candidates seeking election as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall qualify using the method provided by ordinance no earlier than noon on the 84th day and no later than noon on the 68th day prior to the date of the election at which he or she is a candidate. Every four years thereafter, all candidates seeking election as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall qualify using the method provided by ordinance with the Clerk of the Circuit Court no earlier than the 84th day and no later than noon on the 70th day prior to the date of the election at which he or she is a candidate. Each candidate for Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall pay a filing fee of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00). All filing fees shall be paid into the general funds of the county. Each candidate for Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be a qualified elector residing within Miami-Dade County for at least three (3) years before qualifying.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All candidates seeking election as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall comply with the Ethical Campaign Practices Ordinance codified at Section 2-11.1.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(e)'>It is unlawful for any candidate, political committee, or other person in connection with the election of any candidate for the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County to knowingly accept or receive any contribution from a corporation incorporated under the laws of the State of Florida or any other state or any foreign country or any partnership or any other legal entity other than a natural person ("Contributing Entity") unless: (1) the Contributing Entity discloses to the campaign treasurer of the campaign receiving the contribution all real and personal property assessed for taxes in Miami-Dade County which is owned by the Contributing Entity, or a parent or subsidiary of the Contributing Entity, or any entity which has the same parent entity as the Contributing Entity; and (2) the campaign treasurer reports, on a form provided by the Supervisor of Elections, all real and personal property assessed for taxes in Miami-Dade County which is owned by the Contributing Entity, or a parent or subsidiary of the Contributing Entity, or any entity which has the same parent entity as the Contributing Entity to the Supervisor of Elections at the same time the campaign treasurer reports the contribution. In addition to any other penalties which may be applicable, any person who violates this subsection shall be punishable by a fine up to five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment not to exceed sixty days, or both. Contributions made prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall be reported in accordance with the requirements of this subsection on or before the next required reporting date. It shall also be unlawful for a candidate for property appraiser to knowingly use or permit the use of campaign material that falsifies, distorts, or misrepresents the property appraiser's ability to appraise property in a manner which is in violation of state law.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The term of office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall commence on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January following his or her election.</section><section prefix='(g)'>In the event of any vacancy in office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County, the person appointed by the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County as his or her deputy or next in authority shall act as the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County. The person serving as the acting Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall meet the eligibility requirements for the office unless waived by the Board of County Commissioners by resolution. The person acting as the Property Appraiser shall serve only until the next countywide election. A person elected at such countywide or runoff election, if necessary, shall serve for the remainder of the unexpired term of office vacated by the Property Appraiser.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-62, ยง 1, 5-20-08)</history></law>