<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAX REVIEW BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-73</section_number>
<catch_line>Employees of the Office of the Property Appraiser; Salary, Compensation and Benefits of Such Employees; Use of County Facilities and Services. County Attorney's Office to Provide Legal Counsel.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000214</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-73. Employees of the Office of the Property Appraiser; Salary, Compensation and Benefits of Such Employees; Use of County Facilities and Services. County Attorney's Office to Provide Legal Counsel.<section prefix='1.'>Upon the commencement of the term of office of the elected Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County elected in November, 2008, the employees assigned to the Property Appraisal department prior to the election of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall be assigned to the Office of the Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County (the "Office"). From that point forward, the Property Appraiser shall have the authority to select all employees of the Office, in accordance with the provisions of the Code and Personnel Rules. Upon selection by the Property Appraiser of an employee for a position in the County's classified service and compliance with the requirements of the Code and Personnel Rules for the appointment of personnel, the Mayor shall formally appoint the selected employee to the County's classified service. The Property Appraiser shall have the authority to directly appoint employees to all positions in the Office which are exempt from the County's classified service. The elected Property Appraiser shall have the authority to hire, evaluate, promote, demote, discipline or discharge Office employees; provided, however, that employees shall continue to have the right to challenge or appeal such decisions on the same terms as other County employees. The Office of the Property Appraiser shall continue to honor and abide by the terms of any existing collective bargaining agreement and to negotiate any changes in such agreement in accordance with state law.</section><section prefix='2.'>The salaries, compensation and benefits of all Office employees shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Property Appraiser, subject to the provisions of any applicable collective bargaining agreement. Except for the purpose of transmitting constituent inquiries, budgeting, funding and carrying out other functions required by this ordinance, the Property Appraiser shall perform his or her duties without supervision or interference from the Mayor or the County Manager.</section><section prefix='3.'>The Property Appraiser of Miami-Dade County shall utilize general County services and facilities, including but not limited to, purchasing, centralized computer services, general services administration, and personnel. Legal services shall be provided by the County Attorney's Office.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-62, ยง 1, 5-20-08)</history></law>