<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAX REVIEW BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-73.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Publication in Spanish, and Haitian Creole of information about certain countywide tax, special assessment, and fee notices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000217</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-73.3. Publication in Spanish, and Haitian Creole of information about certain countywide tax, special assessment, and fee notices.<section prefix='(a)'>It is the official policy of Miami-Dade County that information about certain legal notices regarding taxes, special assessments, and fees that are published or delivered in English also be published or delivered in Spanish and Haitian Creole to the communities that speak Spanish or Haitian Creole.</section><section prefix='(b)'>This policy applies when:<section prefix='(1)'>There is an increase or creation of a tax, special assessment, or fee;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The tax, special assessment, or fee is countywide;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notice of such increase or creation is legally required by statute to be published or delivered; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>The legally required notice is published or delivered in English.</section></section><section>In addition, when it is reasonably foreseeable that the creation or increase of a tax, special assessment, or fee that is less than countywide in scope will impact a substantial number of persons who speak Spanish or Haitian Creole, efforts shall be made to provide information in Spanish or Haitian Creole about any legally-required notices which are published or delivered in English.</section><section prefix='(c)'>This policy does not require a word-for-word translation of the legal notice, but only the publication or delivery of information about such notice. Such information may include a reference to sources such as the 311 call center or the Miami-Dade County Web Pages for more precise information. This policy does not require the publication of the budget book in any language other than English.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The official in charge of providing the legal notice shall have discretion to determine the best and most cost effective method to provide information about the notice in Spanish and Haitian Creole.</section><section prefix='(e)'>This additional information is intended to supplement and not replace formal legal notice as required by governing law. Any mistakes or failure to provide such supplemental information, therefore, shall not provide a basis to challenge any legal action taken pursuant to the formal legal notice.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-51, ยง 1, 6-30-09)</history></law>