<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-77</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000222</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-77. Powers and duties.<section prefix='(a)'>The Department of Public Health shall plan, develop and supervise a systematic program designed to prevent, control and cure diseases, their origin and diffusion among inhabitants of the County, and for the education of the public on health and sanitation problems.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In addition to general duties prescribed in subsection (a) above, and without limitation thereupon, the Department shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Enforce the State sanitary code as promulgated by the State Board of Health, and all other general laws, or rules promulgated pursuant thereto, affecting the public health of the County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Declare, enforce, modify and abolish quarantine as the circumstances may require.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Compile and cause to be put into effect appropriate rules and regulations promulgated by the Manager for the prevention and control of public health nuisances, sanitary practices relating to drinking water made accessible to the public, disposal of excreta, sewage or other wastes, disposal of garbage and refuse, plumbing, rodent control, pollution of lakes, rivers, canals, bays, streams and other waters, the production, handling, processing, and sale of food products and drinks, canning plants, fisheries, restaurants and all other places serving food and drink to the public, toilets and washrooms in all public places and places of employment, factories, trailer, tourist, recreation and other camps offering ac- commodations to the public, swimming pools and bathing places, state, county, municipal and private institutions serving the public, public and privately owned schools, vehicles offering transportation to the public, all places used for the incarceration of prisoners and any other condition, place or establishment necessary for the control of communicable diseases or the protection and safety of the public health and for the prevention of air pollution.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Prescribe the qualifications of operators of milk plants, water purification plants, sewage treatment plants and public swimming pools.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Investigate and study the frequency of occurrence, cause and modes of promulgation and means of prevention, control and cure of communicable diseases among humans, animals, fowl and fish.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Administer a program to improve material and child health with particular emphasis on the school health program.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Be responsible for finding active cases of pulmonary tuberculosis and placing them under proper treatment, and take the necessary steps for the prevention and control of this disease in the County.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Administer a program to prevent and cure venereal diseases, and issue all health certificates for food handlers as may be required by law.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Conduct the children's dental clinic.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Make special studies of the care, cure, control of diseases and improvement of the public health.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Provide nursing service to all Health Department clinics and to all other divisions of the Health Department as required. It shall also provide the necessary public health services to the public schools and related facilities.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Keep a complete and current record of all births and deaths in the County and such other records and duties as the Manager may require.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Inform the public on health problems, their cure and elimination.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Maintain supervision over the operation of public water and sewage facilities, bottled water plants, industrial waste disposal and public swimming pools, and furnish consultation to public and private organizations relative to sanitary engineering problems as well as review plans of new treatment plants and alterations to existing plants.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Maintain sanitary supervision of eating and drinking establishments, food processing and handling establishments, dairy farms and plants, typhus control, rabies control, and over-all environmental sanitation.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Discover and eliminate all unsanitary conditions found in the County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-15, §§ 13.03, 13.05, 13.07, 13.17, 10-2-57)</history></law>