<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.2.11</section_number>
<catch_line>Water and Sewer Department Contracting Authority.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000101</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.2.11. Water and Sewer Department Contracting Authority.<section prefix='(1)'>Intent. This ordinance grants the Mayor or his designee authority to accelerate the processing and procurement of contracts and agreements related to design and construction of the improvements on Exhibits A and B attached to the ordinance from which this Section derives. Copies of Exhibits A and B are attached in their entirety and incorporated herein by reference.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Authority of the County Mayor With Respect to Specified Projects. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, the Mayor or his designee shall have the authority to take the following actions with respect to the projects specified in Section 2-8.2.11(1), and for which the appropriate contract measures as provided in Sections 10-33.02(3)(b)(6) and 10-33.02(3)(b)(7)(c) have been applied:<section prefix='(a)'>Competitive solicitation of capital improvements contracts, including the ability to:<section prefix='1.'>Approve Request to Advertise construction contracts or solicitations for professional services with applicable measures subject to ratification by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='2.'>Issue bid and proposal documents including addenda thereto;</section><section prefix='3.'>Receive, open and review bids and proposals;</section><section prefix='4.'>Appoint selection committee and negotiation committee members for professional services in accordance with Florida Statute 287.055.</section><section prefix='5.'>Recommend award or rejection of bids or proposals, including professional service agreements and construction contracts.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Mayor or his designee shall be entitled to exercise all provisions of all contracts awarded pursuant to this ordinance. The County Mayor or his designee may, if specified in the bid specifications and contract document, negotiate and settle contractor claims, waive liquidated damages, extend contract time, and issue change orders for additional work under contracts and amendments for professional services agreements; as to any specific contract or agreement, change orders or amendments thereto shall not exceed $500,000 in cumulative dollar amount and shall not exceed 15 percent of the contract price in cumulative percentage amount; provided however, that the foregoing limitation shall not apply to any change order or amendment related to environmental remediation or health requirements and the foregoing change orders and amendments shall require ratification by the Board; provided further that the County Mayor or his designee may reduce in any amount the scope and compensation payable under any contract and grant compensable and non-compensable time extensions thereunder.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All actions executed by the Mayor or his designee pursuant to subsections 2-8.2.11(a) and (b) shall be submitted to the next meeting of the Governmental Operations and Environment Committee and shall be waived to the agenda of the next scheduled Board of County Commissioners meeting for ratification. However, no ratification is required of an action executed by the Mayor or his designee which involves waiving liquidated damages as a result of rescheduling contract activities or internal milestones provided neither the total contract time inclusive of time allowances nor the total contract amount inclusive of contingency allowances is exceeded. Any such action shall be included in a report submitted to the Board of County Commissioners on a quarterly basis.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Authority to Award. The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall not have the authority to award contracts pursuant to this section, and all awards of such contracts shall be made by the Board of County Commissioners. Any contract recommended for award under this Chapter shall be heard by the committee to which it is assigned by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners. If the contract recommended for award is recommended favorably by the committee, recommended favorably with committee amendment or forwarded without recommendation or if the chair of the committee to which the item has been assigned requests waiver of the item to the Board of County Commissioners before the item has been considered by committee, it shall be placed on the agenda of the next regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners and shall not be subject to Rule 5.05(c) (the "4-Day Rule").</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-108, ยง 1, 7-24-07; Ord. No. 08-132, ยง 1, 12-2-08; Ord. No. 13-30, ยง 1, 4-2-13)</history></law>