<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.6.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Purchase, sale, lease of real property.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000108</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.6.5. Purchase, sale, lease of real property.<section prefix='(1)'>Definitions. As used in this section:<section prefix='(a)'>The term "Principal" means an owner, officer, or director. By exception, the term Principal shall not include the shareholders of a publicly traded corporation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The term "Tenant" means an individual, corporation, partnership, joint venture, or other legal entity, including both for-profit and not-for-profit entities.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Documenting ownership interest.<section prefix='(a)'>Prior to the County's entering into any contract, agreement or lease relating to the purchase, sale or leasing of real property by, to or from the County, all individuals, corporations, partnerships, joint ventures or other legal entities having any interest of any kind in the property to be purchased, sold or leased, shall file with the County a document identifying the extent of its ownership interest in the subject real property.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Failure by any party to comply with the requirements of subsection (2)(a) hereof shall render the entire agreement to purchase, sale or lease voidable.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Criminal background checks of certain proposed Tenants.<section prefix='(a)'>Prior to the County entering into a nonresidential lease of County-owned property with a proposed Tenant where the property is to be used by the proposed Tenant as a facility for, or to provide programs and services to, children and/or developmentally disabled individuals, the County Mayor or Mayor's designee shall perform a national criminal background check of the proposed Tenant, of its Principals, and of any spouses, parents and children of the proposed Tenant and its Principals that will be working at the nonresidential County-owned property to be leased. The cost of the criminal background check(s) performed by the County shall be the responsibility of the proposed Tenant and payment for the cost of the criminal background checks shall be made by the proposed Tenant to Miami-Dade County prior to the County incurring the cost thereof.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Together with any recommendation to approve a nonresidential lease of County-owned property to be used as a facility for, or to provide programs and services to, children and/or developmentally disabled individuals, the County Mayor shall report to the Board of County Commissioners any instance where the criminal background check required by subsection (3)(a) hereof revealed information which may adversely affect a finding of Tenant responsibility.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-4, §§ 1, 2, 1-25-00; Ord. No. 12-53, § 1, 7-3-12)</history></law>