<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Protest procedures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000103</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.4. Protest procedures.<section>This section shall govern any protest made by a participant in any competitive process utilized for selection of a person or other entity to construct any public improvement, to provide any supplies, materials or services (including professional or management services other than professional services whose acquisition procedure is governed by the Consultant's Competitive Negotiation Act, F.S. Section 287.055 et seq.), or to lease any county property.</section><section>The foregoing notwithstanding, the protest procedures contained in this section shall not apply to contracts and purchases which the County Manager has the delegated authority to award under(b) of this Code, and protests thereon shall be governed by procedures established by administrative order approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>A protest hereunder may not challenge the relative weight of the evaluation criteria or the formula specified for assigning points therefor contained in bid, request for proposals ("RFP") or request for qualifications ("RFQ") specifications which have been approved by the Commission.</section><section prefix='(a)'>Responsiveness. Prior to this Board or any committee thereof hearing any protests relating to a competitive bid, request for proposal or request for qualifications, the County Manager shall request the County Attorney to certify whether the bid or proposal in question is responsive. Upon receiving such request, the County Attorney shall, in consultation with the County Manager if necessary, determine whether the bid or proposal is responsive. This Board and any committee thereof shall be bound by the determination of the County Attorney with regard to the issue of responsiveness.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A written intent to protest shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board and mailed to all participants in the competitive process and to the County Attorney within three (3) working days of the filing of the Manager's recommendation. For purposes of calculating this period, the day of filing of the County Manager's recommendation with the Clerk shall not be counted. Such written intent to protest shall state the particular grounds on which it is based and shall be accompanied by a filing fee. The protester shall then file all pertinent documents and supporting evidence with the Clerk of the Board and mail copies to all participants in the competitive process and to the County Attorney within three (3) working days after the filing of a written intent to protest. No bid protest shall be accepted unless it complies with the requirements of this Section. Notwithstanding the above, in the event that a public records request is made within the first three days of the above referenced period, a protester may utilize any public records obtained as evidence or additional grounds for protest, provided that, a) the protester met all the deadlines set forth above, and, b) a supplementary filing is made with the Clerk of the Board within 48 hours of receipt of the records responsive to the request.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Protests filed in accordance herewith shall be referred to a hearing examiner. A hearing examiner shall be appointed not later than five (5) working days following the filing of a bid protest. The hearing examiner shall conduct a hearing in connection with the bid protest which shall be completed within ten (10) working days following his or her appointment. The hearing examiner shall, within five (5) working days of the hearing, file written findings and recommendations with the Clerk of the Board and shall submit or mail a copy of same to all participants in the competitive process and to the County Attorney. The hearing examiner may extend the deadline for completion of the hearing upon written petition for good cause shown, but such extension shall not exceed an additional five working (5) days. The hearing examiner shall consider the written protest and supporting documents and evidence appended thereto, the County Manager's recommendation, and supporting documentation, and all evidence presented at the hearing. The hearing examiner may also require written summaries, proffers, affidavits and other documents the hearing examiner determines to be necessary in order to conclude the hearing and issue the report and recommendation within the time limits set forth in this ordinance. The hearing examiner shall be entitled to rely on evidence of a type commonly relied upon by reasonably prudent persons in the conduct of their affairs, whether or not such evidence would be admissible in a trial in the courts of Florida.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The hearing examiner shall allow a maximum of two hours for the protester's presentation of its protest and a maximum of two hours for the County's response to each protest. In the event of multiple protests, the hearing examiner shall allocate the time as necessary to ensure that the hearing shall not exceed one day.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The County Manager shall prepare an administrative order, to be approved by this Commission, amending Administrative Order No. 3-21 and setting forth a fee schedule for filing of bid protests. The fee shall be in the amount necessary to defray the cost of the bid protest process established in this Section. The administrative order shall also establish the amount of compensation to be paid the hearing examiner, and shall provide for a prorated reduction of that compensation in the event the hearing examiner fails to abide by the time limitations set forth in Section 2-8.4(c) above.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Hearing examiners shall be selected from a panel of retired judges who have served ten (10) or more years as Circuit Judges in the Eleventh Judicial Circuit in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida. Hearing examiners may be selected from alternate sources where the County Attorney recommends in writing that such action is necessary to achieve greater diversity.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The hearing examiner's findings and recommendation shall be presented to the Commission together with the recommendation of the County Manager. Notice thereof shall be mailed to all participants in the competitive process at least five (5) days in advance of such presentation. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code or any prior resolution, the matter shall be heard by the Commission without prior presentation to any committee. The matter shall be resolved on the basis of the record before the hearing examiner and no evidence or issue which was not presented or raised at such hearing shall be considered. Presentations to the Commission by any participant in the competitive process or their representatives if authorized by subsection (h) below shall be limited to ten (10) minutes per side. The foregoing time limitation shall be inclusive of all speakers addressing the Commission on behalf of each side.</section><section prefix='(h)'>If the hearing examiner concurs in the County Manager's recommendation, a two-thirds () vote of the Commission members present shall be required to take other than the recommended action. Provided however, a two-thirds () vote shall not be required to reject all bids. If the hearing examiner concurs in the County Manager's recommendation, the Commission shall not allow presentations by any participants in the competitive process or their representatives at the time the matter is presented to the Commission. If the hearing examiner does not concur in the County Manager's recommendation, the participants in the competitive process and their representatives may make presentations to the Commission and the Commission shall decide the matter by majority vote.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The County Manager may provide different time periods for the taking of any actions required hereunder when the interest of the County so requires by including appropriate language in the specifications or addenda thereto.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The foregoing notwithstanding, the Commission, by two-thirds () vote of the members present, may waive the requirements of this section and entertain a bid protest, upon written recommendation of the County Manager.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 93-135, § 2, 12-14-93; Ord. No. 94-26, § 1, 2-1-94; Ord. No. 95-22, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-126, § 1, 7-11-95; Ord. No. 95-201, § 2, 11-7-95; Ord. No. 99-146, § 1, 10-19-99; Ord. No. 00-86, § 1, 7-6-00; Ord. No. 01-68, § 1, 4-10-01; Ord. No. 04-77, § 1, 4-27-04; Ord. No. 06-124, § 1, 9-12-06)</history></law>