<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.2.8</section_number>
<catch_line>County manager's authority as to contract relating to construction of Performing Arts Center of Greater Miami.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000098</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.2.8. County manager's authority as to contract relating to construction of Performing Arts Center of Greater Miami.<section>Notwithstanding and prevailing over any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida to the contrary, the County Manager shall have the following authority related to the construction and development of the Performing Arts Center of Greater Miami:<section prefix='(1)'>The County Manager may negotiate and settle contractor claims and issue change orders for additional work under the construction contract and any amendments thereto; as to the construction contract, change orders or amendments to such construction contract shall not exceed five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) in dollar amount and shall not exceed fifteen (15) percent of the contract price in cumulative percentage amount; provided, however, that the foregoing limitation shall not apply to any change order or amendment related to environmental remediation or health requirements and the foregoing change orders and amendments shall require ratification by the Board; provided further that the County Manager may reduce in any amount the scope and compensation payable under the construction contract and grant compensable and noncompensable time extensions thereunder. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any change orders or amendments to the construction contract which exceed the total amount appropriated by the Board to the Performing Arts Center construction budget shall be approved by the Board.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The County Manager may provide in the bid specifications and contract documents that the contract time may be extended and that liquidated damages for failure to comply therewith may be waived before or after the specified date for completion of the contract.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All actions taken by the County Manager under this Section shall not require review by any Committee of the Board, but the County Manager shall submit to the Board for ratification all contracts and amendments thereto executed by the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The County Manager may delegate authority for execution by the Director of the Performing Arts Center Management Office or his immediate designee of actions and authorizations permitted hereunder.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-12, ยง 2, 1-25-2000)</history></law>