<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.2.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Economic stimulus ordinance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000096</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.2.7. Economic stimulus ordinance.<section prefix='(1)'>Policy: This section to be known as the "Economic Stimulus Ordinance," is intended to provide an expedited process to award certain contracts with the express purpose of stimulating the local economy.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Scope: This section, and the expedited processes set forth herein, shall, to the extent permitted by law, be applicable to the processing, design, and construction of the capital improvement projects specifically identified by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, capital projects funded in whole or in part through the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act ("ARRA") (the "Capital Stimulus Projects"). The Board of County Commissioners may from time to time, by subsequent resolution, add or delete projects from the list of Capital Stimulus Projects to which this Section applies. All Capital Stimulus Projects must have been approved as part of the Annual Proposed Resource Allocation and Multi-Year Capital Plan. This section shall also be applicable to contracts for the purchase of goods or services funded in whole or in part through ARRA (the "Economic Stimulus Purchases").</section><section prefix='(3)'>All actions taken under this ordinance shall be subject to review by the Office of Strategic Business Management to ensure adequate funding for each project and that appropriate operational and maintenance funding is in place for the foreseeable future and review by the Office of Capital Improvements for Capital Stimulus Projects and the Department of Procurement Management for Economic Stimulus Purchases to ensure compliance with contract documents and all applicable resolutions, ordinances, and statutes.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, the Mayor or his/her designee shall have the following authority with respect to contracts within the scope of this Section:<section prefix='(a)'>To issue bid and proposal documents including addenda thereto;</section><section prefix='(b)'>To receive, open and review bids and proposals;</section><section prefix='(c)'>To appoint standing selection committee and negotiation committee members to obtain professional services in accordance with Section 2-10.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and Section 287.055 of the Florida Statutes, provided each such committee shall contain, whenever possible, representation from the user department;</section><section prefix='(d)'>To award or reject bids for contracts including, but not limited to, professional service agreements, construction contracts and contracts for the purchase of goods and services and issue Notices to Proceed where:<section prefix='1.'>For Capital Stimulus Projects the award value of the contract and operational considerations have been reviewed and approved by the Office of Strategic Business Management; and</section><section prefix='2.'>For Capital Stimulus Projects the base value of a recommended award does not exceed the base estimate by more than ten (10) percent; and</section><section prefix='3.'>The contractor, vendor or consulting firm receiving the award is in good standing with the County including, but not limited to: no outstanding debts; demonstrated acceptable past performance; and has submitted required insurance, bonds, affidavits and documentation provided for by the solicitation; and</section><section prefix='4.'>None of the bidders have filed a timely bid protest; and</section><section prefix='5.'>All awards are subject to ratification by the Board of County Commissioners at the next available meeting and contracts for Capital Stimulus Projects approved under this authority must contain a Termination for Convenience clause.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>For Capital Stimulus Projects negotiate and settle contractor claims, and issue change orders for additional work under contracts and amendments for professional services agreements where:<section prefix='1.'>The change order or claim does not increase the contract amount, including contingencies; and</section><section prefix='2.'>The contingency allowance established in accordance with Section 2-8.1(h) shall be utilized to ensure minimal disruption in work flow and shall be documented on the appropriate contingency authorization draw. Change orders shall be submitted to replenish the contingency account in a timely manner; and</section><section prefix='3.'>The limitations provided in (4)(e)1 above shall not apply to any change order or amendment related to emergency actions impacting environmental remediation, public safety, health requirements or recovery from natural disaster.</section></section></section><section prefix='(5)'>All actions taken by the Mayor or his/her designee under this Section shall not require review by any Committee, but shall be submitted to the next available Board of County Commissioners meeting for ratification. Awards that do not meet the requirements of subsection (4)(d) above shall not require Committee review but shall be submitted to the next available meeting of the Board of County Commissioners for approval. The authority delegated to the Mayor or the Mayor's designee pursuant to this Section shall be in addition and not in derogation to other delegations of authority set forth elsewhere in this Code.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Special exemptions: This process shall be modified to ensure full conformance with any special provisions or review processes established by the Board. As such, any proposed County contract for a project included in the TIP approved by the MPO that is funded in whole or in part by proceeds of the Charter County Transit System Sales Surtax authorized by Article XVI of Chapter 29 of the County Code, the Mayor or his/her designee shall have the authority to advertise and issue bid or proposal documents for such contracts where the bid or proposal documents expressly provide that no award shall be effective and no contractual relationship shall arise with the County unless and until ratified by the County Commission and that ratification is approved by the Citizens' Independent Transportation Trust or reaffirmed by the County Commission as provided in subsection (e) of Section 29-124 of the County Code, and the authority to issue notices to proceed after award for such contracts shall be limited to those instances where the County Commission has ratified the award and the Citizens' Independent Transportation Trust has approved the Commission's action or, if the Trust disapproves such Commission action, the Commission has reaffirmed same as provided in subsection (e) of Section 29-124 of the County Code.</section><section prefix='(7)'>This ordinance shall sunset July 1, 2013.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-92, ยง 1, 7-17-08; Ord. No. 09-60, ยง 1, 6-30-09; Ord. No. R-11-49, ยง 1, 7-7-11)</history></law>