<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.5.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure to Provide Preference to Local Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprises in County Contracts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000106</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.5.1. Procedure to Provide Preference to Local Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprises in County Contracts.<section prefix='(1)'>Definition: "Local Certified Service Disabled Veteran Business Enterprise" is a firm that is (a) a local business pursuant to Section 2.8.5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and (b) prior to proposal or bid submittal is certified by the State of Florida Department of Management Services as a service-disabled veteran business enterprise pursuant to Section 295.187 of the Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A Local Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprise that submits a bid for a contract shall receive a bid preference of five percent of the price bid. These preferences will only be used for evaluating and awarding the bids and shall not affect the contract price. However, if a Local Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprise is the lowest bidder as a result of a Best and Final Bid (also known as a BAFO), then the price submitted as part of the Best and Final Bid shall be the contract price.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A Local Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprise that submits a proposal in response to an RFP, RFQ, RFI or a Notice to Professional Consultants that assigns weights to evaluation and selection criteria shall receive an additional five percent of the evaluation points scored on the technical portion of such bidder's proposal.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In procurements where SBE (Small Business Enterprises) measures are being applied, a Local Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprise who is also an SBE shall not receive the veteran preferences provided in this section and shall be limited to any applicable SBE preferences.</section><section prefix='(5)'>At the time of bid or proposal submission, the firm must affirm in writing its compliance with the certification requirements of Section 295.187 of the Florida Statutes and submit this affirmation and a copy of the actual certification along with the bid or proposal submission.</section><section prefix='(6)'>In the event that Broward, Palm Beach or Monroe County extend preferences to Local Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprises, Miami-Dade County may enter into an inter-local agreement with such County wherein the preferences of this section may be extended and made available to vendors that are both Certified Service-Disabled Veteran Business Enterprises and considered local vendors in those counties pursuant to Section 2-8.5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Nothing in this ordinance is meant to limit any preferences otherwise available to local businesses pursuant to the Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-68, ยง 1, 9-1-09)</history></law>