<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Contracts and purchases generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000080</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.1. Contracts and purchases generally.<section prefix='(a)'>Scope. Except as provided in subsections (b), (f), (h) and (l), this section shall apply to all contracts for public improvements and purchase of all supplies, materials and services other than professional services.<section prefix='(b)'>Bid requirement for certain purchases; delegation of authority to advertise, award and reject bids or proposals for certain purchases. Formal sealed bids shall be secured for all contracts and purchases within the scope of this section when the transaction involves the expenditure of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000.00) or more, except that the Board of County Commissioners, upon written recommendation of the Mayor or Mayor's designee, may, by resolution adopted by two-thirds () vote of the members present, waive competitive bidding when it finds this is to be in the best interest of the County. The Mayor or Mayor's designee is hereby delegated the authority to advertise for bid all County contracts, including contracts for public improvements, purchases of supplies, materials and services, and purchases of professional services, without the need for action by the County Commission. The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall be required to include in any such advertisement the measures approved by the Review Committee relating to the County's small and community business programs established in this Code. The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall further be required to report to this Board on a bi-annual basis all contracts advertised with the measures included, and other steps taken to foster small and community business programs. The Commission Auditor shall review and evaluate the Mayor's or Mayor's designee exercise of authority delegated pursuant to this section and report the results of his or her evaluation to the Board of County Commissioners on a periodic basis. The Mayor or Mayor's designee is hereby delegated the authority to award and reject bids or proposals for contracts for public improvements (construction), and purchases of supplies, materials and services (including professional services, other than professional architectural, engineering and other services subject to section 2-10.4 and Section 287.055, Florida Statutes) costing one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) or less, or in the case of miscellaneous construction contracts designed to provide opportunities for Community Small Business Enterprises specifically authorized by Board resolution five million dollars ($5,000,000.00) or less, without the need for action by the County Commission. The authority to award contracts provided in the preceding sentence shall not constitute authority for the Mayor or Mayor's designee to exercise an option to renew any contract where the combined value for such contract's initial term and the option to renew would exceed one million dollars ($1,000,000.00), and in such instances the Mayor or Mayor's designee shall obtain the prior authorization of the County Commission to exercise such option. The Mayor or Mayor's designee may recommend that the foregoing requirement to obtain prior Commission authorization to exercise an option to renew be waived for a specific contract when the Mayor or Mayor's designee deems it to be in the best interests of the County. The Inspector General shall be invited to participate as appropriate in the processes by which the authority delegated hereby is exercised. The Mayor or Mayor's designee is delegated the authority to utilize any of the following processes for selection of a contractor to perform contracts for public improvements: competitive price bidding, request for proposals, or request for qualifications without the need for prior approval of the County Commission. The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall review all construction projects to determine whether the break-up of the project into smaller contracts will increase the opportunity for CSBEs to participate therein. For those contracts where the Mayor or Mayor's designee requests authority from the County Commission to advertise, the request for such authority shall advise the steps taken to accomplish the foregoing sentence. The Mayor or Mayor's designee may designate appropriate County staff to exercise the authority delegated hereunder by implementing order, approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Legacy Purchases. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 2-8.1(b)(1), formal sealed bids shall not be required for Legacy Purchases which do not result in the budget for the user department(s) exceeding the amount approved by the County Commission during the annual budget approval process. Such Legacy purchases may be awarded by the Board of County Commissioners upon a majority vote of those Board Members present, where the amount of such award exceeds the threshold for purchases by the Mayor set forth in section 2-8.1(b)(1). The County Mayor shall include, in any Legacy Purchase award recommendation, a statement as to the need for such purchase and the provisions taken to reduce or eliminate the future need for Legacy Purchases for the particular good or service. For the purposes of this section, Legacy Purchases shall mean the purchase of goods and services where competition is unavailable, impractical or constrained as a result of the need to continue to operate an existing County system which may not be replaced without substantial expenditure.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Establishment of purchasing procedure by administrative order. By administrative order, subject to the approval of the Board of County Commissioners, the County Manager shall establish procedures for all purchases and the award of all contracts within the scope of this section. Except in the case of small purchase orders and sole source contracts, as defined by Administrative Order 3-2 or successor thereto, said procedures shall make it a condition of award that the contractor or entity receiving a contract or purchase from Miami-Dade County verify that all delinquent and currently due fees or taxes (including, but not limited to, real and personal property taxes, utility taxes, and occupational license taxes) collected in the normal course by the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector and County issued parking tickets for vehicles registered in the name of the contractor or business entity, have been paid. Failure to comply with this policy may result in debarment. Such purchasing procedures may include i) a petty cash program for the purchase of goods and services of not to exceed the amount specified in Administrative Order 3-6; and ii) a purchase card program for the purchase of goods and services of not to exceed the amount specified by Administrative Order for such program and in no event greater than that provided for small purchases under Administrative Order 3-2. Notwithstanding any other Section of this Code or Resolution of this Board, purchases under the petty cash and purchasing card programs shall be subject only to the limitations, conditions and requirements specified in the Administrative Orders therefore and shall not be subject to the requirements specified elsewhere in this Code or in Board Resolutions applicable to County contracting or procurement.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Disclosure required of contractors and entities transacting business with Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='(1)'>All contracts or business transactions or renewals thereof with Miami-Dade County, or any person or agency acting for Miami-Dade County, including but not limited to: Contracts for public improvements; contracts for purchase of supplies, materials or services; and leases, franchises, concessions or management agreements, shall require the person contracting or transacting such business with the County to disclose under oath his or her full legal name, and business address. Such contract or transaction shall also require the disclosure under oath of the full legal name and business address of all individuals having any interest (legal, equitable, beneficial or otherwise) in the contract; provided, however, no disclosure shall be required of subcontractors, materialmen, suppliers, laborers or lenders. Post office box addresses shall not be accepted hereunder. If the contract or business transaction is with a corporation the foregoing information shall be provided for each officer and director and each stockholder holding, directly or indirectly, five (5) percent or more of the outstanding stock in the corporation. If the contract or business transaction is with a partnership, the foregoing information shall be provided for each partner. If the contract or business transaction is with a trust, the foregoing information shall be provided for the trustee and each beneficiary of the trust. All assignments of any such contract or transaction, if otherwise authorized, shall comply with the provisions hereof. All transferees of interests required to be disclosed hereunder shall within thirty (30) days of the transfer notify the County that the transfer has occurred. The County Manager shall include in the resolution approving any assignment of any contract or business transaction or transfer of interest therein, or any change of ownership in contracts with the County, the names and business addresses of the officers, directors, partners or trustees, as applicable, of the companies involved in the contract assignment or business transaction or transfer of interest therein, or change of ownership. Notwithstanding anything in this section to the contrary, the foregoing disclosure requirements shall not apply to contracts with publicly-traded corporations, or to contracts with the United States or any department or agency thereof, the State or any political subdivision or agency thereof, or any municipality of this State. Any contract or transaction entered into in violation of this section shall be voidable.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Except where precluded by federal or State law or regulations, each contract or business transaction or renewal thereof specified in the first sentence of subsection (1) of this Section 2-8.1(d) shall also require the entity contracting or transacting such business to disclose the following additional information under oath:<section prefix='(i)'>Whether the entity has a collective bargaining agreement with its employees; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Whether the entity provides company paid health care benefits to be paid to employees; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>A current breakdown of the entity's work force and ownership as to race, national origin and gender; and</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Any other information as may be required by Administrative Order.</section><section>The foregoing disclosure requirements shall not apply to contracts with the United States or any department or agency thereof, the State or any political subdivision or agency thereof, or any municipality of this State.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Any and all requirements for affidavits, oaths or affirmations contained in Sections 2-8.1(d), 2-8.1.2(b), 10-38, 2-8.1(c), 2-8.1(i), 2-11.1, Article V of Chapter 11A Sections 11A-29 through 11A-33, 2-8.9, Article VIII of Chapter 11A Sections 11A-60 through 11A-67 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and Resolution R-182-00 shall be satisfied by the proper completion of a uniform County affidavit packet to be developed for this purpose by the Department of Procurement Management (the "Uniform County Affidavit") and maintained with the proposer's vendor registration file. A duly executed Uniform County Affidavit shall be on file prior to the award of any County contract and the sufficiency and veracity of the Uniform County Affidavit shall, at all times, be the responsibility of the vendor or proposed contractor. The execution of any contract shall be deemed a representation by the vendor or proposed contractor that a duly executed Uniform County Affidavit is on file, and that it is true and accurate through the date of bid or proposal submission. No vendor or proposed contractor shall be eligible for award unless the requirements of this Section are duly satisfied. Bid documents shall contain a statement alerting bidders of the requirements of this section.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Any person who willfully fails to disclose the information required by subsection (1) of this Section 2-8.1(d), or who knowingly discloses false information in this regard, shall be punished by a fine of up to five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment in the County Jail for up to sixty (60) days, or both in the discretion of the court.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, entities contracting or transacting business with the County for performances; honorariums; training services; historical preservation services; rehabilitative services; cable and satellite services; video conferencing services; dental services for inmates; tutoring services; animal medication purchases; shipment of animals; anti-venom purchases; purchases of land; and car leases for County officials shall only be required to submit, at a minimum, a W9, the entity's full legal name, business address, telephone number and email address on a form to be provided by the Department of Procurement Management and shall not be required to submit any other affidavit, disclosure or registration otherwise required by the Code.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Bids from related parties. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, where two (2) or more related parties each submit a bid or proposal for any contract within the scope of this section, such bids or proposals shall be presumed to be collusive. The foregoing presumption may be rebutted by presentation of evidence as to the extent of ownership, control and management of such related parties in the preparation and submittal of such bids or proposals. Related parties shall mean bidders or proposers or the principals thereof which have a direct or indirect ownership interest in another bidder or proposer for the same contract or in which a parent company or the principals thereof of one (1) bidder or proposer have a direct or indirect ownership interest in another bidder or proposer for the same contract. Bids or proposals found to be collusive shall be rejected.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Listing of subcontractors required on certain contracts. The requirements of this subsection shall apply to those county contracts for purchase of supplies, materials or services, including professional services, which involve the expenditure of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) or more where the contract specifications do not expressly preclude the use of subcontractors to perform a portion of the work. All such contracts shall require the entity contracting with the County to list all first tier subcontractors who will perform any part of the contract work and all suppliers who will supply materials for the contract work direct to such entity. The contracts shall also require the entity contracting with the County to report to the County the race, gender and ethnic origin of the owners and employees of all such first tier subcontractors. When a competitive process is utilized to select the entity that will contract with the County, the specifications shall provide that it shall be a condition of award for the successful bidder to provide the listing of subcontractors, if required. Section 10-34 of this Code governs the subcontractor listing requirements for contracts for public improvements. The contract shall require the contractor to provide to the County the race, gender and ethnic information as soon as reasonably available and in any event prior to final payment under the contract. The County Mayor or Mayor's designee shall include language in all contracts and specifications to which this subsection applies to implement this subsection and to provide that the contractor shall not change or substitute subcontractors or suppliers from those listed except upon written approval of the County.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The County Manager shall include language in the specifications for all County contracts providing that a bidder's or proposer's performance as a prime contractor or subcontractor on previous County contracts shall be taken into account in evaluating bids and proposals received for County contracts.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Dedicated allowances, contingency allowances and additional service allowances on contracts involving the expenditure of more than $500,000. For any contract for the construction of public improvements and any professional service agreement involving the expenditure of more than $500,000, an item shall be added to the advertisement recommendation memorandum presented by the County Manager to the Board of County Commissioners identifying (1) each proposed dedicated allowance, contingency allowance and additional services allowance including the specific purpose for each and the dollar amount that shall be available for each, and (2) the corresponding percentage of each proposed dedicated allowance, contingency allowance and additional services allowance in relation to the estimated contract price. When the aggregate percentage of all proposed non-dedicated allowances, such as contingency allowances and additional services allowances, exceeds the applicable threshold set forth below, the County Manager's advertisement recommendation shall also include specific information to define and substantiate the proposed utilization of the particular allowances:<section prefix='(1)'>Five percent of the contract price for new construction on public property;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Ten percent of the contract price for remodeling, renovation or expansion of existing facilities on public property, or for infrastructure projects within the public right-of-way; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Ten percent of the contract price for professional service agreements.</section></section><section>For each contract covered by this subsection (h), an item shall be added to the recommendation for award memorandum presented by the County Manager to the Board of County Commissioners identifying (1) each dedicated allowance, contingency allowance and additional services allowance including the specific purpose for each and the dollar amount that shall be available for each, and (2) the corresponding percentage of each dedicated allowance, contingency allowance and additional services allowance in relation to the actual contract price.</section><section>For each contract covered by this subsection (h), during the course of contract performance, the director of the department administering the contract shall: (1) review and maintain full and complete documentation to support the specific items and associated costs utilized under the contract's dedicated allowance, contingency allowance and additional services allowance, and shall maintain such information available for inspection as a public record; and (2) whenever the actual utilization of a dedicated allowance, contingency allowance or additional services allowance exceeds the particular dollar amount or percentage for that allowance stated in the recommendation for award memorandum presented by the County Manager to the Board of County Commissioners, shall immediately inform the County Manager, or his designee, in writing, and shall disclose the actual, project-to-date utilization of that account including the specific items and associated costs incurred and the County Manager shall promptly report the utilization of each such account to the Board of County Commissioners with a copy to the Director of Procurement and Director of Audit and Management Services. The procedures provided in this subsection (h) shall not constitute a delegation of authority to increase the contract price or contract ceiling of any contract without approval of the County Commission.<section prefix='(i)'>This subsection shall apply to all county contracts for public improvements; purchases of all supplies, materials and services, including professional services; leases, franchises, concessions, management agreements and permits to do business on county property; and loan transactions.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>No individual or entity who is in arrears in excess of the enforcement threshold, defined below, under any obligation or contract, including but not limited to those described in (h)(i) above, final non-appealable judgment, or lien with the County, or any of its agencies or instrumentalities, including the Public Health Trust (hereinafter referred to as "County"), either directly or indirectly through a firm, corporation, partnership or joint venture in which the individual or entity has a controlling financial interest as that term is defined in Section 2-11.1(b)(8) of this Code, shall be allowed to receive any additional County contracts described in (h)(i) above, purchase orders or extensions of County contracts until either the arrearage has been paid in full or the County has agreed in writing to a repayment schedule. Notwithstanding the above, the County Manager may enter into or extend a contract or business transaction with any individuals or entities who are not current in their obligations to the County when the County Manager determines it to be in the best interest of the County or when the County Manager determines that the individuals or entities are engaged in pending settlement negotiations regarding change orders. Such action shall be subject to ratification by the Board of County Commissioners. The County Manager shall include language in the specifications of all contracts to which this subsection applies that the failure to meet the terms and conditions of any obligation or repayment schedule shall constitute a default of the subject contract and may be cause for suspension, termination and debarment, in accordance with the terms of the contract and the debarment procedures of the County.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>All contracts, business transactions and renewals thereof with the County to which this subsection applies, shall require the individual or entity seeking to transact business with the County to verify by affidavit that the individual or entity is current in its obligations to the County and is not otherwise in default of any County contract. Any contract or transaction entered into in violation of this subsection shall be voidable.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>By administrative order, the County Manager shall establish procedures for the implementation of this subsection. Said procedures shall require the County Manager to maintain a list of all individuals and entities who are not current in their obligations to the County. Such list shall be updated periodically and distributed or made available electronically to each County department, agency and instrumentality.</section><section prefix='(v)'>The County Manager shall include language in all promissory notes and loan documents that require the borrower to assign the proceeds of any contract with the County or any of its agencies or instrumentalities to which the borrower or any firm, corporation, partnership or joint venture in which the borrower has a controlling financial interest is a party to the County in order to secure repayment of the loan.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>The provisions of the "cone of silence" as set forth in subsection 2-11.1(t)(a) as it pertains to the prohibition of any communications with the Mayor, County Commissioners or their respective staffs shall apply to this subsection (h) and no repayment schedule or settlement agreement entered into by the County administration shall be reported to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>"Enforcement Threshold," shall mean any arrearage under any individual contract, final non-appealable judgment, or lien with Miami-Dade County that exceeds $25,000 and has been delinquent for greater than 180 days.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Each person or entity that seeks to do business with the County shall adopt a Code of Business Ethics ("Code") and shall, prior to the execution of any contract between the contractor and the County, submit an affidavit, on a form provided by the County, stating that the contractor has adopted a Code that complies with the requirements of this Section. Any person or entity that fails to submit the required affidavit shall be ineligible for contract award. The Code of Business Ethics shall apply to all business that the contractor does with the County and shall, at a minimum, require the contractor to comply with all applicable governmental rules and regulations including, among others, the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance and the Miami-Dade County False Claims Ordinance.</section><section>The Code of Business Ethics shall also require the contractor to comply with all applicable rules and regulations regarding Disadvantaged Business Enterprises, the Small Business Enterprise (SBE) Program and Community Small Business Enterprises (CSBEs) and shall specifically prohibit the following practices:<section prefix='(1)'>Pass-through Requirements. The Code shall prohibit pass-throughs whereby the prime firm requires that the SBE or CSBE firm accept payments as a SBE or CSBE and pass through those payments or a portion of those payments to another entity including, but not limited to, the owner/operator of the prime firm;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Rental Space Requirements, Equipment Requirements or Flat Overhead Fee Requirements. The Code shall prohibit rental space requirements, equipment requirements and/or flat overhead fee requirements, whereby the prime firm requires the SBE or CSBE firm to rent space or equipment from the prime firm or charges a flat overhead fee for the use of space, equipment, secretary, etc.;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Staffing Requirements. The Code shall prohibit a prime firm from mandating, as a condition to inclusion in the project, that a SBE or CSBE hire, fire, or promote certain individuals not employed by the prime firm, or utilize staff employed or previously employed by the prime firm.</section><section prefix='(4)'>SBE or CSBE staff utilization. The Code shall prohibit the prime firm from requiring the SBE or CSBE firm to provide more staff than is necessary and then utilizing the SBE or CSBE staff for other work to be performed by the prime firm.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Fraudulently creating, operating or representing SBE or CSBE. The Code shall prohibit a prime firm including, but not limited to, the owners/operators thereof from fraudulently creating, operating or representing an entity as a SBE or CSBE for purposes of qualifying for certification as a SBE or CSBE.</section></section><section>The Code shall also require that on any contract where SBE or CSBE participation is purported, the contract shall specify essential terms including, but not limited to, a specific statement regarding the percent of participation planned for SBEs or CSBEs, the timing of payments and when the work is to be performed.</section><section>The failure of a contractor to comply with its Code of Business Ethics shall render any contract between the contractor and the County voidable, and subject violators to debarment from future County work pursuant to(h)(2) of the Code of Miami-Dade County. The Inspector General shall be authorized to investigate any alleged violation by a contractor of its Code of Business Ethics. Upon the completion of any investigation, the Inspector General shall forward the report to the appropriate entity. The Inspector General may delay the publication of a report when requested to do so by a law enforcement agency including, but not limited to, the State Attorney's Office or the United States Attorney's Office. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to limit the powers and duties of the Inspector General as stated in other sections of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Electronic Commerce, Electronic Signatures, and On-Line Procurement of Goods and Services.<section prefix='(1)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Electronic means relating to technology having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Reverse Auction means a procurement method wherein bidders, anonymous to each other, electronically submit real-time bids on designated goods or services.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Electronic Signature means a manual or electronic identifier or the electronic result of an authentication technique attached to, or logically associated with, a record that is intended by the person using it to have the same full force and effect as manual signature.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>On-Line Procurement. The County Manager is authorized to pursue electronic commerce and on-line procurement of goods and services through the use of electronic means including the use of electronic signatures. Procurement by electronic means includes, but is not limited to, the advertising and receipt of competitive sealed bids, competitive sealed proposals and informal quotations, reverse auctions, vendor registration, and any other current or future procurement method or process.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>Unsolicited Proposals.<section prefix='(1)'>Any person or legal entity may submit an unsolicited proposal to the County to contract for the design, construction, operation, ownership, acquisition, or leasing of public infrastructure which unsolicited proposal shall be governed by the provisions of this section. For purposes of this section, public infrastructure shall mean transit structures, housing structures, roads, bridges, streets, highways, drainage, underground excavation, piping and all structures incidental thereto regardless of cost and any other public building with estimated cost in excess of fifteen million dollars ($15,000,000.00).</section><section prefix='(2)'>The County shall charge a fee to the private entity to cover the costs of processing, reviewing, and evaluating any unsolicited proposal, including a fee to cover the costs of attorneys, engineers, consultants, and financial advisors. The fee charged for the review of the proposal shall be based on the level of expertise deemed necessary by the Mayor or his designee and required to review the proposal, and will not be greater than the direct costs associated with evaluating the unsolicited proposal. "Direct costs" may include, but are not limited to, (i) the cost of staff time required to process, evaluate, review and respond to the proposal and (ii) the costs of attorneys, engineers, financial advisors and other consultants. Should the project proceed beyond the initial review, and be published for competition, additional fees for review and evaluation may be charged as agreed to by the parties.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The County shall require the initial processing fee of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00). Additional fees may be charged based on the nature of the proposal and the complexity of the review required. All requested fees shall be paid prior to the County's further evaluation of the proposal. The Mayor or his designee shall refund any portion of the initial processing fee paid which in the discretion of the Mayor or his designee exceeds the direct costs associated with evaluating the proposal.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Upon receipt of an unsolicited proposal or group of proposals and payment of any required fees by the proposer or proposers, the Mayor or his designee shall note the date and time of receipt of such proposal and shall determine within 90 days whether to accept the unsolicited proposal solely for the purpose of proceeding to publication as described below. Alternatively, the Mayor or his designee shall reject the proposal within such ninety (90) days or, in the event that the time for consideration is insufficient, request an extension of this time from the Board; however, the Board shall not grant more than one such extension. Final determination of whether to publish a proposal shall be made by the Board of County Commissioners. Following such determination, the Mayor or his designee shall respond to the proposer in writing as to the acceptance or rejection of the unsolicited proposal. The initial review time may be extended by mutual agreement of the Mayor or his designee and the proposer. The proposal shall be published not later than thirty (30) days following acceptance by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(5)'>In his/her sole and absolute discretion, the County may reject or return an unsolicited proposal. The decision to reject an unsolicited proposal which is accompanied by the applicable fee shall be subject to ratification by the Board of County Commissioners. The Mayor or his designee shall provide a written explanation of the reasons for rejection in the item requesting ratification. It is not the intention or obligation of the County to correct and/or assist in the preparation of an unsolicited proposal in any manner.</section><section prefix='(6)'>In determining whether to accept the unsolicited proposal for publication, the County shall take into consideration such factors as: whether the proposed project is in the public's best interest; the costs of the proposed project and its funding sources; whether the proposed project may be accomplished through the use of County resources; the need for the proposed project; the scientific, technical or socioeconomic merits of the proposal; the contribution of the proposal to the County's goals and objectives; the qualifications, technical and management capabilities and experience of the proposer considered as a whole and considered in terms of the legal entities who may comprise the proposer or who may be serving as subcontractors to the proposer; the general reputation and financial condition of the proposer and its team members; the proposer's financial capacity to perform its obligations in the proposed contract; the financial viability and feasibility of the submitted proposal; the cost, if any, to the County to proceed with implementation of the proposal; and any other information the County deems appropriate for such initial evaluation.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any unsolicited proposal shall include sufficient detail and information for the County to evaluate the proposal in an objective and timely manner and to determine if the proposal meets the above criteria and benefits the County. If such proposal is not deemed by the County to be complete or in sufficient detail, it may be rejected at the sole discretion of the Mayor or his designee. The Mayor or his designee shall inform the proposer in writing of the reason for rejection and shall provide the proposer a copy of the item explaining the reason for rejection delivered to the Board of County Commissioners. It is not the intent or obligation of the Mayor or his designee to assist the proposer in completing the proposal and the Mayor or his designee shall bear no responsibility to itemize or advise the proposer of the incomplete items or terms of the proposal.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Any unsolicited proposal shall contain at a minimum the following items, as appropriate to the proposed project:<section prefix='(a)'>Information and supporting documentation necessary for the County to evaluate the factors listed in paragraph (6) above.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A site plan indicating the location of the project proposed.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A description of the project, including the conceptual design of the facility.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The proposed schedule for development of the project and/or the proposed term for operation of the project, along with an estimate of the life cycle cost of the proposed proposal.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A statement setting forth a method by which the private entity proposes to secure any property interests required for the proposed project.</section><section prefix='(f)'>A list of all public utilities, railroad lines, navigable waters and flight paths, if any, that will be crossed or affected by the proposed project and a statement of the plan to accommodate such crossings or effects.</section><section prefix='(g)'>A statement setting forth the proposer's plans for developing, financing, constructing and/or operating and maintaining the project, including identification of any revenue, public or private of proposed debt or equity investment proposed by the proposer. The financing plans shall address any and all means by which the costs of the project will be borne by persons other than the County.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Names and addresses of persons who may be contacted for further information concerning the request.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Information on how the project would benefit small and community based contractors within Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(j)'>A financial plan for the entire time period of the proposed private entity involvement in the project.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Performance guarantees, if any, and any proposed bonding to be provided by the proposer.</section><section prefix='(l)'>The names of owners, directors and officers of the proposer, and such information as may be necessary to evaluate the qualifications of the critical personnel to be engaged in the project.</section><section prefix='(m)'>A list of all engineering or construction firms to be proposed on the project and their qualifications and a description of their role in the proposal.</section><section prefix='(n)'>A listing of all proposed obligations and requirements of the County and any other governmental agencies, including, but not limited to, contributions to the project financing, staffing and permitting.</section><section prefix='(o)'>A listing of all small business enterprises (as defined in applicable County ordinances) that will participate in the project and the proposed scope of work of each.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Such additional material and information that a responsible public entity may reasonably expect, in order to review and evaluate such proposal.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>The County may seek the advice of internal staff or outside advisors, attorneys or consultants, or any combination thereof, with relevant experience in determining whether to accept the unsolicited proposal for publication and/or whether to enter into an agreement with the private entity or any competing proposer. At its option, the County may seek further clarification of the proposal.</section><section prefix='(10)'>If the County accepts the unsolicited proposal for publication, then the Mayor or his designee shall publish a competitive solicitation statement that the County has received a proposal and will accept, for ninety (90) days after the initial date of the publication, other proposals for the same project purpose (the "Response Period"). Such period may be extended by the Board of County Commissioners, upon written request by the Mayor or his designee explaining why a longer period for response is in the best interest of the County. The Mayor or his designee shall identify the procedures that will be used for evaluating the proposals in the notice or in a subsequent publication. Once the County decides to receive competing proposals, it may utilize its existing procedures for evaluating the proposals or may adopt project-specific procedures. The proposer shall be authorized to respond to the competitive solicitation and offer to the County a proposal in terms not less favorable to the County than the original proposal.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Proposal documents submitted by private entities are public records under Chapter 119, Florida Statutes (Florida's Public Records Law), subject to any exemption otherwise provided by law. Any competing proposer may request and receive a copy of such proposal, and the County reserves the right to publish such unsolicited proposal and solicit competing proposals within the Response Period. Proposers are advised to familiarize themselves with the provisions of the Public Records Law and to seek legal advice regarding any proprietary or intellectual property rights which they may have in the proposal. In no event shall the County be liable to a proposer for the disclosure of all or a portion of a proposal submitted under this subsection.</section><section prefix='(12)'>When the private entity requests that the County not disclose information that is exempt from the disclosure requirements of the Public Records Law, the private entity must (i) invoke the exemption when the data or materials are submitted to the County or before such submission, (ii) identify the data and materials for which protection from disclosure is sought, and (iii) state why the exclusion from disclosure is necessary, citing the specific exemption to Chapter 119, Florida Statutes, that the proposer believes applies. The County's determination as to confidentiality shall be final and binding upon the proposer. The proposer shall bear all attorneys' fees and costs associated with litigation for public access to claimed confidential documents. The County's need to maintain certain information confidential may be taken into consideration in the County's decision not to publish a solicitation.</section><section prefix='(13)'>After the Response Period has expired, the Mayor or his designee shall within forty-five (45) days, or longer, as specified in the advertisement, evaluate all the competing proposals and rank them in order of preference utilizing the criteria published for the specific project.</section><section prefix='(14)'>The Mayor or his designee may negotiate with the top-ranked proposers in the order of their ranking, and may, through such negotiations, aim to arrive at a mutually satisfactory agreement.</section><section prefix='(15)'>If only one proposal is received, the Mayor or his designee may negotiate in good faith and if he or she is not satisfied with results, may at his or her sole discretion terminate negotiations with the proposer.</section><section prefix='(16)'>No proposer is guaranteed the award of a contract as a result of being favorably ranked for this project. The issuance of an unsolicited proposal shall create no rights in the proposer including rights as a bidder, under contract or intellectual property. The County, in its discretion, reserves the right to reject all proposals at any point in the process prior to the full execution of a contract with a proposer.</section><section prefix='(17)'>The bid protest process provided for in this Code shall not apply to any decision to reject an unsolicited proposal but shall apply to any decision to recommend a contract award rejection, unless such protest is waived in accordance with this Code. The Cone of Silence provided for in this Code shall be imposed only following the publication of the competitive solicitation.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Nothing in this ordinance shall affect the County Manager's authority to recommend a waiver of competitive bids when he determines such waiver to be in the best interest of the County.</section></section><section prefix='(l)'>Mayor's conflicts of interest. When the County Mayor declares a conflict of interest in the procurement of a County contract in accordance with Section 5.03(d) of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, the County Mayor shall give written notice of such conflict to the Chairperson of the Board and shall designate a member of the County's staff, familiar with County procurement processes, who shall serve as the Chairperson's primary contact to oversee the affected procurement. Upon the notification of such conflict, the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners shall exercise all authority provided by the Charter or the County Commission to the Mayor with regard to such procurement including the authority to recommend a bid waiver. For purposes of the affected procurement only, all powers and responsibilities given to the County Mayor in any and all provisions of this Code relating to the advertisement, solicitation, protest and award of contracts, and in any implementing order related to such Code provisions, shall be transferred to the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners for the duration of the conflict. The County Mayor shall include language in competitive solicitation documents to give effect to the provisions of this subsection. Nothing in this subsection shall affect the rights and responsibilities of the Mayor and Chairperson following the award of any contract.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-23, §§ 1—3, 3-6-79; Ord. No. 81-35, § 1, 4-7-81; Ord. No. 88-121, § 1, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 90-133, § 1, 12-4-90; Ord. No. 91-32, § 2, 3-5-91; Ord. No. 92-45, § 5, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 93-112, § 1, 10-19-93; Ord. No. 95-178, § 1, 10-5-95; Ord. No. 95-201, § 1, 11-7-95; Ord. No. 97-52, § 2, 5-20-97; Ord. No. 97-104, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 98-31, § 1, 2-19-98; Ord. No. 98-42, § 1, 4-21-98; Ord. No. 99-162, § 1, 12-7-99; Ord. No. 00-30, § 1, 2-24-00; Ord. No. 00-65, § 1, 5-23-00; Ord. No. 00-67, § 1, 5-23-00; Ord. No. 01-94, § 1, 5-22-01; Ord. No. 01-96, § 1, 5-24-01; Ord. No. 02-24, § 1, 2-12-02; Ord. No. 02-122, § 1, 7-9-02; Ord. No. 03-67, § 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 04-64, § 1, 3-16-04; Ord. No. 05-15, § 1, 1-27-05; Ord. No. 05-17, § 1, 1-27-05; Ord. No. 05-147, § 1, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 06-16, § 1, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 07-42, § 1, 3-6-07; Ord. No. 07-76, § 1, 6-5-07; Ord. No. 07-143, § 1, 10-2-07; Ord. No. 08-79, § 1, 7-1-08; Ord. No. 08-81, § 1, 7-1-08; Ord. No. 09-52, § 1, 6-30-09; Ord. No. 09-55, § 2, 6-30-09; Ord. No. 10-40, § 1, 6-3-10; Ord. No. 10-47, § 1, 7-8-10; Ord. No. 11-67, § 1, 8-2-11; Ord. No. 11-90, § 1, 11-15-11; Ord. No. 12-55, § 1, 7-3-12; Ord. No. 12-107, § 2, 12-4-12; Ord. No. 13-02, § 1, 1-23-13; Ord. No. 13-67, § 1, 7-2-13)</history></law>