<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.1.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Nondiscrimination.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000087</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.1.5. Nondiscrimination.<section>Entities with annual gross revenues in excess of five million dollars ($5,000,000.00) seeking to contract with the County shall, as a condition of receiving a county contract, have: i) a written affirmative action plan which sets forth the procedures the entity utilizes to assure that it does not discriminate in its employment and promotion practices; and, ii) a written procurement policy which sets forth the procedures the entity utilizes to assure that it does not discriminate against minority- and women-owned businesses in its own procurement of goods, supplies and services. Such affirmative action plans and procurement policies shall provide for periodic review to determine their effectiveness in assuring the entity does not discriminate in its employment, promotion and procurement practices. The foregoing notwithstanding, corporate entities whose boards of directors are representative of the population make-up of the nation shall be presumed to have non-discriminatory employment and procurement policies, and shall not be required to have written affirmative action plans and procurement policies in order to receive a county contract. The foregoing presumption may be rebutted.</section><section>The requirements of this section may be waived upon written recommendation of the County Manager that it is in the best interests of the County to do so and approval of the County Commission by majority vote of the members present.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-30, ยง 1, 2-19-98)</history></law>