<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.1.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Program for expedited purchasing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000088</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.1.6. Program for expedited purchasing.<section>Notwithstanding any contrary provision of this Code, a program for expedited purchasing is hereby created, subject to the terms and conditions of this Section. The program shall be referred to as the "Expedited Purchasing Program."<section prefix='(a)'>The County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee is hereby authorized to utilize the Expedited Purchasing Program for the competitive purchase of supplies, materials and services, including professional services other than professional architectural, engineering and other services subject to Section 2-10.4 of this Code and Section 287.055 of the Florida Statutes, which are estimated to cost one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) or less.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For purposes of this Program, the County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall be expressly authorized to waive any irregularity in any bid or proposal submission which he or she determines to be non-material.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For any purchase to be made under the Expedited Purchasing Program, the County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall be authorized to issue competitive solicitation documents which in the discretion of the County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee procure the best value to Miami-Dade County for the goods or services to be purchased. The method of solicitation shall be determined in the discretion of the Mayor or County Mayor's Designee and may include, but not be limited to, invitations to bid, request for proposals or qualifications, negotiations, and best and final offers. In determining the best value to Miami-Dade County, the County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall consider criteria to include but not be limited to price, quality, experience, the ability to deliver the required goods and services, the availability of the goods and services, and the nature and urgency of the County's needs. The selection method and criteria to be used shall be set forth in the solicitation documents.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall make the final determination of best value in accordance with the method and criteria set forth in the solicitation documents. In making the determination of best value, the County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall utilize a review team of his or her technical and professional staff and of the County Attorney's Office for purchases made under the Expedited Purchasing Program.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall be authorized to award contracts pursuant to the determinations of best value made in accordance with this Section without further action of the Board, subject to bi-annual reports to the Board.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In the event the County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee determines at any time that a waiver of the competitive process for purchases greater than two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000.00) is in the best interests of the County, the Mayor or Mayor's County Designee shall make a written recommendation to the Board for such waiver.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The written recommendation of the County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee to award a contract under the Expedited Purchasing Program shall be sufficient to commence the bid protest period and terminate the Cone of Silence as provided elsewhere in this Code.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The protest of any award under the Expedited Purchasing Program shall be made in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-8.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall be authorized to advertise and issue solicitation documents for purchases under the Expedited Purchasing Program.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Any provisions of the Code or of any applicable resolution or administrative order contrary to the provisions of this section shall be deemed suspended or amended as necessary to give effect to the intent of this section. Similarly, any provisions of the Code or of any applicable resolution or administrative order not deemed suspended or amended hereunder shall apply to any purchase administered under the Expedited Purchasing Program.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The County Mayor may, by duly executed written instrument which specifically identifies this section, delegate any and all of the responsibilities set forth in this section, whereupon the provisions of this section and its limitations shall be understood to apply to the County Mayor's designee.</section><section prefix='(1)'>The County Mayor or County Mayor's Designee shall provide bi-annual reports to the Board of County Commissioners regarding the application of this Section for contract awards greater than two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000.00). The reports shall include a description of the goods and services procured, the procurement methodology, the existence and resolution of any bid protest, the identity of the awarded vendors and the amount of the contract awarded. The Commission Auditor shall include the Expedited Purchasing Program within his/her review of the County Mayor's or County Mayor's Designee's exercise of delegated authorities pursuant to Section 2-8.1(b).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-26, § 1, 1-27-05; Ord. No. 06-15, § 1, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 08-42, § 1, 4-8-08; Ord. No. 09-12, § 1, 3-3-09; Ord. No. 12-106, § 1, 12-4-12)</history></law>