<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.1.3</section_number>
<catch_line>[Printed publications]</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000085</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.1.3. [Printed publications]<section prefix='(a)'>Whenever any County department, agency, instrumentality or official prints, or causes to be printed, publications as defined in Subsection (b) hereof and which are paid for in whole or in part by County funds and which cost in excess of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00), including the cost of materials, labor and overhead, the department, agency, instrumentality or official shall report the true and actual cost of producing the publication, including materials, labor and overhead, to the County Manager. The County Manager shall report this printed information to the Board of County Commissioners on a monthly basis.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Publication includes all books, brochures, flyers, manuals, newsletters, pamphlets, programs, reports, and other like documents, and excluding:<section prefix='(1)'>All agenda items</section><section prefix='(2)'>All requests by the Mayor</section><section prefix='(3)'>All requests by County Commissioners</section><section prefix='(4)'>All legally required documents</section><section prefix='(5)'>All budget-related, bonding-related and financial disclosure documents, including, but not limited to, the annual proposed budget, annual external audit reports, quarterly budgetary reports, engineering reports, annual bond holder report</section><section prefix='(6)'>All documents required by grant funding agencies or paid by grant funds</section><section prefix='(7)'>All grant applications</section><section prefix='(8)'>All purchasing documents, including bid documents and RFP and RFQ documents</section><section prefix='(9)'>All audit reports</section><section prefix='(10)'>All reports from the Commission on Ethics and the Public Trust and the Inspector General</section><section prefix='(11)'>All documents of the Courts and the Clerk of the Courts</section><section prefix='(12)'>The County newsletter, "The County Chronicle"</section><section prefix='(13)'>All accounting reports</section><section prefix='(14)'>All recruitment advertising and other personnel documents, including, but not limited to, payroll and tables of organization</section><section prefix='(15)'>All electronic communications</section><section prefix='(16)'>All documents concerning quasi-judicial hearings, including all zoning-related documents</section><section prefix='(17)'>All procedural and operating manuals produced for internal use only</section><section prefix='(18)'>All Administrative Orders and the Administrative Order Manual</section><section prefix='(19)'>All documents related to litigation or any other adversarial process, including, but not limited to, court documents, briefs, opinions, affidavits, and zoning documents</section><section prefix='(20)'>All compilations of the Commission Rules of Procedure, the County Charter, the County Code, the Building Code, and Zoning Code</section><section prefix='(21)'>All statistical performance reports, including, for example and not limited to, reported crime statistics, the quarterly portfolio performance report, and the weekly report on construction products approved</section><section prefix='(22)'>All election-related documents and all voter registration documents, including, pollworker handbooks</section><section prefix='(23)'>Traveler, travel industry-related and trade-related documents including, but not limited to, Airport Guide, airport flight schedule, Top Ten Trading Partners, Cruise Guide, Seaport Directory and seaport cruise schedule</section><section prefix='(24)'>Tourism promotional materials</section></section><section>This list of excluded items may be amended at any time by resolution.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-89, §§ 1, 2, 7-27-99)</history></law>