<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.1.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Bids from related parties and bid collusion for the purchase of goods and services, leases, permits, concessions and management agreements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000081</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.1.1. Bids from related parties and bid collusion for the purchase of goods and services, leases, permits, concessions and management agreements.<section prefix='(a)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, where two (2) or more related parties each submit a bid or proposal for any County purchases of supplies, materials and services (including professional services, other than professional architectural, engineering and other services subject to section 2-10.4 and Section 287.055, Florida Statutes), lease, permit, licensing agreement, concession or management agreement, such bids or proposals shall be presumed to be collusive. The foregoing presumption may be rebutted by presentation of evidence as to the extent of ownership, control and management of such related parties in the preparation and submittal of such bids or proposals. Related parties shall mean bidders or proposers or the principals, corporate officers, and managers thereof which have a direct or indirect ownership interest in another bidder or proposer for the same agreement or in which a parent company or the principals thereof of one (1) bidder or proposer have a direct or indirect ownership interest in another bidder or proposer for the same agreement. Bids or proposals found to be collusive shall be rejected.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All bids or proposals submitted for any County purchases of supplies, materials and services (including professional services, other than professional architectural, engineering and other services subject to section 2-10.4 and Section 287.055, Florida Statutes), lease, permit, concession or management agreement must be genuine and not sham or collusive, or made in the interest or on behalf of any person not therein named, and the contractor may not have, directly or indirectly, induced or solicited any other proposer to put in a sham proposal, or any other person, firm, or corporation to refrain from proposing, and that the proposer has not in any manner sought by collusion to secure to the proposer an advantage over any other proposer. Any bid or proposal submitted in violation of this subsection shall be rejected and the proposer shall be subject to debarment and referred for prosecution.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A contractor recommended for award as the result of a competitive solicitation for any County purchases of supplies, materials and services (including professional services, other than professional architectural, engineering and other services subject to section 2-10.4 and Section 287.055, Florida Statutes), purchase, lease, permit, concession or management agreement shall, within five (5) business days of the filing of such recommendation, submit an affidavit under the penalty of perjury, on a form provided by the County stating either that the contractor is not related to any of the other parties bidding in the competitive solicitation or identifying all related parties, as defined in this section, which bid in the solicitation; and attesting that the contractor's proposal is genuine and not sham or collusive or made in the interest or on behalf of any person not therein named, and that the contractor has not, directly or indirectly, induced or solicited any other proposer to put in a sham proposal, or any other person, firm, or corporation to refrain from proposing, and that the proposer has not in any manner sought by collusion to secure to the proposer an advantage over any other proposer. In the event a recommended contractor identifies related parties in the competitive solicitation its bid shall be presumed to be collusive and the recommended contractor shall be ineligible for award unless that presumption is rebutted in accordance with the provisions of this section. Any person or entity that fails to submit the required affidavit shall be ineligible for contract award.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-32, ยง 3, 3-5-91; Ord. No. 08-113, ยง 1, 10-7-08)</history></law>