<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.2.7.01</section_number>
<catch_line>Miscellaneous Construction Contracts Program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000097</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.2.7.01. Miscellaneous Construction Contracts Program.<section prefix='(1)'>Policy: This ordinance, to be known as the Miscellaneous Construction Contracts Program ("MCC"), is intended to enhance the contracting opportunities of Community Small Business Enterprises ("CSBE") as defined in Section 10-33.02 and to facilitate and expedite the award of construction contracts to small businesses.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Scope: This Section, and the processes set forth herein, shall be applicable to the prequalifying, registration, award and construction of miscellaneous construction contracts designed to provide opportunities for Community Small Business Enterprises.</section><section prefix='(3)'>MCC participants shall be allowed to participate in two different contracting plans, with contracting procedures and specifications to be developed, maintained and amended by the Office of Capital Improvements ("OCI") specifically for these purposes, all in accordance with an Implementing Order ("IO") to be approved by the Board:<section prefix='(a)'>7040 Plan ("CSBE Rotational Set Aside Plan"):<section prefix='1.'>The Set Aside Plan shall be a 100 percent CSBE set aside. To qualify, participants must be certified by the Department of Small Business Development ("SBD") in their contracting trade.</section><section prefix='2.'>OCI shall establish and administer a rotational pool to distribute work among program participants in an equitable manner through competitive bids. The pool shall be designed to effect the maximum distribution of work among qualified firms, established in accordance with the contractor's license and abilities to do the work, all in accordance with the provisions of the IO.</section><section prefix='3.'>The SBD Review Committee shall establish an annual Community Workforce Program ("CWF") goal applicable to all contracts with construction costs of more than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00).</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>7360 Plan ("Open Competitive Plan"):<section prefix='1.'>Bidders under this plan shall be prequalified prior to award in forms to be developed for this purpose by IO.</section><section prefix='2.'>This plan shall be used whenever the funding source prohibits the use of CSBE set asides or when SBD determines that there is insufficient availability for a CSBE set aside within the 7040 Plan to accomplish the proposed work.</section><section prefix='3.'>This plan shall provide contract award opportunities to CSBEs through subcontracting.</section><section prefix='4.'>CWF goals shall be established for each award under the 7360 Plan by the Review Committee of the Department of Small Business Development.</section></section></section><section prefix='(4)'>The MCC Program shall be subject to an Overall Program Expenditure Limit ("OPEL") which is to be set by the Board of County Commissioners by resolution. OCI shall be authorized to allocate the OPEL among the plans as necessary. Individual awards within the plans shall be subject to the dollar limitations set forth in Section 2-8.1(b) of this Code. The first OPEL shall be the unexpended balance of the amount previously authorized by the Board by Resolution R-597-08.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County to the contrary, the Mayor or Mayor's designee shall have the following authority with respect to the Miscellaneous Construction Contracts Program:<section prefix='(a)'>To issue bid and proposal documents including addenda thereto;</section><section prefix='(b)'>To receive, open and review bids and proposals;</section><section prefix='(c)'>To make revisions to the MCC Contract and Program documents to address ambiguities and to make other clarifications as needed.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To award or reject bids for construction contracts and issue the Notice to Proceed on each where:<section prefix='1.'>Operational considerations, if applicable, have been reviewed and approved by the Office of Strategic Business Management; and</section><section prefix='2.'>The base value of a recommended award does not exceed the dollar limitations set forth in Section 2-8.1(b); and</section><section prefix='3.'>The contractor receiving the award is a registered vendor who is licensed, properly insured and in good standing with the County including, but not limited to: no outstanding debts; demonstrated acceptable past performance; and has submitted required insurance, bonds, affidavits and documentation provided for by the solicitation; and</section><section prefix='4.'>Participants have submitted a program participation application form.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>To negotiate and settle contractual disputes, and issue change orders for additional work: and</section><section prefix='(f)'>To terminate contracts in accordance with the contract documents.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>All actions taken by the Mayor or Mayor's designee under this section shall not require review by the Board of County Commissioners. The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall submit to the Board, on a quarterly basis, reports on the contracting activities during the previous quarter. These reports shall include the number of awards, total dollars awarded and CSBE activity.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Special Exemptions: This process shall be modified to ensure full conformance with any special provisions or review processes established by the Board. As such, any proposed County contract for a project that is funded in whole or in part by proceeds of the Charter County Transit System Sales Surtax shall be governed in accordance with the authority granted in Section 29-124 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. The County Mayor or Mayor's designee shall have the authority to advertise and issue bid or proposal documents for those contracts funded in whole or in part by proceeds of the Charter County Transit System Sales Surtax.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-101, ยง 1, 11-3-09)</history></law>