<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional information required from bidders or proposers seeking to demonstrate that joint venturer DBEs, BBEs, HBEs, WBEs, CBEs, CSBEs or small or local businesses will perform a commercially useful function in the work of a County contract.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000109</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-8.7. Additional information required from bidders or proposers seeking to demonstrate that joint venturer DBEs, BBEs, HBEs, WBEs, CBEs, CSBEs or small or local businesses will perform a commercially useful function in the work of a County contract.<section>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, whenever: i) a DBE contract goal; ii) a BBE, HBE, WBE, CBE or CSBE measure (other than a set-aside); or, iii) a small or local business participation requirement is applied to the bid or competitive process for award of a County contract, the County Manager shall include language in the specifications therefor requiring a bidder or proposer who seeks to meet such goal or measure by means of a joint venture in which a DBE, BBE, HBE, WBE, CBE, CSBE or small or local business is a joint venturer to submit a copy of the written joint venture agreement with the bid or proposal submission. The joint venture agreement shall specify the role of the DBE, BBE, HBE, WBE, CBE, CSBE or small or local business joint venturer and its principals in the overall ownership, control, management responsibilities, risks and profits of the joint venture. The joint venture agreement shall also specify a clearly defined portion of the contract work which the DBE, BBE, HBE, WBE, CBE, CSBE or small or local business joint venturer will be responsible to perform and the extent of time to be devoted by and personal involvement of the principals of such joint venturer therein. The foregoing information shall be considered in determining whether the DBE, BBE, HBE, WBE, CBE, CSBE or small or local business joint venturer will perform a commercially useful function in the work of the contract.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-04, ยง 1, 1-23-03)</history></law>