<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00080' order_by='00080' level='3'>ARTICLE LXIV. EMPOWERMENT PLANNING AND DEVELOPMENT TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-853</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers, duties and responsibilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000671</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-853. Powers, duties and responsibilities.<section>The trust shall have the following powers, duties, functions and responsibilities:<section prefix='(1)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting or relating to the Empowerment Zone and implementation of the Strategic Plan.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To recommend to the Board of County Commissioners, in accordance with the Strategic Plan, an annual budget and plan for use of the federal grant and other funds allocated to carry out the Strategic Plan to recommend to the Board of County Commissioners, in accordance with the Strategic Plan, the allocation of funds to public agencies, the award of contracts and grants to organizations, entities and agencies, including independent 501(c)(3) corporation and others. The Board of County Commissioners shall accept such recommendations unless rejected by an affirmative vote of a majority plus one additional vote of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All requests for proposals for such contracts and grants shall be prepared at the direction of the trust and issued by the County Manager. In addition, the County Manager shall collect and open such proposals, evaluate each proposal for responsiveness, rank all responsive proposals and make recommendations to the trust regarding the award of the contract or grant. In the event of a bid protest, the party protesting the bid award shall first appear before the trust. The trust shall consider the protest and make a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To review the Strategic Plan on a regular basis and at least annually to assure that the plan implementation is achieving Plan goals and addressing the needs of the Empowerment Zone communities.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To evaluate performance and recommend any needed amendments, delegation or modifications to the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners only shall have the power to amend the plan based upon changed circumstances.</section><section prefix='(6)'>To submit annually to the Board of County Commissioners and the City Commissions of Miami, Florida City and Homestead, a report summarizing and evaluating the performance of all programs and activities in the Strategic Plan during the previous fiscal year, including the timetable for performance. The report shall include an audit and accounting, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, of all funds received and expended.</section><section prefix='(7)'>To monitor, review, and evaluate Miami-Dade County's economic links to the Zone, including the airport and seaport and the direct benefit to the residents of the Empowerment Zone.</section><section prefix='(8)'>To submit reports required by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-143, ยง 3, 7-14-94)</history></law>