<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00080' order_by='00080' level='3'>ARTICLE LXIV. EMPOWERMENT PLANNING AND DEVELOPMENT TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-852</section_number>
<catch_line>Governing body.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000670</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-852. Governing body.<section prefix='(a)'>The governing body of the trust shall be a board of trustees composed of thirty-four (34) voting members. The trustees shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Composition. The voting membership of the board of directors shall be ethnically, racially and gender balanced, and dedicated to fulfillment of the goals of the Empowerment Strategic Plan. It shall be composed of the following members:<section prefix='(1)'>Twelve (12) members representing the Empowerment Zone communities of Liberty City/Model City; Wynwood; Overtown; Allapattah; Little Havana; and Homestead/Florida City. Each community shall select two (2) representatives.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Four (4) members representing eligible communities not included within the Empowerment Zone boundaries which participated in the development of the Strategic Plan. One representative shall be selected by each of the communities of Opa-Locka; Miami Beach; Goulds; and the community of Edison/Little River/Little Haiti.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners Committee on Finance, Budget and Empowerment Zone.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Mayor and City Manager of the City of Miami, who together shall have one vote.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Mayor and City Manager of Florida City, who together shall have one vote.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Mayor and City Manager of the City of Homestead, who together shall have one vote.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Mayor and City Manager of Miami Beach, who together shall have one vote.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Mayor and City Manager of Opa-Locka, who together shall have one vote.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Superintendent of the Miami-Dade County Public Schools and the chairperson of the School Board who together shall have one vote.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Four (4) members of the Empowerment Zone Opportunities Council which shall be selected by the Council to represent a cross-section of the Council including business, labor, education and community-based organizations.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Two (2) members of the Service Coordinating Council which shall be selected by the Council to represent the different fields of service affecting very young children; elementary and middle school children; adolescents; and youth.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The District Administrator of the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services for the district encompassing Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Two (2) representatives from the academic, non-profit or professional sectors, selected by the Chair of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(14)'>A student body president from a high school located within the Empowerment Zone shall be selected by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(15)'>The County Manager.</section></section><section>Vacancies on the Board of Trustees shall be filled in the same manner by which the original trustees were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community, and the segments of the community necessary to achieving the goals of the Strategic Plan.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Tenure and removal of trustees. All voting trustees shall serve staggered terms of three (3) years each; provided, however, of the original Board of Trustees, the trust shall select one-third () for a term of one year and one-third () for a term of two (2) years. No trustee, with the exception of ex officio trustees, shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by two-thirds () vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners. Trustees may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Qualifications. Each member of the Board of Trustees shall comply with the requirements of Chapter 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Ex officio members. The Board of Trustees may, from time to time, appoint ex officio members. The Directors of Miami International Airport, the Port of Miami and the Community Action Agency, the President of each campus of Miami-Dade Community College, and the chairperson of the South Florida Employment and Training Consortium shall serve as ex officio members.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Organizations and procedure.<section prefix='(1)'>Officers. The Board of Trustees shall organize after the members thereof have qualified to serve and shall select one (1) of its members as chairperson and such other officers as the Board of Trustees may determine to be necessary. In addition, the Board of Trustees shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Meetings. The Board of Trustees shall hold regular meetings and such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the trust shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the trust and all meetings shall be public.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Committees. The trust shall appoint any committees it deems necessary.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Applicability of County rules and procedures. The trust shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government Laws, including the "Sunshine Law," Public Meetings Laws and Public Records Laws and shall be governed by all state and county conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Voting requirements. Trustees may designate alternatives to serve and/or vote on their behalf.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-143, ยง 2, 7-14-94)</history></law>