<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE X. PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-86.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Appointment of litter enforcement officers; qualifications.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000226</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-86.1. Appointment of litter enforcement officers; qualifications.<section>The County Director of Parks and Recreation is hereby authorized to designate and appoint such employees of the Department of Parks and Recreation as he deems advisable as litter enforcement officers of the County, solely for the purposes of Section 403.413, Florida Statutes, also known as the Florida Litter Law.</section><section>The directors of any municipal park and recreation departments in the County are similarly authorized to designate and appoint such of their employees as they in their discretion deem advisable as litter enforcement officers of the county, solely for the purposes of Section 403.413, Florida Statutes, also known as the Florida Litter Law.</section><section>Such employees as are designated and appointed as litter enforcement officers by their respective directors of parks and recreation shall have the following qualifications:<section prefix='(a)'>They shall have attended a course of at least five (5) days' duration on the duties of litter enforcement officers jointly given or approved by the directors of the departments of public safety and parks and recreation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>They shall be personally approved and certified by the director of the Miami-Dade Police Department as persons of good moral character and standing in the community, and suited by temperament and learning to be litter enforcement officers of the County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-105, ยง 1, 11-18-75; Ord. No. 76-7, ยง 1, 1-20-76)</history></law>