<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. PUBLIC WELFARE DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-88</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000229</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-88. Powers and duties.<section>The Public Welfare Department shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Administer public assistance and care and child welfare programs.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Operate County welfare institutions for children, the aged and the infirm.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Accumulate and analyze data concerning the volume, nature, and cost of welfare programs, assemble data for State and national reporting systems, serve as liaison between the County and the reporting units of other public and privately sponsored welfare organizations, and conduct special research studies of welfare problems, programs and activities.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Inform the public of the operations and programs of the Department.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Perform specialized case work directed toward returning persons to self-support or self-care; provide employment and placement services; and be responsible for the conduct of a rehabilitation program for recipients of welfare services.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Administer programs of financial aid and care for families and unattached individuals in need, supplemental aid to persons on State public assistance or awaiting eligibility for State grants, and aid and service to nonresidents; certify eligibility for hospital care under the State hospital aid program.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Administer a program of assistance and care to adults and the aged; provide housekeeper and homemaker services, place adults and the aged in foster family homes; provide placement in boarding and nursing homes, including placement in voluntary nonprofit institutions, and certify cases for admission to the County home for the aged and infirm.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Accept for shelter in the Home for Dependent Children, maintained and operated by the County, any children who are referred to it by the Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Administer programs of housekeeper, homemaker, and day care services to children in their own homes where necessary and advisable as an alternative to placement in foster homes.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Place children in foster homes both directly and through voluntary agencies and the State Department of Public Welfare; provide adoption services, and place children needing special treatment or care in the County children's home or with other group care agencies.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-5, §§ 11.01, 11.06—11.09, 8-27-57)</history></law>