<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. PUBLIC WELFARE DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-88.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Effective date; superiority; filing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000232</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-88.3. Same—Effective date; superiority; filing.<section>The lien created hereunder shall be effective from the date the agreement for lien is filed in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court in the County in which real property owned by the recipient is located. Such lien shall secure the principal amount of all assistance paid from Miami-Dade County funds on or after September 1, 1959, whether paid before or after execution and filing of the agreement of lien. Said agreement shall be filed and cross-indexed in the same manner as other liens or judgments of record and if the property is located within Miami-Dade County the Clerk shall file such notice without cost to Miami-Dade County. Such agreement for lien shall be filed in each county in which a recipient owns real property. Such lien shall be superior to all subsequent liens except that the Miami-Dade County Welfare Director shall have authority to subordinate any lien created hereunder to a mortgage or lien created against the property of a recipient for necessary repairs or improvements to such property, and shall have authority to enter into an agreement with appropriate federal or State authorities claiming reimbursement for public assistance payments made pursuant to Chapter 409, Florida Statutes, to divide the lien proceeds, after deduction of costs, in proportion to contributions made by the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-11, § 3, 5-19-59)</history></law>