<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00082' order_by='00082' level='3'>ARTICLE LXVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY DOMESTIC VIOLENCE OVERSIGHT BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-892</section_number>
<catch_line>Governing body.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000679</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-892. Governing body.<section prefix='(a)'>Membership; compensation. The governing body of the board shall be composed of fifteen (15) voting members. Members shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Composition. The voting membership of the board shall be ethnically, racially and gender balanced and shall be composed of at least one person from each of the following categories:<section prefix='(1)'>Providers of services to domestic violence victims, including but not limited to a representative of Safe Space Shelter Inc.;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Domestic violence victim advocates;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Members of the judiciary, preferably a full-time, sitting domestic violence judge or a former or acting administrative judge of the domestic violence court;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Concerned citizens (at-large);</section><section prefix='(5)'>Victims of domestic violence;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Representatives of impacted jurisdictions; and</section><section prefix='(7)'>A representative of the Public Health Trust.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Appointment. Each member of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County shall appoint one (1) member to the board and the County Manager shall appoint two (2) members, one of which shall be a member of the law enforcement community.</section><section>Vacancies on the board shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Tenure and removal of board members. All board members shall serve terms of three (3) years each. No board member shall be permitted to serve more than two (2) consecutive and complete terms of three (3) years each unless so authorized by two-thirds () vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners. Board members may be removed in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Qualifications. Each member of the board must comply with the requirements of Section 2-11.38 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Organization and procedure.<section prefix='(1)'>Officers. The board shall organize after the members thereof have qualified to serve and shall elect one of its members as chairperson and such other officers as the board may determine to be necessary. In addition, the board shall make, adopt and amend bylaws, rules and regulations for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Meetings. The board shall hold regular meetings and such other meetings as it deems necessary. A majority of the members of the board shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the board and all meetings shall be public.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Committees. The board shall appoint any committees it deems necessary.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Applicability of county rules and procedures. The board shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-156, ยง 2, 9-13-94)</history></law>