<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. Miami-Dade POLICE DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-91</section_number>
<catch_line>Established; Director as head, appointment, term; organization and operating procedures; appointment, compensation of personnel; psychological testing of personnel.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000236</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-91. Established; Director as head, appointment, term; organization and operating procedures; appointment, compensation of personnel; psychological testing of personnel.<section prefix='(a)'>A Miami-Dade Police Department is hereby established.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The head of this Department shall be the Miami-Dade Police Director who shall also be known by the title of Metropolitan Sheriff. The Director shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the Manager.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The organization and operating procedures of the Department shall be described in administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Manager shall appoint such employees and other personnel as may be necessary to operate the Department. The salaries and compensation of all personnel, except employees within the classified service, shall be fixed by the County Commission upon recommendation of the Manager.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The County Manager, or his designee, shall within a reasonable time adopt rules or regulations for the formulation and implementation of valid and relevant psychological testing to be required of all applicants for employment as Police Officers in the Miami-Dade Police Department, and said rules or regulations shall further authorize such psychological testing of officers presently employed as shall be considered by the Manager upon the advice of the Miami-Dade Police Department and Director to be conducive to effective law enforcement and sound community relations.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-15, ยง 6.01, 5-6-58; Ord. No. 80-5, ยง 1, 1-22-80; Ord. No. 81-87, ยง 1, 7-21-81)</history></law>