<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. Miami-Dade POLICE DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-92.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Availability of records to public.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000239</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-92.2. Availability of records to public.<section prefix='(a)'>Files of internal investigations; procedures generally. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall designate a place where records or files of investigations conducted by the internal review section of the Miami-Dade Police Department shall be kept and maintained; the location thereof shall be disseminated to the public, and the public shall have free access thereto during normal business hours. Sufficient qualified personnel shall be assigned to such location to assist in locating and producing any such record or file for inspection or copying by any person making request therefor. Photographic copies of any such file or record, or portion thereof, shall be provided to any person upon request and upon payment by such person of the actual cost of duplication. All other expenses shall be borne by the County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Officer profiles. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall compile a profile on each officer in alphabetical order by name. Such profile shall indicate each and every commendation received by each officer and shall identify every complaint against the officer where the identity of the complainant is known. Such complaints shall be identified by the name of the complainant, nature of the complaint and case file number and indicate the disposition. This profile shall be available to the public pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Records not available. All public records exempt from statutory disclosure requirements by Florida Statutes, subsections 119.07(3), (4), and (5), as defined by Florida Statutes, subsections 119.011(3) and (4), shall be exempt from provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-4, ยง 3, 1-22-80; Ord. No. 81-87, ยง 1, 7-21-81)</history></law>