<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. Miami-Dade POLICE DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-92</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000237</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-92. Powers and duties generally.<section>The Miami-Dade Police Department shall:<section prefix='(a)'>Preserve the public peace, prevent crime, detect and arrest offenders, protect the rights of persons and property, and regulate and control traffic in accordance with the laws of this State and the ordinances of this County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Have all powers and perform all duties, powers and functions formerly exercised by the Sheriff of this County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Recruit and provide training for Department personnel.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Provide central records, investigation, and communications of police protection and require each municipality to furnish the department with all police records prescribed by the Director.</section><section prefix='(f)'>[Reserved].</section><section prefix='(g)'>Provide police protection in the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Perform such additional duties as may be prescribed by ordinance or by administrative orders and regulations of the Manager.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Charge and collect a fee for administrative services rendered for or on behalf of any person by furnishing copies of background investigations, photographs taken or processed by it, accident reports, and any other reports authorized to be furnished to members of the public; provided that a schedule of the type and amount of fees to be charged will be established in accordance with an administrative order governing the setting of such fees pursuant to Section 4.02 of the Miami-Dade County Charter. Any and all fees charged and collected by the Miami-Dade Police Department prior to enactment of this subsection [May 21, 1975], for the furnishing of those items enumerated in this subsection are hereby ratified, approved and declared to have been legal, proper and authorized.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-15, § 6.02, 5-6-58; Ord. No. 60-26, §§ 1, 2, 9-20-60; Ord. No. 66-37, §§ 9—11, 9-7-66; Ord. No. 68-79, § 2, 12-17-68; Ord. No. 72-60, § 1, 9-19-72; Ord. No. 75-32, § 1, 5-21-75; Ord. No. 81-87, § 1, 7-21-81)</history></law>