<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00084' order_by='00084' level='3'>ARTICLE LXVIII. AGRICULTURAL PRACTICES ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-931</section_number>
<catch_line>Creation; purpose; duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000685</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-931. Creation; purpose; duties.<section>There is hereby created and established an advisory board to be known as the Agricultural Practices Advisory Board. Its purpose shall be to review proposed or existing regulations or legislation pertaining to agricultural practices in Miami-Dade County, and to provide recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners with regard to such regulations and legislation.</section><section>The duties of the Board shall be to:<section prefix='(a)'>Evaluate on an ongoing basis all pertinent existing or proposed federal, state, regional and local regulations, statutes, ordinances and policies concerning or impacting the agricultural industry in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Provide recommendations for eliminating or reducing duplication of effort when two (2) or more governmental entities administer similar regulatory programs;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Provide recommendations for eliminating or modifying language in the Code of Miami-Dade County and/or regulatory activities that have mutually exclusive or contradictory criteria or goals;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Provide recommendations for eliminating or modifying language in the Code of Miami-Dade County and/or regulatory activities that create undue burden or hardship on the agricultural industry;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Provide recommendations for modifying or implementing provisions from any future or previously conducted study or plan that has the ability to impact the agricultural industry; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>Prepare draft language to the Board of County Commissioners amending relevant sections of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-03, § 1, 1-17-95; Ord. No. 96-14, § 1, 1-16-96; Ord. No. 96-181, § 1, 12-3-96; Ord. No. 98-16, § 1, 2-3-98; Ord. No. 08-101, § 1, 9-2-08)</history></law>