<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00084' order_by='00084' level='3'>ARTICLE LXVIII. AGRICULTURAL PRACTICES ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-935</section_number>
<catch_line>Vacancies; election of officers; committees; meetings and records.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000689</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-935. Vacancies; election of officers; committees; meetings and records.<section prefix='(a)'>Vacancies. If a vacancy occurs, it shall be filled by the Board of County Commissioners. The designated organizations listed in Section 2-933 shall submit at least one nominee from their respective organizations, including the nominee's resume and the minutes of the board meeting approving the nominee to the County Manager, who shall forward the nominee to the Board of County Commissioners in a timely manner. In the case where a member organization fails to submit a nomination for a replacement member within 45 days of notification of a vacancy, the Board shall propose a nominee to fill the vacancy. The nominee shall be approved at a meeting of the Board, and the Board shall forward the minutes approving such nominee, together with the nominee's resume, to the County Manager, who shall forward the nominee to the Board of County Commissioners in a timely manner.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Election of officers. The Board shall annually elect a Chairperson and Vice-Chairperson from among its members at the Board's last meeting of each calendar year, or at the first Board meeting after a vacancy may occur in such positions. The Chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which he or she is present. The Vice-Chairperson shall act as Chairperson in the absence or inability of the Chairperson.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Committees. The Board may establish or eliminate committees at its discretion; however, only two such committees may be in existence at any time. In no instance shall the authority to act or speak in the name of the Board be delegated to any committee. The Chairperson shall nominate and appoint the chairperson and members of such committees as the Board shall find helpful to their mission. The committee chairperson shall schedule committee meetings, set the agenda, establish guidelines for discussion at committee meetings, and ensure that committee meeting minutes are properly recorded. Committees shall consist of at least three (3) members appointed by the Chairperson. Fifty-one percent of a committee's membership shall constitute a quorum.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Meetings. The Board shall hold regular meetings at least bimonthly and at other times in consultation with the Director.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-101, ยง 2, 9-2-08)</history></law>