<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII. TRAFFIC AND TRANSPORTATION DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-95.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Traffic and Transportation Department created; duties, powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000244</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-95.1. Traffic and Transportation Department created; duties, powers.<section>There is hereby created and established the Miami-Dade County Traffic and Transportation Department.</section><section>The Traffic and Transportation Department is hereby empowered and shall have the duty and responsibility to perform, under the administrative direction and supervision of the County Manager, and in accordance with policies adopted by the Board of County Commissioners, the following functions:<section prefix='(a)'>Master plan. To provide, develop, maintain, improve, implement and enforce a comprehensive master plan for the control, regulation and appropriate movement of traffic for Miami-Dade County, Florida, including both the incorporated and unincorporated areas thereof.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Traffic-control devices. The planning, installation, operation and maintenance of all traffic control devices, including but not limited to, traffic signals, signs, markings and street name signs on all public streets.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Street uses, traffic regulations. To determine and designate arterial streets, residential streets, parkways, play streets, bus streets, scenic routes, bus routes, truck routes, one-way streets, alleys, service roads, speed zones, stop signs, crosswalks, safety zones, truck loading zones, passenger loading zones, taxi zones, bus loading zones, no-parking zones, restricted parking zones, time limit parking zones, school crossing zones, automatic signal devices, pedestrian signals, channelization, pavement markings, warning signs, yield right-of-way signs, advisory speed signs, turn restrictions, regulation and routing of overweight vehicles.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Traffic engineering. The Department shall have exclusive jurisdiction in respect to all matters of traffic engineering within the territorial areas of Miami-Dade County, subject only to the jurisdiction of the state road department in respect to state highways. For the purposes of this article, "traffic engineering" shall mean that phase of engineering which deals with the planning and geometric design of streets, highways, roads, alleys, or other places used for travel or parking of motor vehicles, and abutting lands, and with traffic operation thereon, as the use thereof is related to the safe, convenient, economical and feasible transportation of persons and goods.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Designation of lanes. To mark lanes upon the roadway of any street where it is deemed and determined that regular alignment of traffic is necessary in the interest of safety and efficiency, including no-passing lanes designated and indicated by double yellow lines. Where such traffic lanes have been marked, it shall be unlawful for the operator of any vehicle to fail or refuse to keep such vehicle within the boundaries of any such lane, except when lawfully passing another vehicle, where permitted, or preparatory to making a lawful turning movement.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Promulgation of regulations; control device testing. The department is hereby empowered to make all regulations necessary to effectuate the provisions of this article and the provisions of Chapter 30 of this Code, and to make temporary or experimental regulations, consistent with this article, to cover emergencies or special conditions. No such traffic regulation shall be effective or in force and effect until and unless adequate signs, signals or other notices or warnings are erected clearly indicating such regulation. The department may test traffic control devices under actual conditions of traffic.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Municipal traffic markings. The department shall assume full responsibility for the operation, maintenance and replacement of all existing signs signals, and markings now in use in the several municipalities, provided that the Traffic Director may at his discretion remove, change, or replace any such installation.</section><section prefix='(h)'>All night parking. The Traffic Director shall have the power and authority to prohibit all night parking upon any public street or portion thereof, and to prohibit the all night parking of trucks or other vehicles bearing commercial signs or advertising upon public streets in residential areas, and cause to be erected signs or markings giving notice of such traffic regulations, whenever such prohibition is necessary in the interest of public safety.</section><section prefix='(i)'>General. It shall be the general duty of the Department to plan and determine the installation and proper timing of all traffic control devices; to plan and direct the operation and movement of traffic on all public streets within Miami-Dade County; to conduct investigations of traffic conditions; to cooperate with other county, municipal and state officials and make recommendations for the improvement of traffic movement and conditions, including improvements in streets; and to perform duties and functions necessary to provide traffic engineering on a County-wide basis, commensurate with the provisions of this article.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-25, §§ 2, 3, 9-6-60)</history></law>