<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00088' order_by='00088' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXI. PROTECTION OF PERSONS DISCLOSING SPECIFIED INFORMATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-967.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure where complaint of retaliation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000706</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-967.7. Procedure where complaint of retaliation.<section prefix='(1)'>Any person protected by this article may file a written complaint within sixty (60) days after the action prohibited by this Article with the County Manager. The County Manager shall refer the complaint to the Independent Review Panel. The Independent Review Panel shall conduct a hearing after notice to the complainant, the respondent and the County department, political subdivision, special district or independent contractor involved. Any interested party may procure the attendance of witnesses and the production of records at such hearings in the manner provided by Section 2-50. All hearings requested pursuant to this paragraph shall be commenced insofar as is practicable within sixty (60) days of the County Manager's receipt of the complaint, except that the County Manager shall have the authority to extend such time for reasonable cause.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Independent Review Panel shall transmit its findings of fact, conclusions of law and any recommendation(s) together with the transcript of all evidence taken and all exhibits received by the Independent Review Panel to the County Manager for a final decision. The Manager may sustain, reverse or modify any action recommended by the Independent Review Panel. In any case in which the Independent Review Panel finds that the person filed a frivolous complaint in bad faith, the Independent Review Panel may direct the person to pay the costs of the hearing, including attorney's fees.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-41, ยง 1, 3-5-96)</history></law>