<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII. TRAFFIC AND TRANSPORTATION DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-96.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Jurisdiction declared exclusive; tampering with control devices prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000246</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-96.1. Jurisdiction declared exclusive; tampering with control devices prohibited.<section>From and after September 16, 1960, all traffic engineering services shall be performed by the traffic and transportation department, and such department shall have exclusive jurisdiction over all traffic control devices in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of the county, and shall have exclusive jurisdiction to exercise the powers, duties and functions set forth herein. All municipalities in Miami-Dade County are prohibited from exercising any such powers, duties and functions, and shall not interfere with the performance thereof by said county department; provided, however, that the County Manager or designee, in his/her sole discretion, may authorize municipalities, which desire and are equipped and able to perform certain traffic engineering functions, to assume, together with all liability and without additional cost to the County, through an individual Intergovernmental Agency Agreement, and for local municipal streets only, the installation and maintenance of regulatory and street name signs, warning signs, construction warning signs, markings and barricades, pavement markings, traffic maintenance and traffic calming devices, all as may be specifically provided in the Agreement and subject to performing appropriate traffic engineering studies if required by such Agreement. The Department shall, however, retain exclusive jurisdiction over the permanent closure of access to any road or street. It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation, or other legal entity, including municipal corporations, to change, modify, install, remove, damage, deface or destroy any traffic control device, unless authorized to do so by the traffic and transportation department, or by an Intergovernmental Agency Agreement.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-25, ยง 9, 9-6-60; Ord. No. 06-55, ยง 1, 4-25-06)</history></law>