<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00088' order_by='00088' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXI. PROTECTION OF PERSONS DISCLOSING SPECIFIED INFORMATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-967.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Persons protected.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000705</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-967.6. Persons protected.<section prefix='(1)'>This article protects persons who disclose information on their own initiative in a written and signed complaint; who are requested to participate in an investigation, hearing, or other inquiry conducted by the County, any state agency or federal government entity having the authority to investigate, police, manage, or otherwise remedy the violation or act; who refuse to participate in any adverse action prohibited by this article, or who are otherwise protected by the State Whistle-blower's Act. The provisions of this article may not be used by persons while they are under the care, custody, or control of the state or county correctional system, or after their release from the care, custody or control of the state or county correctional system, with respect to circumstances that occurred during any period of incarceration.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No remedy or other protection under this article applies to any person who has committed or intentionally participated in committing a violation or suspected violation for which protection under this article is being sought.</section><section prefix='(3)'>lt shall be an affirmative defense to any complaint brought pursuant to this article that the adverse action was predicated upon grounds other than, and would have been taken absent, the person's exercise of rights protected by this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-41, ยง 1, 3-5-96)</history></law>