<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00089' order_by='00089' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXIA. OFFICE OF CITIZEN ASSISTANCE AND OUTREACH ("TEAM METRO")</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-972</section_number>
<catch_line>Remedies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000716</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-972. Remedies.<section>In addition to any other remedies provided in this chapter, in of the Code of Miami-Dade County, or in any other applicable provision of the County Code, the Director shall have the following judicial remedies available for violations of this chapter or any other lawful rule or regulation promulgated hereunder.<section prefix='(1)'>Any person who violates a provision of this chapter or any lawful rule, regulation or written order promulgated under this chapter is subject to injunction or other equitable relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of this chapter. Further, such person is liable for any damage to Miami-Dade County caused by such violation, and for the reasonable costs and expenses incurred by Miami-Dade County in enforcing the provisions of this chapter, including but not limited to the costs of enforcement, inspections, preparation of enforcement reports, photographs, title searches, postage and other demonstrable administrative costs for enforcement and collection. All such sums shall become immediately due and payable upon expenditure by the County and shall become delinquent if not paid within thirty (30) days after receipt by the violator of the Department's bill itemizing the enforcement costs incurred in enforcing the provisions of this chapter (the "due date"). All such delinquent sums shall bear interest at the rate of twelve (12) percent per annum.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In addition to the foregoing, any person who violates a provision of this chapter or any lawful rule, regulation or written order promulgated under this chapter is subject to the judicial imposition of a civil penalty for each offense of an amount not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) per day per offense. In assessing the penalty, the court may receive evidence in mitigation. Each day during any portion of which a violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this State against any person and in favor of the Director or the County in any action to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of the provisions of this chapter, the court shall adjudge or decree against that person and in favor of the Director or the County a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney acting on behalf of the Director or the County in the suit in which recovery is had. This provision shall apply to all civil actions filed after the effective date of this ordinance. Cessation of the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter prior rendition of a judgment or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action has been filed by the Director or the County to enforce the provisions of this chapter, shall be deemed for the purpose of this section the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director or the County, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded as set forth in the Department's Administrative Order.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit or require the Director to bring an action on behalf of any private person.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-86, ยง 1, 6-4-96)</history></law>