<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIIA. NUISANCE ABATEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-98.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative findings and intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000253</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-98.4. Legislative findings and intent.<section>This article [Ordinance No. 92-42] is enacted pursuant to the provisions of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter and Florida Statute, Section 893.138, as it may be renumbered or amended from time to time, and shall be known and may be cited as the "Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Ordinance."</section><section>The Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, hereby finds and declares that any places or premises which are used as the site of the unlawful sale or delivery of controlled substances, prostitution, youth and street gang activity, gambling, illegal sale or consumption of alcoholic beverages, or lewd or lascivious behavior, may be a public nuisance that adversely affects the public health, safety, morals, and welfare. This Board also finds that abating the public nuisance which results from said criminal activity is necessary to improve the quality of life of the residents of Miami-Dade County and that said abatement will safeguard the public health, safety, and welfare.</section><section>This article is hereby declared to be remedial and essential to the public interest and it is intended that this article be liberally construed to effect the purposes as stated above. The provisions of this article and the standards set forth herein shall be applicable only to the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section>The provisions of this article shall be cumulative and supplemental to and not in deregation of any provision of the Florida Statutes, the Code of Miami-Dade County, or any other applicable law.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-42, ยง 1, 5-19-92)</history></law>