<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIIA. NUISANCE ABATEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-98.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Public Nuisance Abatement Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000256</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-98.7. Public Nuisance Abatement Board.<section>The Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Board is hereby created and established. The Board shall consist of nine (9) members with one member appointed by each County Commissioner.<section prefix='(a)'>Qualification of members. The composition and representative membership of the Board shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>All members shall reside in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>One (1) member shall be a law enforcement officer as defined in Florida Statutes, Section 943.10 who is retired or inactive and who is not employed by Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>One (1) member shall be an attorney practicing law in Miami-Dade County and a members in good standing of the Florida Bar.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Eleven (11) members of the general public, who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability, with interest or experience in abating public nuisances.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Terms of office. The initial appointments to the Board shall be as follows: Seven (7) members shall be appointed for the term of one year, six (6) members shall be appointed for the term of two (2) years. Thereafter all appointments shall be made for the term of two (2) years. No members shall serve more than three (3) consecutive terms or seven (7) years. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Board shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. A member may be removed with or without cause by the affirmative vote of not less than a majority of the entire County Commission. Should any member of the Board fail to attend three (3) consecutive meetings without due cause, the chairperson shall certify the same to the County Commission. Upon such certification, the member shall be deemed to have been removed and the County Commission shall fill the vacancy by appointment.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Organization of the Board. The members of the Board shall elect a chairperson and such other officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Board. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Meetings of the Board. Meetings of the Board shall be held monthly, or more frequently if necessary, to hear and dispose of the pending complaints. Notice of the time and place of meetings shall be given to all complaintants and owners of premises scheduled to be heard. Notice shall be given in writing at least ten (10) days prior to the hearing. Any aggrieved person may request a continuance of the hearing. The Board may grant a continuance of any hearing for good cause. The chairperson may call an emergency meeting of the Board, and meetings may also be called by written notice signed by three (3) members of the Board. The meetings of the Board shall be recorded and be transcribed at the expense of the party requesting the transcript. All meetings shall be in compliance with Florida's "Government in Sunshine Law" and Chapter 286.011, Florida Statute. No less than seven (7) members shall constitute a quorum. No less than six (6) members voting affirmatively shall be required to declare any place or premises a public nuisance under this provision. The County Manager shall provide adequate and competent clerical and administrative personnel, and such technical or scientific personnel as may be reasonably required by the Board for the proper performance of its duties. The County Manager shall provide a regular meeting place for the Board. All records shall be public records as defined by Chapter 119.011, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Conduct of hearings.<section prefix='(1)'>The Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department or his designee shall present cases before the Board. All parties shall have an opportunity to present evidence and argument on all issues involved, to conduct cross-examination and submit rebuttal evidence, and to be represented by counsel. When appropriate, the general public may be given an opportunity to present oral or written communications. If the Board proposes to consider such material, then all parties shall be given an opportunity to cross-examine or challenge or rebut it. The Board may consider any evidence, including evidence of the general reputation of the place or premises. All testimony shall be under oath and shall be recorded. Formal rules of evidence shall not apply, but fundamental due process shall be observed and shall govern the proceedings. Orders of the Board shall be based on competent and substantial evidence and must be based on a preponderance of the evidence.</section><section prefix='(2)'>After considering all evidence, the Board may declare the place or premises to be a public nuisance as defined in this chapter and may enter an order prohibiting:<section prefix='(i)'>The maintaining of the nuisance;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The operating or maintaining of the place or premises; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The conduct, operation, or maintenance of any business or activity on the premises which is conducive to such nuisance.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>An order entered under subsection (2) shall expire after one year or at such earlier time as stated in the order. The Board may retain jurisdiction to modify its orders prior to the expiration of said orders.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Board may bring a complaint under Section 60.05 of the Florida Statutes, seeking a permanent injunction against any public nuisance.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-42, ยง 4, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 94-11, ยง 1, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-84, ยง 1, 5-2-95)</history></law>