<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIIA. NUISANCE ABATEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-98.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Operating procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000255</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-98.6. Operating procedure.<section>Any employee, officer or resident of Miami-Dade County may file a complaint and request for prosecution with the Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Board regarding the existence of a public nuisance located within Miami-Dade County. Said complaint shall be filed with the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department, or his designee. Upon the filing of more than two (2) complaints on any particular place or premises, the Director or his designee shall mail written notice of such complaints by certified mail with return receipt to the owner of the place or premises complained of at the owner's address as shown in the Miami-Dade County property tax collector's file. Said notice shall provide for the owner of the place or premises to contact the Director or his designee within fourteen (14) days of receipt of the notice. This time period shall be allowed for the purpose of allowing the owner to take such good faith measures as are appropriate to abate the nuisance. The Director or his designee may extend the fourteen (14) days to allow the owner to institute or continue actions to abate the nuisance provided the actions are reasonable. In the event the owner fails to respond to Notice of Complaint or fails to take reasonable action to abate the nuisance, the Director or his designee shall schedule a hearing on the complaint before the Miami-Dade County Public Nuisance Abatement Board, and written notice of said hearing shall be by certified mail with return receipt to the owner of the premises and the complaintant at least ten (10) days prior to the scheduled hearing.</section><section>The aforesaid notice of hearing shall include:<section prefix='(a)'>A statement of the time, place and nature of the hearing;</section><section prefix='(b)'>A statement of the legal authority and jurisdiction under which the hearing is to be held;</section><section prefix='(c)'>A reference to the particular sections of the statutes and ordinances involved;</section><section prefix='(d)'>A short and plain statement summarizing the incidents complained of.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-42, ยง 3, 5-19-92)</history></law>