<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='2'>ARTICLE 2. MAYOR</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2.02</section_number>
<catch_line>RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE MAYOR.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000015</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 2.02. RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE MAYOR.<section>The Mayor shall serve as head of the county government with the following specific powers and responsibilities:<section prefix='A.'>The Mayor shall be responsible for the management of all administrative departments of the County government and for carrying out policies adopted by the Commission. The Mayor, or such other persons who may be designated by the Mayor, shall execute contracts and other instruments, and sign bonds and other evidences of indebtedness. The Mayor shall serve as the head of the County for emergency management purposes.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Mayor shall have the right to attend and be heard at any regular or special open session meeting of the Commission, but not the right to vote at such meetings.</section><section prefix='C.'>Unless otherwise provided by this Charter, the Mayor shall have the power to appoint all department directors of the administrative departments of the County. Appointment of these department directors shall become effective unless disapproved by a two-thirds majority of those Commissioners then in office at the Commission's next regularly scheduled meeting. The Mayor shall also have the right to suspend, reprimand, remove, or discharge any administrative department director, with or without cause.</section><section prefix='D.'>The Mayor shall within ten days of final adoption by the Commission, have veto authority over any legislative, quasi-judicial, zoning, master plan or land use decision of the Commission, including the budget or any particular component contained therein which was approved by the Commission; provided, however, that (1) if any revenue item is vetoed, an expenditure item in the same or greater dollar amount must also be vetoed and (2) the Mayor may not veto the selection of the chairperson or vice-chairperson of the commission, the enactment of commission committee rules, the formation of commission committees, or the appointment of members to commission committees. The Commission may at its next regularly scheduled meeting after the veto occurs, override that veto by a two-thirds vote of the Commissioners present.</section><section prefix='E.'>The Mayor shall prepare and deliver a report on the state of the county to the people of the county between November 1 and January 31 annually. Such report shall be prepared after consultation with the Commissioners.</section><section prefix='F.'>The Mayor shall prepare and deliver a budgetary address annually to the people of the county in March. Such address shall set forth the Mayor's funding priorities for the County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Am. of 11-2-10)</history></law>