<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='2'>ARTICLE 2. MAYOR</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2.03</section_number>
<catch_line>TEMPORARY TRANSFER OF MAYORAL POWERS AND RESPONSIBILITIES UPON A VACANCY OR INCAPACITY IN THE OFFICE OF MAYOR.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000016</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 2.03. TEMPORARY TRANSFER OF MAYORAL POWERS AND RESPONSIBILITIES UPON A VACANCY OR INCAPACITY IN THE OFFICE OF MAYOR.<section>Upon a vacancy or incapacity in the Office of Mayor and until such time as the vacancy is filled in accordance with of the Charter or the Mayor is no longer incapacitated, the powers and responsibilities vested by this Charter in the Office of Mayor to head the County for emergency management purposes, to hire department directors and to recommend waivers of competitive bidding shall be temporarily vested in the Office of the Chairperson of the County Commission as supplementary powers and responsibilities of such Office and shall not reside in the Office of Mayor. During such time, if the Chairperson relinquishes such supplemental powers and responsibilities in writing filed with the Clerk of the Board, such supplemental powers shall be vested in the Office of Vice-Chairperson of the County Commission. If the Vice-Chairperson relinquishes such supplemental powers and responsibilities in writing filed with the Clerk of the Board, such supplemental powers shall be vested in a commissioner chosen by a majority of those Board members present. The temporary removal and transfer of powers and responsibilities provided for in this Section shall not be construed to fill the vacancy in the Office of Mayor. Immediately upon filling the vacancy in the Office of Mayor the powers and responsibilities vested in the Office of Mayor shall be as provided in this Charter without regard to this Section. The Board shall by ordinance establish a definition of incapacity in the Office of Mayor for purposes of this Section.</section></section></text></law>