<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. INCORPORATION PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-29</section_number>
<catch_line>Municipal Advisory Committee—Creation and Limitation of Study Area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002782</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-29. Municipal Advisory Committee—Creation and Limitation of Study Area.<section prefix='(A)'>A Municipal Advisory Committee may only be created by ordinance of the Board in accordance with the provisions of this section to study and give advice to the County Commission regarding the creation of a proposed municipality. However, as of the effective date of this ordinance, no Municipal Advisory Committee shall be created by the County Commission, unless no less than twenty-five (25) percent of the resident electors in the area to be studied consent to the creation of a Municipal Advisory Committee on a consent form which shall be approved by the Office of Strategic Business Management. The signed consent forms shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. Upon submission of the signed consent forms, the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall submit the signed consent forms to the Department of Elections for certification as to the sufficiency of signatures on the consent forms. Upon notification of certification by the Department of Elections, the Clerk of the Board shall forward to the County Commission the signed consent forms of area residents and the certification of the sufficiency of the consent forms. Following public hearing, the County Commission may create a Municipal Advisory Committee by ordinance. It is provided, however, that where a Municipal Advisory Committee has been established, prior to the effective date of this ordinance, no consent of resident electors shall be required for the adoption of an ordinance creating a Municipal Advisory Committee involving the same study area. Upon receipt of the Municipal Advisory Committee report, which shall include findings of fiscal feasibility, evidence of desirability, and a plan for the development of a viable community, and upon motion of the district commissioner whose district comprises the majority of the proposed area to be incorporated, the Board of County Commissioners, at a regular meeting of the Board, may schedule the Municipal Advisory Committee report and resolution for consideration by the Planning Advisory Board.</section><section prefix='(B)'>In the event a Municipal Advisory Committee is created where part of the study area is outside the sponsoring Commissioner's district, such area shall automatically be excluded from the Municipal Area Committee's consideration.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The restriction set forth in Paragraph (B) may be waived by the Commissioner(s) whose district the study area comes within by filing a memorandum with the Clerk of the Board indicating consent to all or part of the study area.</section><section prefix='(D)'>This section shall apply to existing as well as to all future Municipal Advisory Committee's created after the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives.</section><section prefix='(E)'>The Municipal Advisory Committee shall complete the required feasibility and desirability study within twenty-four (24) months of its initial creation. If the Municipal Advisory Committee does not meet the required deadline, the Municipal Advisory Committee shall automatically sunset. Any Municipal Advisory Committee in existence as of the effective date of this ordinance shall include as part of its report a study of the feasibility and desirability of incorporating and shall be required to complete its study and submit the required report within twenty-four (24) months of the adoption of this ordinance. If a Municipal Advisory Committee in existence as of the effective date of this ordinance does not meet this required deadline it shall automatically sunset. It is provided however, in the event that the Board of County Commissioners adopts an ordinance which suspends the processing of incorporation requests, the calculation of the twenty-four (24) month period of time provided by this section shall be tolled during the pendency of such suspension.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Any public hearing held by the Board of County Commissioners to consider a proposed incorporation of an unincorporated area shall required that prior to such hearing the Office of Strategic Business Management provide the Board an updated Impact to the Unincorporated Municipal Service Area Analysis.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-130, § 1, 7-23-02; Ord. No. 03-128, § 1, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 05-140, § 4, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 07-177, § 2, 12-4-07)</history></law>