<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. INCORPORATION PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-27</section_number>
<catch_line>Future Municipalities' Elections.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002779</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-27. Future Municipalities' Elections.<section prefix='(A)'>As a condition of incorporation approval pursuant to Article V of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall conduct its regular election(s) to fill municipal elective offices as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For those municipalities that elect their officeholders in a single election without a provision for a run-off, elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in March of even numbered years.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For those municipalities that elect their officeholders by means of a primary election, used to narrow down the list of candidates to appear on the general election ballot, and a general election, primary elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in March of even numbered years and general elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in April of even numbered years. In those election years where it is not necessary to conduct a primary election, the general election shall be held on the second Tuesday in March.</section><section prefix='(3)'>For those municipalities that elect their office holders by means of a general election and a run-off election held for those races in which no candidate receives a majority of the votes cast in the general election, general elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in March of even numbered years and run-off elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in April of even numbered years.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The election dates specified in (A)(1)-(3) above shall not apply to the election or elections held to fill the municipal elective offices following the vote to approve the charter of a new municipality.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>As a condition of incorporation approval pursuant to Article V of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall provide a period for candidates for municipal elective office to file such qualifying papers and pay such fees as may be required by law with the applicable city clerk no earlier than noon on the first workday in January and no later than noon on the 14th day following the first weekday in January of the calendar year in which the election is to be held.</section><section prefix='(C)'>As a condition of incorporation approval pursuant to Article V of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall provide for all of its elections to be canvassed by a County Canvassing Board as provided under the election laws of this state.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-19, ยง 2, 1-20-04)</history></law>