<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. INCORPORATION PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-26A</section_number>
<catch_line>Process for Amending Pre-agreed Conditions of Incorporation in a Municipal Charter.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002778</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-26A. Process for Amending Pre-agreed Conditions of Incorporation in a Municipal Charter.<section prefix='(a)'>Any municipality which is desirous of amending the pre-agreed conditions to incorporation contained in its municipal charter shall request the County's approval of the proposed amended charter language indicating language to be added and deleted and stating the ballot question, prior to calling an election on the question of amending the municipal charter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The municipality shall submit the proposed amended charter language and ballot question to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners with copies to the County Attorney and County Manager for placement by the Clerk on the agenda of the appropriate committee. Upon review of the municipality's proposed amended charter language and ballot question, the Board of County Commissioners may direct the County Attorney to prepare a resolution approving such amendment for placement on a subsequent County Commission agenda.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the County Commission by resolution approves the proposed amended charter language and ballot question by an affirmative vote of two-thirds () of its members then in office, the municipality may consider and adopt a resolution calling an election on the proposed charter changes, subject to compliance with Section 5.03 of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-201, ยง 1, 11-30-04)</history></law>