<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. INCORPORATION PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-22</section_number>
<catch_line>Planning Advisory Board's consideration of petition for incorporation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002773</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-22. Planning Advisory Board's consideration of petition for incorporation.<section prefix='(A)'>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, prior to transmittal to the Planning Advisory Board, shall request the directors of all other applicable County departments to review and comment on the incorporation petition with respect to their areas of expertise and responsibility.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The Director of the Office of Strategic Business Management, upon receipt of comments and information from other departments, shall prepare a report on the petition containing the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>Summary of petition,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Socio-economic profile of area,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Development profile of area,</section><section prefix='(4)'>Any Municipal Advisory Committee Report, and</section><section prefix='(5)'>Other information outlined in Section 20-23(B)(1),</section></section><section>The report shall be transmitted to the Planning Advisory Board.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The Planning Advisory Board, upon receipt of a petition and appropriate County department staff review and comment shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Create a five-member committee of the Planning Advisory Board appointed by its chair for the purpose of studying and making a recommendation to the full Board on the petition. The chair of the Planning Advisory board shall designate a chair for such committee. In making its report and recommendation to the full Board the committee shall utilize the guidelines set forth in subsection (4).</section><section prefix='(2)'>Conduct a properly advertised public hearing within the area proposed for incorporation.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Require additional information from appropriate County departments as needed.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Make written recommendations with respect to the petition and any Municipal Advisory Committee Report which shall include the following:<section prefix='(a)'>An analysis of the issues outlined in Section 20-23(B);</section><section prefix='(b)'>Whether the proposed incorporation:<section prefix='(1)'>will divide a historically recognized community;</section><section prefix='(2)'>is compatible, to the degree possible, with existing planned land uses and zoning of the areas surrounding the proposed municipality;</section><section prefix='(3)'>will, if currently qualified, continue to be eligible for any benefits derived form inclusion in federal or state enterprise zones, or targeted area assistance provided by federal, state and local government agencies;</section><section prefix='(4)'>will impact public safety response times;</section><section prefix='(5)'>creates barriers to municipal traffic circulation due to existing security taxing districts, walled communities and/or private roads;</section><section prefix='(6)'>if identified by the federal government as a flood zone or by emergency planners as an evacuation zone, has the proposed municipality indicated its preparedness to address any extraordinary needs that may arise;</section><section prefix='(7)'>to the degree possible, will be contained in one or more school district boundaries governing admission to elementary, middle and high schools.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Other considerations deemed relevant by the Board</section></section></section><section prefix='(D)'>The Planning Advisory Board recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners shall be either:<section prefix='(1)'>Approval of the petition;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Approval of the petition on a modified basis;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Deferral of the petition for more information;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Deferral of the petition to permit modification; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Denial of the petition.</section></section><section prefix='(E)'>The Director of the Office of Strategic Business Management shall forward the petition and recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board as well as the Municipal Advisory Committee Report, to the County Manager for review and recommendation. The County Manager shall transmit the Manager's recommendation, the petition, the recommendation of the Planning Advisory Board, as well as the Municipal Advisory Committee Report, to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(F)'>The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, upon receipt of the recommendations by the Planning Advisory Board and County Manager, shall set the matter of such proposed incorporation for public hearing at a regular meeting of the County Commission and cause notice of such public hearing to be published in a daily newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least once not less than one (1) week prior to the date of such public hearing. Notice of such public hearing shall be furnished to all property owners within the area and within six hundred (600) feet thereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-78, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-176, § 2, 10-5-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 13, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 01-168, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 05-86, § 3, 5-3-05; Ord. No. 05-140, § 3, 7-7-05)</history></law>