<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. INCORPORATION PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-20</section_number>
<catch_line>Petition for incorporation initiated by individual or group; Creation of Municipal Advisory Committee related to petition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002770</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-20. Petition for incorporation initiated by individual or group; Creation of Municipal Advisory Committee related to petition.<section prefix='(A)'>An individual or group of area residents may file a request for approval of the form of a petition and authorization to circulate such petition for incorporation with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners.<section prefix='(1)'>The petition form shall provide for the following information about the proposed municipality:<section prefix='(a)'>General description and map of area boundaries, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Statement of the reason for seeking incorporation.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall report to the Commission that a request to approve the form of a petition for incorporation and authorize the circulation of such petition has been received. The Board of County Commissioners may approve the form of the petition and may authorize the petitioners to circulate the petition for incorporation and obtain signatures of resident electors within the area.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In order for the submitted petition to be complete, the petition shall include consent from no less than twenty-five (25) percent of the electors in the area proposed for incorporation.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Signed petitions shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board within 90 days of the date the County Commission approves the form and authorizes the circulation of the petition in order for the petition to receive any further review or consideration by the County. Petitioners should submit any resolutions of support or opposition, if any exist, from the closest existing municipality within such 90 day period.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall upon receipt of a petition for incorporation transmit a copy to the Office of Strategic Business Management for determination of completeness in accordance with the requirement of subsection (A)(1) and to the Department of Elections for certification as to the sufficiency of signatures on the petition. Upon determining that the petition is complete and that a sufficient number of valid signatures has been obtained, the Office of Strategic Business Management shall notify the Clerk of the Board of such occurrence.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners shall notify the County Commission that the petition is complete and contains sufficient signatures. Upon notification of the completeness and sufficiency of the petition and upon sponsorship of the County Commissioner whose district comprises the majority of the area proposed to be incorporated by the petition, the Board of County Commissioners may create a Municipal Advisory Committee ("MAC"), which shall carry out the functions set forth in the resolution or ordinance creating the MAC and be subject to the requirements of Section 20-29 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (the "Code"), excluding the requirement of consent of resident electors. Notwithstanding the creation of a MAC, the procedures for consideration of a petition set forth in Section 20-20
                     et seq. of the Code shall apply. If the boundaries in the completed petition differ from the boundaries of the MAC study area, the boundaries of the MAC study area shall supplant and be substituted for the boundaries included in the petition; provided, however, 25% of the electors residing within the boundaries as revised to conform to the MAC study area shall have signed the completed petition indicating their interest in incorporating the area.</section><section prefix='(D)'>The requirement of filing a petition for incorporation pursuant to Sec. 20-20 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (the "Code") and the procedures for such filing contained in Sec. 20-21(A) of the Code shall not apply to incorporation proposals by the County Commission or County Manager. It is provided, however, that a Commission or Manager-initiated incorporation proposal shall be deemed a petition for proposed incorporation for purposes of Section 20-21; 20-22, and 20-23 and shall be required to comply therewith. Notwithstanding Section 20-23A herein, the Board of County Commissioners may hold a public hearing on a Commission initiated incorporation proposal during any regular or special meeting of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-78, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-131, § 1, 7-13-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-136, § 1, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 13, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-124, § 1, 10-3-00; Ord. No. 01-168, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 01-183, § 1, 11-6-01; Ord. No. 05-140, § 1, 7-7-05)</history></law>