<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. INCORPORATION PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-26</section_number>
<catch_line>Future Municipalities' Obligations to the County.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002777</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-26. Future Municipalities' Obligations to the County.<section prefix='(a)'>As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include a provision in its charter and shall agree to remain a part of the Miami-Dade County Fire-Rescue District and the Miami-Dade County Library System in perpetuity.</section><section prefix='(b)'>As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include a provision in its charter and shall agree in perpetuity to contract with the Miami-Dade County Police Department ("MDPD") and pay for specialized police services from its municipal millage or other municipal funds. For purposes of this subsection, specialized police services include, but are not limited to, narcotics, criminal intelligence, economic crimes, homicide, robbery, sexual crimes, environmental crimes, domestic crimes, and crime scene investigations; property and evidence efforts; tactical operations activities; and aviation patrol.</section><section prefix='(c)'>As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include a provision in its charter and shall agree to contract with the Miami Dade County Police Department ("MDPD") and pay for local patrol police services for three years or such longer period of time as may be requested by the municipality.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The fiscal impact of an incorporation on the remainder of the unincorporated area shall be revenue neutral; provided, however, any municipality which does not meet the foregoing requirement, as a condition of incorporation pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, shall agree to make an annual mitigation payment to the County's Municipal Services Trust Fund in the Unincorporated Municipal Service Area Budget, the amount of which shall be determined by the Board of County Commissioners, in the event of a negative fiscal impact of the municipality's incorporation on the unincorporated area. For purposes of this subsection, "a revenue neutral municipality" is defined as an area that previously, as part of the unincorporated municipal service area, generated revenues equal to or less than the cost of services provided to the area by the County. Any annual mitigation amount determined by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to the provisions of this paragraph shall be established so as not to trigger "most-favored-nation-status" clauses which are contained in any municipal charter.</section><section prefix='(e)'>As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall include in its charter that such municipality shall be responsible for (i) its pro-rata share of any County debt outstanding at the time the municipality incorporates and with respect to the Stormwater Utility, outstanding at the time the municipality elects to be separate from the Stormwater Utility through an interlocal agreement or by exemption and (ii) its prorata share of any refunding of such debt. The municipality's annual pro-rata share of debt service shall be determined by multiplying the total debt service in each Fiscal Year by the municipality's percentage share of pledged revenues (revenues pledged by the County to the repayment of the debt). The municipality's percentage share shall be determined by dividing the pledged revenues collected within the municipality during the County's Fiscal Year in which municipality incorporates, and with respect to the Stormwater Utility in the Fiscal Year in which the municipality elects to separate from the Stormwater Utility district; by the total pledged revenues collected in that same Fiscal Year. It is further provided that the municipality's charter shall authorize the County to continue to collect and distribute the pledged revenues in a manner that is consistent with the requirements of the debt and shall recognize the municipality's obligations pursuant to this subsection.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Board of County Commissioners may by way of resolution allow the distribution of existing unincorporated bond proceeds to municipalities created after September 1, 2000 for the same type of project originally described in the bond documents.</section><section prefix='(g)'>As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article I of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality, as a part of its charter, shall provide for adoption of Miami-Dade County's workforce housing development program established at Chapter 33, Article XIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended, provided, however, that any municipality may establish and enforce more stringent regulations as necessary to ensure provision of workforce housing units within its jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(h)'>As a condition of incorporation approved pursuant to Article VI of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, each new municipality shall provide, as a part of the charter, that the Board of County Commissioners retains jurisdiction over the modification or deletion of declarations of restrictive covenants accepted by either the Board of County Commissioners or a Community Zoning Appeals Board in connection with a Comprehensive Development Master Plan application or zoning application, regardless of whether such declaration provides for modification or deletion by a successor governmental body. It is provided, however, that the Board of County Commissioners may not exercise such jurisdiction unless the applicable municipality has first approved the modification or deletion.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-26, § 2, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 05-97, § 2, 5-17-05; Ord. No. 05-98, § 1, 5-17-05; Ord. No. 05-142, § 2, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 07-05, § 20, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08; Ord. No. R-13-06, § 2, 1-23-13)</history></law>