<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. INCORPORATION PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-23</section_number>
<catch_line>Board of County Commissioners consideration of proposed incorporation petition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002774</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-23. Board of County Commissioners consideration of proposed incorporation petition.<section prefix='(A)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall only hold a public hearing on the petitions for incorporation during the period between September 1 and September 30 inclusive and during the period between March 1 and March 31 inclusive in each year, which shall be conducted as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Persons requesting incorporation shall make a presentation outlining the merits of their petition,</section><section prefix='(2)'>The County Commission shall consider and review the recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board and the County Manager, and</section><section prefix='(3)'>The County Commission shall hear from any other interested persons.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>At the conclusion of the public hearing the Board of County Commissioners, in evaluating the appropriateness of a petition for incorporation, shall consider the following guidelines:<section prefix='(1)'>The suitability of the proposed boundaries to provide for a municipal community of interest that is both cohesive and inclusive. Specifically, the area should:<section prefix='(a)'>Not divide a U.S. Census Designated Place, to the extent feasible.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Include adjacent areas of ethnic minority and lower income residents in which a majority of those residents have so petitioned.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Have contiguity and not create any unincorporated enclave area(s). An unincorporated enclave area is defined as an area that would be 1) surrounded on more than eighty (80) percent of its boundary by one (1) or more municipalities and of a size that could not be serviced efficiently or effectively.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Have natural or built barriers as boundaries, to the extent feasible, and</section><section prefix='(e)'>Include a mixture of residential and non-residential land uses.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Evidence of support of area residents and property owners sufficient to warrant the costs of balloting of electors,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Existing and projected property tax costs for municipal-level services to average homeowner in the area as currently unincorporated and as incorporated as a comparable Miami-Dade County city with a similar per capita property tax base.</section><section prefix='(4)'>There are no suitable alternatives to incorporation, including annexation to an existing municipality,</section><section prefix='(5)'>Is totally contained within the Urban Development Boundary depicted on the future Land Use Plan map of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan,</section><section prefix='(6)'>The impact of the proposal, as updated by the Office of Strategic Business Management prior to the public hearing, on the revenue base of the unincorporated area, and on the ability of the County to efficiently and effectively provide services to adjacent remaining unincorporated areas, including the potential for the area to:<section prefix='(a)'>Continue to participate in the County's Fire-Rescue and Library Districts, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Contract with the County for other municipal services,</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Potential revenue sources and facilities to be made available to the proposed municipality upon incorporation, and</section><section prefix='(8)'>The financial impacts of the proposed incorporation on the remaining unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. Specifically in order to insure fiscal equity the per capita taxable property value of the area proposed for incorporation should fall between twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) and forty-eight thousand dollars ($48,000.00) in order to assure that fiscal viability is maintained in both the potential new municipality and the remaining unincorporated area.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Any other factor that arises by virtue of recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board, pursuant to Section 20-22 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Any other factor that arises by virtue of any special or unique circumstances of a given area.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall at the conclusion of the public hearing take one (1) of the following actions:<section prefix='(1)'>Call for the election of the area electors on the incorporation petition as presented by the applicant(s),</section><section prefix='(2)'>Call for the election of the area electors on the incorporation petition as modified with respect to boundaries or other aspects,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Deny the proposed incorporation petition, or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Defer such petition for further consideration by the applicant(s), Board of County Commissioners, the County Manager or the Planning Advisory Board.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-78, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-131, § 1, 7-13-95; Ord. No. 95-176, § 2, 10-5-95; Ord. No. 02-99, § 1, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 05-86, § 3, 5-3-05; Ord. No. 07-177, § 1, 12-4-07)</history></law>