<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. BOUNDARY CHANGE PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Initiated by governing body of municipality.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002752</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-3. Initiated by governing body of municipality.<section>Any proposed boundary change desired by the governing body of a municipality shall be initiated by resolution of such governing body adopted after a public hearing held pursuant to written notice mailed to all owners of property within the area and within six hundred (600) feet thereof in such proposed boundary changes, according to the current tax assessment roll, and pursuant to published notice; provided, however, that no notice shall be required when all owners of property within the area and within six hundred (600) feet thereof shall consent in writing to the proposed boundary change. The cost of such notice shall be paid by the governing body of the municipality. Three (3) duly certified copies of such resolution requesting the proposed boundary changes, together with proof of compliance with the notice requirements aforesaid, shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission, and shall be accompanied by the following:<section prefix='(A)'>An accurate legal description of the lands or land area involved in such proposed boundary change.</section><section prefix='(B)'>A map or survey sketch accurately showing the location of the area involved, the existing boundaries of the municipality or municipalities affected, and indicating the relation of the area involved to the existing municipal boundaries.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Certificate of the County Supervisor of Registration certifying that the area involved in the proposed boundary change contains either more than two hundred fifty (250) residents who are qualified electors, or less than two hundred fifty (250) residents who are qualified electors.</section><section prefix='(D)'>A brief statement setting forth the grounds or reasons for the proposed boundary changes.</section><section prefix='(E)'>A statement declaring whether an enclave, as defined in Section 20-7(A)(1)(c), borders the municipality and whether the proposed boundary change includes such enclave.</section><section prefix='(F)'>In addition to the foregoing, there shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>Land use plan and zoning. The municipality shall present a general land use plan and a map showing proposed zoning for the subject area which, if annexed, will be enacted by the municipality. This information shall be submitted regardless of size of area or state of existing development.</section><section prefix='(2)'>List of services to be provided. In this section the municipality shall describe in detail the character and amount of services which the municipality would provide to the area if annexed. The discussion of service levels shall take into account not only existing development but changes in the character and extent of development which may be reasonably anticipated in the near future based on the land use plan and zoning for the area as submitted by the municipality in accordance with (1) above. The statements pertaining to the various services shall be set forth under the headings listed below. The character and amount of services now being received in the area sought for annexation shall be set forth for comparative purposes.<section prefix='(a)'>Police protection.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Fire protection.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Water supply and distribution.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Facilities for the collection and treatment of sewage.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Garbage and refuse collection and disposal.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Street lighting.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Street construction and maintenance.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Park and recreation facilities and services.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Building inspection.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Zoning administration.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Local planning services.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Special services not listed above.</section><section prefix='(m)'>General government.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Timetable for supplying the services listed above. For each of the services listed the time schedule for the provision of that service shall be set forth. The timetable shall be in terms of how soon after the annexation ordinance is finally adopted will the service be provided. If changes in the character and extent of the development in the area can reasonably be anticipated, these changes shall be taken into account in the proposed timetable.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Financing of the services listed above. For each of the services listed above, estimates of the costs of providing, maintaining and operating the service shall be set forth along with the methods used in making the estimates. The sources of funds which the municipality would utilize in providing, maintaining and operating the services listed shall be stated for each service and the effect this will have on the remainder of the municipality shall be analyzed.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The tax load on the area to be annexed. This section of the report shall discuss in narrative form, including estimated figures, the direct and indirect tax revenue from the area sought for annexation after annexation compared with the current period before annexation. Particularly this section shall clearly and concisely appraise the tax impact on the property owners and others residing and/or doing business in the area, and on those residing and/or doing business within the municipality. Methods utilized in making estimates contained in this section shall be fully and clearly set forth.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Identification of any areas designated as terminals in the County's Adopted Land Use Plan Map ("terminals"). The municipality shall set forth the following information in its annexation petition or shall supplement its annexation petition, if such petition is pending as of the effective date of this ordinance:<section prefix='a.'>The reason that any area designated terminals and areas located within one-half (½) mile surrounding any area designated terminals ("surrounding areas") should be annexed to the municipality;</section><section prefix='b.'>The impact that annexation may have on the operation and future development of facilities within any area designated terminals and surrounding areas;</section><section prefix='c.'>The municipality's assessment of the present and future importance to the economy, job generation, and future development of the County and the region of any area designated terminals and surrounding areas proposed to be included in the area annexed;</section><section prefix='d.'>Whether the land uses within areas designated terminals and surrounding areas are compatible with adjacent land uses within the annexing municipality; and</section><section prefix='e.'>A proposed Interlocal Agreement with the County which would include provisions agreeing to the County's retention of master plan and regulatory control over any area designated terminals and surrounding areas, which shall set forth with specificity the limitations and conditions to be imposed on the municipality's jurisdiction of the area proposed for annexation.</section></section></section><section prefix='(G)'>Certificate of the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning certifying that in the Director's sole determination an area proposed for annexation or separation having two hundred and fifty (250) or fewer registered electors is more than fifty (50) percent developed residential. This certification will determine whether an election of registered electors will be required as provided in Section 20-9</section><section prefix='(H)'>A petition filed with the Clerk of the County Commission indicating the consent of twenty-five (25) percent plus one (1) of the electors in the area proposed for annexation provided however, no petition shall be required where the property proposed for annexation is vacant or where there are two hundred fifty (250) or less resident electors.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-42, § 3, 11-29-60; Ord. No. 64-21, § 1, 5-19-64; Ord. No. 66-60, § 1, 11-15-66; Ord. No. 70-2, § 2, 1-7-70; Ord. No. 96-39, § 1, 2-20-96; Ord. No. 96-73, § 1, 5-21-96; Ord. No. 96-136, § 1, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 01-168, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 05-112, § 2, 6-7-05; Ord. No. 07-176, § 1, 12-4-07)</history></law>