<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY COUNCILS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-43.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Community Councils; recall.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002788</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-43.1. Community Councils; recall.<section>Any elected member of a Community Council or any member appointed by the Community Council pursuant to(A)(7) may be removed from office by the electors of the Council area. The procedure for removal by electors shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>The person proposing the exercise of recall shall submit the recall petition to the Clerk of the Circuit Court for approval of the form of the petition. Recall petitions shall be submitted for approval during the months of January and June only.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The person or persons circulating the recall petition shall, within sixty (60) days after approval of the form of the petition, obtain the valid signatures of electors in the council area in numbers at least equal to ten (10) percent of the registered voters in the council area on the date on which the recall petition is approved, according to the official records of the County Supervisor of Elections. Each signer of a petition shall place thereon, after his or her name, the date and the signer's place of residence or precinct number. Each person circulating a copy of the petition shall attach to it a sworn affidavit stating the number of signers and the fact that each signature was made in the presence of the circulator of the petition.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The signed petition shall be filed with the Clerk of the Circuit Court which shall within thirty (30) days after filing order a canvass of the signatures thereon to determine the sufficiency of the signatures. If the number of signatures is insufficient or the petition is deficient as to form or compliance with this section, the Clerk shall notify the person filing the petition that the petition is insufficient and has failed. The Clerk shall certify the petition if the number of signatures is sufficient and the petition if sufficient as to form and compliance with this section.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Board of County Commissioners must provide for a recall election not less than forty-five (45) days nor more than ninety (90) days after certification of the petition.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The question of recall shall be placed on the ballot in a manner that will give the elector a clear choice for or against the recall. The result shall be determined by a majority vote of the electors voting on the question.</section><section prefix='(6)'>If the majority is against recall the Community Council member shall continue in office under the terms of the member's previous election or appointment. If the majority is for recall, the member shall, regardless of any defect in the recall petition, be deemed removed from office immediately.</section><section prefix='(7)'>No recall petition against an elected Community Council member shall be certified within one (1) year after the member takes office nor within one (1) year after a recall petition against the member is defeated.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Any vacancy created by recall in a Community Council shall be filled for the remaining term by appointment in the manner prescribed for filling vacant positions.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-196, ยง 1, 11-4-97; Ord. No. 01-72, ยง 1, 4-10-01)</history></law>