<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY COUNCILS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-44</section_number>
<catch_line>Community Councils; organization; new member orientation; Community Council workshop.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002790</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-44. Community Councils; organization; new member orientation; Community Council workshop.<section prefix='(A)'>The County Manager shall assign existing County staff positions to provide support for the Community councils, to the fullest extent feasible. Such staff may include: a Community Council Administrator, an Administrative Assistant, clerical staff and others as the County Manager deems needed. Team Metro shall develop strong linkages to each Community Council.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The County Manager shall coordinate the activities and schedules of Community Councils with other County activities to ensure maximum effectiveness and efficiency. The County Manager may limit the total staff time available to each Community Council.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Within parameters recommended by the County Manager and approved by the County Commission, Community Councils shall be empowered to establish their own procedures for conducting their business and to select from the activities described in Section 20-41(B) those in which it wishes to engage. It is provided however that zoning procedures shall be adopted pursuant to Sections 33-308 of the Code. It is further provided that no zoning or non zoning meeting of a Community Council or Community Zoning Appeals Board shall extend beyond 11:00 p.m.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Prior to serving on a Community Council, a Community Council member appointed or elected to a Council after the effective date of this ordinance shall attend a New Member Orientation Seminar conducted by the Department of Planning and Zoning, the Commission on Ethics, Team Metro and the County Attorney's Office. The seminar shall include, but shall not be limited to, review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, review of zoning regulations, incorporation and annexation issues, workforce and affordable housing issues and applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Community Council members.</section><section prefix='(E)'>All Community Council members shall attend in every even-numbered year a Community Council Workshop organized and conducted by the Department of Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement, the Department of Permitting, Environment and Regulatory Affairs, the Commission on Ethics, and the County Attorney's Office. The Workshop shall include, but shall not be limited to, review of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and issues related thereto, review of zoning regulations, incorporation and annexation issues, workforce and affordable housing issues and applicable laws, rules and regulations pertaining to duties and responsibilities of Community Council members.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Notwithstanding Section 20-43.2, failure of any elected or appointed member of a Community Council to attend a Community Council Workshop shall be deemed sufficient cause for removal.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-126, ยง 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-67, ยง 1, 6-8-99; Ord. No. 05-171, ยง 1, 9-8-05; Ord. No. 12-40, ยง 1, 6-5-12)</history></law>