<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY COUNCILS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-42</section_number>
<catch_line>Community Councils; configuration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002786</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-42. Community Councils; configuration.<section prefix='(A)'>There shall be no more than (10) Community Councils each of which shall have jurisdiction within its boundary within the unincorporated area. Council areas should be large enough to reasonably accommodate local zoning issues without unduly increasing staffing requirements. The boundaries of Community Councils' jurisdiction, to the extent feasible, shall coincide with those of groupings of Census Designated Places.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Each Community Council area shall contain no more than six (6) subareas. The boundaries of these subareas, to the extent feasible, shall coincide with those of existing election precincts. Enclave areas that are fully surrounded by municipal boundaries and are not large enough to be subareas shall be part of the nearest subarea.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The boundaries and numerical designations of the Community Councils and of the subareas within them are depicted and described in Attachment I attached hereto and incorporated herein by reference [which can be found in the County Clerk's office]. These boundaries may be amended from time to time by resolution of the County Commission after public hearing. The names of the Community Councils shall be designated by the respective Community Council.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Notwithstanding anything in this Code to the contrary, when, as a result of municipal incorporation or annexation, a Community Council does not have enough members in office to act, the Board of County Commission may by resolution after public hearing, reassign the remaining areas of the affected Community Council to a different Community Council and modify the total number of Councils accordingly.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-126, § 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-16, § 2, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 97-163, § 1, 9-23-97; Ord. No. 01-17, § 1, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 04-101, § 1, 5-11-04)</history></law>