<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY COUNCILS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-41</section_number>
<catch_line>Community Councils; responsibilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002785</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-41. Community Councils; responsibilities.<section prefix='(A)'>Community Councils shall perform the duties and responsibilities of Community Zoning Appeals Boards as set forth in Section 33-306 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Community Councils may, at their option, perform the following duties and responsibilities:<section prefix='(1)'>Planning.<section prefix='(a)'>Compile profiles of their respective community's social, physical and economic conditions to assist them in performing their duties;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Prepare an annual statement of community needs including development patterns and regulations, public facilities and services to assist the Council;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Make recommendations to the Planning Advisory Board and Board of County Commissioners on proposed Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan amendments that impact each Council's area; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>Make recommendations to the County Commission on the location and siting of specific public facility and infrastructure projects.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Protection of persons and property programming.<section prefix='(a)'>Recommend policies to coordinate the Fire Rescue District and Police Department in the enhancement of public safety and protection of property in the council area through improved communications and service needs assessments.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Budgeting.<section prefix='(a)'>Make recommendations to the County Manager and County Commission on priorities for community facilities and services and on community based organization grants for the council area; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Make recommendations to the County Manager and County Commission on revenue needs including unincorporated area property taxes millages and special taxing districts.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Communication.<section prefix='(a)'>Conduct forums on council area issues to facilitate the exchange of information between residents, property owners, businesses, institutions and County Officials and Administrators;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Disseminate information about council area related organizations, programs and activities; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Coordinate with Miami-Dade County's Team Metro in the exercise of that agency's responsibilities within the council area.</section></section></section><section prefix='(C)'>No member of a Community Council shall appear at any public hearings or meetings before the Board of County Commissioners or any other federal, state, or local board or tribunal, to advocate concerning any zoning application that was heard by, or that could reasonably be expected to be heard by, any Community Council.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-126, ยง 1, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 05-139, ยง 1, 7-7-05)</history></law>