<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. BOUNDARY CHANGE PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Public hearing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002758</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-7. Public hearing.<section>The Clerk of the County Commission, upon receipt of the recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board, shall set the matter of such proposed boundary changes for public hearing at a regular meeting of the County Commission and cause notice of such public hearing to be published in a daily newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least once not less than one (1) week prior to the date of such public hearing. Notice of such public hearing shall be furnished to a representative of the petitioner or the municipality initiating the proposed boundary change, to all property owners within the area and within six hundred (600) feet thereof and any adjacent municipality. The cost of such notice shall be paid by the individual, group or municipality initiating the proposed change. At such public hearing, the County Commission shall review and consider the recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board, and shall afford to all interested persons an opportunity to be heard upon the merits and propriety of the proposed boundary changes.<section prefix='(A)'>At the conclusion of the public hearing the Board of County Commissioners, in evaluating the appropriateness of a petition for boundary change shall consider the following guidelines:<section prefix='(1)'>The suitability of the proposed boundaries, in conjunction with the existing municipality, provide for a municipal community of interest that is both cohesive and inclusive. The proposed annexation area should:<section prefix='(a)'>Not divide a U.S. Census Designated Place, to the extent feasible.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Include adjacent areas of ethnic minority and lower income residents in which a majority of those residents have so petitioned.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Have contiguity and not create any unincorporated enclave area(s). An unincorporated enclave area is defined as an area that would be 1) surrounded on more than eighty (80) percent of its boundary by one (1) or more municipalities and 2) of a size that could not be serviced efficiently or effectively.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Have natural or built barriers as boundaries, to the extent feasible, and</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The existing and proposed projected property tax cost for municipal-level services to average homeowners in the area as currently unincorporated and as included as part of the annexing municipality,</section><section prefix='(3)'>The proposed annexation area is totally contained within the Urban Development Boundary depicted on the future Land Use Plan map of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan,</section><section prefix='(4)'>The impact of the proposal on the revenue base of the unincorporated area, and on the ability of the County to efficiently and effectively provide services to adjacent remaining unincorporated areas,</section><section prefix='(5)'>The financial impacts of the proposed boundary change on the remaining unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. Specifically in order to insure fiscal equity the per capita taxable property value of the proposed annexation area should fall between twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) and forty-eight thousand dollars ($48,000.00) in order to assure that fiscal viability is maintained in the unincorporated area. The range of per capita taxable value shall not apply to the annexation of unincorporated enclave areas that are surrounded by more than eighty (80) percent of their boundary by one (1) or more municipalities and are of a size that can not be served efficiently or effectively.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Any other factor that arises by virtue of recommendations of the Boundaries Commission, pursuant to Section 20-30 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any other factor that arises by virtue of any special or unique circumstances of a given area.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Whether the proposed annexation excludes areas designated terminals on the County's Adopted Land Use Plan Map; alternatively, if included, the County retains applicable master plan and regulatory authority over any area designated terminals and areas, excluding existing incorporated municipalities, located within one-half (½) mile surrounding any area designated terminals ("surrounding areas") so as to protect the operations, land uses authorized within such area, and future development of areas designated terminals and surrounding areas located therein.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Whether the proposed annexation provides that the County retains master plan and regulatory authority over areas designated terminals and surrounding areas to encourage the use of public transportation and urban infill development.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>At the conclusion of such public hearing, the County Commission, in the exercise of its discretion, may deny the requested boundary change, by motion, or may direct the County Attorney to prepare an appropriate ordinance accomplishing the proposed boundary change, which ordinance shall be placed on the official agenda of a subsequent regular meeting of the County Commission for consideration and adoption on first reading, or the County Commission may defer such requested boundary change for further consideration at a subsequent meeting, at which no public hearing or discussion by others than members of the County Commission shall be required.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-42, § 7, 11-29-60; Ord. No. 70-2, § 5, 1-7-70; Ord. No. 95-176, § 1, 10-5-95; Ord. No. 02-99, § 1, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 05-86, § 2, 5-3-05; Ord. No. 05-112, § 2, 6-7-05; Ord. No. 07-176, § 4, 12-4-07)</history></law>