<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='2'>Chapter 20 MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. BOUNDARY CHANGE PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>20-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Election on proposed boundary changes; required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002768</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 20-9. Election on proposed boundary changes; required.<section prefix='(a)'>If a boundary change involves the annexation or separation of an area having two hundred fifty (250) or fewer resident electors, and the area is more than fifty (50) percent developed residential, no proposed boundary change shall be accomplished unless a majority of resident electors voting at such an election approve such boundary change. All costs of such elections shall be paid in advance by the persons, group or municipality initiating the proposed boundary change. If a boundary change involves the annexation or separation of an area having two hundred fifty (250) or fewer resident electors, and the area is less than fifty (50) percent developed residential, the Commission may by ordinance effect the boundary change in accordance with Section 5.04.B of the Home Rule Charter. The determination of whether an area is more or less than fifty (50) percent developed residential shall be made in the sole discretion of the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event that a boundary change involves the annexation or separation of an area of which more than two hundred fifty (250) residents are electors, the Board of County Commissioners, pursuant to Section 5.04(B) of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County, Florida, may call an election to be held for the purpose of submitting to these electors the question whether the proposed boundary change shall be approved or disapproved. All costs of such elections shall be paid in advance by the persons, group or municipality initiating the proposed boundary change.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-42, § 9, 11-29-60; Ord. No. 64-21, § 3, 5-19-64; Ord. No. 68-83, § 1, 12-17-68; Ord. No. 96-39, § 1, 2-20-96; Ord. No. 96-73, § 1, 5-21-96; Ord. No. 01-168, § 1, 10-23-01)</history></law>