<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. BINGO</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-137</section_number>
<catch_line>Identification of bingo cards; equipment and supplies to be purchased from bona fide distributor; display of placard containing manufacturer's name and address.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002915</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-137. Identification of bingo cards; equipment and supplies to be purchased from bona fide distributor; display of placard containing manufacturer's name and address.<section prefix='(a)'>No individual bingo card shall be used for more than one (1) bingo game and it shall be identified by a unique combination of numbers consisting of card number and the number of the particular series or lot. These numbers shall be imprinted on one (1) side of the card, along with the trade name or logo of the manufacturer. No prizes shall be awarded unless the player surrenders his signed bingo card to the operator, who shall indicate thereon the amount, character and value of the prize awarded. Operators shall retain surrendered bingo cards for a period of at least ninety (90) days.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Operators of bingo games on premises owned by a charity or leased from a charity as defined in Section 21-131(c), which owns said premises shall be exempt from the provisions of subsection (a) of this section to the extent that they may reuse cardboard bingo cards and the winner will not have to surrender the winning card. In such cases the winner must sign a receipt for the prize that is won. To qualify for this exemption the premises may not be used for bingo activities more often than three (3) days per week.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It shall be unlawful for any operator to employ, to distribute or to sell bingo cards other than the type described in subsection (a) above. The operator is further required to maintain adequate records of its purchase of bingo cards from whatever source acquired showing the serial numbers system as described in subsection (a) above of all such cards. These records will be subject to the same inspection provisions as stated in Section 21-134. All cards shall be sold to players at a flat price throughout any bingo session, and no quantity discounts will be allowed to players except that operators of bingo games on premises owned by a charity or leased from a charity, as defined in Section 21-131(c), which owns said premises may sell cards to players in accordance with a published sale price schedule and subject to the following conditions: At the time of the sale each player is issued a numbered, color-coded admission ticket which will indicate the number of cards he is authorized to play during the session and the price paid. Receipts records will be maintained by the operator to report sales by color categories. The admission ticket must be a bingo card as defined in Section 21-131(b) and subsection (a) of this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Supplies and equipment bought by operators for all games shall be purchased from a bona fide distributor authorized to do business in the State of Florida and maintaining an office therein.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A distributor of bingo equipment and supplies, who shall sell said equipment or supplies to an operator of a game to be held in Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall provide said operator with a card having dimensions of not less than twenty-four (24) inches by thirty-six (36) inches stating thereon the name and address of the manufacturer of the bingo cards supplied by the distributor. The operator shall affix and permanently display said card or placard on a wall during each game said supplied cards are used.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-50, ยง 7, 7-2-75)</history></law>