<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='3'>ARTICLE X. TRUTH IN LIVE ENTERTAINMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-122</section_number>
<catch_line>False or deceptive advertising or promotion prohibited; information required in advertisement or promotion; responsibility of producer to advise public when tickets unavailable.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002904</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-122. False or deceptive advertising or promotion prohibited; information required in advertisement or promotion; responsibility of producer to advise public when tickets unavailable.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to falsely or deceptively advertise or to promote to the public, in any manner with the intent to mislead or misrepresent, the sale of admission to live entertainment performances to be conducted within Miami-Dade County, Florida, unless such advertisement or promotion discloses the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>The name(s), title(s), description of the performance or act to be presented to the public;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where a lead artist, musician or performer is advertised, the minimum length of time that said lead artist, musician or performer will actually be on stage and performing or, in a dramatic performance, the role to be played by said lead performer, artist or musician.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be the responsibility of the producer of a live entertainment performance who has publicly advertised the sale of tickets for admission to such a performance to advise the public at the earliest possible time when such tickets are no longer available for purchase.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-93, ยง 2, 11-5-74)</history></law>