<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. WELLS (OPEN IRRIGATION HOLES) IN AGRICULTURAL FIELDS OPEN TO PUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-114</section_number>
<catch_line>Permit required to open self-harvest agricultural field; requirements and conditions prerequisite to issuance of permit.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002897</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-114. Permit required to open self-harvest agricultural field; requirements and conditions prerequisite to issuance of permit.<section>It shall be unlawful to open a self-harvest agricultural field to the public unless and until the owner or lessee of such field obtains a permit for such an enterprise. The County Manager or his designated agent is hereby empowered and directed to issue such permits upon proof of compliance with the following requirements and conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That the applicant for such a permit is the owner or lessee of agricultural fields for which a permit is sought;</section><section prefix='(b)'>That a survey or map of said field is presented showing the boundaries of the field and the location of all known "wells (irrigation holes)" located within the boundaries of said field;</section><section prefix='(c)'>That an affidavit is presented and filed wherein the owner or lessee states under oath that all known wells (irrigation holes) have been marked and covered in compliance with the provisions of this article;</section><section prefix='(d)'>That written permission is granted by said owner or lessee for the entrance to and for inspection of the permitted field by the County Manager or his designees to determine whether there is compliance with the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>That payment of a one dollar ($1.00) fee to cover the cost of processing the permit is tendered. This permit shall be valid for six (6) months.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-6, ยง 1, 1-7-75)</history></law>