<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. BINGO</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-133</section_number>
<catch_line>Owner's and/or lessor's permit.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002911</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-133. Owner's and/or lessor's permit.<section>It shall be unlawful for any owner or lessor to rent or provide space to or permit its premises to be utilized by an operator without having first obtained a valid annual permit from the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector. In order to receive said permit, the lessor and/or owner shall tender to the Tax Collector the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and in addition shall provide the following information under oath:<section prefix='(1)'>Complete information as to the rentals and other financial benefits received from any operators using the premises during the preceding twelve (12) months.</section><section prefix='(2)'>(a)If the owner or lessor is a corporation, the names and addresses of its officers and directors and a true copy of its articles of incorporation and bylaws;<section prefix='(b)'>If the owner or lessor is a partnership, the names and addresses of all the partners and a copy of the partnership agreement;</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the owner or lessor is not a corporation or partnership, the names and addresses of all persons who constitute the owner or lessor, and any agreement or document under which the owner or lessor exists or conducts itself;</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>The address of all premises held by the owner or lessor in which the operator or any operator performs, conducts and/or supervises bingo games and days of the week in which any and all operators perform, conduct and/or supervise bingo games;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The names and addresses of all persons, firms, corporations or business entities owning directly or indirectly ten (10) percent or more of the owner or lessor; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>A financial statement of the said owner or lessor, evidencing the amount and sources of its previous year's gross revenue. This statement must be certified as correct by the officers of the corporation, one (1) of the partners, or one who controls the owner or lessor but need not be audited.</section></section><section>If the operator is the owner and/or lessor, it shall not be required to pay the one hundred dollar ($100.00) owner or lessor fee or supply the other information required of owners and/or lessors under this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-50, ยง 3, 7-2-75; Ord. No. 01-118, ยง 17, 7-12-01)</history></law>