<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. BINGO</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-131</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002909</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-131. Definitions.<section>The following terms and phrases when used in this article shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section, except where the context clearly indicates a different meaning:<section prefix='(a)'>Bingo games shall mean and refer to the activity commonly known as bingo wherein participants pay a sum of money for the use of one (1) or more cards. When the game commences, numbers are drawn by chance, one (1) by one (1), and announced, the players covering or marking those numbers on cards which they have purchased until the player who gets given numbers in the same preannounced sequence for that particular game calls out "bingo" and is declared the winner of a predetermined prize.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Bingo card shall mean and refer to the flat, usually rectangular, piece of paper or thin pasteboard normally employed by players engaged in the game of bingo. More than one (1) set of bingo numbers may be printed on any single piece of paper.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Charity shall mean a nonprofit or veterans' organization having been in existence for three (3) years or more, and engaged in charitable, civic, community, benevolent, religious or scholastic works and/or similar activities.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Lessor shall mean and refer to the person or persons, partnership or corporation that rents to or provides space to an operator (as further defined in this section).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Operator shall mean and refer to the person or persons, partnership or corporation that performs, conducts and/or supervises a bingo game or a series of bingo games. The following described activities are not exclusive, but they shall constitute performing, conducting and/or supervising of a bingo game or of a series of bingo games:<section prefix='(1)'>Supply, distribution and collection of bingo cards.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Acceptance or collection of money from players for the purpose of participating in a bingo game or a series of bingo games.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Distribution of prizes to players.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Selecting and/or announcing numbers or other characters involved in playing the game of bingo.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Owner shall mean and refer to the person or persons, partnership or corporation that holds legal title to the physical premises in which a bingo game or a series of bingo games are played.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Player shall mean any person who has paid some amount of money to the operator for one (1) or more bingo cards, and who has some expectation of receiving a prize if one (1) or more of his bingo cards contains a sufficient number of numbers which are the same as those announced by the operator during a bingo game.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Prizes shall mean and refer to any cash or other thing of value awarded to a player of a bingo game or players in a series of bingo games.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-50, ยง 1, 7-2-75)</history></law>