<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. BINGO</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-132</section_number>
<catch_line>Operator's permit.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002910</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-132. Operator's permit.<section>It shall be unlawful for any operator to perform, conduct and/or supervise a bingo game or a series of bingo games without having first obtained a valid annual permit. Every operator shall obtain an annual permit from the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector. In order to receive said permit, the operator shall tender to the Tax Collector the sum of two hundred dollars ($200.00) and in addition shall provide the following information under oath:<section prefix='(1)'>(a)If the operator is a corporation, the names and addresses of its officers and directors and a true and correct copy of its articles of incorporation and bylaws;<section prefix='(b)'>If the operator is a partnership, the names and addresses of all the partners and a copy of the partnership agreement;</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the operator is not a corporation or partnership, the names and addresses of all persons who constitute the operator, and any agreement or document under which the operator exists or conducts itself;</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>A detailed description of the charitable, civic, community, benevolent, religious or scholastic works and/or other similar activities in which the operator is involved and the endeavors to which the proceeds from the bingo games shall be donated;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The address of the premises in which the operator performs, conducts and/or supervises bingo games, and the days of the week on which the operator performs, conducts and/or supervises bingo games. If the days are changed, a supplemental statement must be filed with the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector prior to such change;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The names and addresses of all persons, firms, corporations or business entities owning directly or indirectly ten (10) percent or more of the operator; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>A financial statement of the operator, evidencing the amount and sources of its previous year's gross bingo revenue and the distributees with the amount of the previous year's distributions. This statement must be certified as correct by the officers of the corporation, one (1) of the partners, or one (1) who controls the operator but need not be audited. The information supplied shall cover the period of the operator's most recently concluded fiscal year.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-50, ยง 2, 7-2-75; Ord. No. 01-118, ยง 16, 7-12-01)</history></law>