<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. PUBLIC AND BUS PASSENGER BENCHES AND SHELTERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-154</section_number>
<catch_line>Permits—Bid procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002922</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-154. Permits—Bid procedure.<section>Permits for bus passenger benches shall be issued pursuant to contract based upon the following procedure:<section prefix='(a)'>Unincorporated Miami-Dade County shall be divided into two (2) territories, hereinafter referred to as the "South Territory" and the "North Territory". Each territory shall be subdivided into three (3) geographic districts. The South Territory shall be comprised of Districts 1, 2, 3, and the North Territory shall be comprised of Districts 4, 5, and 6.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The territories shall be bounded as follows:<section><section>North boundary, between U.S. 1 and Biscayne Bay, the boundary is Coral Reef Drive which is not included in District 1. Between U.S. 1 and the County line to the west, the boundary is North Kendall Drive which is not included in District 1; south boundary, County line; east boundary, between Kendall Drive and Coral Reef Drive, the boundary is U.S. 1 which is included in District 1. Between Coral Reef Drive and the County line to the south, the boundary is Biscayne Bay; west boundary, County line.</section><section>North boundary, Tamiami Trail which is not included in District 2; south boundary, North Kendall Drive which is included in District 2; east boundary, S.W. 87 Avenue which is not included in district 2; west boundary, County line.</section><section>North boundary, Flagler Street which is included in District 3; south boundary, between U.S. 1 and Biscayne Bay, the boundary is Coral Reef Drive [sic] loway Road, the boundary is North Kendall Drive which is included in District 3; east boundary, Biscayne Bay. Key Biscayne, Virginia Key and the Rickenbacker Causeway are included in District 3; west boundary, between Kendall Drive and Coral Reef Drive, the boundary is U.S. 1 which is not included in District 3. Between Flagler Street and Kendall Drive, the boundary is S.W. 87 Avenue which is included in District 3.</section></section><section><section>North boundary, between Biscayne Bay and the County line to the west, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 103 Street which is included in District 4. Between Biscayne Bay and the Atlantic Ocean, the boundary is 87 Street which is included in the district; south boundary, between S.W. 87 Avenue and the County line to the west, the boundary is the Tamiami Trail which is included in District 4. Between S.W. 87 Avenue and Biscayne Bay, the boundary is Flagler Street which is not included in the District; east boundary, between Tamiami Trail and Flagler Street, the boundary is S.W. 87 Avenue which is not included in the District. Between N.W./N.E. 103 Street and Flagler Street, the boundary is the Atlantic Ocean; west boundary, County line.</section><section>North boundary, between the intercoastal waterway and the Atlantic Ocean, the boundary is the County line. Between the intercoastal waterway and the County line to the west, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 167 Street, N.E. 163 Street, and Sunny Isles Boulevard which are included in District 5; south boundary, between Biscayne Bay and the County line to the west, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 103 Street which is not included in the district. Between Biscayne Bay and the Atlantic Ocean, the boundary is 87 Street which is not included in District 5; east boundary, between N.E. 103 Street and 163 Street, the boundary is Biscayne Bay or the intracoastal waterway. Between N.E. 163 Street and the County line to the north, the boundary is the Atlantic Ocean; west boundary, County line.</section><section>North boundary, County line; south boundary, between the intercoastal waterway and the County line, the boundary is N.W./N.E. 167 Street, N.E. 163 Street, and Sunny Isles Boulevard which are not included in the district; east boundary, intercoastal waterway; west boundary, County line.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>A contract(s) for placement of bus passenger benches in the public right-of-way in unincorporated Miami-Dade County shall be awarded by territory based upon competitive bids or request for proposals. The bid specifications or requests for proposals shall contain a complete listing of all official bus stops of the Metro Miami-Dade Transportation Administration within the applicable territory. Such contracts may be extended beyond their term without the need for further competitive process upon compliance with the requirements for bid waivers contained in Section 4.03D of the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter and Section 2-8.1(b) of this Code.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-32, § 1(4), 5-7-85; Ord. No. 91-58, § 1, 5-21-91)</history></law>