<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. BINGO</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-134</section_number>
<catch_line>Maintenance of records; subject to inspection by law enforcement officers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002912</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-134. Maintenance of records; subject to inspection by law enforcement officers.<section>Each operator shall maintain adequate records for a minimum of two (2) years of the daily bingo activity on a per-game basis which shall include:<section prefix='(1)'>Gross game receipts and all income from any source, including but not limited to, admission charges;</section><section prefix='(2)'>All payout for prizes whether in cash or merchandise;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any and all operating expenses; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Net proceeds.</section></section><section>These records shall be made available on demand for immediate inspection by any law enforcement officer at reasonable times during normal business hours and whenever bingo games are in progress, but law enforcement officers shall not interrupt an actual bingo game in progress or interfere with the operation of the premises where bingo is played unless necessary in order to make an inspection.</section><section>Each lessor or owner shall maintain records for a minimum of two (2) years of all income from such leases or rentals and they shall require their lessees to furnish the information to them as enumerated in the above paragraph on a monthly basis for all bingo activity on their premises. All such records shall be made available on demand for immediate inspection by any law enforcement officer at reasonable times.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-50, ยง 4, 7-2-75)</history></law>