<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. PUBLIC AND BUS PASSENGER BENCHES AND SHELTERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-165</section_number>
<catch_line>Compliance with article required; removal of benches.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002933</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-165. Compliance with article required; removal of benches.<section prefix='(a)'>Failure to comply with any of the terms, conditions or requirements of this article shall constitute cause for cancellation of the permit for, and/or removal of the bench to which the violation pertains.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All benches in the public right-of-way in the unincorporated area of the County shall be subject to this article and shall comply with all provisions hereof. Any bench found in violation may be removed without prior notice by MDTA immediately.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, the Department may, at its discretion, require a permittee to remove a bus bench and deliver such bench to a County-owned or leased facility for storage and disposal if MDTA or the permittee finds a bench that:<section prefix='(1)'>Displays a bus passenger bench company name different than the company name of the existing bus bench permittee.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Lacks a bus passenger bench company name, or any of the identification required by Section 21-161 of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Is not located at an MDTA authorized bus stop.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Is in violation of any of the terms, conditions and requirements of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Permittee shall be responsible for removal of all its bus passenger benches from the public right-of-way upon termination of its right to operate in Miami-Dade County for any reason including, but not limited to, expiration of the contract, default, or voluntary termination on the part of the permittee. Nothing contained in this subsection or in any other section of this article shall relieve the permittee of this obligation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-32, ยง 1(15), 5-7-85)</history></law>