<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII. JUVENILE CURFEW PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-202</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative intent, findings and purposes.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002940</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-202. Legislative intent, findings and purposes.<section prefix='(a)'>This commission hereby finds and determines as a matter of fact that Miami-Dade County is facing a mounting crisis caused by increasing crime, including juvenile crime and delinquency which threatens peaceful citizens, residents, and visitors. This commission further determines that this criminal activity, both individually and collectively, presents a clear and present danger to the citizenry and to the public order and safety. The economic cost of crime in Miami-Dade County continues to drain existing resources. Additionally, the effect on victims, both economic and psychological, is traumatic and tragic.</section><section prefix='(b)'>This commission finds that fighting crime effectively requires a multipronged effort, with one (1) aspect focusing on those age groups particularly vulnerable to and injured by crime, and susceptible to being induced into committing crime. Consequently, it is the intent of the Commission to create and implement a juvenile curfew program aimed at protecting juveniles from crime and reducing juvenile crime and the direct and indirect consequences thereof.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Juveniles in Miami-Dade County have themselves become victims of crime and violence in steadily increasing numbers. Violent crimes against juveniles in Miami-Dade County are dramatically high in number, and the psychological effect of crime committed upon juveniles is particularly tragic and traumatic. A juvenile curfew program would have the additional benefit of reducing juvenile victimization.</section><section prefix='(d)'>It is the intent of this Commission to substantially reduce, if not eradicate, acts of crime and delinquency committed by juveniles and to provide for the care, safety and protection of law abiding juveniles and other citizens, residents and visitors.</section><section prefix='(e)'>This article is enacted in recognition of the peculiar vulnerability of juveniles, their frequent inability to make critical decisions in an informed, mature manner, and the importance of the parental role in child-rearing.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The purposes of this article are:<section prefix='(1)'>To protect juveniles themselves and other citizens, residents and visitors of Miami-Dade County from the dangers of crimes which occur on sidewalks, streets, and in public, and semi-public places during late night and early morning hours.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To decrease the amount of criminal activity engaged in by juveniles.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To promote and enhance parental control over juveniles.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-1, ยง 2, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-208, ยง 2, 11-21-95)</history></law>