<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII.5 PROTECTION OF UNDERGROUND UTILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-221</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002955</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-221. Definitions.<section>The following words and phrases when used in this Ordinance shall have the following meanings:<section prefix='(a)'>As-Builts shall mean drawings made by an excavator after facilities have been installed, showing the location, grade, and type of the facility as installed.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Business days shall mean Monday through Friday, excluding those holidays established by State law which are listed in Section 556.102 (1), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Conflict shall mean a situation that exists when installation of a new underground facility will result in that facility being installed within twenty-four (24) inches horizontally or vertically of another underground facility as measured from the closest point between the utilities, except as otherwise specified in Section 21-225(c).</section><section prefix='(d)'>Demolition shall mean any operation by which a structure or mass or material is wrecked, razed, rended, moved, or removed by means of any tool, equipment, or discharge of explosives, or any disturbance of the earth in any manner on public or private lands which could damage any underground facility.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Directional Boring shall mean any process of installing a product underground without open trench excavation and with the capacity to directionally control the bore path. The term directional boring shall be used interchangeably with the term horizontal boring technique.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Emergency shall mean any condition constituting a clear and present danger to life or property; a situation caused by the escape of any substance transported by means of an underground facility; any interruption of vital public service or communication caused by any break or defect in an underground facility; or any condition impairing use of public streets or roads which requires immediate repair.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Excavation shall mean any manmade cut, cavity, trench, or depression in the earth's surface, formed by removal of earth, intended to change the grade or level of land, or intended to penetrate or disturb the surface of the earth.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Excavator shall mean any person performing excavation or demolition operations.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Exploratory Digging shall mean a controlled excavation made to the bottom depth of a proposed excavation in order to, where the existing facility is in conflict with the proposed facility, determine and verify the actual vertical or horizontal location of existing underground facilities; exploratory digging shall be accomplished by any method of excavation that affords substantial protection to existing underground facilities; notwithstanding the foregoing, excavators may use any means for removal of pavement or masonry, but only to the depth of such pavement or masonry.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Member operator shall mean any person who furnishes or transports materials or services by means of an underground facility and who participates in the one-call notification system established in Chapter 556, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Underground facility shall mean any public or private personal property which is buried, placed below ground, or submerged on any member operator's right-of-way, easement, or permitted use which is being used or will be used in connection with the storage or conveyance of water; sewage; electronic, telephonic or telegraphic communication; electric energy; oil; petroleum products; natural gas; optical signals; or other substances, and includes, but is not limited to, pipelines, pipes, sewers, conduits, cables, valves, and lines. Storm drainage systems are not considered underground facilities, nor are petroleum storage systems subject to regulation pursuant to Chapter 376 Florida Statutes, unless a petroleum storage system is located on a member operator's right-of-way.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-137, ยง 1, 9-15-98; Ord. No. 00-97, ยง 1, 7-25-00)</history></law>