<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII.5 PROTECTION OF UNDERGROUND UTILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-223</section_number>
<catch_line>Exemptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002957</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-223. Exemptions.<section>Exemptions from the mandatory pre-excavation procedures requirements of are only the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Emergencies, provided that the one-call system or the member operator was notified at the earliest opportunity and all reasonable precautions had been taken by the excavator to protect any underground facilities.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any excavation or demolition performed by the owner of single-family residential property; or for such owner by a member operator or an agent of a member operator when such excavation or demolition is made entirely on such land, and only up to a depth of ten (10) inches; provided due care is used and there is no encroachment on any member operator's right-of-way, easement, or permitted use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any excavation or demolition associated with normal agricultural or railroad activities, provided such activities are not performed on any member operator's marked right-of-way, easement, or permitted use.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any excavation or demolition that occurs as the result of normal industrial activities, provided such activities are confined to the immediate secured property of the facility and the activities are not performed on any operator's marked right-of-way, easement, or permitted use, and subject to any further restrictions set forth in State law.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any excavation of 18 inches or less for:<section prefix='(1)'>Surveying public or private property by surveyors or mappers as defined in Chapter 472 Florida Statutes, excluding marked rights-of-way, marked easements, or permitted uses where marked, provided mechanized equipment is not used and the surveying is performed in accordance with the practice rules established under Section 472.027 Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Maintenance activities performed by a State or County agency and its employees when such activities are within the right-of-way of a public road, provided, if a member operator has permanently marked facilities on such right-of-way, no mechanized equipment may be used without first providing notification.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Any excavation with hand tools by a member operator or its agent:<section prefix='(1)'>For locating, repairing, connecting, or protecting, or routine maintenance of, the member operator's underground facilities; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>For the extension of a member operator's underground facilities onto the property of a person to be served by such facilities.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The exemption provided in sub-paragraphs (1) and (2) is limited to excavations to a depth of 30 inches if the right-of-way has permanently marked facilities of a company other than the member operator or its agents performing the excavation.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-137, ยง 1, 9-15-98; Ord. No. 00-97, ยง 1, 7-25-00)</history></law>