<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-29</section_number>
<catch_line>Secondhand dealers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002826</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-29. Secondhand dealers.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Secondhand dealers: For the purpose of this section, the term "secondhand dealers" shall mean any person, firm, corporation or partnership engaged in the business of buying, selling, bartering, exchanging in any manner at retail or wholesale or otherwise dealing for profit in secondhand goods as defined in subsection (2) hereof, whether or not at a fixed place of business. Such term shall include pawnbrokers and all dealers who buy, trade or sell or who make loans of money upon the deposit or pledge of any secondhand goods. Provided, however, that nothing in this section shall apply to:<section prefix='a.'>Registered religious or charitable organizations selling reconditioned or used articles;</section><section prefix='b.'>Licensed garage sales;</section><section prefix='c.'>Any person whose primary business is dealing in gold or silver coins if such business is licensed pursuant to law or ordinance.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Secondhand goods: For the purposes of this section, "secondhand goods" shall mean personal property previously owned or used which is not purchased or sold as new and shall include but shall not be limited to items containing gold, silver, platinum or other precious metal; jewelry, diamonds, gems, and other precious stones; audio and video electronic equipment, including but not limited to television sets, radios, amplifiers, receivers, turntables, tape recorders, videotape recorders, speakers and citizens' band radios; photographic equipment, including but not limited to cameras, lenses, electronic flashes, tripods and developing equipment; machinery; tools, electric motors, calculators, tires, hub caps, musical instruments, typewriters and firearms.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Records of transactions to be kept. Every secondhand dealer shall keep a record approved as to type and form by the Miami-Dade Police Director. The record shall be clearly and legibly written in ink in the English language at the time of each acquisition and shall contain an accurate and true description of each article purchased, bartered, exchanged or received, including a notation as to any identifying markings or characteristics such as serial numbers; the amount of money or other consideration loaned thereon or paid or given therefor; the date and time of the acquisition of such article by the secondhand dealer; the true name of the person dealt with, as nearly as known, as well as such person's signature and thumbprint, place of residence, sex, age, height, weight, build, color of hair, color of eyes, complexion and reasonable proof of identification by an exhibition of a driver's license or other picture identification or other reliable means of identification. The record shall contain the type of identification exhibited, the issuing agency, and the number thereon. For purposes of this section, credit cards, Social Security cards, handwritten identification cards and nonphoto I.D. shall not constitute acceptable I.D. No entry made in such record shall be erased, obliterated or defaced. Every secondhand dealer shall deliver to the Office of the Miami-Dade Police Director a complete and correct copy of said record within forty-eight (48) hours of the date of acquisition of items covered under this section.</section><section>A special tag shall be affixed to all items not bearing a serial number. The tag shall exhibit information sufficient to enable ready reference to be made to the portion of the above record which pertains to the item bearing the tag. The County Manager shall issue an administrative order specifying a uniform format and design for the tag. The tag shall not be required to be affixed to articles of clothing. Organizations exempt from federal taxation pursuant to 26 U.S.C. Sec. 501(c)(3) and religious organizations shall be exempt from the requirement of affixing the tag.</section><section>The records created and maintained as required by subsections (b) and (c) of this section shall be made available for inspection and copying by any person desiring to do so, in the same manner and in accordance with the same procedures provided for the inspection and duplication of public records by the provisions of Florida Statutes, Section 119.07(1)(a), (b), as set forth at the time this paragraph becomes law.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Holding period.<section prefix='(1)'>Items containing gold, silver, platinum or other precious metal and jewelry, diamonds, gems and other precious stones shall be held by the secondhand dealer for a period of fifteen (15) days prior to sale, exchange or other disposition thereof. All other property covered by this section acquired in the course of a secondhand dealer's business shall be held for a period of thirty (30) days prior to disposition thereof; provided, however, that the provisions of this subsection shall not be applicable when the person known by the secondhand dealer to be the true owner of any article desires to redeem, repurchase or recover such article at any time within the required hold period. The secondhand dealer shall keep a record of the proof of ownership presented by the true owners.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If a police officer has probable cause to believe that an item acquired by a secondhand dealer in the course of his business is the subject of a criminal investigation, such police officer may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for an order which would prohibit the release of such property for a period of sixty (60) days. Upon release of such property, the secondhand dealer shall keep a record of the disposition thereof.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Inspection of premises and records. Any law enforcement officer shall, upon authorization of the Miami-Dade Police Director or his designee, have the right to inspect during normal business hours the records required to be kept by this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Certain acts and practices prohibited. Each of the following acts of either a secondhand dealer or any of his or her employees is hereby declared to be unlawful and shall subject the person convicted thereof by a court of competent jurisdiction to the penalties prescribed by Section 1-5, Code of Miami-Dade County:<section prefix='(1)'>Knowingly purchasing or otherwise acquiring any article covered by this section from:<section prefix='a.'>Any person under the influence of drugs or alcohol, or</section><section prefix='b.'>Any minor unless said minor has the written consent of his or her parent or guardian, or</section><section prefix='c.'>Any person using a name other than his own.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Refusing, denying or interfering with the lawful inspection of the records required to be kept by this section by a police officer.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Disposing of any property covered by this section contrary to the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Failing or neglecting to comply with any applicable provision of this section.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Possessing property owned by Miami-Dade County, or any municipality within Miami-Dade County without documentation of the receipt of such property as required by this ordinance is prohibited and shall subject the person convicted thereof to a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or imprisonment in the county jail for a term not to exceed one (1) year imprisonment.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Hours of operation. No pawnshop shall engage in business within the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County except between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and 7:00 p.m.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Applicability and enforcement. This chapter [section] shall apply to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas, and in the unincorporated areas shall be enforced by the County and in the incorporated areas shall be enforced by the municipalities unless the County is notified by any municipality, in the form of a resolution of the governing council or commission that it is desirous of having the County enforce this chapter [section] in which event enforcement within the incorporated areas shall be by the County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-64, § 1, 6-2-81; Ord. No. 89-1, § 1, 1-17-89; Ord. No. 94-27, § 1, 2-1-94; Ord. No. 94-189, § 1, 10-7-94; Ord. No. 97-146, § 1, 9-9-97; Ord. No. 00-161, § 1, 12-7-00)</history></law>