<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. FALSE CLAIMS ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-258</section_number>
<catch_line>Liability for false claims; penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002970</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-258. Liability for false claims; penalties.<section prefix='(1)'>The following action(s) shall constitute a violation of this article:<section prefix='(a)'>Any person who knowingly presents or causes to be presented to the County, or to any officer, employee, agent, or consultant of the County, a false or fraudulent claim for payment or approval;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person who knowingly makes, uses, or causes to be made or used, a false record or statement to get a false, fraudulent, or inflated claim paid or approved by the County;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any person who conspires to defraud the County by facilitating the payment of a false, fraudulent, or inflated claim allowed or paid by the County;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any person who delivers, with the intent to defraud the County, goods or services of different quality or quantity than that specified in the applicable contract or specification;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any person who is authorized to make or deliver a document certifying receipt of property used, or to be used, by the County and, intending to defraud the County, makes or delivers the receipt without completely knowing that the information on the receipt is true;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any person who knowingly buys, or receives as a pledge of an obligation or debt, public property from an officer, employee, or agent of the County who lawfully may not sell or pledge the property; or</section><section prefix='(g)'>Any person who knowingly makes, uses, or causes to be made or used, a false record or statement to conceal, avoid, or decrease an obligation to pay or transmit money or property to the County.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Any beneficiary of an inadvertent submission of a false claim to the County, who subsequently discovers the falsity of the claim, and who fails to disclose the falsity of the claim to the County within thirty (30) days of discovering the error, shall also be found to have submitted a false claim to the County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any person found to have submitted a false claim to the County shall:<section prefix='(a)'>Be liable to the County for an amount equal to three (3) times that part of the claim which is false, fraudulent, or inflated;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Immediately, fully, and irrevocably forfeit the entire amount of the claim;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Be liable to the County for all costs and fees (including, without limitation, reasonable legal, expert, and consulting fees) incurred by the County to review, defend, and evaluate the claim; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>Be subject to debarment from County contracting for a period not to exceed five (5) years. Additionally, any person who certified a claim later found to be false shall be subject to debarment from County contracting for a period not to exceed five (5) years.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Liability under this section shall be joint and several for any act committed by two (2) or more persons.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-152, ยง 1, 11-2-99)</history></law>