<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII. JUVENILE CURFEW PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-205</section_number>
<catch_line>Exceptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002943</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-205. Exceptions.<section>The provisions of this article shall not apply if the juvenile is:<section prefix='(a)'>Accompanied by a parent or legal guardian or another adult person at least twenty-one (21) years of age given permission by the parent or legal guardian to have the care, custody or control of the juvenile.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Engaged in a lawful employment activity or traveling to or returning home from a lawful employment activity without any detour.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Engaged in interstate travel.</section><section prefix='(d)'>On an errand at the written approval and direction of the juvenile's parent or legal guardian, without any detour.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Involved in or attempting to remedy, alleviate or respond to an emergency.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Attending an official school, religious, or recreational activity supervised by adults at least twenty-one (21) years of age and sponsored by the County of Miami-Dade, the Miami-Dade County School Board, municipality, a civic organization or other similar entity, which organizations take responsibility for the juvenile as an invitee, or going to or returning home from, any such activity without any detour.</section><section prefix='(g)'>On the swale or sidewalk abutting the juvenile's residence or abutting the residence of a next door neighbor if the neighbor has not complained to the police department about the juvenile's presence.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Exercising First Amendment rights protected by the United States Constitution (or those similar rights protected by Article 1, Sections 3, 4 and 5 of the Florida Constitution), such as free exercise of religion, freedom of speech, and the right of assembly.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Attending or returning to current residence from a specific activity at a public or semi-public place which is open to the general public and supervised by adults at least twenty-one (21) years of age; provided further, that any such activity begins no later than 10:00 p.m.; provided further, that the juvenile possesses written permission from his or her parent or legal guardian authorizing the juvenile to attend or engage in that specific activity.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Married in accordance with law or had disability of nonage removed by a court of competent jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Homeless or uses a public or semi-public place as his or her usual place or abode.</section><section prefix='(l)'>When the County Commission pursuant to an application by a sponsor of an event not provided for in this subsection, or any other person, authorizes juvenile(s) to be in a public or semi-public place during curfew hours.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-1, ยง 5, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-208, ยง 5, 11-21-95)</history></law>