<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-28</section_number>
<catch_line>Noises; unnecessary and excessive prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002824</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-28. Noises; unnecessary and excessive prohibited.<section>It shall be unlawful for any person to make, continue, or cause to be made or continued any unreasonably loud, excessive, unnecessary or unusual noise. Any person violating any of the provisions of this section shall be punished by (i) a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00); (ii) imprisonment in the county jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days; (iii) both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause; (iv) fines in accordance with of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or (v) completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners. The following acts, among others, are declared to be unreasonably loud, excessive, unnecessary or unusual noises in violation of this section, but this enumeration shall not be deemed to be exclusive, namely:<section prefix='(a)'>Horns, signaling devices, etc. The sounding of any horn or signaling device on any automobile, motorcycle, bus or other vehicle on any street or public place of the County, except as a danger warning; the creation by means of any such signaling device of any unreasonably loud or harsh sound; and the sounding of any such device for any unnecessary and unreasonable period of time.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Radios, televisions, phonographs, etc. The using, operating, or permitting to be played, used or operated any radio receiving set, television set, musical instrument, phonograph, or other machine or device for the producing or reproducing of sound in such manner as to disturb the peace, quiet and comfort of the neighboring inhabitants, or at any time with louder volume than is necessary for convenient hearing for the person or persons who are in the room, vehicle or chamber in which such machine or device is operated and who are voluntary listeners thereto. The operation of any such set, instrument, phonograph, machine or device between the hours of 11:00 p.m. and 7:00 a.m. in such manner as to be plainly audible at a distance of one hundred (100) feet from the building, structure or vehicle in which it is located shall be prima facie evidence of a violation of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Animals, birds, etc. The owning, harboring, possessing or keeping of any dog, animal or bird which causes frequent, habitual or long continued noise which is plainly audible at a distance of one hundred (100) feet from the building, structure or yard in which the dog, animal or bird is located.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Whistles. The blowing of any locomotive whistle or whistle attached to any stationary boiler except to give notice of the time to begin or stop work or as a warning of fire or danger or upon request of the proper municipal or County authorities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Exhausts. The discharge into the open air of the exhaust of any steam engine, stationary internal combustion engine, or motor vehicle except through a muffler or other device which will effectively prevent unreasonably loud or explosive noises therefrom.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Defect in vehicle or load. The use of any automobile, motorcycle, jet ski, water bike, recreational vehicle, dirt bike or motor vehicle so out of repair, so loaded or in such manner as to create unreasonably loud or unnecessary grating, grinding, rattling or other noise within a residential area.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Schools, courts, hospitals. The creation of any excessive or unreasonably loud noise on any street adjacent to any school, institution of learning, house of worship or court while the same are in use, or adjacent to any hospital, which unreasonably interferes with the workings of such institutions, or which disturbs or unduly annoys the patients in the hospital, provided conspicuous signs are displayed in such streets indicating that it is a school, hospital or court street.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Hawkers, peddlers. The shouting and crying of peddlers, hawkers, and vendors which disturbs the peace and quiet of the neighborhood.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Noises to attract attention. The use of any drum, loudspeaker or other instrument or device for the purpose of attracting attention by creation of any unreasonably loud or unnecessary noise to any performance, show, sale, display or advertisement of merchandise.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Loudspeakers, etc. The use or operation on or upon the public streets, alleys and thoroughfares anywhere in this County for any purpose of any device known as a sound truck, loud speaker or sound amplifier or radio or any other instrument of any kind or character which emits therefrom loud and raucous noises and is attached to and upon any vehicle operated or standing upon such streets or public places aforementioned. It is provided, however, that this subsection is not intended to be construed in a manner that would interfere with the legitimate use of the foregoing loudspeaker type devices in political campaigns.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Power tools and landscaping equipment. The operation of noise-producing lawn mowers, lawn edgers, weed trimmers, blowers, chippers, chain saws, power tools and other noise-producing tools which are used to maintain or at a residence out-of-doors between 8:00 p.m. and 7:00 a.m.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Shouting. Any unreasonably loud, boisterous or raucous shouting in any residential area.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-5, ยง 21.07, 2-18-58; Ord. No. 96-130, ยง 1, 9-10-96; Ord. No. 10-52, ยง 5, 9-21-10)</history></law>