<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-27.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Merchandise—Selling, serving, vending in public rights-of-way near schools.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002820</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-27.1. Merchandise—Selling, serving, vending in public rights-of-way near schools.<section prefix='(a)'>Prohibited. It shall be unlawful for any person to sell, offer for sale, serve, vend, or otherwise dispose of any goods, wares or merchandise, including ice cream, peanuts, popcorn, soda water products, drinks, candy, and food products, in the public rights-of-way, including streets, sidewalks or other public property, within five hundred (500) feet of any property used, owned or operated for public or private school purposes, or for any person to station himself, or operate any stand, establishment or vehicle, for such purpose within the prohibited areas unless within five hundred (500) feet of the school in a secure vending area established and controlled by the school principal. The term "secure vending area" means an area designated by the school principal which is cordoned off by movable barriers, is of sufficient size to accommodate a parked vehicle and student customers in numbers reasonably anticipated by the principal, is supervised by the principal or his or her designee, and for which specific designation thereof is made in writing and filed in the school and at the police station which provides service to the area.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Enforcement and penalties for violations. It shall be the duty of all County and municipal peace officers to enforce the provisions of this section. Any person convicted of a violation of the provisions of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days, or both, in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 61-31, §§ 1, 2, 7-11-61; Ord. No. 89-74, § 1, 7-25-89)</history></law>