<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-29.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Private business, advertising on public property prohibited; exceptions; penalty; enforcement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002827</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-29.1. Private business, advertising on public property prohibited; exceptions; penalty; enforcement.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to engage in any private business, commercial activity, or to undertake to provide any service for compensation, or to advertise or display merchandise, or to transact any business for profit, or to solicit business, on any property or facilities owned or operated by Miami-Dade County without first obtaining a permit, concession, lease, or other authorization in writing approved or authorized by the Board of County Commissioners. A County occupational license shall not authorize any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to engage in any of the prohibited activities on County property or facilities.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity to post, display or distribute any signs, advertisements, circulars, handbills, printed or written matter relating to any business or commercial activities on any property or facilities owned or operated by or for Miami-Dade County, without first obtaining a written permit issued or authorized by the Board of County Commissioners; provided that the provisions of this section shall not be applicable to licensees, concessionaires, lessees or agencies of the County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The provisions of this section shall be applicable to all lands, buildings, improvements, facilities, equipment, projects, and all property, either real or personal, owned, operated, or under the custody or control of Miami-Dade County, or its agents, representatives, officials, departments or instrumentalities, except public streets, roads, highways and sidewalks.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity violating any provisions of this section shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the County Court.</section><section prefix='(e)'>It shall be the duty of the Miami-Dade Police and the police officers of each municipality to enforce the provisions of this section against any person, firm, corporation or other legal entity found violating the same within their jurisdiction.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-22, §§ 1—5, 5-19-64)</history></law>