<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII. JUVENILE CURFEW PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-203</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002941</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-203. Definitions.<section>For the purpose of this article, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>Emergency shall mean an unforseen combination of circumstances or the resulting state or any situation requiring immediate action to care for or prevent serious bodily injury or loss of life. This term includes, but is not limited to, a fire, natural disaster, or an automobile accident.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Juvenile shall mean a person under seventeen (17) years of age whose disabilities have not been removed by marriage or a court of competent jurisdiction or otherwise.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Legal guardian shall mean a person or agency appointed by a court to act in the role of a parent.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Operator shall mean any individual, firm, association, partnership or corporation operating, managing, or conducting any business or other establishment. The term includes the members or partners of an association, or partnership and the officers of a corporation.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Parent shall mean the natural parent, adoptive parent, or step-parent of a juvenile.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Public place shall mean any property owned or controlled by the County, any municipality, the School Board, the State or other governmental entity to which the general public has access and a right to resort for business, recreation, entertainment, or other lawful purpose, including streets and highways.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Semi-public place shall mean any privately-owned or privately-operated real property (including any structure thereon) to which the general public is invited or has the legal right of access and right to resort for business, recreation, entertainment, or other lawful purpose such as, but not limited to, any store, shop, restaurant, tavern, theater, parking lot, alley, road, shopping center, bowling alley, pool hall, any vacant lot, or any vacant or abandoned building.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Law enforcement officer shall mean a certified law enforcement officer of any rank who is a duly sworn officer of the Miami-Dade Police Department, a municipal police department in Miami-Dade County, the Florida Highway Patrol or other state or federal law enforcement agency.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Curfew hours shall mean the hours of 11:00 p.m. until 6:00 a.m. the following day from Sunday to Thursday, and the hours of 12:00 midnight until 6:00 a.m. the following day from Friday evening to Sunday morning.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-1, ยง 3, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-208, ยง 3, 11-21-95)</history></law>