<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. THE LAUREN BOOK CHILD SAFETY ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-285</section_number>
<catch_line>Loitering or prowling in child safety zone; penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002989</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-285. Loitering or prowling in child safety zone; penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>It is unlawful for any sexual offender or sexual predator:<section prefix='(1)'>To loiter or prowl with the intent to commit a sexual offense as listed in Section 21-280 of this article;</section><section prefix='(2)'>While knowingly within a child safety zone when children are present; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>To engage in overt conduct that, under the circumstances, manifests an intent to commit a sexual offense as listed in Section 21-280 of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Conduct which may, under the circumstances, be deemed adequate to manifest an intent to commit a sexual offense as listed in Section 21-280 of this article includes, but is not limited to, conduct such as the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Making sexual conversation or sexual remarks to a child;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Making lewd or sexual gestures to a child, or exposing sexual organs to a child;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Giving gifts of candy, money, music, or other items to a child to which he or she is not related or acquainted.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Unless flight by the sexual offender or sexual predator or other circumstance makes it impracticable, a law enforcement officer shall, prior to any arrest for an offense under this section, afford the sexual offender or predator an opportunity to explain his or her presence and conduct. No sexual offender or predator shall be convicted of an offense under this section if the law enforcement officer did not comply with this procedure or if it is proven at trial that the explanation given by the sexual offender or predator is true, and that the sexual offender or predator had no intent to commit a sexual offense.</section><section prefix='(d)'>As used in this section a sexual offender or predator is related to a child if he or she is the father, mother, step-father, step-mother, grandparent, sibling, cousin, aunt, uncle or resides with the child. As used in this section a sexual offender or predator is acquainted with a child if he or she has been introduced to the child in the presence of an adult with legal authority to supervise the child.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Penalties. A person who violates Section 21-285(a) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $500.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 60 days or by both fine and such imprisonment.</section><section prefix='(f)'>This provision is not intended to limit or affect the applicability of any general loitering and prowling statutes to sexual offenders or predators, including, but not limited to, F.S. ยง 856.021.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-01, ยง 3, 1-21-10; Ord. No. 10-67, ยง 2, 10-5-10)</history></law>