<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. FALSE CLAIMS ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-256</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002968</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-256. Definitions.<section>The following terms and phrases when used in this article shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section, except when the context clearly indicates a different meaning:<section prefix='(1)'>Bid takeoff means the final estimate, tabulation, or worksheet prepared by the contractor in anticipation of the bid submitted, and which shall reflect the final bid price.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Claim means any invoice, statement, request, demand, lawsuit, or action under contract or otherwise, for money, property, or services made to any employee, officer, or agent of the County, or to any contractor, grantee, or other recipient if any portion of the money, property, or services requested or demanded was issued from, or was provided by, the County (hereinafter "County funds").</section><section prefix='(3)'>Claimant means any person who brings, submits, files, maintains, or pursues a claim.</section><section prefix='(4)'>County means the government of Miami-Dade County or any department, division, bureau, section, commission, planning agency, board, district, authority, agency, or instrumentality of the County, including the Miami-Dade County Public Health Trust.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Extended overhead means the amount of a claim relating to an increase in overhead costs resulting from a delay in contract performance that is not compensated by a markup of direct costs.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Knowing or knowingly means that a person, with respect to information:<section prefix='(a)'>Has actual knowledge of the information;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Acts in deliberate ignorance of the truth or falsity of the information; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Acts in reckless disregard of the truth or falsity of the information.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Overhead per diem means the amount calculated by dividing the total overhead costs set forth in the final bid takeoff by the number of days for substantial completion of the work set forth in the contract.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Person means any natural person, corporation, firm, association, organization, partnership, agency, limited liability company, business, or trust.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-152, ยง 1, 11-2-99)</history></law>