<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. THE LAUREN BOOK CHILD SAFETY ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-280</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002984</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-280. Definitions.<section>The following terms and phrases when used in this article shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section unless the context otherwise requires:<section prefix='(1)'>"Child" or "children" means any person(s) less than sixteen (16) years of age.</section><section prefix='(2)'>"Child care facility" means day nurseries, and family day care homes, licensed by the Department of Children and Families, and as defined in Section 33-151.11 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>"Child safety zone" means an area three hundred (300) feet extending from schools, child care facilities, parks, and school bus stops measured in a manner similar to the measurement of the residency restriction area provided in this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(4)'>"Convicted" or "conviction" means a determination of guilt which is the result of a trial or the entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld. A conviction for a similar offense includes, but is not limited to: a conviction by a federal or military tribunal, including courts-martial conducted by the Armed Forces of the United States, and includes a conviction or entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere resulting in a sanction in any state of the United States or other jurisdiction. A sanction includes, but is not limited to, a fine, probation, community control, parole, conditional release, control release, or incarceration in a state prison, federal prison, private correctional facility, or local detention facility.</section><section prefix='(5)'>"Legal guardian" or "guardian" shall mean biological or adoptive parent of a child registered at a child care facility or a person who is responsible for the care and maintenance of said child pursuant to Florida Statutes or similar laws of another jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(6)'>"Park" means a County or municipal park excluding a park that includes a shooting range.</section><section prefix='(7)'>"Permanent residence" means a place where a person abides, lodges, or resides for fourteen (14) or more consecutive days.</section><section prefix='(8)'>"Reside" or "residence" means to have a place of permanent residence or temporary residence.</section><section prefix='(9)'>"School" means a public or private kindergarten, elementary, middle or secondary (high) school.</section><section prefix='(10)'>"Sexual offender" shall have the meaning ascribed to such term in Section 943.0435, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(11)'>"Sexual offense" means a conviction under Section 794.011, 800.04, 827.071, 847.0135(5) or 847.0145, Florida Statutes, or a similar law of another jurisdiction in which the victim or apparent victim of the sexual offense was less than sixteen (16) years of age, excluding Section 794.011(10), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(12)'>"Sexual predator" shall have the meaning ascribed to such term in Section 775.21, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(13)'>"Temporary residence" means a place where the person abides, lodges, or resides for a period of fourteen (14) or more days in the aggregate during any calendar year and which is not the person's permanent address, or a place where the person routinely abides, lodges, or resides for a period of four (4) or more consecutive or nonconsecutive days in any month and which is not the person's permanent residence.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-206, ยง 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-01, ยง 2, 1-21-10)</history></law>