<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII.5 PROTECTION OF UNDERGROUND UTILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-225</section_number>
<catch_line>Excavation procedures and installation of facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002959</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-225. Excavation procedures and installation of facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>Excavators are prohibited from removing or destroying any markings used by a member operator to mark the horizontal route of an underground facility. If markings are no longer visible, the excavator shall stop activities in that vicinity and notify the State one-call notification system to have the route remarked.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No excavator may excavate or engage in demolition where such excavation or demolition is substantially certain to result in damage to any underground facility; this section shall not preclude an excavator from engaging in exploratory digging. If an excavation or demolition causes damage to any existing underground facility, the excavator must cease excavation or demolition at that depth and immediately notify the affected utility.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No new underground facility shall be installed in such a way that creates a conflict with an existing underground facility unless the excavator submits a permit drawing showing the existence of the conflict and this permit drawing is approved by the permitting agency, or, when the excavator discovers a conflict the existence of which the excavator was unaware of when the excavator applied for a permit, that excavator ceases excavation, immediately notifies the owner of the existing facility, and:<section prefix='1.'>Takes such measures as are reasonable in the determination of the owner of the existing facility to prevent interference with the operation or maintenance of the existing facility, where the existing facility is a water or sewer facility owned, operated, or maintained by the County or a municipality; or</section><section prefix='2.'>Consults with the owner of the existing facility to determine whether measures to prevent interference with the operation, or maintenance of the existing facility are reasonably necessary, if the existing facility is not a water or sewer facility owned, operated, or maintained by the County or a municipality; in the event that the excavator and the owner of the existing facility are not able to determine whether such measures are reasonably necessary, the permitting agency shall determine what measures are reasonably necessary to allow installation of the new facility.</section></section><section>If the owner of the existing facility does not respond to notification provided by an excavator under this section within twenty-four hours of such notification, the excavator shall be allowed to continue installation. All conflicts of which the excavator is aware of when applying for a permit shall be disclosed on the permit drawings; for the purposes of this subpart (c), a conflict which does not involve a water and sewer facility shall refer to twelve (12) and not twenty-four (24) inches. Nothing in this section shall empower any agency or person to approve any installation in violation of any state or federal statute, rule, or code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An excavator shall not engage in directional boring unless the equipment used for such directional boring allows the excavator to monitor the location of the excavator's bore-head, or equivalent equipment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-137, ยง 1, 9-15-98; Ord. No. 00-97, ยง 1, 7-25-00)</history></law>