<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII. JUVENILE CURFEW PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-207</section_number>
<catch_line>Responsibility of parents.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002945</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-207. Responsibility of parents.<section>It shall be unlawful for the parent, legal guardian or other adult person at least twenty-one (21) years of age having the care, custody or control of a juvenile to permit or by insufficient control to permit such juvenile to linger, stay, congregate, move about, wander, or stroll on or upon the public streets, highways, roads, alleys, parks, public buildings, places of amusement and entertainment, vacant lots or any public places in Miami-Dade County during curfew hours, unless the juvenile is accompanied by his or her parent, legal guardian or other adult person at least twenty-one (21) years of age having his or her care, custody or control. Any parent, legal guardian or other adult person at least twenty-one (21) years of age having the care, custody or control of a juvenile who shall have made a missing person notification or informs the police department that the juvenile left or remained away from his or her residence during curfew hours over the objection of the parent, legal guardian or other adult person at least twenty-one (21) years of age having the care, custody or control of the juvenile shall not be considered to have permitted any person to be in violation of this section. It shall also constitute a defense hereto that such parent, legal guardian or other adult person at least twenty-one (21) years of age having the care, custody or control of such juvenile, did not have knowledge of the presence of such juvenile in, or about or upon any place in the county away from the current residence or usual place of abode of said juvenile during curfew hours, if said parent, legal guardian or other person having care, custody or control of such juvenile, in the exercise of reasonable care and diligence, should not have known of the unlawful acts of such juvenile.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-1, ยง 7, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-208, ยง 7, 11-21-95)</history></law>