<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. THE LAUREN BOOK CHILD SAFETY ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-283</section_number>
<catch_line>Property Owners or Lessors Prohibited from Renting Real Property to Certain Sexual Offenders or Sexual Predators; Penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002987</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-283. Property Owners or Lessors Prohibited from Renting Real Property to Certain Sexual Offenders or Sexual Predators; Penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>It is unlawful to let or rent any place, structure, or part thereof, trailer or other conveyance, with knowledge that it will be used as a permanent or temporary residence by any person prohibited from establishing such permanent or temporary residence pursuant to this Article of the Code, if such place, structure, or part thereof, trailer or other conveyance, is located within 2,500 feet of a school. Knowingly renting to a sexual offender or predator shall include, but shall not be limited to, renting or leasing a residence after being notified that the prospective renter, lessee or adult resident is a sexual offender or predator as defined in this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Prior to letting, renting or leasing any place, structure, or part thereof, trailer or other conveyance for use as a permanent or temporary residence that is located within 2,500 feet of a school, and annually thereafter if a rental agreement is entered into, the owner or lessor shall obtain confirmation of a nationwide search from the Miami-Dade County Police Department or other law enforcement agency that the prospective renter, lessee or adult resident is not a registered sexual offender or sexual predator as a result of a conviction of a sexual offense as defined in section 21-280 herein. A person may call the Miami-Dade County Answer Center (311) to obtain assistance or referrals to determine whether a prospective renter, lessee or adult resident is a sexual offender or predator and to determine whether a residence is 2,500 feet, from a particular school.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Penalties.<section prefix='(1)'>A person who violates section 21-283(a) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $500.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 60 days, or both such fine and imprisonment. A person who is convicted of a second or subsequent violation of section 21-283(a) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $1,000.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 364 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A person who violates section 21-283(b) herein shall be punished by a civil penalty of five hundred dollars ($500.00) in the manner established by Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-206, ยง 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-67, ยง 2, 10-5-10)</history></law>