<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-21</section_number>
<catch_line>Alcoholic beverage establishments, solicitation of drinks in.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002806</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-21. Alcoholic beverage establishments, solicitation of drinks in.<section prefix='(a)'>Soliciting drinks. It shall be unlawful for any host, hostess, waiter, waitress, male or female entertainer or employee in a place dispensing alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises to solicit any beverage, whether an alcoholic beverage or otherwise, for which the customer or patron in such establishment pays.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Mingling incident to soliciting drinks. It shall be unlawful for any male or female employee or entertainer in places dispensing alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises to mingle or fraternize with the customers or patrons of such establishments incident to soliciting the purchase of beverages, alcoholic or otherwise, for any such employee and for which the patron or customer in such establishment pays.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Employing persons to solicit drinks. It shall be unlawful for any owner, operator, manager or other employee of a place dispensing alcoholic beverages for the consumption on the premises to employ or permit on the premises any person to solicit drinks for himself or herself or any other person.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Loitering to solicit drinks. It shall be unlawful for any man or woman to frequent or loiter in any tavern, cabaret or night club for the purpose of soliciting drinks.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-5, ยง 24.02, 2-18-58)</history></law>