<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. THE LAUREN BOOK CHILD SAFETY ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-284</section_number>
<catch_line>Sexual Offender and Sexual Predator Access to Parks and Child Care Facilities Restricted; Penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002988</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-284. Sexual Offender and Sexual Predator Access to Parks and Child Care Facilities Restricted; Penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>It is unlawful for a sexual offender or sexual predator convicted of a sexual offense, as defined in section 21-280, to knowingly be present in a County or municipal park, when a child under the age of sixteen (16) years is present, unless the sexual offender or sexual predator is the parent or legal guardian of a child present in the park.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Signage at the entrance of County and municipal parks shall include notification that a person convicted of a sexual offense, as defined in section 21-280 herein, shall not be present in a park when a child under the age of sixteen (16) years is present, unless the sexual offender or sexual predator is the parent or guardian of a child present in the park.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It is unlawful for a sexual offender or sexual predator convicted of a sexual offense, as defined in section 21-280, to knowingly enter or remain in a child care facility ("facility") or on its premises unless the sexual offender or sexual predator:<section prefix='(1)'>Is dropping off or picking up a child registered at the facility and is the parent or legal guardian of said child; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Remains under the supervision of a facility supervisor or his or her designee while on the facility premises.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Penalties. A person who violates section 21-284(a) or (c) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $500.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 60 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. A person who is convicted of a second or subsequent violation of section 21-284(a) or (c) herein shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $1,000.00 or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 364 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-206, ยง 2, 11-15-05; Ord. No. 10-67, ยง 2, 10-5-10)</history></law>