<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. FALSE CLAIMS ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-265</section_number>
<catch_line>Burden of proof; presumption of false claim.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002977</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-265. Burden of proof; presumption of false claim.<section prefix='(1)'>Whenever practicable, bid specifications for County contracts shall contain a requirement that the successful bidder maintain, as a condition precedent to submitting a claim against the County, a final bid takeoff. The final bid takeoff shall contain a line item for allocation of overhead costs.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Upon request from the County, a contractor making a claim against the County for delay or other damages shall submit, within twenty (20) days, a copy of the final bid takeoff, certified pursuant to this subsection. Failure to provide the requested certification shall constitute a forfeiture of the claim for delay or other damages. The certification shall be submitted under oath by a person duly authorized by the claimant and shall contain a statement that:<section prefix='(a)'>The final bid takeoff was prepared contemporaneously with the bid and in anticipation of the bid for the project;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The contractor relied on the final bid takeoff to prepare the bid and the original schedule of values; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>The final bid takeoff has not been altered in any way.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Any claim for extended overhead costs that exceeds, on a per diem basis, more than ten (10) percent of the overhead per diem contained in the final bid takeoff shall be presumed to be a false claim, and the contractor shall have the burden of proving that any such claim for extended overhead is not false.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-152, ยง 1, 11-2-99)</history></law>