<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII.5 PROTECTION OF UNDERGROUND UTILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-224</section_number>
<catch_line>Excavation in the absence of underground facilities markings by member operators.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002958</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-224. Excavation in the absence of underground facilities markings by member operators.<section>Excavators who have complied with the requirements of may proceed without first having a member operator mark underground facilities only in the following situations:<section prefix='(a)'>If a member operator has not located and marked its underground facilities, nor notified the excavator that the area is clear, nor negotiated a new schedule for marking its facilities, within 48 hours, excluding days other than business days, after the excavator's notification to the State one-call notification system; then the excavator may proceed with excavation (but not with demolition), provided the excavator does so with reasonable care, using detection equipment, exploratory digging, or other acceptable means to locate underground facilities. Except as provided below, no demolition shall proceed until all underground facilities have been marked and either safeguarded or removed.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If a member operator certifies that it does not have accurate information concerning the exact location of its underground facilities and provides the best information available, an excavator may proceed, provided that the excavation or demolition is performed with reasonable care and detection equipment, exploratory digging, or other acceptable means to locate underground facilities are used.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-137, ยง 1, 9-15-98; Ord. No. 00-97, ยง 1, 7-25-00)</history></law>