<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-26</section_number>
<catch_line>Firefighters, policemen, service, execution of process; court order; hindering, obstructing justice.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002818</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-26. Firefighters, policemen, service, execution of process; court order; hindering, obstructing justice.<section prefix='(A)'>Prohibitions.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly resist or obstruct the performance by one, who the person knows or has reason to believe is a police officer or firefighter, of any authorized act within such officer's official capacity.</section><section prefix='(2)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly resist or obstruct the authorized service or execution of any civil or criminal process or order of court.</section><section prefix='(3)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly obstruct justice. A person obstructs justice when, with intent to prohibit the apprehension or obstruct the prosecution or defense of any person, the person knowingly commits any of the following actions:<section prefix='(a)'>Destroys, alters, conceals or disguises physical evidence, plants false evidence, or furnishes false information; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Induces a witness having knowledge material to the subject at issue to leave the State or conceal himself; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Leaves the State or conceals himself when the person possesses knowledge material to the subject at issue.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Penalties. Any person convicted of a violation of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-5, ยง 21.02, 2-18-58; Ord. No. 69-92, ยง 2, 12-17-69)</history></law>