<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-21.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Alcoholic beverages and drugs at open house parties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002808</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-21.2. Alcoholic beverages and drugs at open house parties.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions. For purposes of this section, the following terms shall be defined as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>"Adult" means a person not legally prohibited by reason of age from possessing alcoholic beverages pursuant to Chapter 562, Florida Statutes, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(2)'>"Alcoholic beverage" means any beverage containing more than one (1) percent of alcohol by weight. The percentage of alcohol by weight shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of Section 561.01(4)(b), Florida Statutes, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(3)'>"Drug" means "controlled substance" as that term is defined in Section 893.02(3) and 893.03, Florida Statutes, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(4)'>"Minor" means a person not legally permitted by reason of age to possess alcoholic beverages pursuant to Chapter 562, Florida Statutes, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(5)'>"Open house party" means a social gathering at a residence.</section><section prefix='(6)'>"Residence" means a home, apartment, condominium or other dwelling unit.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Responsibility of adults. No adult having control of any residence shall allow an open house party to take place at said residence if any alcoholic beverage or drug is possessed or consumed at said residence by any minor where the adult knew or reasonably should have known that an alcoholic beverage or drug was in the possession of or being consumed by a minor at said residence, and where the adult failed to take reasonable steps to prevent the possession or consumption of the alcoholic beverage or drug.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Exception. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the use of alcoholic beverages at legally protected religious observances or activities.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Penalties. The penalties for violation of this section are as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For the first violation, a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00);</section><section prefix='(2)'>For subsequent violations, a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-60, §§ 1—4, 7-17-84)</history></law>