<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. FALSE CLAIMS ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-261</section_number>
<catch_line>Awards to plaintiffs bringing action.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002973</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-261. Awards to plaintiffs bringing action.<section prefix='(1)'>If the County proceeds with and prevails in an action brought by a person under this article, except as provided in subsection (2), the court shall order the distribution to the person of ten (10) percent of the proceeds recovered under any judgment obtained by the County in an action under Section 21-258 or of the proceeds of any settlement of the claim.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the County proceeds with an action which the court finds to be based primarily on disclosures of specific information, other than that provided by the person initiating the action, relating to allegations or transactions in a criminal, civil, or administration hearing; a legislative, administrative, or inspector general report, hearing, audit, or investigation; or from the news media, the court may award such sums as it considers appropriate, but in no case more than five (5) percent of the proceeds recovered under a judgment or received in settlement of a claim under this article, taking into account the significance of the information and the role of the person bringing the action in advancing the case to litigation.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If the County does not proceed with an action under this article, the person bringing the action or settling the claim shall receive twenty-five (25) percent of the proceeds recovered under a judgment rendered in an action under this article or in settlement of a claim under this article.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Any payment under this section to the person bringing the action shall be paid only out of the proceeds recovered from the defendant.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Whether or not the County proceeds with the action, if the court finds that the action was brought by a person who planned, initiated, or furthered the violation of Section 21-258 upon which the action was brought, the person shall be dismissed from the civil action and shall not receive any share of the proceeds of the action. Such dismissal shall not prejudice the right of the County to continue the action.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-152, ยง 1, 11-2-99)</history></law>