<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-22.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Sale, offer for sale, purchase with intent to sell and public display for sale prohibited of synthetic stimulant bath salts, synthetic cathinones, synthetic amphetamines and other synthetic stimulants that mimic illegal drugs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002811</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-22.1. Sale, offer for sale, purchase with intent to sell and public display for sale prohibited of synthetic stimulant bath salts, synthetic cathinones, synthetic amphetamines and other synthetic stimulants that mimic illegal drugs.<section prefix='(a)'>Purpose and intent. The Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners finds and declares that the products and synthetic substances described hereunder are commonly used as alternatives to amphetamines, cocaine, ecstasy and other illegal drugs. The Board further finds that these synthetic substances are particularly appealing to youth, and that these synthetic substances are potentially dangerous to users in the short term and the long term effects are not yet known. The Board finds that the products which contain these synthetic substances often use a disclaimer that the product is "not for human consumption" to avoid regulations that require the manufacturer to list the product's active ingredients. The Board finds that drug designers and chemists can quickly create new synthetic drugs once federal or state law makes a particular synthetic drug illegal. As such, the Board finds there is a need to declare illegal the sale, offer for sale, purchase with intent to sell and public display for sale of synthetic substances that mimic illegal controlled substances, even though such synthetic substances have not yet themselves been categorized as illegal controlled substances under federal or state law. The Board further finds that it is proper and necessary for the Board to exercise its authority to safeguard and protect the public health, safety and welfare by taking this action.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Application. This section shall be applicable in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, with the enforcement of the provision of this section in the unincorporated area being the responsibility of Miami-Dade County and in the incorporated area being the responsibility of the respective municipalities.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Preemption. This section shall not preempt any municipal ordinance governing this subject area that is more stringent than this ordinance or that declares illegal a substance that is not declared illegal by this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Definitions. For purposes of this section, the following terms apply;<section prefix='(1)'>Structurally similar as used in this section shall mean chemical substitutions off a common chemical backbone associated with cathinone, methcathinone, amphetamine, methamphetamine, cocaine, 3,4-methylenedioxymethamphetamine (MDMA), 3,4-methylenedioxymethcathinone, 3,4- methylenedioxypyrovalerone (MDPV), methylmethcathinone, methoxymethcathinone, methylethcathinone, fluoromethcathinone, BZP (benzylpiperazine), fluorophenylpiperazine, methylphenylpiperazine, chlorophenylpiperazine, methoxyphenylpiperazine, DBZP (1,4- dibenzylpiperazine), TFMPP (3-Trifluoromethylphenylpiperazine), MBDB (Methylbenzodioxolylbutanamine), 5-Hydroxy-alpha-methyltryptamine, 5-Hydroxy-N-methyltryptamine, 5-Methoxy-N-methyl-N-isopropyltryptamine, 5-Methoxy-alpha-methyltryptamine, methyltryptamine, 5-Methoxy- N,N-dimethyltryptamine, 5-Methyl-N,N-dimethyltryptamine, 5-Methoxy-N,N-Diisopropyltryptamine, DiPT (N,N-Diisopropyltryptamine), DPT N,N-Dipropyltryptamine) 4-Hydroxy-N,N-diisopropyltryptamine, N,N-Diallyl-5-Methoxytryptamine, DOI (4-Iodo-2,5-dimethoxyamphetamine), DOC (4-Chloro-2,5- dimethoxyamphetamine), 2C-E (4-Ethyl-2,5- dimethoxyphenethylamine), 2C-T-4 (2,5-Dimethoxy-4-isopropylthiophenethylamine), 2C-C (4-Chloro-2, 5-dimethoxyphenethylamine), 2C-T (2,5-Dimethoxy-4-methylthiophenethylamine), 2C- T-2 (2,5-Dimethoxy-4-ethylthiophenethylamine), 2C-T-7 (2,5-Dimethoxy-4-(n)-propylthiophenethylamine), 2C-I (4-Iodo-2,5-dimethoxyphenethylamine), Butylone (beta-keto-N-methylbenzodioxolylpropylamine), Ethcathinone, Ethylone (3,4-methylenedioxy-N-ethylcathinone), Naphyrone (naphthylpyrovalerone), N-N-Dimethyl-3,4-methylenedioxycathinone, N-N-Diethyl-3,4-methylenedioxycathinone, 3,4-methylenedioxy-propiophenone, 2-Bromo-3,4-Methylenedioxypropiophenone, 3,4-methylenedioxy-propiophenone-2-oxime, N-Acetyl-3,4-methylenedioxycathinone, N-Acetyl-N-Methyl-3,4-Methylenedioxycathinone, N-Acetyl-N-Ethyl-3,4-Methylenedioxycathinone, Bromomethcathinone, Buphedrone (alpha-methylamino-butyrophenone), Eutylone (beta-Keto-Ethylbenzodioxolylbutanamine), Dimethylcathinone, Dimethylmethcathinone, Pentylone (beta-Keto-Methylbenzodioxolylpentanamine), (MDPPP) 3,4-Methylenedioxy-alpha pyrrolidinopropiophenone, (MDPBP) 3,4-Methylenedioxy-alpha pyrrolidinobutiophenone, Methoxy-alpha-pyrrolidinopropiophenone (MOPPP), Methyl-alpha-pyrrolidinohexiophenone (MPHP), Benocyclidine (BCP), benzothiophenylcyclohexylpiperidine (BTCP), Fluoromethylaminobutyrophenone (F- MABP), Methoxypyrrolidinobutyrophenone (MeO- PBP), Ethyl-pyrrolidinobutyrophenone (Et-PBP), 3-Methyl-4-Methoxymethcathinone (3-Me-4-MeO- MCAT), Methylethylaminobutyrophenone (Me-EABP), Methylamino-butyrophenone (MABP), Pyrrolidinopropiophenone (PPP), Pyrrolidinobutiophenone (PBP), Pyrrolidinovalerophenone (PVP), Methyl-alpha-pyrrolidinopropiophenone (MPPP), or related salts, isomers, and salts of isomers, listed in the controlled substance schedules in Chapter 893, Florida Statutes, as amended, or otherwise prohibited by federal or state law.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Synthetic stimulant bath salts as used in this section shall mean any substance, whether in powder, crystal, liquid, tablet or capsule form, containing a synthetic stimulant as defined herein or to which a synthetic stimulant has been added or applied, that can be ingested by smoking, inhaling or other method, regardless of whether the substance is marketed as not for the purpose of human consumption, and regardless of how the substance is labeled, including, but not limited to, bath salts, insect repellant, plant food, herbs, incense, iPod cleaner, nutrient, dietary supplement or spice.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Synthetic stimulant as used in this section shall mean any chemical or mixture of chemicals, however packaged, that has a stimulant effect on the central nervous system and is structurally similar to cathinone, methcathinone, amphetamine, methamphetamine, cocaine, MDMA or any other substance listed in paragraph (1) above, or related salts, isomers, and salts of isomers, as listed in the controlled substance schedules in Chapter 893, Florida Statutes, or otherwise prohibited by federal or state law. "Synthetic stimulant" shall also include any chemical or mixture of chemicals, however packaged, that mimics the pharmacological effects of cathinone, methcathinone, amphetamine, methamphetamine, cocaine, MDMA or any other substance listed in paragraph (1) above, or related salts, isomers, and salts of isomers. Packaging that indicates, suggests or implies that a product mimics the pharmacological effects of cathinone, methcathinone, amphetamine, methamphetamine, cocaine, ecstasy or any other substance listed in paragraph (1) above, shall create a presumption that the product mimics the effects of the substance. "Synthetic stimulant" shall not include any substance currently listed in the controlled substance schedules in Chapter 893, Florida Statutes, or otherwise prohibited by federal or state law, as such may be amended from time to time.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Sale, offer for sale and purchase with intent to sell synthetic stimulant bath salts and synthetic stimulants prohibited. It shall be unlawful for any store owner, store manager, store purchasing agent or other person to sell, offer for sale or purchase with intent to sell any synthetic stimulant bath salts as defined herein or any synthetic stimulants as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Public display for sale of synthetic stimulant bath salts and synthetic stimulants prohibited. It shall be unlawful for any store owner, store manager, store purchasing agent or other person to publicly display for sale any synthetic stimulant bath salts as defined herein or any synthetic stimulants as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Affirmative defense. It shall be an affirmative defense to prosecution of a violation of this section if the sale, offer for sale, purchase with intent to sell or public display for sale of synthetic stimulant bath salts as defined herein or synthetic stimulants as defined herein is pursuant to the direction or prescription of a licensed physician or dentist authorized in the State of Florida to direct or prescribe such act.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Seizure and destruction of synthetic stimulant bath salts and synthetic stimulants. Synthetic stimulant bath salts and synthetic stimulants prohibited herein may be seized by law enforcement officers and may be destroyed in the same manner used to destroy narcotics and contraband substances, after its use for evidentiary purposes in any judicial proceeding is no longer required.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Injunctive relief. Miami-Dade County shall have the authority to seek an injunction against any person or business violating the provisions of this section. In any action seeking an injunction, Miami-Dade County shall be entitled to collect its enforcement expenses, including forensic costs, law enforcement costs and reasonable attorney fees and costs incurred at the trial level and on appeal.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Subsequent federal or state action. If Congress or a federal agency amends federal law to include a particular substance or otherwise enacts or amends a federal law providing for criminal penalties for the prohibitions of substances set forth in this ordinance, then upon the effective date of such enactment or amendment, the provisions of this ordinance addressed by federal law shall no longer be deemed effective. Any violations of this ordinance committed prior to Congress or a federal agency enacting a federal law may be prosecuted.</section><section>If the Florida Legislature amends the controlled substance schedules in Section 893.01, Florida Statutes, to include a particular substance or otherwise enacts, or amends a state statute providing for criminal penalties for the prohibitions of substances set forth in this ordinance, then upon the effective date of such enactment or amendment, the provisions of this ordinance addressed by the state statute shall no longer be deemed effective.</section><section>If the Florida Attorney General pursuant to the rulemaking authority provided in Chapter 893[, Florida Statutes,] adds a particular substance to the controlled substance schedules in Section 893.01, Florida Statutes, then upon the effective date of such enactment or amendment, the provisions of this ordinance addressed by the state statute shall no longer be deemed effective.</section><section>Any violations of this ordinance committed prior to the Florida Legislature enacting such a statute or the Florida Attorney General promulgating rules may be prosecuted.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Penalty. Any store owner, store manager, store purchasing agent or other person violating any provision of this section shall be punishable by:<section prefix='(1)'>A fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00);</section><section prefix='(2)'>Imprisonment in the county jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-45, ยง 1, 7-3-12)</history></law>