<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-37</section_number>
<catch_line>Persons confined in Miami-Dade County Jail for violations of the Miami-Dade Code; unlawful acts; penalty.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002846</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-37. Persons confined in Miami-Dade County Jail for violations of the Miami-Dade Code; unlawful acts; penalty.<section prefix='(a)'>Escape or attempted escape. It shall be unlawful for any person arrested for or convicted of a violation of the Miami-Dade Code, who is confined in the Miami-Dade County Jail, or who is being transported to or from said place of confinement, or who is working outside of said place of confinement as a prisoner, to escape or attempt to escape from such custody or confinement.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Conspiracy to violate subsection (a). It shall be unlawful for any person to conspire, combine or confederate with another to violate the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Harboring, concealing, aiding escaped prisoners. It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly harbor, conceal, maintain, assist or give any aid to any person violating subsections (a), (b) or (d) of this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Failure to return to jail under release time program. It shall be unlawful for any person who has been convicted of a violation of the Miami-Dade Code and whose sentence permits participation in the release time program to fail to return to the Miami-Dade County Jail at the time specified by the program.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Penalties. Every person who is convicted of a violation of this section shall be punished by imprisonment in the Miami-Dade County Jail for not more than ninety (90) days. Any sentence imposed for a violation of this section shall run consecutively to any former sentence imposed upon any person convicted hereunder.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 67-79, §§ 1—5, 10-17-67)</history></law>