<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-35</section_number>
<catch_line>Glue and cement; sales to minors; exception; intoxication; applicable areas; penalty for section violation; trials.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002843</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-35. Glue and cement; sales to minors; exception; intoxication; applicable areas; penalty for section violation; trials.<section prefix='(a)'>Sales to persons under eighteen prohibited. Except as otherwise provided herein, no person shall sell, deliver or give to any individual under the age of eighteen (18) years, any glue, cement, or automotive transmission or brake fluids containing one (1) or more of the following volatile solvents:<section prefix='(1)'>Toluol or toluene</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hexane</section><section prefix='(3)'>Trichloroethylene</section><section prefix='(4)'>Acetone</section><section prefix='(5)'>Toluene</section><section prefix='(6)'>Ethyl acetate</section><section prefix='(7)'>Methyl ethyl ketone</section><section prefix='(8)'>Trichloroethane</section><section prefix='(9)'>Isopropanol</section><section prefix='(10)'>Methyl isobutyl ketone</section><section prefix='(11)'>Methyl cellosolve acetate</section><section prefix='(12)'>Cychlohexanone</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Exception—Glue or cement. The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply where no more than one (1) tube of the glue or cement is sold, delivered or given simultaneously with or as part of a kit used for the construction of model airplanes, model boats, model automobiles, model trains or other similar models.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Same—Transmission or brake fluids. The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to the sale or delivery of transmission or brake fluids when those substances are placed directly into the automobiles of minors sixteen (16) or seventeen (17) years of age who possess a valid drivers license.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Intoxication in public place. It shall be unlawful for any person to be found in a public place under the influence of or in a state of intoxication as the result of inhaling any glue, cement or automotive transmission or brake fluids containing one (1) or more of the solvents named in subsection (a).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Applicable areas. This section is applicable in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Penalty for violation of section. Any person violating any of the provisions of this section shall be punished by fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days or both at the discretion of the court.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 67-33, §§ 1—6, 5-16-67; Ord. No. 75-82, §§ 1, 2, 4, 10-1-75)</history></law>