<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-31.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Warning signs required for retail sale of alcoholic beverages.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002838</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-31.3. Warning signs required for retail sale of alcoholic beverages.<section prefix='(a)'>For the purposes of this section the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(1)'>Alcoholic beverages shall mean alco- holic beverages as set forth in Section 561.01(4)(a), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Sale and sell shall mean "sale" and "sell" as set forth in Section 561.01(9), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Retail shall mean sale to the ultimate consumer.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall sell at retail any alcoholic beverage unless said person has posted in a conspicuous place where the sale is to occur a sign which is at least eleven (11) inches by seventeen (17) inches in size, which is plainly visible and legible to all persons entering the premises and which shall read as follows:</section><section>HEALTH WARNING<section>ALCOHOL IN BEER, WINE AND LIQUOR CAN CAUSE:</section><section prefix='*'>INTOXICATION</section><section prefix='*'>ADDICTION</section><section prefix='*'>BIRTH DEFECTS</section><section>REDUCE YOUR RISKS:</section><section prefix='•'>DO NOT DRINK BEFORE DRIVING OR OPERATING MACHINERY.</section><section prefix='•'>DO NOT MIX ALCOHOL WITH OTHER DRUGS (IT CAN BE FATAL).</section><section prefix='•'>DO NOT DRINK DURING PREGNANCY.</section></section><section>Notwithstanding any provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, said sign shall also be translated into Spanish and posted.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Hotels, restaurants, lounges and other establishments which are permitted to sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises are expressly exempt from the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any person violating any of the provisions of this section shall, upon conviction of such offense, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both, in the discretion of the court. Each day of continued violation shall be considered a separate offense.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-49, § 1, 5-7-91)</history></law>