<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-33</section_number>
<catch_line>Races, automobiles and motorcycles.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002841</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-33. Races, automobiles and motorcycles.<section prefix='(a)'>Permit required. It shall be unlawful for any person to engage in, participate in, conduct, operate, or assist in the conducting or operating of a motor vehicle or motorcycle race or race meet in any public place or on any public street, road or highway in Miami-Dade County, Florida, without first obtaining a permit issued under and pursuant to the provisions of this section. The requirement of this section shall not relieve any person from compliance with the provisions of Chapter 549, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Application for permit; conditions for issuance. All applications for permits under this section shall be filed with the Miami-Dade Police Director or Metropolitan Sheriff and shall set forth in detail the full name and address of the applicant, the time when, and the place where such race or race meet is to occur, and what safeguards will be taken to protect the public and the participants from injury, and such other information as may be prescribed by the Public Safety Director. Such application shall be signed and sworn to by the applicant. The Director shall prescribe the form of application and furnish such application forms to applicants upon request.</section><section>Permit shall not be issued when the Director has good reason to believe that the proposed race or race meet will disturb the public peace, cause congestion of traffic, or endanger the lives or property of the public, participants or spectators.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Fees; contents of permits. The County Manager shall establish a schedule of filing fees to cover the cost of investigating and processing applications for permits. The permit issued hereunder shall show the time or period of time when and the place where the race or race meet is to occur; however, no race meet shall be permitted for a period of time in excess of thirty (30) days.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Intent of section; supplementary to State law. This section is intended to implement and supplement Chapter 549, Florida Statutes, and not to supersede or conflict with any provisions thereof. The intent and purpose of this section is hereby declared to be to provide more stringent regulation and control of motor vehicle and motorcycle races and race meets in this County, for the public safety, health and welfare. Any person who violates any of the provisions of Chapter 549, Florida Statutes, shall be deemed to have violated the provisions of this section and may be prosecuted in the court of appropriate jurisdiction of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-28, §§ 1—3, 9-20-60; Ord. No. 61-5, § 1, 2-14-61)</history></law>