<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-32</section_number>
<catch_line>Tip sheets for racing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002840</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-32. Tip sheets for racing.<section prefix='(a)'>Selling or offering for sale papers predicting outcome of races. No person shall engage in or manage the business of displaying, selling or offering for sale any tip sheet or touting services, the sole purposes of which is to predict the outcome of any horse or dog race or other lawful competitive contest without first having obtained a permit from the Miami-Dade Police Director.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Papers to be printed only under true name of person making prediction. No sheet, paper or pamphlet described in this section shall be printed except under the true and correct name of the person making such prediction, and all such sheets, papers and pamphlets shall contain the following words stamped thereon, "Prediction Made Prior to 1 o'clock P.M. on the  day of //, 19", with the true date inserted in the blank spaces appearing thereon.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Registration of production with police. No person shall display, sell or offer for sale any sheet, paper or pamphlet, as herein described, without first having registered the prediction of the horses or dogs or other contestant designated to win with the Miami-Dade Police Director or his duly authorized agent, not later than 1:00 p.m. of the day on which the race or other event is to be held.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Newspapers and operators of licensed race tracks exempt. Newspapers, as that term is defined in Section 49.01, Florida Statutes, and operators of licensed race tracks are expressly exempt from the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Application for tip sheet permit. Application for a tip sheet permit shall be made, in writing, to the Miami-Dade Police Director and accompanied by an application fee, which fee shall be utilized to defray the cost of enforcement of this section. The amount of such application fee shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager, in accordance with Section 4.02 of the Miami-Dade County Charter. All applicants shall be fingerprinted and photographed by the Miami-Dade Police Department, which shall issue a permit, if said application is approved, within ten (10) days from the date of such application.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-5, ยง 24.03, 2-18-58; Ord. No. 77-33, ยง 1, 6-21-77)</history></law>