<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-30.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Public dance halls.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002832</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-30.1. Public dance halls.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions of terms.</section><section>The term "public dance" or "public ball," as used under this section, shall be taken to include any dance or ball conducted in connection with instruction in dancing for hire, and any dance or ball to which admission may be had by the payment of a fee or by the purchase, possession, or presentation of a ticket or token, or in connection with which a charge is made for caring for clothing or other property; and any dance or ball to which the public generally may gain admission with or without the payment of a fee.</section><section>The term "dance hall" or "ballroom," as used in this section, shall be taken to include any room, place, or space, in which a public dance or public ball, as herein defined, shall be held, and any room, hall, or academy, in which classes in dancing are held and instruction in dancing is given for hire.</section><section>The term "owner", as used in this section, shall be taken to include the owner, operator, manager or other person having supervision of a dance hall or ballroom as defined herein. Any license required by State or municipal laws for the operation of a dance hall or ballroom shall be prima facie evidence that the licensee named therein is the owner of said dance hall or ballroom as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Regulation of employees and other persons. It shall be unlawful:<section prefix='(1)'>For any hostess, waitress, female entertainer, or female employee in a dance hall or ballroom to be served any beverage, whether an alcoholic beverage or otherwise, for which a customer or patron in such establishment pays;</section><section prefix='(2)'>For any person in or about any dance hall or ballroom to solicit dancing partners on a commission basis, directly or indirectly;</section><section prefix='(3)'>For any person in or about any dance hall or ballroom to solicit the purchase of refreshment on a commission basis, directly or indirectly;</section><section prefix='(4)'>For a female employee in a dance hall or ballroom to sell her time to a male customer other than for the purpose of giving dance instructions to such customer;</section><section prefix='(5)'>For female employees or entertainers in dance halls or ballrooms to mingle or fraternize with the customers or patrons of such establishments except when actually providing dance instruction to such customers or patrons.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Responsibility of owners. It shall be unlawful for the owner of any dance hall or ballroom to permit or allow therein any solicitation, sale, or fraternization as prohibited in this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Penalty. Any person violating any of the provisions of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 65-43, §§ 1—4, 5-18-65)</history></law>