<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-31.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Disorderly conduct, loitering; penalties, trial for violations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002836</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-31.1. Disorderly conduct, loitering; penalties, trial for violations.<section prefix='(a)'>Disorderly conduct. Any person commits the offense of disorderly conduct when he knowingly:<section prefix='(1)'>With intent to harass, annoy, abuse or threaten another, makes a telephone call, whether or not conversation thereby ensures; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Enters upon the property of another and for lewd or unlawful purpose deliberately looks into a dwelling on the property through any window or other opening in it; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Engages in fighting or brawling in any public place or place open to the general public; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Uses profane, vulgar, or indecent language, in any public place, or upon the private premises of another, or so near thereto as to be heard by another.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Loitering. For the purpose of this section "loitering" means the act of standing, remaining or sleeping on, in or about any public street, public sidewalk, public overpass, public bridge, public library or other place specifically enumerated herein. A person commits the offense of loitering when he knowingly:<section prefix='(1)'>Loiters on any public street, public sidewalk, public overpass, public bridge or public place so as to hinder or impede the passage of pedestrians or vehicles.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Loiters in or about any police station, police headquarters building, County building, hospital, court building, or any other public building or place for the purpose of soliciting employment of legal services or sureties upon criminal recognizances.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Loiters in or about a school, college or university campus so as to hinder or impede the orderly conduct of instructional, recreational or other school activities.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Loiters in or about a public library so as to hinder or impede the normal operation of the library.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Penalties for violation. Any person convicted of a violation of subsection (a)(3) or (a)(4) of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed thirty (30) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court. Any person convicted of a violation of any other subsection of this section shall be punished by a fine of five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court. This section is applicable in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and all violations thereof shall be prosecuted in the County Court.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Trial in Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court. Where the offense set forth involves violation by minors, the same shall be tried in the Miami-Dade County Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court when so required by the laws of the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Fingerprinting. Every person charged with any violation of the provisions of subsection (a) or (b) of this section may be fingerprinted and photographed by the Miami-Dade Police Department. Upon an adjudication of not guilty of a charged violation of subsection (a) or (b), the Miami-Dade Police Department will cause all fingerprints and photographs to be expunged and destroyed, including any forwarded to the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the Florida Sheriff's Bureau, provided such fingerprints and photographs result solely from such charge or charges so adjudicated.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 67-17, §§ 1—3, 3-7-67; Ord. No. 67-56, § 1, 7-25-67; Ord. No. 69-93, § 1, 12-17-69; Ord. No. 70-68, § 1, 9-15-70; Ord. No. 71-81, § 1, 10-5-71; Ord. No. 71-96, § 1, 2-21-71; Ord. No. 73-34, § 1, 4-3-73; Ord. No. 74-43, § 1, 6-18-74; Ord. No. 80-76, § 1, 7-15-80; Ord. No. 82-14, § 1, 3-2-82)</history></law>