<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-31.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Aggressive or obstructive panhandling prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002839</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-31.4. Aggressive or obstructive panhandling prohibited.<section prefix='(A)'>Definitions. The following definitions apply in this section:<section prefix='(1)'>Aggressively beg means to beg with the intent to intimidate another person into giving money or goods.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Intimidate means to engage in conduct which would make a reasonable person fearful or feel compelled. Among the circumstances which may be considered in determining whether the actor intends to intimidate another person into giving money or goods are that the actor: (a) touches the person solicited; (b) follows the person solicited, and persists in begging after the person solicited has given a negative response; (c) directs profane or abusive language toward the person solicited; or (d) uses violent or threatening gestures toward the person solicited.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Beg means to ask or solicit for money or goods as a charity, whether by word, bodily gestures, signs, or other means.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Obstruct pedestrian or vehicular traffic means to walk, stand, sit, lie, or place an object in such a manner as to block passage by another person or a vehicle, or to require another person or a driver of a vehicle to take unreasonable evasive action to avoid physical contact.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Public place means an area generally visible to public view and includes alleys, bridges, buildings, driveways, parking lots, parks, plazas, sidewalks and streets open to the general public, including those that serve food or drink or provide entertainment, and the doorways and entrances to buildings or dwellings and the grounds enclosing them.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Unreasonable evasive action means causing a vehicle to depart from the lane of traffic in which it is traveling to change lanes, to straddle lanes, or to enter onto a swale to obtain passage; it also means causing a pedestrian to leave the sidewalk on which she or he is traveling or to make contact with a wall or fence bordering the sidewalk.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Prohibited acts. A person is guilty of pedestrian interference if, in a public place, he or she intentionally:<section prefix='(1)'>Obstructs pedestrian or vehicular traffic; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Aggressively begs.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Permitted activities. Acts authorized as an exercise of one's constitutional right to picket or to legally protest, and acts authorized by a permit duly issued by a lawful authority shall not constitute obstruction of pedestrian or vehicular traffic.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Penalties. Any person convicted of:<section prefix='(1)'>A violation of this section shall be punished by:<section prefix='a.'>Not more than thirty (30) days imprisonment;</section><section prefix='b.'>A fine of not more than one hundred dollars ($100.00);</section><section prefix='c.'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='d.'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='e.'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>A second or subsequent violation of this section shall be punished by:<section prefix='a.'>Not more than sixty (60) days imprisonment;</section><section prefix='b.'>A fine not more than two hundred dollars ($200.00);</section><section prefix='c.'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='d.'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='e.'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section><section prefix='(E)'>Alternative programs. Nothing herein shall limit the discretion of the police, court personnel, and judges from referring individuals suspected, charged, or convicted of a violation of this provision to treatment programs or facilities as an alternative to prosecution or incarceration, provided that the individual freely consents. For homeless individuals, such alternative programs shall include, but not be limited to, the Miami-Dade County Homeless Assistance Project.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-41, ยง 1, 3-17-94; Ord. No. 10-52, ยง 7, 9-21-10)</history></law>