<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-38</section_number>
<catch_line>Hypodermic syringe or needle; sale prohibited without prescription; discarding prohibited without destruction or mutilation and packaging and sealing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002847</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-38. Hypodermic syringe or needle; sale prohibited without prescription; discarding prohibited without destruction or mutilation and packaging and sealing.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to sell or distribute on a retail basis any hypodermic syringe or needle, designed principally for subcutaneous injection, except when authorized by prescription, as such terms is defined in Section 465.031(2), Florida Statutes, by such persons as are authorized under Florida law to issue prescriptions for drugs to be administered subcutaneously by hypodermic syringe.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to discard any hypodermic syringe or needle, designed principally for subcutaneous injection, without first rendering such hypodermic syringe or needle useless by destruction or mutilation of the syringe barrel and needle.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to place any item set forth in subsection (b) of this section, including the destroyed or mutilated remains thereof, into a garbage or trash container unless said item shall have been first packaged and sealed.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Every person who is convicted of a violation of subsection (a), (b) or (c) shall be punished by fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 70-79, §§ 1, 2, 10-27-70; Ord. No. 73-12, §§ 1—3, 2-6-73)</history></law>