<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-44</section_number>
<catch_line>Manholes; safety requirements; penalty.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002854</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-44. Manholes; safety requirements; penalty.<section prefix='(a)'>No person, firm or corporation shall cause any person to enter a manhole being used for repairs, maintenance, installation or inspection of underground utilities unless the following requirements are fulfilled:<section prefix='(1)'>A second person shall remain abovegrade at all times to provide surveillance of the manhole and the person(s) belowgrade until the manhole cover is in place and no person(s) remains belowgrade at or near the location of the manhole.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The person required herein to remain abovegrade shall be trained and shall be capable of providing first aid and emergency rescue procedures and shall be furnished with communication equipment to summon additional aid in the event of an emergency.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The person providing aboveground surveillance shall keep animals and unauthorized persons away from the open manhole.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The person required herein to remain abovegrade may be assigned other duties provided such other duties do not interfere with the requirements of this section.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Every violation of any provision of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment in the County Jail for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days or both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court. Each day of continued violation shall be considered as a separate offense.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 83-3, ยง 1, 2-1-83)</history></law>