<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-43</section_number>
<catch_line>Promotion, delivery, possession with intent to promote or deliver torture materials, instruments or devices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002853</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-43. Promotion, delivery, possession with intent to promote or deliver torture materials, instruments or devices.<section prefix='(A)'>Definitions. As used herein the following words shall be construed as defined:<section prefix='(1)'>"Promote" means to manufacture, issue, sell, give, provide, lend, rent, mail, deliver, transfer, transmit, publish, distribute, circulate, disseminate, produce, present, direct, exhibit or to offer or to agree to do the same.</section><section prefix='(2)'>"Deliver" means the actual, constructive, or attempted transfer from one (1) person to another of torture materials, instruments or devices, whether or not there is an agency relationship.</section><section prefix='(3)'>"Person" includes individuals, children, juveniles, firms, associations, joint ventures, partnerships, estates, trusts, syndicates, fiduciaries, corporations and all other groups or combinations.</section><section prefix='(4)'>"Juvenile" means any person under the age of seventeen (17).</section><section prefix='(5)'>"Knowingly" means having general knowledge of, or reason to know, or a belief or ground for belief which warrants further inspection or inquiry of:<section prefix='(a)'>The character or content of any material, instrument or device which is reasonably susceptible of examination by the defendant, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the case of a juvenile, the age of the juvenile; provided, however, that an honest mistake shall constitute an excuse from liability hereunder if the defendant made a reasonable, bona fide attempt to ascertain the true age of such juvenile.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Offenses and penalties.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to promote, deliver or possess with the intent to promote or deliver materials, instruments or devices whose sole or primary purpose is for the torture of human beings or animals. By way of example, and not limitation, such materials, instruments or devices include: Dungeons, torture chambers, discipline helmets, fetters, gags, chastity torture or spanker belts, punishment bras, paddles, chain hanging cages, suspension harnesses, pillories or stocks, whipping posts or platforms, racks, impalers, thumb screws, iron maidens.</section><section prefix='(2)'>It shall be unlawful to knowingly advertise to juveniles the promotion, delivery or possession of materials, instruments or devices whose sole or primary purpose is for the torture of human beings or animals.</section><section prefix='(3)'>It is unlawful for any person or juvenile to falsely represent to an owner or advertiser or his agent, with regard to this subsection that such juvenile is seventeen (17) years of age or older, for the purpose of gaining entrance to any premises where such materials, instruments or devices prescribed in this subsection are promoted, delivered or possessed or for the promotion, delivery or possession of such materials, instruments or devices.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Every act, thing or transaction forbidden by this section shall constitute a separate offense and be punishable as such.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Whenever any person is convicted under this section, the County Court in awarding sentence may make an order confiscating the material, instrument or device or advertisement and authorize the executive officer of the court to destroy same.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Proof that a defendant knowingly committed an act or engaged in any conduct referred to in this section may be made by showing that at the time such act was committed or conduct engaged in such person had actual knowledge of the contents or character of the material, instrument or device or thing promoted, delivered or possessed or by showing facts and circumstances from which it may fairly be inferred that such person had such knowledge, or by showing that such person had knowledge of such facts and circumstances as would put a person of ordinary intelligence and caution on inquiry as to such content or character.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any person violating the provisions of this section, upon conviction, shall be punished by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment for a term not exceeding six (6) months, or both in the discretion of the court.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Legislative intent.<section prefix='(1)'>This section shall not pertain to the exposure of persons over seventeen (17) years of age to harmful motion pictures, exhibitions, shows, representations and presentations, in accordance with Section 847.09, Florida Statutes 1975.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Nothing herein shall be construed to limit the free exercise of free speech or picketing by any person, organization or group for the purpose of upholding community standards.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-63, ยง 1, 7-6-76)</history></law>