<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. USED MOTOR VEHICLE PARTS DEALERS, WRECKERS AND REBUILDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-53</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Prerequisite for issuance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002864</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-53. Same—Prerequisite for issuance.<section>The Director shall file each application received and, when satisfied that the applicant, if an individual, or each of the partners or principal officers of the applicant, if a partnership or corporation, is of good moral character and that the applicant, so far as can be ascertained, has complied and will comply with the provisions of this article, the zoning laws, and the laws of the State relating to registration of and certificates of title to motor vehicles, shall issue to the applicant a license to conduct the kind or kinds of business specified in the application at the address herein specified until October 1st next following the date on which the license is issued. In determining good moral character, for the purposes of this section, the Director's determinations shall be subject to the following provisions:<section prefix='(a)'>Prior arrests of the applicant may not be considered unless they resulted in conviction; provided, however, allegations which are the basis for any pending criminal charges may be considered if the charges are pending when the application is considered.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the applicant has had his or her civil rights restored, the Director shall only consider acts or omissions on the part of the applicant subsequent to the restoration of civil rights.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In the case of subsequent applications of the same applicant, the Director shall only consider acts or omissions on the part of the applicant which have occurred subsequent to the date of the issuance of prior permits to the applicant.</section></section><section>This license shall be considered by the Tax Collector to be a prerequisite to the issuance of any occupational license to conduct the business.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-37, § 3, 9-15-59; Ord. No. 60-1, 1-5-60; Ord. No. 79-31, § 5, 4-17-79)</history></law>