<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. USED MOTOR VEHICLE PARTS DEALERS, WRECKERS AND REBUILDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-56</section_number>
<catch_line>Records to be maintained.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002867</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-56. Records to be maintained.<section>Every licensee shall maintain in its possession for the period of three (3) years, in such form as shall be prescribed by the Director, an accurate and complete record of:<section prefix='(a)'>Each motor vehicle, and every part, accessory, body, chassis or engine purchased or acquired unattached from a motor vehicle which can be identified by serial number, including, but not limited to, such accessories as radios, heaters, air conditioners, wheels, mirrors and hubcaps. Such record shall set forth the description, identifying or serial number, date of acquisition, name and address of person from whom acquired.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Every motor vehicle dismantled, wrecked or destroyed by the licensee, and the description, date of its dismantling, wrecking or destruction and the documentation required by Section 21-57 of this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Every licensee, upon purchase or acquisition of any motor vehicle or part(s) thereof, shall require the seller to produce written identification, such as his driver's license, and shall make and maintain a record of the identification of the seller and the particular items acquired. All such records shall be open and available to inspection during reasonable business hours by any representative of the Director or any peace officer of the State, any County or municipality.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 59-37, ยง 5, 9-15-59; Ord. No. 60-1, 1-5-60; Ord. No. 77-34, ยง 2, 6-21-77; Ord. No. 90-4, ยง 1, 1-16-90)</history></law>