<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. UNIFORM PENAL CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-81</section_number>
<catch_line>Misdemeanor; adoption of State law; penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002879</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-81. Misdemeanor; adoption of State law; penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful and a violation of this article for any person to commit within Miami-Dade County, Florida, any act which is recognized by the laws of the State of Florida as a misdemeanor.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All statutes of the State of Florida defining and prohibiting criminal offenses against the State not punishable by death or by imprisonment in the state prison and defined by State law as misdemeanors are adopted and incorporated by reference as part of this article to the same extent and to the same effect as if the provisions of each such statute was set out in full herein defining and prohibiting each such offense against the State to be an act prohibited by or an offense in violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All acts defined as misdemeanors in said State statutes are hereby prohibited and declared to be violations of this article and any person or corporation shall, upon conviction in the court of appropriate jurisdiction for violation thereof, be punished by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, but in no case shall the fine or imprisonment imposed under this article be greater than the maximum fine or penalty for the same offense under the State statute.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 70-15, ยง 1, 2-25-70)</history></law>