<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. UNIFORM PENAL CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-86</section_number>
<catch_line>Court of appropriate jurisdiction vested with trial jurisdiction.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002884</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-86. Court of appropriate jurisdiction vested with trial jurisdiction.<section prefix='(a)'>Exclusive jurisdiction; exception. All violations of this article shall be prosecuted only in the court of appropriate jurisdiction which shall have original, exclusive jurisdiction to try all cases arising hereunder. Provided, however, that where an act is recognized by State law as a misdemeanor and by this article as an offense, complaints against persons charged with such unlawful acts may be filed and prosecuted in either the court of appropriate jurisdiction or the Criminal Court of Record of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as the prosecuting attorney shall direct. Provided, further, that where an act is recognized as an offense, both by this article and a municipal ordinance, complaints against persons charged with such unlawful acts may be filed and prosecuted in either the court of appropriate jurisdiction or the appropriate municipal court.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Trial in Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court. Where offenses set forth involve violations by juveniles, the same shall be tried in the Miami-Dade County Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court when required by the laws of the State of Florida; however, such offenses involving traffic violations shall be tried in accordance with Section 11-1.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Chapter 30
                      Nothing in this article is intended to nor shall it have the effect of superseding, nullifying or amending any provision of Chapter 30 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. All laws pertaining to traffic violations shall continue to be prosecuted under and pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 30 of the Code of Miami-Dade County from and after the effective date of this article.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Prosecution by State agency officers. When and if any officer of a State agency deems it desirable and in the public interest to prosecute in the court of appropriate jurisdiction violators of State laws, rules and regulations adopted by reference herein, he shall do so with the permission of the prosecuting attorney, and may issue summons or have warrants issued as he deems appropriate.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 70-15, ยง 4, 2-25-70)</history></law>