<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='2'>Chapter 22 WAGE THEFT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>22-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement of wage theft violations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002995</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 22-5. Enforcement of wage theft violations.<section prefix='(1)'>Order Issued. At the conclusion of a hearing and upon a finding of a wage violation, the Hearing Examiner shall issue a written order as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>If the preponderance of the evidence demonstrates a wage theft violation, the Hearing Examiner shall order the employer to pay wage restitution to the affected employee in an amount equal to three times the amount of back wages that the respondent employer is found to have unlawfully failed to pay the complainant employee; this treble amount shall include the back wages in addition to liquidated damages as compensation for the economic losses suffered by reason of the employee not receiving their wage at the time it was due; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>The County shall order the employer to pay to the Board of County Commissioners an assessment of costs in an amount not to exceed actual administrative processing costs and costs of the hearing.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Failure to Comply with Initial Order. If the County finds that any respondent employer has failed to comply with the Hearing Examiner's order within forty-five (45) days after written notice from the County, the County shall issue a further written order on the respondent employer as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>The County may, upon request of the respondent, grant the respondent an additional forty-five (45) days to comply with any portion of the order, unless such an extension has previously been granted; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>The County shall order the employer, in addition to wage restitution ordered, to pay the prevailing complainant employee an amount equal to the applicable interest rate which accrues on the full amount of treble damages from the date upon which the finding of wage violation was made until the date upon which the amount is paid in full; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County shall order the employer, in addition to assessment of costs ordered, to pay to the Board of County Commissioners an amount equal to the applicable interest rate which accrues on the assessment of costs from the date upon which the Hearing Examiner's order is issued until the date upon which the amount is paid in full.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Joint and Severable Liability. In any order issued by the Hearing Examiner, the County may specify two or more respondents as jointly and severally liable for any amount payable to the complainant or the County or both; however, the total amount the complainant or the County may receive from jointly and severally liable respondents shall not exceed the total amount for which respondents are jointly and severally liable.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Cumulative Rights Preserved. Nothing in this article shall be construed to limit, preclude or in any way abrogate the cumulative rights or remedies available to employees at common law or by other statute which were not the subject of a complainant employee's complaint or the County's enforcement actions; such cumulative rights which shall be unaffected by the provisions of this article unless they are made the subject of a complaint or the County's enforcement action, shall include, but shall not be limited to, rights related to the violation of overtime, minimum wage, living wage, prevailing wage, or equal pay laws.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-16, ยง 1, 2-18-10)</history></law>