<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='2'>Chapter 23 PENSIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. POLICE RELIEF AND PENSION FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>23-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003001</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 23-12. Definitions.<section>The following words and phrases shall, for the purpose of this ordinance [article], have the meanings hereinafter respectively ascribed to them. Other words and phrases shall have meanings as commonly understood with respect to the context; the singular shall include the plural, and the masculine, the feminine.<section prefix='(a)'>Active duty. "Active duty" shall mean actual services as a Police Officer with permanent status in the Metro-Dade Police Department, except for approved leaves of absence as set forth below under paragraph (i) of this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Board. "Board" shall be understood to mean Board of Trustees of the Metropolitan Dade County Police Officers Retirement System, or such other board, or boards, as may be created by Dade County, to administer the pension system.</section><section prefix='(c)'>County. "County" shall be understood to mean Dade County, Florida, and the lands under the jurisdiction thereof from time to time, as determined by law.</section><section prefix='(d)'>State. "State" shall be understood to mean the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Police Officer. The Metropolitan Dade County Sheriff and all Police Officers of Dade County, with permanent status in the Metro-Dade Police Department, as the Board shall determine to be engaged directly in enforcement of the ordinances of Dade County and statutes of the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Fund. "Fund" shall mean the Metropolitan Dade County Police Relief and Pension Fund, as provided for herein.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Participant. Every Police Officer of the County, as defined herein, who is eligible to have monies credited to his individual account and to receive benefits therefrom under this ordinance [article] shall automatically become a participant.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Permanent status. The term "permanent status" shall have the meaning ascribed to it from time to time by the rules and regulations of the Personnel Advisory Board of Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Service. Service shall mean all time served as a Police Officer permanently appointed, which shall include the probationary period, under the rules and regulations of the Personnel Advisory Board of the County, for which regular compensation is paid by the County; and at all times, not to exceed a period of five (5) years during which a participant is absent on a military leave of absence. It shall include all leaves of absence without pay for sickness, for such period of time as may be determined by the Board, in excess of accumulated sick time for which compensation is received.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Chapter 28230. "Chapter 28230" shall mean and refer only to Chapter 28230, Laws of Florida, Acts of 1953, as amended.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-2, ยง 2, 1-14-64)</history></law>