<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='2'>Chapter 23 PENSIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. POLICE RELIEF AND PENSION FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>23-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Board of trustees generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003004</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 23-15. Board of trustees generally.<section>There is hereby created a Board of Trustees of the Metropolitan Dade County Police Relief and Pension Fund, which Board shall consist of three (3) Police Officers of the Metro-Dade Police Department to be elected by Police participants, the Metropolitan Sheriff, and a resident member appointed by the Board. At the first election of Trustees, there shall be elected one (1) Police Officer to serve as Trustee for a one-year term; one (1) Police Officer to serve as Trustee for a two-year term; one (1) Police Officer to serve as Trustee for a three-year term. Thereafter, each year, one (1) Police Officer shall be elected to serve as Trustee for a three-year term. The Police Officers thus elected as Trustees shall appoint the fifth resident Trustee to serve on the Board for a term of one (1) year. The Board shall annually elect from its membership a Chairman and a Secretary and a Treasurer. The Chairman, when present, shall preside at all meetings. The Secretary shall keep complete minutes of all proceedings of the Board. The Treasurer shall supervise the books and records which record the receipts and disbursements of the fund and the inventory of assets of the fund. He shall report, at each quarterly meeting, the assets and liabilities of the fund as of the date of such meeting. All elections of the Board shall be by a majority vote, a quorum being present. Three (3) or more members shall constitute a quorum. Trustees shall receive no compensation as such.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-2, ยง 5, 1-14-64)</history></law>