<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='2'>Chapter 23 PENSIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. FIREFIGHTER'S RELIEF AND PENSION FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>23-31</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003020</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 23-31. Definitions.<section>The following words and phrases shall, for the purpose of this ordinance [article], have the meanings hereinafter respectively ascribed to them. Other words and phrases shall have meanings as commonly understood with respect to the context; the singular shall include the plural, and the masculine, the feminine.<section prefix='(a)'>Active duty: Active duty shall mean actual services as a Firefighter with permanent status in the Fire Department of Dade County, Florida, except for approved leaves of absence as set forth below under paragraph (i) of this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Board: Board shall be understood to mean Board of Trustees of the Metropolitan Dade County Firefighters' Retirement System, or such other Board, or Boards, as may be created by Dade County to administer the pension system.</section><section prefix='(c)'>County: County shall be understood to mean Dade County, Florida, and the lands under the jurisdiction thereof from time to time, as determined by law.</section><section prefix='(d)'>State: State shall be understood to mean the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Firefighter: The Fire Chief, Officers, Inspectors, Enginemen and Firefighters with permanent status in the Fire Department of the County, including Firefighters on detached duty, as the Board shall determine to be engaged directly in fire fighting or fire prevention work, shall be deemed Firefighters for the purpose of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Fund: Fund shall mean the Metropolitan Dade County Firefighters' Relief and Pension Fund, as provided for herein.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Participant: Every Firefighter of the County, as defined herein, who is eligible to have monies credited to his individual account and to receive benefits therefrom under this ordinance [article] shall automatically become a participant.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Permanent status: The term permanent status shall have the meaning ascribed to it from time to time by the rules and regulations of the Personnel Advisory Board of Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Service: Service shall mean all time served as a Firefighter permanently appointed, which shall include the probationary period, under the rules and regulations of the Personnel Advisory Board of the County; and at all times, not to exceed a period of five (5) years during which a participant is absent on a military leave absence. It shall include all leaves of absence without pay for sickness, for such period of time as may be determined by the Board, in excess of accumulated sick time for which compensation is received.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Chapter 19112: Chapter 19112 shall mean and refer only to Chapter 19112, Laws of Florida, Acts of 1939, as amended.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-6, ยง 2, 2-4-64)</history></law>