<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='2'>Chapter 23 PENSIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. FIREFIGHTER'S RELIEF AND PENSION FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>23-34</section_number>
<catch_line>Board of Trustees generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003023</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 23-34. Board of Trustees generally.<section>There is hereby created a Board of Trustees of the Metropolitan Dade County Firefighters' Relief and Pension Fund, which Board shall consist of the Mayor of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, the Chief of the Fire Department of Dade County, Florida, two (2) Firefighters of the Fire Department of Dade County, Florida, to be elected by a majority of the Firefighters whose names appear on the rolls as members of the Fire Department of Dade County, Florida, and one (1) legal resident of Dade County, to be appointed by the County Commission. At the first election of Trustees, there shall be elected one (1) Firefighter to serve as Trustee for a one-year term; one (1) Firefighter to serve as Trustee for a two-year term; the Mayor or designee and Fire Chief shall serve as long as they continue to hold office as Mayor or designee or Fire Chief, respectively; the fifth member appointed by the County Commission shall serve for a one-year term. Thereafter, each year, one (1) Firefighter shall be elected to serve as Trustee for a two-year term. The Board shall annually elect from its membership a Chairman and a Secretary and a Treasurer. The Chairman, when present, shall preside at all meetings. The Secretary shall keep complete minutes of all proceedings of the Board. The Treasurer shall supervise the books and records which record the receipts and disbursements of the fund and the inventory of assets of the fund. He shall report at each quarterly meeting the assets and liabilities of the fund as of the date of such meeting. All elections of the Board shall be by a majority vote, a quorum being present. Three (3) or more members shall constitute a quorum. Trustees shall receive no compensation as such.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-6, ยง 5, 2-4-64; Ord. No. 65-51, ยง 1, 7-27-65; Ord. No. 65-54, 7-27-65)</history></law>