<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='2'>Chapter 23 PENSIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. DEATH BENEFITS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>23-62</section_number>
<catch_line>When payments made; amount paid; to whom paid.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003040</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 23-62. When payments made; amount paid; to whom paid.<section>Upon proper proof of the death of any County employee indicating that such death was the natural and proximate result of an accident or overt act occurring at some definite time and place while said employee was in the actual performance of duty and not caused by wilful negligence on the part of the employee, there shall be paid one-half of the average weekly wage of said employee to the dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse until said dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse remarries or twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) is expended, whichever first occurs. If said employee leaves no dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse, or if said dependent widow or dependent surviving spouse dies or remarries before the youngest child of the deceased employee shall have attained the age of eighteen (18) years, then such payment shall be paid to said employee's child or children under such age until the youngest child attains the age of eighteen (18) years or the sum of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) is expended, whichever first occurs; or if said employee is unmarried, then to any relative or relatives dependent upon said deceased employee until said relative attains the age of eighteen (18) years or marries or dies or ceases to be dependent, or twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00) is expended, whichever first occurs.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 65-46, ยง 1, 6-17-65)</history></law>