<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Sulfur dioxide.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003049</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.3. Sulfur dioxide.<section prefix='(1)'>Ambient air quality standards. No person, firm, corporation, or other entity shall cause, let, permit, suffer or allow any emission of sulfur dioxide which would exceed any of the following standards in any part of Miami-Dade County:<section prefix='(a)'>Annual arithmetic mean—25 micrograms per cubic meter (0.007 parts per million);</section><section prefix='(b)'>Twenty-four-hour concentration—110 micrograms per cubic meter (0.040 parts per million), not to be exceeded more than once per year;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Three-hour concentration—350 micrograms per cubic meter (0.130 parts per million), not to be exceeded more than once per year.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Emission standards. No person, firm, corporation or other entity shall cause, let, permit, suffer or allow the emission of sulfur dioxide from any stationary fossil fuel fired combustion source located in Miami-Dade County and exceeding the following standards:<section prefix='(a)'>Source with more than two hundred fifty million (250,000,000) Btu per hour heat input:<section prefix='(i)'>New sources subsequent to the effective date of this section:<section prefix='1.'>0.8 pound per million Btu heat input when liquid fuel is burned;</section><section prefix='2.'>1.2 pounds per million Btu heat input when solid fuel is burned.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>Existing sources no later than one (1) year after the effective date of this section:<section prefix='1.'>1.1 pounds per million Btu heat input when liquid fuel is burned;</section><section prefix='2.'>1.5 pounds per million Btu heat input when solid fuel is burned.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>New and existing stationary fossil fuel fired combustion sources with two hundred fifty million (250,000,000) or less Btu per hour heat input:<section prefix='(i)'>1.1 pounds per million Btu heat input, when liquid fuel is burned;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>1.5 pounds per million Btu heat input, when solid fuel is burned.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding any other requirement of this section, fossil fuel fired steam generating plants with stack heights less than four hundred (400) feet above ground level shall not cause, let, permit, suffer or allow the emission of sulfur dioxide to exceed 0.55 pound per million Btu heat input. In addition, any such fossil fuel fired steam generating plants with a maximum heat input greater than two hundred fifty million (250,000,000) Btu per hour heat input shall limit the use of fuel oils to start up only, and shall burn one hundred (100) percent natural gas during all other phases of operation.</section></section><section>New sources approved after the effective date of this section shall comply with the provisions herein. Existing sources approved on or before the effective date of this section shall comply with the provisions of this section no later than one (1) year after effective date of this section.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Sampling and testing.<section prefix='(a)'>All persons shall, upon request of the Department, provide continuous automatic monitoring, testing and records of contaminants being emitted from a source;</section><section prefix='(b)'>All persons shall provide facilities for continuously determining the input process weight or input heat when such factors are the basis for limiting standards;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any person, firm, corporation or other entity responsible for the emission of air pollutants from any source shall, upon request of the Department, provide in connection with such sources and related source operations, such sampling and testing facilities as may be necessary for the proper determination of the nature and quantity of air pollutants which are, or may be emitted as a result of such operation;</section><section prefix='(d)'>When the Department, upon investigation, has good reason to believe that the provisions of this section concerning emission of pollutants are being violated, it may require the person, firm, corporation or other entity responsible for the source of pollutants to conduct tests which will identify the nature and quantity of pollutant emissions from the source and to provide the results of said tests to the Department. These tests shall be carried out under the supervision of the Department, and at the expense of the person responsible for the source of pollutants;</section><section prefix='(e)'>All analyses and tests shall be conducted in a manner specified by the Department. Results of analyses and tests shall be calculated and reported in a manner specified by the Department;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Analyses and tests for compliance may be performed by the Department at the cost of the person responsible for the emission of air pollutants.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>