<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibitions against motor vehicles as sources of air pollution.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003047</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.1. Prohibitions against motor vehicles as sources of air pollution.<section prefix='(1)'>Prohibited Conditions: It shall be unlawful after the effective date of this section for the owner of a motor vehicle to operate, permit or allow to be operated a motor vehicle which:<section prefix='(a)'>Emits air contaminants as dark as or darker in shade than that designated as number 1 on the Ringelmann Chart or of such an opacity equal to or greater than twenty (20) per cent for longer than five (5) consecutive seconds; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Has had any of its emission control devices, as installed at the time of manufacture, removed, disconnected and/or disabled; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Is powered by any fuel that may defeat the design purpose of the motor vehicle's emission control devices, including but not limited to leaded gasoline used in a motor vehicle designed to be powered by unleaded gasoline.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Emission Limiting Standards Applicable to Gasoline-Powered Motor Vehicles:<section prefix='(a)'>Light duty vehicles (passenger vehicles with net weight of 5,000 pounds or less):</section><section prefix='(b)'>Light duty trucks, vans, and passenger vehicles (gross vehicle weight of 6,000 pounds or less):</section><section prefix='(c)'>Light duty trucks, vans, and passenger vehicles (gross vehicle weight of 6,001 pounds to 10,000 pounds):</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Motor Vehicles Exempted: The provisions of this section shall not apply to off-highway farm, forest and construction equipment being moved from one (1) work location to another.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Inspection:<section prefix='(a)'>Compliance shall be verified through an inspection program established by the Department. Vehicle emission levels shall be tested in accordance with applicable criteria contained in Chapter 62-242 of the Florida Administrative Code, as amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Whenever evidence has been obtained or received establishing that a violation of this section has been committed, the Director or Director's designee, shall issue a notice to correct the violation or a citation to cease the violation and cause the same to be served upon the violator by personal service or certified mail. Such notice or citation shall set forth the nature of the violation and specify a reasonable time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped, commensurate with the circumstances.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Such notice or citation shall specify a reasonable time and place for a reinspection of the motor vehicle to confirm that the violation has been corrected. "Reasonable time" herein means the shortest practicable time to rectify or stop the violation. If a determination has been made by the Director or the Director's designee that a violation of the provisions of this section may result in adverse health impact in a public area, the owner/operator of the vehicle in violation shall be required to correct the violation by immediately removing the vehicle from the affected public area.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Further, said vehicle shall not be allowed to resume operation within the affected public area until it demonstrates full compliance with the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If notice to correct the violation or citation to cease the violation is not obeyed within the time set forth therein, the Director or the Director's designee shall have the power and authority to issue an order requiring the violator to restrict, cease or suspend operation of the motor vehicle causing the violation until the violation is corrected. Any order issued by the Director or the Director's designee hereunder may be enforced by suit brought by the Director in the appropriate court of competent jurisdiction.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>