<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.9</section_number>
<catch_line>Reduction of animal matter.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003055</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.9. Reduction of animal matter.<section>A person shall not operate or use any article, machine, equipment or other contrivance for the reduction of animal matter unless all gases, vapors and gas-entrained effluents from such an article, machine, equipment or other contrivance are:<section prefix='(1)'>Incidental at temperatures of not less than one thousand six hundred (1,600) degrees Fahrenheit for a period of not less than three-tenths second; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Proceed in a manner determined by the Director to be equally, or more, effective for the purpose of air pollution control than (1) above.</section></section><section>A person incinerating or processing gases, vapors, or gas-entrained effluents pursuant to this section shall provide, properly install and maintain in calibration, in good working order and in operation, devices as specified by the Director for indicating temperature, pressure or other operating conditions.</section><section>For the purpose of this section, "reduction" is defined as any heated process, including rendering, cooking, drying, dehydrating, digesting, evaporating and protein concentrating.</section><section>The provisions of this section shall not apply to any article, machine, equipment or other contrivance used exclusively for the processing of food for human consumption.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>