<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.11</section_number>
<catch_line>Refrigerants.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003057</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.11. Refrigerants.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, after September 26, 1991, to recharge or cause, let, allow, permit, or suffer the recharging of refrigerant into any refrigeration system without properly using approved recycling or recovery equipment and without an operating permit pursuant to Section 24-18 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(2)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, after September 26, 1991, to release or cause, let, allow, permit or suffer the releasing of any refrigerant from any refrigeration system into the ambient air of the Earth.</section><section prefix='(3)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, after September 26, 1991, to sell, offer for sale or cause, let, allow, permit or suffer the sale or offering for sale of any kind of refrigerant in any container with a capacity of less than twenty (20) pounds.</section><section prefix='(4)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, after September 26, 1991, to sell or distribute or to offer to sell or distribute any kind of refrigerant to any person who has not obtained an operating permit pursuant to Section 24-18 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(5)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, after September 26, 1991, to sell or distribute or offer to sell or distribute any refrigerant without having obtained an operating permit pursuant to Section 24-18 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Recovered refrigerant which cannot be reused or recycled shall be disposed in a manner approved in writing by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>