<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Oil-effluent water separator.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003054</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.8. Oil-effluent water separator.<section>A person shall not use any compartment of any single or multiple compartment oil-effluent water separator which compartment receives effluent water which contains two hundred (200) gallons a day or more of any petroleum product or mixture of petroleum products from any equipment processing, refining, treating, storing or handling kerosene or other petroleum product of equal or greater volatility than kerosene, unless such compartment is equipped with one (1) of the following vapor loss control devices, properly installed, in good working order and in operation:<section prefix='(1)'>A solid cover with all openings sealed and totally enclosing the liquid contents. All gauging and sampling devices shall be gastight except when gauging or sampling is taking place.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A floating roof, consisting of a pontoon type or double-deck roof resting on the surface of the liquid contents and equipped with a closure seal, or seals, to close the space between the roof edge and container wall. All gauging and sampling devices shall be gastight except when gauging or sampling is taking place.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A vapor recovery system, consisting of a vapor gathering system capable of collecting the hydrocarbon vapors and gases discharged and a vapor disposal system capable of processing such hydrocarbon vapors and gases so as to prevent their emission to the atmosphere and with all tank gauging and sampling devices gastight except when gauging or sampling is taking place.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Other equipment of equal efficiency, provided plans for such equipment are submitted to and approved by the Director or the Director's designee. For the purpose of this section, "kerosene" is defined as any petroleum product which, when distilled by ASTM standard test Method D 86-56, will give a temperature of four hundred one (401) degrees Fahrenheit or less at the ten (10) percent point recovered.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>