<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.10</section_number>
<catch_line>Sampling and testing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003056</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.10. Sampling and testing.<section>A person responsible for the emission of air contaminants from any source shall, upon request of the Director, provide in connection with such sources and related source operations, such sampling and testing facilities exclusive of instruments and sensing devices as may be necessary for the proper determination of the nature, extent, quantity, and degree of air contaminants which are, or may be, emitted as a result of such operation.<section prefix='(1)'>Such facilities may be either permanent or temporary at the discretion of the person responsible for their provision and shall be suitable for the use of methods and equipment specified by the Director, who shall indicate in writing the required size, number and location of sampling holes; the size and location of the sampling platform; and the utilities for operating the sampling and testing equipment.<section>The facilities shall comply with all applicable laws and regulations concerning safe construction and safe practice in connection with such facilities.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>When the Director has good reason to believe that the provisions of this chapter concerning emission of contaminants are being violated, the Director may require the person responsible for the source of contaminants to conduct tests which will show the contaminant emissions from the source and to provide the results of said tests to the Director. These tests shall be carried out under the supervision of the Director or the Director's designee and at the expense of the person responsible for the source of contaminants.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All analyses and tests shall be calculated and reported on the basis of dry gas at standard conditions as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Analyses and tests for compliance may be performed by the staff of the Director at the cost of the operator.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>