<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Exceptions to prohibition against open burning.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003051</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.5. Exceptions to prohibition against open burning.<section>The following fires are excepted from the provisions of this chapter:<section prefix='(1)'>Fires used only for noncommercial cooking of food for human beings or for recreational purposes.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any fire set or permitted by the Director in the performance of official duty, if such fire is set or permission given for the purpose of weed abatement, the prevention of a fire hazard, including the disposal of dangerous materials when there is no safe alternate method of disposal, or in the instruction of public employees in the methods of fighting fires, which fire is, in the opinion of such official, necessary.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Fires set for the purpose of instruction in the methods of fighting fires, provided prior permission has been granted by a public officer in the performance of official duty and by the Director.</section><section prefix='(4)'>An agricultural fire set by or permitted by the Director if such fire is for the purpose of disease and pest prevention, or for frost protection.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Smokeless flares or safety flares for the combustion of waste gases.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A fire set or permitted by the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management, Miami-Dade Fire Rescue Department, and under his control for the purpose of nonrecurrent clearing of debris from land, agricultural and silviculture.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>