<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. AIR QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-41.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Storage and handling of petroleum products.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003052</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-41.6. Storage and handling of petroleum products.<section prefix='(1)'>The provisions of this section shall apply to the owners and operators of all loading facilities, motor vehicle fuel delivery vessels and motor vehicle fuel service stations dispensing, distributing or storing gasoline, gasohol or other petroleum distillates having a Reid vapor pressure of one and five-tenths (1.5) pounds per square inch absolute or greater under actual storage conditions. For the purpose of this section, any petroleum distillate having a Reid vapor pressure of four (4.0) pounds per square inch or greater shall be included in the term "gasoline."</section><section prefix='(2)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to place, store or hold in any stationary tank, reservoir or other container of more than forty thousand (40,000) gallons capacity any gasoline, gasohol or any petroleum distillate unless such stationary tank, reservoir, or other container is a pressure tank maintaining working pressure sufficient at all times to prevent hydrocarbon vapor or gas loss to the atmosphere, or is designed and equipped with one (1) of the following vapor loss control devices, properly installed, in good working order and in operation:<section prefix='(a)'>A floating roof, consisting of a pontoon type or double-deck type roof, resting on the surface of the liquid contents and equipped with a closure seal, or seals, to close the space between the roof edge and tank wall. The control equipment provided for in this paragraph shall not be used if the gasoline, gasohol or petroleum distillate has a Reid vapor pressure of eleven (11.0) pounds per square inch absolute or greater under actual storage conditions. All tank gauging and sampling ports shall be vapor-tight except when gauging or sampling is taking place.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A vapor recovery system capable of collecting and processing the hydrocarbon vapors and gases produced in order to prevent their emission to the atmosphere. All tank gauging and sampling ports shall be maintained in a vapor-tight condition except when gauging or sampling is taking place.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Other equipment of equivalent efficiency, provided that plans for such equipment are submitted to and approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to dispense or to permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the dispensing of gasoline, gasohol or any petroleum distillate into any motor vehicle fuel tank or into any motor vehicle fuel delivery vessel from any loading facility unless such loading facility is equipped with a vapor collection system or its equivalent, properly installed, and operational, as approved by the Director or the Director's designee. When dispensing gasoline, gasohol or other petroleum distillates through the hatches of a motor vehicle fuel delivery vessel with a loading arm equipped with such vapor collection system, a pneumatic, hydraulic or other mechanical device shall be installed to create a vapor-tight seal between the loading arm and the hatch. For all other loading of gasoline, gasohol and other petroleum distillates effected through means other than hatches, delivery lines shall be equipped with fittings which create vapor-tight connections and which close automatically when disconnected. The vapor collection system required herein shall be one (1) of the following:<section prefix='(a)'>A vapor-liquid absorption system with a minimum recovery efficiency of ninety (90) percent by weight of all the hydrocarbon vapors and gases entering into such collection system.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A variable vapor space tank, compressor, and fuel gas system of sufficient capacity to receive all hydrocarbon vapors and gases entering into such collection system or displaced from the motor vehicle delivery vessel.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Another system of equivalent efficiency to the vapor collection systems described in (1) and (2) above, provided that plans for such systems are submitted to and approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to construct or operate, or to permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the construction or operation of a motor vehicle fuel service station after December 14, 1990 without said station being completely equipped with balanced or vacuum assist systems or equivalent systems approved by the Director or the Director's designee, with a minimum design efficiency of a ninety-five (95) percent recovery rate.</section><section prefix='(5)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to operate, or to permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the operation of a motor vehicle fuel service station utilizing a balanced or vacuum assist system or approved equivalent system for the control of gasoline or gasohol vapors resulting from motor vehicle fueling operations without conspicuously posting operating instructions for the system in the motor vehicle fuel dispensing area. The instructions shall clearly describe the correct method to dispense fuel to motor vehicles with the vapor recovery nozzles utilized at the station.</section><section prefix='(6)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to utilize, or to permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the utilization of any vapor recovery system not operating in accordance with plans approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, the following persons shall not be required to comply with the requirements of this section until December 14, 1993.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person who is operating a motor vehicle fuel service station with all the required operating permits pursuant to Section 24-18 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida on December 14, 1990.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person who has obtained, on or before December 14, 1990, the written approval of the Director or the Director's designee for the construction of a new motor vehicle fuel service station and has a certificate of occupancy.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>