<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. STORMWATER UTILITY*</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-51.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Billing; liens.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003068</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-51.5. Billing; liens.<section prefix='(1)'>Fees shall be billed to the owner, tenant, or occupant of each developed property in accordance with the administrative orders of the County Manager. If the fees are not fully paid by said owner, tenant or occupant on or before the past due date set forth on the bill, a ten (10) percent late charge may be added to the bill and imposed by the Utility in accordance with regulations prescribed by the County Manager. Any unpaid balance for such fees and late charges shall be subject to an interest charge at the rate of eight (8) percent per annum. Imposition of said interest charge shall commence sixty (60) days after the past due date of the fees set forth on the bill.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Fees and late charges, together with any interest charges, shall be debts due and owing the Utility and all of same shall be recoverable by the County or its assignee, on behalf of the Utility, in any court of competent jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Utility shall establish procedures to notify owners, tenants, occupants, and managers of developed property of delinquent fee accounts. Subscribers to this service shall pay in advance a fee in an amount set forth in the administrative orders of the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All fees, late charges, and interest accruing thereupon, due and owning to the Utility which remain unpaid sixty (60) days after the past due date of the fees shall become a lien against and upon the developed property for which the fees are due and owing to the same extent and character as a lien for a special assessment. Until fully paid and discharged, said fees, late charges, and interest accrued thereupon shall be, remain, and constitute a special assessment lien equal in rank and dignity with the liens of County ad valorem taxes and superior in rank and dignity to all other liens, encumbrances, titles, and claims in, to or against the developed property involved for the period of five (5) years from the date said fees, late charges, and interest accrued thereupon, become a lien as set forth in this article. Said lien may be enforced and satisfied by the County, on behalf of the Utility, pursuant to Chapter 173, Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, or by any other method permitted by law. The lien provided for herein shall not be deemed to be in lieu of any other legal remedies for recovery of said fee, late charges, and accrued interest available in the County and to the Utility.</section><section prefix='(5)'>For fees which become more than sixty (60) days past due and unpaid, the County or the Utility shall cause to be filed in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, a notice of lien or statement showing a legal description of the property against which the lien is claimed, its location by street and number, the name of the owner, and an accurate statement of the fees and late charges then unpaid. A copy of such notice of lien shall be mailed within a reasonable time to the owner of the property involved as shown by the records of the Tax Collector of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Liens may be discharged and satisfied by payment to the County, on behalf of the Utility, of the aggregate amounts specified in the notice of lien, together with interest accrued thereon, and all filing and recording fees. When any such lien has been fully paid or discharged, the County shall cause evidence of the satisfaction and discharge of such lien to be filed with the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Any person, firm, corporation, or other legal entity, other than the present owner of the property involved, who fully pays any such lien shall be entitled to receive an assignment of lien and shall be subrogated to the rights of the County and the Utility with respect to the enforcement of such lien.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Notwithstanding other provisions to the contrary herein, the County, on behalf of the Utility, shall have the discretion not to file notices of lien for fees, late charges, and interest accrued thereupon in an amount less than fifty dollars ($50.00). If the County or the Utility elects not to file a notice of lien, said fees, late charges, and accrued interest shall remain as debts due and owing in accordance with (2) above.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The Utility is authorized and directed to execute and deliver upon request written certificates certifying the amount of fees, late charges and interest accrued thereupon, which are due and owing to the Utility and the County, for any developed property which is subject to payment of said fees, or the Utility may certify that no fees, late charges or accrued interest are due and owing. Said certificates shall be binding upon the County and the Utility.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>