<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. STORMWATER UTILITY*</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-51.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003065</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-51.2. Applicability.<section prefix='(1)'>The provisions of this article shall be effective in both the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 24-51.2(1) above, the provisions of this article shall not apply within any municipality which files with both the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners and the Director certified copies of a resolution of the governing body of such municipality which notifies the Board of County Commissioners and the Director that the municipality exercises thereby its option to exempt that the municipality exercises thereby its option to exempt the municipality from the provisions of this article, provided, however, (1) such certified copies are filed as set forth above no later than ninety (90) days from the date of enactment of this article and (2) the municipality commits in said resolution to implement within said municipality the provisions of Section 403.0893(1), (2), or (3), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, no later than two (2) years from the effective date of this article. Failure to file such certified copies or to implement Section 403.0893(1), (2) or (3), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, within the aforesaid respective time periods shall render the municipality's exemption from the provisions of this article null and void. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any municipality, at any time after the effective date of this article, may request, by resolution, that the Board of County Commissioners render the municipality's exemption from the provisions of this article null and void or grant the municipality an exemption from the provisions of this article subject to conditions determined by the Board of County Commissioners. Upon receipt of such a resolution of a municipality the Board of County Commissioners may, by resolution, render the municipality's exemption from the provisions of this article null and void or grant the municipality an exemption from the provisions of this article subject to conditions determined by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>