<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='2'>Chapter 25 AVIATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Aircraft and Aircraft Operations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003079</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25-10. Aircraft and Aircraft Operations.<section prefix='25-10.1'>Negligent operations prohibited. No person shall operate aircraft at the Airport:<section prefix='(a)'>In a careless or negligent manner,</section><section prefix='(b)'>In disregard of the rights and safety of others,</section><section prefix='(c)'>Without due caution and circumspection, or</section><section prefix='(d)'>At a speed or in a manner which endangers, or is likely to endanger, persons or property, or if such aircraft is so constructed, equipped or loaded, so as to endanger, or be likely to endanger, persons or property. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 129, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.2'>Compliance with orders. All aeronautical activities at the Airport shall be conducted in conformity with the current applicable provisions of the Federal Aviation Regulations and Orders, these rules and regulations, Operational Directives issued by the Department and directions of the air traffic control tower. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-10.3'>Denial of departure.<section prefix='(a)'>The Director may prohibit an aircraft from taking-off from the Airport at any time, under any known circumstances which in the judgment of the Director may result in danger to persons or property on or off the Airport, or for any other justifiable reason. Such justifiable reason may include, but is not limited to, the failure to obtain such departure authorization from the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), as may be required.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall fuel an aircraft when a specific order has been issued by the Department prohibiting the fueling of such aircraft.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Department may, at any time, prohibit an aircraft from taking off from an Airport for failure of the aircraft owner or operator to report or pay all required aviation fees, or if the Department has placed a lien on the aircraft in accordance with state statutes, said lien has not been satisfied or satisfactorily resolved. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 130, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.4'>Payment of fees. Unless otherwise approved by the Department, no aircraft shall take-off from an Airport unless payment or arrangements for payment of fees and charges, if any, for use of Airport facilities, parking or other services rendered by the Department shall have been made. All aircraft operators, except operators of scheduled air carriers operating under special lease contracts or those whose operations are paid for in advance or who have established a credit account with the Department, upon landing and prior to take-off shall register such landing or take-off with the Department in accordance with Operational Directives issued by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 131, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-10.5'>Denial of use of Airport. The Director may deny the use of the Airport to any aircraft owner, operator or pilot who violates these rules and regulations and Operational Directives issued by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-10.6'>Aircraft accidents.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person operating an aircraft involved in an accident on the Airport resulting in injury to any person or damage to any property, shall immediately stop such aircraft at the scene of such accident, or as close thereto as possible so as to minimize the obstruction of other aircraft operations or motor vehicle traffic. The person operating said aircraft shall then comply with Federal Aviation Administration Notification Procedures and notify the Department. Such person shall then return to and remain at the scene of the accident until he has fulfilled all reporting requirements, including those specified in subsection 25-10.6(b).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person operating an aircraft involved in an accident on the Airport, of the type specified in subsection 25-10.6(a) and the owner of such aircraft, if other than the operator thereof, shall make a full report of such accident to the Metro-Dade Police Department, and to an authorized representative of the Department as soon after the accident as possible, including the names and addresses of the individuals involved, the description of the property and all aircraft involved, the registration and license number of all aircraft involved, and such other information relevant to the accident on request of any law enforcement officer investigating the same; and the operator of any such aircraft involved in such accident shall, upon request, exhibit such licenses, registrations or other documents relevant to such accident or the persons or property involved to any law enforcement officer investigating the same.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The owner or operator of an aircraft involved in an accident on the Airport shall not move such aircraft from the scene of the accident until authorized to do so by the appropriate federal agencies and the Director. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 132, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.7'>Removal of disabled aircraft.<section prefix='(a)'>Aircraft owners, operators and tenants shall be responsible for the prompt disposal of disabled aircraft and parts thereof, unless required or directed to delay such action by the Director or an authorized federal agency.</section><section prefix='(b)'>When a disabled aircraft is blocking or delaying the use of any portion of the AOA, the owner or operator of the aircraft shall make immediate arrangements to have such aircraft moved as soon as an authorized representative of the Department and appropriate governmental agencies have authorized such movement. In the event that removal of the aircraft is not initiated as soon as possible, or is not progressing at a rate acceptable to the Department, the Director shall have the right to initiate action to remove the aircraft at the expense and risk of the owner. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 133, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.8'>Tampering with aircraft. No person shall interfere or tamper with any aircraft, or put in motion such aircraft, or use or remove any aircraft, aircraft parts, instruments or tools without appropriate positive evidence of the owner's approval thereof. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 134, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-10.9'>Enplaning and deplaning.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall enplane or deplane passengers or cargo at Miami International Airport except in specific areas, assigned by the Department, designated by posted painted ramp markings, established by Operational Directives, or pursuant to permits issued by the Department or Airport lease agreements with the County. Where a passenger aircraft is being loaded or unloaded at ground level, all passengers shall be channeled by the shortest and safest route across the aircraft apron area, under the direction and supervision of the aircraft operator or his authorized representatives. All such aircraft operators shall load and unload an aircraft through designated restricted areas, in accordance with security and operational procedures established by the Department and Federal Aviation Regulations.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person operating an aircraft shall enplane or deplane passengers or cargo at Miami International Airport other than at aircraft gates or positions or areas established pursuant to subsection 25-10.9(a). All such operators, when deplaning passengers through any part of such an established or authorized area, that has been restricted by the Department for enplaning passengers that have been previously screened in accordance with Federal Aviation Regulations, must insure that the arriving passengers have previously passed through such established Federal Aviation Administration security screening procedures before entering such designated restricted area, or must make arrangements for physical escort through such restricted area, in accordance with requirements of federal law and Federal Aviation Regulations.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person operating a general aviation or military aircraft shall enplane or deplane passengers or cargo on the terminal apron at Miami International Airport, without having made prior arrangements thereof with the Department or unless such operation is in accordance with Operational Directives of the Department.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person operating an aircraft shall enplane or deplane passengers at the terminal apron without having made prior arrangements for all required aircraft and passenger services.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No persons, including scheduled or nonscheduled air carriers, certified helicopter operators, supplemental air carriers, air carrier charterers, or other aircraft operators, shall utilize an Airport for any commercial activities except as are specifically authorized by Operational Directives, permits issued by the Department, lease or other agreement with the County or in accordance with the Airport's Federal Aviation Administration certification.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All fees charged others by the lessee of any exclusively leased aircraft parking position at the Airport, for the use of such parking position shall be subject to approval annually by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 135, 136, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.10'>Cleaning, maintenance and repair of aircraft.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall clean, paint, wash, polish or otherwise maintain an aircraft, other than in areas approved by the Department for such purpose.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person, unless authorized by FAA regulations, shall maintain or repair or permit the maintenance or repair of an aircraft at any Airport other than:<section prefix='(1)'>At Federal Aviation Administration approved repair station;</section><section prefix='(2)'>At Federal Aviation Regulations, Part 121 airline maintenance station; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>At an area authorized by the Department for such maintenance or repair by an FAA approved and licensed mechanic holding a valid Department approved identification badge and required vehicle entry permit, as appropriate, issued by the Department.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>No person, unless an employee of or under contract to an Airport lessee authorized by its lease agreement with the County to perform aircraft maintenance and repair, or an aircraft owner to the extent that self-maintenance is allowed under Federal Aviation Regulations and is otherwise authorized and permitted under the provisions of Chapters 24 and 25 of this Code, shall perform any aircraft maintenance and repair work at any Airport. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 137, 138, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.11'>Radio communications. No person shall operate an aircraft at Miami International Airport, unless such aircraft is equipped with functioning two-way radio, tuneable to and operating on the frequencies set out in notices to airmen as being assigned to the Miami International Airport Control Tower and such other communications equipment as may be required by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA). Aircraft which land, in emergencies, without functioning required communications equipment shall be required to have such equipment operational before clearing for take-off, unless authorized by FAA Air Traffic Control. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-10.12'>Aircraft equipment. Except as may be otherwise authorized by the Department pursuant to Section 25-10.17 of the Code, no person shall operate an aircraft on the Airport, other than a helicopter, unless it is equipped with main landing gear, a tail or nose wheel, and wheel brakes, and unless the aircraft has been issued all certificates then required by the FAA to operate at the Airport. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 139, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-10.13'>Landing and taking-off.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall land at or take-off in an aircraft, other than a helicopter, from an Airport having a control tower except on the runway and in the direction assigned by the control tower. Aircraft not requiring a runway, such as a helicopter, shall operate in strict accordance with directions of the FAA Control Tower, where such tower facilities are available and in use.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall land at or take-off from the Airport in a helicopter except at designated helicopter landing and take-off areas, in strict compliance with air traffic control tower procedures or preestablished operational procedures where no tower facilities are available.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Persons landing at or taking-off in an aircraft from an Airport having a control tower shall conform to the air traffic instructions given by the control tower.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall turn an aircraft in order to reverse direction on the runway, unless given specific instructions or authorization to do so by the control tower.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No person shall take-off or land in an aircraft on or from an unserviceable runway, or on or from any ramp area or taxiway, without prior authorization of the Department and Federal Aviation Administration.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Persons landing an aircraft at the Airport shall make the landing runway available to other aircraft by leaving the runway as promptly as possible.</section><section prefix='(g)'>No person shall take-off or land an "engine-out" ferry flight (e.g., three-engine operation of four-engine aircraft) at Miami International Airport, except under the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>When conducted by Federal Aviation Regulations Part 121 operator, in strict compliance with its FAA approved maintenance program; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>When authorized by a written FAA permit, and, under either condition,</section><section prefix='(3)'>In accordance with established Airport Operational Directives.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Any person operating or controlling an aircraft landing at or taking-off from the Airport shall ensure the aircraft meets applicable federal noise emission standards and maintains engine noise within applicable aircraft engine noise limits as promulgated by the federal government, the State of Florida or Dade County. Aircraft pilots shall utilize thrust and flap management techniques consistent with industry noise abatement guidelines and FAA air traffic control instructions and are encouraged to follow noise abatement programs described in Operational Directives and Bulletins issued by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 140, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.14'>Taxiing.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall taxi an aircraft until he has ascertained that there is no danger of collision with any person or object in the immediate area by visual inspection of the area, and when available, through information furnished by attendants.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall taxi an aircraft except at a safe and reasonable speed.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall taxi an aircraft onto or across any active runway or taxiway until cleared to do so by the control tower, or where such clearance authorization is not managed by the control tower, until ascertaining that said taxiway or runway is clear of other traffic.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall taxi an aircraft near buildings, parked aircraft, or ground equipment, unless an attendant is present on the ground to assist the operator thereof.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No person shall taxi an aircraft other than in accordance with the taxiing patterns and procedures prescribed for the particular runway to be used or, where applicable, in accordance with the instructions of the control tower.</section><section prefix='(f)'>No person shall push, tow, or back an aircraft away from a designated parking position, in the terminal area or on the apron without assuring that conditions are safe to do so, and in accordance with Operational Directives.</section><section prefix='(g)'>No person shall engage in a power-back an aircraft on any Terminal apron or Terminal aircraft parking position, except at Department approved power-back parking positions, without advance written permission from the Department for such power-back operations and clearance from the FAA control tower for each power-back movement. Except as specifically authorized by the Department, for each power-back movement, the operator of the aircraft shall provide or arrange for the provision of (1) guide persons or wing walkers for each wing, so positioned that vehicles on any adjoining vehicular route will be instructed to stop before the power-back movement commences, and (2) an additional guide person must also be so provided in proper position to provide signals to the aircraft operator to assure safe power-back conditions throughout the movement. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 141, 142, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.15'>Airport marking and lighting. No person shall take-off from, land, park or maneuver an aircraft at the Airport, without complying with all Airport lighting and pavement marking signals and designations, unless the Department or the Federal Aviation Administration has waived such compliance. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 143, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-10.16'>Motorless aircraft. No person shall land at or take-off from Miami International Airport in a motorless aircraft. No person shall land or take-off from any other Airport in a motorless aircraft except as provided by Operational Directive and, where applicable, clearance from the Airport control tower. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 144, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-10.17'>Airport operational restrictions. Unless contrary to Federal Aviation Regulations, the Department shall have the authority to designate or restrict the use of Airports or runways at an Airport with respect to but not limited to, the following types of operations:<section prefix='(a)'>Student pilot training.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Training flights.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Experimental flights.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Equipment demonstration.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Air shows.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Maintenance flight checks.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Ultralight aircraft flights.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Parachuting activities.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Towing, pick up or release of any banner.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Hot air balloons.</section></section><section>Such designations or restrictions shall be established through the issuance by the Department of appropriate Operational Directives. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 145, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-10.18'>Aircraft parking.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall park an aircraft at a parking position on the terminal apron, other than pursuant to and for purposes authorized by Operational Directives issued by the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall park an aircraft at a gate position at the Miami International Airport Terminal without having received prior assignment to such gate position from the Department. However, such assignment is not required if said aircraft to be parked is being directly operated by an Airport user which has been given authorization by the Department to assign its aircraft to the gate position involved.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When an aircraft parking position on the Terminal apron is not needed for other aircraft, an aircraft operator may, following assignment of that gate, park at such gate position according to the time and rate schedule established by the Board, or by the Department, if duly authorized by the Board.</section><section prefix='(d)'>When an aircraft parking position on the Terminal apron is needed for other aircraft, an aircraft operator to whom such gate position is assigned shall park at such gate position no longer than the maximum allowable turn-around time according to aircraft type as established by the Department or as otherwise permitted by lease. Failure of the aircraft operator to remove the aircraft from the gate position within the allotted maximum time shall subject the aircraft operator, in addition to any other penalties prescribed by these rules and regulations, to a charge in accordance with the time and rate schedule established by the Board, or by the Department if duly authorized by the Board, and, if the Department deems it necessary for the efficient operation of the Airport, removal of the aircraft from the gate position at the owner's or operator's risk and expense.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No person shall park an aircraft at the Terminal, or on an apron area, whether leased or not, including designated taxilanes, other than at such positions and in such configurations as may be established by the Department.</section><section prefix='(f)'>No person shall use any area of an Airport, including designated taxiways and taxilanes, other than Department designated public aircraft parking and storage areas, for parking and storage of aircraft, except as otherwise specifically authorized by lease, permit or Operational Directive. Notwithstanding the provisions of any lease or permit to the contrary, if any person uses unauthorized areas, including designated taxiways and taxilanes, without the prior, specific approval of the Department, and the payment of applicable rentals or aircraft parking charges, for aircraft parking or storage, the aircraft so parked or stored may be removed by the Department at the risk and expense of the owner or operator thereof. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 146, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.19'>Radio ground control. The operator of an aircraft taxiing or being towed at an Airport having a control tower shall monitor the ground control frequency being used by the control tower and shall remain in direct communication with the control tower at all times when so operating anywhere on the AOA. In addition, all persons taxing or towing an aircraft at Miami International Airport, other than pilots licensed to operate the particular aircraft being taxied, must be certified as having successfully completed the "movement area driver's training program" given by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 147, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-10.20'>Propeller slipstream and jet blast. No person shall position, start or taxi an aircraft in such a manner that propeller slipstream or jet blast could cause injury to persons or damage to property on the Airport or adjacent to the Airport, or contrary to Operational Directives. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 148, 3-7-95)</section><section>25-10.21<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall start engines or operate an aircraft unless he is a qualified licensed pilot or mechanic.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Blocks or chocks shall be placed in front of the wheels before starting the aircraft engine or engines, unless the aircraft is provided with adequate parking brakes and the same are in applied position.</section><section prefix='(c)'>(1)  An "aircraft engine run-up" is defined as the operation of the engines on an aircraft for any purpose other than for proceeding expeditiously to and from an Airport runway system for takeoff, or for landing or taxiing to and from an approved run-up location. Aircraft engine run-ups include, but are not limited to, engine trim checks, oil pressure checks, propeller checks, various diagnostic tests and aircraft engine idle thrust runs. This definition of aircraft engine run-ups specifically excludes reciprocating engine run-ups performed as part of pre-takeoff procedures, such as magneto checks, conducted on a runway run-up pad, and all engine operations in approved test cells. The term "idle thrust" means the minimum power setting on an engine required to maintain constant, stable engine power output. An "aircraft engine idle thrust run" is defined as the idle thrust operation of an aircraft engine for any purpose other than proceeding expeditiously to and from an Airport runway system for takeoff or for taxiing to an approved run-up location.<section prefix='(2)'>Miami International Airport nighttime aircraft engine run-ups, as defined in (1) above, are prohibited commencing at 11:00 p.m. every night through 7:00 a.m. on Mondays through Fridays and through 10:00 a.m. on Saturdays and Sundays, unless a specific exemption has been granted by the Department. Exemptions will be granted subject to the following:<section prefix='(i)'>All requests for exemption must be made by letter, telephone or radio, at the office designated by the Department, at least one hour prior to the time the run-up is requested. The person requesting the exemption must provide the following information:<section>Name, title and telephone number of requesting individual</section><section>Name of airline and/or owner or other party having custody and control of aircraft</section><section>Aircraft registration</section><section>Aircraft type</section><section>The mechanical and/or operational reason why the run-up is required</section><section>The scheduled departure time and flight number of the aircraft</section><section>The expected duration of the run-up</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>Exemptions will only be granted for aircraft scheduled to depart the Airport during the same prohibition period in which the requested run-up is to occur or within one hour after expiration of such prohibition period and the requesting party provides information, acceptable to the Department, as to why the run-up can not be performed prior to or after the prohibition period for which the exemption is sought.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>All aircraft engine run-ups during the prohibition period, under exemptions granted by the Department, shall be conducted only at the airport's midfield blast fence, unless the aircraft owner or other party in custody and control of the aircraft can demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Department that use of another location will result in less noise and/or air pollution. In the event the midfield blast fence is out of service, the Department shall designate an alternative acceptable location.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>All aircraft engine run-ups during the prohibition period, under exemptions granted by the Department, shall be limited to a maximum period of fifteen (15) minutes, of which the run-up at maximum engine power shall be limited to no more than one minute.</section><section prefix='(v)'>All aircraft engine run-ups during hours not included in the prohibition period shall be conducted only at the midfield blast fence or at other locations which have been authorized for such use by the Department.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>All aircraft engine idle thrust runs during the prohibition period, under exemptions granted by the Department, shall be conducted only at aircraft parking positions in the terminal apron area, or at locations designated by aircraft power-on markers, or at other locations approved by the Department.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>All aircraft thrust runs during the prohibition period, under exemptions granted by the Department, shall be conducted with only a single engine operating, unless multi-engine operation is required for aircraft maintenance purposes and is approved in advance by the Department.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>No person shall perform aircraft engine run-ups, at any County general aviation Airport, other than in places on such general aviation Airport and at such times as may be established from time to time in Operational Directives issued by the Department.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The restrictions hereunder shall not apply to any normal pre-takeoff aircraft engine run-ups performed on a run-way run-up pad if the aircraft is departing the Airport.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 25-1.7, for the first violation of this Section 25-10.21(c) the operator shall be given a written warning and the person having custody and control of the aircraft at the time of the violation shall be punished by a fine of two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00). For each subsequent violation of this Section 25-10.21(c) by an operator, the provisions of Section 15-1.7 shall apply. In the event that a person having custody and control of an aircraft commits a second violation of this Section 25-10.21(c) within a three (3) month period, said person shall be punished by a fine of five hundred dollars ($500.00). In the event that such a person commits a third violation of this Section 25-10.21(c), within a twelve-month period, in addition to a punishment by fine of five hundred dollars ($500.00), such violation shall also constitute a material breach of the lease agreement or other written agreement by which the person is permitted to use the Airport, and shall, therefore, entitle the County to terminate such agreement. Upon conviction of the person for such third violation, the Director shall direct, to the extent such action is permitted by the agreements, that such agreements be terminated and shall effect the removal or eviction of the person from the Airport facilities.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Noise emanating from aircraft engines during ground operations shall be maintained within the then applicable aircraft engine noise limits as promulgated by the Federal government, the State of Florida, or Dade County, whichever be the most restrictive.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Aircraft shall be parked so that fumes, prop wash and jet blast are not directly blown into non-enclosed passenger holding or loading and baggage make-up areas at the Terminal. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 91-134, § 1, 11-5-91; Ord. No. 95-41, § 149, 3-7-95)</section></section><section>25-10.22 No person shall park an aircraft at a terminal parking position, or such other areas that may be established by the Department at the Airport, during periods of low visibility or between the hours of sunset and sunrise, unless the wingtip lights or other suitable warning lights for such aircraft are kept lighted while the aircraft is so parked, or apron lighting is such that all portions of the aircraft are clearly visible. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section>25-10.23<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall, while on the Airport, disturb, interrupt or otherwise interfere with:<section prefix='(1)'>The enplanement or deplanement of aircraft passengers;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The departure or arrival of any aircraft, other than as permitted in Section 25-10.3; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any member of a flight crew aboard an aircraft in the performance of his duties.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The refusal of any person to comply with the request of any member of the flight crew to observe and obey regulations of the Federal Aviation Administration relating to the safety of passengers or aircraft shall constitute disturbance, interruption or interference with a member of a flight crew in the performance of his duties.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall, while aboard an aircraft on the Airport as a passenger, refuse to leave such aircraft upon the request of an agent or representative of the air carrier whose aircraft the person is aboard, when that person has committed an act which is a breach of his contract of carriage under the terms and conditions set out in the air carrier's tariffs. Such acts shall include, but shall not be limited to, violations of the Federal Aviation Regulations concerning fastenings of seat belts, observance of no smoking signs, placement of luggage, consumption of alcoholic beverages, intoxication, and obstruction of aisles and exits.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall, while aboard an aircraft on the Airport as a passenger, refuse to leave such aircraft upon the request of an agent or representative of the owner or operator thereof, when such person has committed an act aboard the aircraft which is an assault, a breach of the peace, an act of intimidation, or a threat against any other person.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No person shall, while aboard an aircraft on the Airport, assault, intimidate or threaten any other person, or commit any act which is a breach of the peace. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 150, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.24'>Non-Operating Aircraft.<section prefix='(a)'>Because the Board has found and determined that Non-Operating aircraft and component parts pose a danger to the life and safety of users of the Airport and their property, as a result of the possibility of the aircraft and components (1) being blown about in storms, (2) becoming fire hazards, (3) being subjected to vandalism, and (4) interfering with orderly and rapid emergency response efforts of firefighters, police, and ambulance services, no person shall park or store any Non-Operating aircraft on Airport property, including leased premises, for a period in excess of sixty (60) days, without written authorization from the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall store or retain aircraft parts or components being held as inventory anywhere on the Airport, other than in an enclosed, authorized facility, or in a manner approved by the Department, in writing.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Whenever any aircraft is parked, stored, or left in Non-Operating condition on the Airport in violation of the provisions of subsections 25-10.24(a), the Department shall follow the procedures required by law to notify the owner or operator thereof and require removal of said aircraft within fifteen (15) days of receipt of such notice, or if the owner or operator be unknown or cannot be found, the Department shall conspicuously post and affix a notice to the said aircraft, requiring removal of said aircraft within fifteen (15) days from date of posting. Upon the failure of the owner or operator of said aircraft to remove said aircraft within the period provided and unless the Department is required to follow Section 25-10.24(d), the Department shall cause the removal of such aircraft from the Airport. All costs incurred by the Department in the removal of any Non-Operating aircraft as set forth herein shall be recoverable against the owner or operator thereof.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Where any federal or Florida law imposes on the County a specific requirement of notice for the removal of Non-Operating aircraft, such law shall prevail and shall be followed by the Department.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To the extent required by state or federal law, the Department shall submit a proposed removal of aircraft under this section to a pre-taking hearing before a court of competent jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(f)'>If any registered owner fails or refuses to respond to notices sent under this section or under federal or Florida law, the Department shall be entitled thereafter to proceed as if the aircraft had no identifiable owner and may effect the removal of the aircraft without a pre-taking hearing.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Department may, but is not obligated to, resort to the administrative hearing provisions of Chapter 8CC of the Code to effect the removal of such aircraft. If required by federal or state law, the Department shall obtain from a court of competent jurisdiction an order of taking of such non-flyable or derelict aircraft. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 151, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-10.25'>Prohibition on removal of liened aircraft. No person shall move or remove any aircraft from any Airport, or parts from such aircraft when an official notice of lien has been posted upon such aircraft by the Department. (Ord. No. 95-41, § 152, 3-7-95)</section><section>25-10.26 Notwithstanding any provision, requirement or prohibition stated in, the Aviation Director or his designee shall have the authority to waive any such provision, requirement or prohibition therein in order for any military branch operating on any County owned or operated airport to operate thereon in accordance with governmental requirements applicable to such operations. (Ord. No. 95-191, § 1, 10-17-95)</section></section></text></law>