<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='2'>Chapter 25 AVIATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Commercial activity.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003072</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25-3. Commercial activity.<section prefix='25-3.1'>Soliciting or carrying on business.<section prefix='(a)'>No person, unless duly authorized in writing by the Board, the County Manager or the Department and unless payment of any fees or charges as established from time to time for such activity, shall be paid by such person, shall, in or upon any area of an Airport:<section prefix='(1)'>Engage in any business or commercial activity; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Sell, or offer for sale, any merchandise, food, beverage or service; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Solicit any business or trade, including the transportation of persons, baggage, or goods, the shining of shoes, or bootblacking; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Sing, dance, or play any musical instrument; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Install or place any coin, currency or debit or credit card operated machine for the sale or provision of any merchandise, food, beverage or service of any type or kind, without the prior written approval of the Department.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>No person authorized to perform services on the Airport shall refuse to perform such services when requested by any orderly person to do so, except as authorized by federal or State law or regulations. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 88-37, § 4, 5-3-88; Ord. No. 95-41, § 62, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-3.2'>Commercial photography, film and recordings. No person unless authorized in writing by the Department, or when appropriate by permit issued under Section 2-11.14 of this Code, shall take still, motion, or sound motion pictures or sound records or recordings of voices or otherwise for commercial, training or educational purposes, other than news coverage, in public areas of the terminal or on the public areas of any facility under the administration of the Department. As a condition of authorization, the Department may require reimbursement for its costs of personnel, equipment and/or supplies used in support of such activity, and may impose fair and equitable rental rates for extended use of any space under the administration of the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 76-112, § 4, 12-21-76; Ord. No. 95-41, § 63, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-3.3'>Building construction and improvements. No person without written authorization from the Department, shall construct or cause to be constructed any buildings or structures, including signs, utility connection or any improvements, modifications (excluding maintenance), or additions to any such buildings or structures, or any paving, excavations, removal of soil or fill material or other improvement to land on the Airport, whether on leaseholds or elsewhere. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-3.4'>Advertising. No person, unless authorized in writing by the Department, shall post or distribute commercial signs, advertisements, literature, circulars, pictures, sketches, drawings, handbills, or any other form of printed or written commercial matter or material at the Airport. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-3.5'>Storage of property.<section prefix='(a)'>Unless otherwise provided in a lease or other written agreement or permit, no person shall use any area of the Airport for storage of cargo, aircraft, vehicles, motor vehicles, mobile equipment or other property without prior written permission of the Department. If such person uses such area for storage without first obtaining permission, the Department shall have such property removed and stored at the risk and expense of the owner or consignee thereof.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall load cargo on or unload cargo from an aircraft, other than in designated areas established by Operational Directive issued by the Department, or in areas totally contained within an established leasehold or restricted area, authorized for such activity. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 64, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-3.6'>Signs. No person, unless authorized by the Department, shall construct or install any sign at any Airport, unless such sign is a traffic-control device within a leasehold area and is in conformity with State and County regulations. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 65, 66, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-3.7'>Protection of property. No person authorized to operate equipment, including but not limited to baggage carts, handcarts, wheelchairs, and powered transporters in the Terminal Building, shall do so unless such equipment is properly equipped with protective materials or devices to minimize damage to property and injury to persons. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 65, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-3.8'>Tipping. No person authorized to accept tips for services performed at the Airport shall solicit a tip, or a specific amount of tip, nor harass, insult or display any form of rudeness to the person for whom the service is being performed. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 65, 3-7-95)</section></section></text></law>