<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='2'>Chapter 25 AVIATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Public health.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003074</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25-5. Public health.<section prefix='25-5.1'>Application. The applicable health laws and regulations of the United States of America, the State of Florida, the County of Dade, and these rules and regulations shall apply to all persons and establishments, whether on or off an Airport, if such persons or establishments are engaged in activities affecting the Airport involving food and beverage service, drinking water service, handling, storage or disposal of water or refuse or any other activity which has a potentially deleterious effect on public health, e.g., food quality, water quality, air quality, or sanitary sewage and industrial waste water or storm water systems.</section><section prefix='25-5.2'>Food and beverage service. All matters of public health at the Airport are subject to the applicable United States Public Health Service, Florida State Board of Health and Dade County Department of Health regulations and policies.<section prefix='(a)'>Any persons authorized to engage in food and beverage service on the Airport, whether from locations on or off the Airport, to Airport employees, airline passengers or the general public shall secure all required health agency licenses and shall abide by all rules and regulations of such agencies.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All food and beverage establishments, whether on or off the Airport in fixed or mobile operations, engaged in food and beverage service to intrastate, interstate, or international aircraft, shall abide by all rules and regulations of appropriate federal, state, and local agencies.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall remove, from an aircraft, any food, garbage or trash, except as authorized under federal, State and/or local health regulations.</section></section><section prefix='25-5.3'>Control of aircraft drinking water.<section prefix='(a)'>The water piping system in aircraft servicing areas shall be under adequate positive pressure at all times with a vacuum break or approved back-flow prevention device installed to prevent siphoning, and there shall be no cross connections between the potable water system and a system of questionable quality. All drinking and culinary water used in connection with the operation of aircraft in interstate, intrastate, or international commerce shall come from sources approved by the United States Public Health Service, the Florida State Board of Health or the Dade County Department of Public Health; and the installation of all aircraft water piping systems shall comply with the requirements established by these agencies.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Potable water supply points on servicing piers or other locations on the Airport labeled "Aircraft Drinking Water Only" or similar wording indicating the same intent, whether the transfer of water is by direct connection from the hose bib to a mounted hose reel or by portable water truck or cart, shall be used for no other purpose, except in an emergency.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Hoses used to deliver potable water to aircraft shall be constructed of such material and stored and handled in such manner as prescribed by the United States Public Health Service regulations, and used for no other purpose. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 71, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-5.4'>Handling and disposal of sanitary waste from aircraft.<section prefix='(a)'>When a removable sanitary waste can is removed from an aircraft, the contents of such can shall be securely enclosed or covered while being transported to a facility for emptying and cleaning.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The sanitary waste accumulated in the fixed waste retention tank on an aircraft shall be discharged through a flexible hose, with a watertight connection to a portable water-tight tank, in order to avoid contamination of the area. Flushing of the retention tank must never be accomplished by direct connection to a potable water distribution system.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All aircraft sanitary waste cans and retention tanks shall be serviced in approved servicing areas only.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All ground facilities and operations for the disposal of sanitary waste and for the cleaning of sanitary waste cans and fixed waste-retention tanks, and all sanitary waste trucks or carts, shall be emptied, flushed, cleaned, and the rinse compartments of same filled at approved servicing areas only.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No water hydrant on the Airport shall be used to service a sanitary waste truck or cart.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All connections in an aircraft sanitary waste discharge line or sanitary tank servicing equipment shall be equipped with positive seals to prevent spillage.</section><section prefix='(g)'>When a defect in an aircraft sanitary waste discharge valve or in a waste tank servicing equipment results in sanitary water spillage or when an improper or illegal discharge of sanitary waste has been made into equipment (valve) pits on the AOA, it shall be the responsibility of the aircraft owner or operator to immediately clean and decontaminate the equipment and ground area soiled. The defective components shall be repaired or replaced before the discharge valve or servicing equipment is placed back in service. The Department may clean up as necessary upon failure by the owner or operator to do so and charge the cost thereof, plus an administrative fee of twenty-five (25) percent, to the owner and/or operator.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The owners or operators of sanitary waste tank trucks shall make any alterations to or add any equipment to such trucks as required by the Department, the Department of Public Health or Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, for the sanitary operation of the aircraft sanitary waste disposal system. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 72, 73, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-5.5'>Handling of aircraft and Airport refuse.<section prefix='(a)'>Receptacles used for the storage of aircraft galley paper and liquid waste, as well as garbage and refuse accumulating from operations in aircraft servicing areas, shall be stored, in accordance with standards and procedures approved by all appropriate federal, State and local public agencies.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Garbage and refuse containers used in the Terminal Building areas shall be of a type and design approved by the Department, with the design compatible to the use and location, so as to preclude odor, insects, and vermin. Type, design and location shall assure no interference with the safe operation of vehicles and/or aircraft operating in its vicinity, and comply with reasonable standards established by the Department.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Under no conditions shall open drums or containers be used for storage of garbage or refuse on the Airport.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The open storage or placement on the Airport of any receptacle, equipment or material, including rubber tires, that holds water and is conducive to mosquito or rodent harborage or breeding is prohibited.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All aircraft and Airport refuse other than sanitary waste shall be disposed of in accordance with applicable County, State and federal standards and procedures. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section></section><section prefix='25-5.6'>Waste removal services.<section prefix='(a)'>All operators of waste removal services on the Airport shall secure a permit from the Director and written approval from the Dade County Department of Public Health as to the suitability of the waste removal vehicle, compactors and/or containers.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No vehicle used for hauling trash, dirt or any other waste materials shall be operated on the Airport unless such vehicle is constructed and equipped so as to prevent the contents thereof from blowing, dropping, sifting, leaking, or otherwise escaping therefrom. Approved waste, trash, and garbage compactors and containers shall be allowed at designated locations only. Such areas shall be kept clean and sanitary at all times by the person in control thereof. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section></section><section prefix='25-5.7'>Water pollution. No person shall introduce, or cause or permit to be introduced, in any water system or any surface or underground water at the Airport, any organic or inorganic matter or deleterious substance in such quantity, proportions, or accumulations which are injurious to human, plant, animal, fish or other aquatic life, or property, or which unreasonably interferes with the enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business on the Airport. The types and permissible quantities of discharge shall be governed by the then applicable water discharge standards as promulgated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act of 1972, or under any amendment or successor legislation thereto, or as established by State statute or County ordinance, whichever be the most stringent. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-5.8'>Air pollution.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall introduce, or cause or permit to be introduced in the outdoor atmosphere or about an Airport any one or more air contaminants or combinations thereof, by burning or otherwise, in such quantities and of such duration as to be injurious to human, plant, or animal life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the enjoyment of life or property or the conduct of business on the Airport, or which in any way interferes with the operation of aircraft on the ground or in the air. The types and permissible quantities of discharge into the air shall be governed by the then applicable atmospheric discharge standards as promulgated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency under the Federal Clean Air Act of 1980, or under any amendment or successor legislation thereto, or as established by State statute or County ordinance, whichever be the most stringent.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All motor operated vehicles used on a regular basis or stationed at an Airport shall comply with Chapter 24 of the Code regarding prohibitions against motor vehicles as sources of air pollution. While on Airport property, it shall be unlawful for the owner of a commercial vehicle to be operated which:<section prefix='(1)'>Emits air contaminants as dark as or darker in shade than that designed as number one on the Ringelmann Chart or of such an opacity equal to or greater than twenty (20) percent for longer than ten (10) consecutive seconds; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Has had any of its emission control devices, as installed at the time of manufacture, removed, disconnected and/or disabled; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Is powered by any fuel that may defeat the design purpose of the vehicle's emission control devices, including but not limited to leaded gasoline used in a commercial vehicle designed to be powered by unleaded gasoline.</section><section>Any vehicle found to be in violation of the above will be subject to fines and penalties and will be immediately prohibited from operating at an Airport until such deficiency has been corrected and the vehicle has been recertified by the Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management or any other authorized government agency. In addition, the Department may through Operational Directive impose further restrictions to a classified group of vehicles if the Department determines the emissions from any such group constitutes an environmental hazard.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Operators of all motor vehicles at the terminal shall turn off the vehicle's engine when such vehicle is parked or is waiting other than at a traffic-control device, requiring the vehicle to stop temporarily, or to permit safe passage of persons or other vehicles. Emergency (police and fire) vehicles are exempt under this subsection when the operator of the vehicle is in close proximity to the vehicle, or when a person or police canine is in the vehicle.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Operators of aircraft at the Airport shall turn off the aircraft engine or engines when such aircraft is not actively being taxied or checked in conjunction with maintenance procedures, except for onboard aircraft power units (APU). (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 74—77, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-5.9'>Sanitary sewage and industrial waste water system pollution. No person, whether on or off an Airport premises, shall introduce or cause or permit to be introduced, in any sanitary sewage and industrial waste water or storm water system under the jurisdiction of the Department, any deleterious substance in such quantities, and for such duration as is or may be injurious to human, plant or animal life, or property, or which unreasonably interferes with the maintenance or operation of the Airport or the County sewage system. The types and permissible quantities of discharge shall be governed by the then applicable sewage discharge standards for sanitary sewage and industrial waste water and storm water systems as promulgated by the appropriate Federal, State and County agencies, whichever are the most stringent. Such effluent shall be discharged only into authorized sewage and waste disposal systems as are provided for such purpose and shall be disposed of in a manner approved by the Department and appropriate controlling agencies. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 78, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-5.10'>Quarantine. International passenger quarantine, animal quarantine and disposition of diseased animals or plants shall be conducted in conformity with all applicable federal, State and County laws and regulations. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 69, 3-7-95)</history></law>