<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='2'>Chapter 25 AVIATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Safety hazards, dangerous articles and fueling operations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003075</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25-6. Safety hazards, dangerous articles and fueling operations.<section prefix='25-6.1'>Cleaning of equipment. No person shall use flammable liquids in the cleaning of aircraft or aircraft engines, propellers or other appliances, equipment or parts of aircraft, unless such cleaning operations are conducted in accordance with National Fire Protection Agency (NFPA) standards and all applicable Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.2'>Open-flame operations. No person shall conduct any open-flame operations in any area on an Airport unless specifically approved in writing by the Department. Any such activities, if authorized, shall be conducted in strict accordance with NFPA standards, the Department's authorization and applicable Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 79, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.3'>Powder-activated tools. No person shall use powder-activated tools or fastening devices any place on the Airport without prior written authorization of the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.4'>Storage of material.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall keep or store material or equipment in such manner as to constitute a fire hazard or be in violation of applicable Dade County codes or Operational Directives of the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All storage of material in buildings shall be arranged in height not to extend above the lower or bottom cord of roof trusses and shall not be closer than eighteen (18) inches below sprinkler heads. Storage areas shall provide aisles adequate for passage of Fire Department personnel and equipment throughout the area and between such storage areas and all outside walls. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 80, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-6.5'>Storage of hazardous material. No person shall keep or store any flammable liquids, gases, explosives, signal flares or other hazardous material on an Airport, except in containers and receptacles, and in structures or areas, specifically approved for such storage, in compliance with the requirements of NFPA standards, Federal Aviation Regulations and applicable Dade County codes and as provided in subsection 25-6.22(a) and (b). (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 81, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.6'>Lubricating oil.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall keep or store lubricating oils on the Airport, except in containers and receptacles, designed for such purpose, and in structures or areas specifically approved for such storage in compliance with the requirements of the NFPA standards, Federal Aviation Regulations and applicable Dade County codes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall transport lubricating oils to points of use except in safety cans or vehicles approved for such purpose by applicable Dade County codes.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall store empty lubricating oil drums or cans except in approved areas.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No hydrocarbon products, oil-water mixtures with concentrations of greater than five (5) parts per million hydrocarbons or other industrial waste water shall be dumped or permitted to drain onto paved or unpaved surface areas of the Airport, directly into Airport drainage ditches, canals, rivers, ponding areas, into Airport storm drains, or directly into the sanitary sewer system. Such matter shall be discharged only into approved industrial waste water collection and treatment systems or disposed of in an alternate manner approved by the Department or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 82, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-6.7'>Waste. Lessees of hangars, aircraft servicing or maintenance buildings, the Terminal Building, or other Airport areas shall provide suitable metal safety receptacles with operating, self-closing covers for the storage of oily wastes, rags and other rubbish and trash. Unless such requirement is waived in writing by the Department, all exterior waste storage and receptacle areas shall be screened from public view, including from aircraft. All waste within this general classification shall be removed by the lessees from the Airport premises daily, or as required by applicable Dade County codes, whichever shall be the more stringent. (Ord. No. 95-41, § 83, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.8'>Smoking. No person shall smoke or carry lighted cigars, cigarettes, pipes, matches or any open flame inside any facility or leasehold designated for bulk fuel storage (a "tank farm") or within fifty (50) feet of any aircraft, or the nearest point of an aircraft being fueled or defueled, or of the site of a flammable liquid spill unless such person is in a building or other enclosed area where smoking is not prohibited. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 84, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.9'>Cleaning fluids.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall use flammable substances for cleaning hangars or other buildings on the Airport.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall store flammable cleaning fluids, except in containers with dispensing devices approved by NFPA standards and applicable Dade County codes.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall transport flammable cleaning fluids to points of use except in safety cans approved by NFPA standards and applicable Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section></section><section prefix='25-6.10'>Leasehold cleanliness. All lessees on the Airport shall keep all areas of the premises leased or used by them clean and free of oil, grease and other flammable material. The floors of hangars and other buildings shall be kept clean and continuously kept free of rags, waste material or other trash or rubbish. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.11'>Care of aircraft ramp, apron and parking areas. Any person, including the owners or operators of aircraft and into-plane fuelers, causing overflowing or spilling of oil, grease, fuel, sanitary waste water, any hazardous material or any similar material anywhere on an Airport, shall be responsible for the immediate clean-up of such spillage and notification as required by subsection 25-6.23(e). Upon the default of the responsible person to clean such area, the Department, or other authorized representative of the County, shall provide the necessary cleaning and charge the responsible person for the expense thereof. In the event of a spill which occurred in connection with the fueling or defueling of an aircraft, the responsible party, for purpose of billing for Department incurred clean-up costs, shall be the party named in the "Fuel Spill Incident Report," prepared by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 85, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.12'>Doping, spray painting and paint stripping.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall perform doping processes, spray painting, or paint stripping except in areas or facilities approved for such purposes under NFPA standards and applicable Dade County codes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall enter or work in a dope room while doping is in process, or in a spray-painting room or area while spray painting is being conducted, unless such person is properly clothed for purposes of safety and self-protection in accordance with NFPA standards and applicable Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section></section><section prefix='25-6.13'>Fire extinguishers. No person shall tamper with fire-extinguishing equipment at the Airport at any time, nor use such equipment for any purpose other than firefighting or emergency fire prevention. All fire-extinguishing equipment shall be maintained in accordance with the adopted recommendations of NFPA, and other applicable Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.14'>Use of potentially wind-borne materials. No person shall use any material, such as oil absorbent or similar material, in such a manner as will create a hazard to persons or property when picked up, swirled or blown about by the blast from an aircraft engine or by a wind. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 86, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.15'>Operating motor vehicles in hangars. No person, except in an emergency, shall operate a tractor, tug, or other motor vehicle in any hangar or other building used for aircraft maintenance facility when an aircraft is present, unless the exhaust system of such tractor, tug, or other motor vehicle is protected by screens or baffles to prevent the escape of sparks or the propagation of flame, in accordance with requirements of NFPA standards and applicable Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.16'>Grounding of aircraft in hangars. No person shall park an aircraft in any hangar or other structure on the Airport, unless the aircraft is grounded in accordance with the requirements of the Federal Aviation Regulations, NFPA standards and applicable Dade County codes as specified in Operational Directives. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.17'>Motorized ground equipment near aircraft. No person shall park motorized ground equipment near any aircraft in such manner so as to prevent it or other ground equipment from being readily driven or towed away from the aircraft in case of an emergency. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.18'>Repairing of aircraft. No person shall repair an aircraft or aircraft engine, propeller, or other aircraft apparatus in any area of an Airport other than an area leased for such purpose or areas, if any, specifically designated by posted sign or Operational Directive for such purpose, except that minor adjustments or repairs may be made while the aircraft is at an aircraft parking position, stand or apron being prepared for departure. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 87, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.19'>Operating aircraft engines in hangars. The starting or operating of aircraft engines, including on-board auxiliary power units (APU's), inside any hangar, other than the air rotation of jet engines without ignition, is prohibited. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 88, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-6.20'>Heating systems in hangars. Heating in any hangar shall be only by approved systems or devices as listed by the Underwriters Laboratories as suitable for use in aircraft hangars, and shall be installed in the manner prescribed by applicable Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-6.21'>Electrical equipment and lighting systems.<section prefix='(a)'>Explosion-proof or vapor-proof electrical equipment shall be used as required in areas defined as hazardous by NFPA or Dade County codes. No portable lamp assembly shall be used in any maintenance shelter or hangar without a proper protective guard or shield over such lamp assembly to prevent breakage.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All electric power-operated tools and equipment shall be shut off while not in actual use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Electrical lighting systems in hangars, aircraft maintenance facilities or other areas where explosive fumes are present shall be as required by NFPA standards and Dade County codes. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section></section><section prefix='25-6.22'>Explosives, corrosives, poisons, compressed gases, and radiological materials.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall store, keep, handle, use, dispense or transport at, to or from the Airport any Class A explosive (as defined by the "Hazardous Material Regulation of the Department of Transportation").</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall store, keep, handle, use, dispense or transport at, to or from the Airport any Class B or Class C explosive, Class A poison, or red label materials (as defined by the "Hazardous Material Regulation of the Department of Transportation") in a manner other than in conformity with the applicable regulations of the Air Transport Association of America, the International Air Transport Association, the United States Department of Transportation, and the recommendations of the National Fire Protection Association.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Other than for emergency purposes as defined by Federal Aviation Regulations, no person shall carry a compressed air or gas tank aboard a commercial aircraft, unless such tank is reduced to zero pressure, or is an integral component of the aircraft system. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 89, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-6.23'>Fueling and defueling. The following rules shall govern and control the fueling and defueling of aircraft and motor vehicles at the Airport:<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall fuel or defuel an aircraft while an operating engine of such aircraft is running; provided, however, that nothing herein shall prohibit fueling or defueling of an aircraft during aircraft APU operations, and provided further in a situation resulting from an inoperative on-board APU, a jet engine mounted at the rear of the aircraft or on the wing on the side opposite the fueling point may be operated to provide aircraft electrical power during fueling, provided:<section prefix='(1)'>The operation follows procedures published by the manufacturer of the aircraft and its operator to assure safety of the operation.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Prior approval is obtained from the Department's Airport operations office.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Fire Department is on standby watch at the aircraft involved.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>As specified by NFPA standards, no person shall place into operation any electrical appliance in an aircraft when the aircraft is being fueled or defueled.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No aircraft shall be fueled or defueled unless the aircraft and the fuel dispensing apparatus shall both be electrically grounded or bonded as required by Federal Aviation Regulations, NFPA standards, Dade County ordinances, and applicable Operational Directives.</section><section prefix='(d)'>When a fuel spill over five (5) feet in diameter occurs, the Fire Department shall be notified immediately and valves and dome covers shall be shut down. If the engine of the fueling vehicle is running at the time of the fuel spill, the vehicle shall be removed from the area unless contrary orders are issued by the senior fire officer at the scene. Conversely, if the engine of a fueling vehicle is shut down at the time of the fuel spill, it shall remain shut down unless a fire has already started or until the senior fire officer at the scene orders the vehicle moved. In no event shall fueling or defueling operations resume following a fuel spill until all areas upon which fuel has spilled or flowed over are thoroughly flushed and the senior fire official at the spill site has issued an order permitting the resumption of fueling operations.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No passenger shall be permitted in any aircraft during fueling or defueling, unless a cabin attendant is present at or near the cabin door and unless a passenger boarding ramp or bridge is in place at the cabin door.</section><section prefix='(f)'>No person shall use any material within fifty (50) feet of the nearest point of an aircraft during fueling or defueling of the aircraft which may cause a static spark.</section><section prefix='(g)'>No person shall engage in aircraft fueling and defueling operations without adequate fire extinguishers within ready reach.</section><section prefix='(h)'>No person shall start the engine of any aircraft when there is a flammable liquid on the ground in the vicinity of such aircraft.</section><section prefix='(i)'>No person shall fuel or defuel an aircraft with fueling hoses and other equipment or apparatus which are not in a safe, sound and nonleaking condition in accordance with NFPA standards.</section><section prefix='(j)'>All hoses, funnels, and appurtenances used in fueling and defueling operations shall be equipped with a positive grounding device in good order to prevent ignition of flammable liquids due to static spark.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The fueling and defueling of aircraft shall be conducted at a distance of at least fifty (50) feet from any hangar or other building unless at a Terminal aircraft loading/unloading gate or fifty (50) feet from any combustion or ventilation air intake to any boiler, heater, or incinerator room in accordance with NFPA standards.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Maintenance and testing of aircraft fueling systems shall be conducted under controlled conditions, in strict compliance with NFPA 410(C) or subsequent replacement publications.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Refueling vehicles shall be stored and maintained outdoors in areas authorized by the Department, except for the accomplishment of minor adjustments or repairs necessary to move such units to the storage area when failure occurs elsewhere on the Airport. No fuel trucks, empty or otherwise, shall be brought into, kept or stored within any building at the Airport, unless said building is used exclusively for that purpose, or in those instances under controlled conditions during approved fueling and defueling operations.</section><section prefix='(n)'>No fueling vehicles other than hydrant carts shall be backed within twenty (20) feet of an aircraft, unless a person is present outside the fueling vehicle to assist the operator thereof.</section><section prefix='(o)'>When a fire occurs in or near a fuel delivery device while servicing an aircraft, the Fire Department shall be notified immediately, fueling shall be discontinued immediately, emergency valves and dome covers shall be shut down at once and the fueling vehicles and equipment shall immediately be removed from the vicinity of the aircraft unless deemed unsafe. Any persons on board the aircraft shall be evacuated and other equipment removed from the area. If necessary, the aircraft shall be towed to a position at a safe distance from buildings and other aircraft. Upon his arrival the senior fire officer will be in charge.</section><section prefix='(p)'>The transfer of fuel from one fuel service vehicle to another (commonly referred to as "tankering") is prohibited within the AOA, except for emergency conditions under the standby watch of the Fire Department, and except for the required resupply of a service vehicle in conjunction with the supply of large quantities of fuel; e.g. for wide-bodied aircraft; provided, however, that all equipment and aircraft must be properly grounded.</section><section prefix='(q)'>No airborne radar equipment shall be operated or ground tested in any area on the Airport where the directional beam of high intensity radar is within three hundred (300) feet, or the low intensity beam is within one hundred (100) feet, of an aircraft fueling operation, aircraft fueling truck, or aircraft fuel or flammable liquid storage facility, unless an approved shielding device is provided and used during the radar operation.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Aircraft fueling vehicles shall be equipped with storage tanks which are sectionalized into compartments of not over two thousand (2,000) gallons' capacity or in lieu thereof shall be equipped and operated in accordance with alternate procedures approved, in writing, by the Department. Fueling vehicles, which are not in compliance with the requirement for sectionalization or for which alternate full operational procedures have not been approved, may be authorized for continued use only on a restricted basis and only upon specific individual authorization by the Department, in writing. (Ord. No. 77-88, § 1, 12-6-77)</section><section prefix='(s)'>Motor vehicles shall be fueled on the Airport only from approved locations and dispensing devices.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Yearly safety inspection shall mean inspection of equipment and vehicles operated on the AOA for emission controls and safety items such as lights, brakes, windshields, tires, and the like. All safety items shall be in good working order.</section><section prefix='(u)'>The use of automobile fuel products is prohibited for use in aircraft, unless the aircraft is individually certified for the use of such fuel.</section><section prefix='(v)'>No person shall vend, sell, or offer for sale on an Airport any petroleum fuel or lubricating product without authorization in writing from the Department.</section><section prefix='(w)'>No person shall transport onto an Airport, other than by aircraft for use in such aircraft, any fuel product or lubricating product, unless authorized in writing by the Department. Notwithstanding the above, aircraft owners shall not be denied the right to bring fuel and lubricating products onto an Airport for the purpose of self-fueling, provided the transport of the fuel and lubricating products onto the Airport and the self-fueling activities are otherwise in compliance with this chapter and applicable fire and environmental codes, and are otherwise authorized by the lessee of the premises on which such self-fueling activity occurs.</section><section prefix='(x)'>No person shall transport onto an Airport. other than by aircraft for use in such aircraft, any fuel product or flammable material unless in approved containers or vehicles.</section><section prefix='(z)'>All persons fueling aircraft at any gate parking position that is equipped with an operable fuel hydrant connected to the underground fueling system, shall use such hydrant system for aircraft fueling, unless otherwise specifically authorized by the Department on a case-by-case basis.</section></section><section>The applicable Standards and Recommendations of the National Fire Protection Association, as they are amended from time to time, are incorporated herein by reference. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 90—94, 3-7-95)</section></section></text></law>