<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='2'>Chapter 25 AVIATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Tenant obligations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003076</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25-7. Tenant obligations.<section prefix='25-7.1'>Structural and decorative changes. No Airport tenant or lessee shall make or cause to be made any new construction, alterations, additions or improvements of any nature whatsoever, including signs, on or to any leased premises without prior written authorization of the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-7.2'>Damages. All Airport tenants and lessees shall be fully responsible for the repair of all damages to buildings, equipment, real property, and appurtenances on their leased premises, resulting from its operations or the actions of its employees, agents, licensees or guests. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-7.3'>Use of premises. No Airport tenant or lessee shall use or permit its leased premises to be used or occupied for any purpose not authorized by its lease or as prohibited by this chapter (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 95, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-7.4'>Trailers, trucks; restricted use. No person shall use or permit the use of any trailed vehicle, truck, bus or van-type vehicle on any Airport for office, storage space, maintenance shop or similar purpose, unless specifically authorized by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-7.5'>Protection of leased areas.<section prefix='(a)'>No Airport tenant under whose control are any vehicle or personnel gates, doors or any other means of ingress and egress to the AOA or SIDA area at Miami International Airport or at any other County Airport which has a fenced, secured AOA, shall fail to keep the same secured or controlled at all times to prevent the access of unauthorized persons to the AOA. Airport tenants shall be responsible for control and prevention of unauthorized access to the AOA or the leasehold areas of other tenants from the tenant's leased premises.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No Airport tenant under whose control are any vehicle or personnel gates, doors or other means of ingress or egress to or from the AOA or a SIDA area at Miami International Airport shall fail at all times to have in effect a positive access control program. In no event shall tenant-controlled keys, lock combinations, or the like be allowed off the leased premises without such tenant's knowledge and consent.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The internal security of leased areas at the Airport shall remain the sole responsibility of the lessee. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 96, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-7.6'>Common use areas.<section prefix='(a)'>No Airport tenant or other authorized Airport user shall utilize a common use area, including an aircraft gate position in a manner which interferes with the use of such area by another or which departs from established and authorized procedures for the use of such area.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No Airport tenant or other authorized Airport user shall utilize a common use area, including an aircraft gate position, unless properly trained and authorized personnel supplied by such tenant or user are present for purposes of control and coordination during all periods of such use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Upon occupancy of any common use aircraft gate position, the user assumes full responsibility for compliance with Federal and local security requirements and shall be liable for all fines and penalties resulting from failure to perform or abide by same. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 97, 98, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-7.7'>Public service.<section prefix='(a)'>Aircraft owners and operators utilizing the Terminal at Miami International Airport shall provide, directly or under contract with others, a full range of services, including, but not limited to, porter service, wheelchair services, screening and security services as required by Federal Aviation Regulations, required by its passengers in connection with their use of the Airport. Minimum standards may be established by Operational Directive of the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All Terminal employees, including but not limited to counter and gate agents, porters and security screening, whose prime responsibility is direct service to the public, shall, in addition to any Department issued identification badge, display clearly discernible employer issued personal identification such as a nameplate and company identification on his or her outer garments, in plain view above the waist. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 99, 3-7-95)</section></section></section></text></law>