<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='2'>Chapter 25 AVIATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Control of landside traffic.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003077</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25-8. Control of landside traffic.<section prefix='25-8.1'>Governing law. The regulation of all traffic using Airport roadways and parking facilities shall be governed by the applicable provisions (including definitions) of the Florida Statutes, Chapter 30 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, and this chapter. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-8.2'>Traffic-control devices. No person shall operate a vehicle on the upper or lower vehicle drives of the Terminal at Miami International Airport or on any roadways on an Airport, in violation of official traffic-control devices. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 100, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-8.3'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall stop, stand or park a vehicle on the upper or lower vehicular drives at the Terminal Building at Miami International Airport, in violation of any official traffic-control device or an oral directive provided by an authorized law enforcement officer or an authorized uniformed traffic enforcement employee of the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person operating a commercial vehicle for hire shall load or unload persons at curbside loading zones not designated for such purpose for such classification of service within the Terminal Building area of Miami International Airport. Such loading and unloading zones and any restricted use by authorized commercial vehicles, or other vehicles shall be established by the Department and shall be designated by appropriate traffic-control devices, signs or Operational Directives.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall stop, stand or park a vehicle on any Airport roadway or in a curbside area at the terminal, unless so permitted or required by an official traffic-control device or pursuant to subsection 25-8.3(b) above.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall stop, stand or park any vehicle on the upper or lower vehicular drives at the Terminal Building at Miami International Airport, for the purpose of making deliveries of goods, wares or merchandise to the Terminal Building except during times or in areas designated by the Department, or as otherwise posted.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No person shall park or stop a trailer, semitrailer, cargo trailer or other vehicle at any loading pier or dock at the Airport except for the purpose of the immediate loading or unloading of such vehicle, unless otherwise authorized by the Department.</section><section prefix='(f)'>No person shall park or stop a vehicle at the Airport in such a manner as to block any Airport roadway or otherwise impede the normal flow of vehicular traffic on any Airport roadway, including those roadways to, from or within any Airport facility, without prior notification of and authorization by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 101, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-8.4'>Airport parking facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall enter or use an Airport motor vehicle parking facility or parking space contrary to its posted or restricted use.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall stop, park or leave a vehicle unattended in any Airport motor vehicle parking facility or parking space or area without having positioned said vehicle in a designated stall or area in such a manner as not to obstruct the proper movement of other vehicles in the parking facility or area or utilization by other vehicles of driveways or adjacent parking spaces.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Public parking facilities.<section prefix='(1)'>No person shall park or leave a vehicle unattended in any motor vehicle parking facility, open to the public, without having properly secured a required parking claim check or having paid the required toll, in the case of metered or similarly controlled parking areas.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No person shall remove or attempt to remove any vehicle from an Airport parking facility open to the public without making payment of the parking charge established by the Board, unless authorized by the Department.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No person, unless authorized by the Department, shall remove or attempt to remove a claim check from an Airport parking facility claim check dispensing machine, other than as an operator of a vehicle entering an Airport parking facility, in which case, such person shall remove only one (1) claim check from the dispensing machine.</section><section prefix='(4)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to remove a claim check or checks from, or to otherwise operate, an Airport parking facility claim check dispensing machine, for the purpose of avoiding or enabling another person to avoid payment of the lawful charge of the use of said parking facilities.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No person shall remove or attempt to remove a vehicle from an Airport parking facility by presenting a claim check other than the claim check originally dispensed to the operator of such vehicle at the time that vehicle entered the parking facility.</section><section prefix='(6)'>No person shall present a parking claim check requiring payment of parking fees upon exiting a motor vehicle parking facility which does not indicate an accurate record of the length of time said vehicle was actually within the parking facility for which the time and charges have accrued, inaccuracies of time recording equipment excepted.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Employee parking facilities.<section prefix='(1)'>No person shall park or operate a vehicle on any Airport parking facility established or authorized for the use of persons employed at the Airport without complying with all procedures established by the Department for the control of such vehicle and for the use of such parking facility.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No person shall enter such employee parking facilities or use the transportation service provided in support thereof unless possessing and displaying, if requested a valid identification badge issued or approved by the Department.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No person shall allow any other person to use their identification badge, their vehicle and/or vehicle parking decal in order for the other person to use any Airport public or employee parking facility or any employee transportation service. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 102—104, 3-7-95)</section></section></section><section prefix='25-8.5'>Removal of vehicles.<section prefix='(a)'>Either law enforcement officers employed by the County's Police Department or specifically designated employees of the Department are authorized to immediately remove or cause the removal of any vehicle, when such vehicle is parked in violation of any provision of these rules and regulations. The operator of any Airport parking facility is authorized to remove or cause the removal of any vehicle from such parking facility to said designated impoundment area when such vehicle is parked in violation of any provision of subsection 25-8.4 of this chapter. Vehicles so removed shall be temporarily impounded on Airport property until the owner has complied with recovery provisions established by the Department or the vehicle is disposed of in accordance with applicable state or local requirements. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing provisions, a vehicle parked in any area or zone designated by signs as a "no parking zone," or "tow away zone," or "parking prohibited" may be removed in accordance with this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Whenever any vehicle is moved to the aforementioned temporary impoundment area, a written report of such removal shall promptly be made in accordance with Operational Directives issued by the Department.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The owner of any vehicle so removed to a temporary impoundment area, or his authorized representative, may recover possession of such vehicle within seven (7) days after its removal to the temporary impoundment area (unless such period is extended by the Department), upon acceptable proof of ownership and payment of appropriate parking charges accrued up to the time of removal and further payment of storage and towing charges incident to such removal at the Airport. Charges for towing and storage of removed vehicles shall be those approved or authorized by the Board from time to time and posted at the vehicle recovery area.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In the event any such vehicle is not recovered by its owner or his authorized representative from the temporary impoundment area within the period established in subsection 25-8.5(c) above, such vehicle may be considered as abandoned and removed from the temporary impoundment area in accordance with Airport procedures for abandoned vehicles.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The owner or authorized representative of any vehicle removed from the temporary impoundment area as abandoned may recover possession of such vehicle upon proof of ownership and payment of appropriate charges accrued against such vehicle for parking, towing and storage on the Airport in addition to the charges provided in the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, unless state law provides otherwise.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Relocation of vehicles. Either law enforcement officers employed by the County's Police Department, designated employees of the County, or authorized persons under contract to the County shall have the right to relocate properly parked private vehicles, when such is necessary to protect such vehicle or when such vehicle is so parked as to interfere with construction or other like activities on the Airport. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 88-37, § 7, 5-3-88; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 105, 106, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-8.6'>Abandoned vehicles and equipment removal.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall abandon any vehicle or equipment on the Airport. Either law enforcement officers employed by the County's Police Department or designated Department personnel are authorized to remove or cause the removal, in accordance with applicable state or County regulations, of any abandoned vehicles or equipment to the area of the Airport designated for the impoundment of such by the Department. For the purposes of this section, any vehicle or equipment, except one properly parked in an Airport parking facility, in a parking facility under the control of an Airport tenant of the County, or other area authorized by the Department, which shall have been left unattended upon the Airport for a period of forty-eight (48) hours or more shall be presumed to have been abandoned and may be considered and treated as abandoned.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall park or store a vehicle or equipment in an Airport parking facility, in a parking facility under the control of an Airport tenant of the County, or other area authorized for parking by the Department, which shall have been left unattended or inoperable upon the Airport for a period of sixty (60) days or more without a written permit from the Department or its authorized agent. Vehicles so left unattended shall be presumed to have been abandoned and may be considered and treated as such, in accordance with provisions of subsections 25-8.5 and 25-8.6(a) of this chapter; however, the Department may approve the removal of an abandoned vehicle to a location off the Airport and not require the interim storage of such vehicle in the Airport impoundment area.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Upon the removal of such abandoned vehicle or equipment to the Airport impoundment area the provisions of subsection 25-8.5(b), (c), (d) and (e) of this chapter shall be observed to the extent applicable. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 107, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-8.7'>Certain vehicular traffic prohibited.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall operate any truck, trailer, semitrailer, truck tractor, special mobile equipment, house trailer, dump truck, truck-mounted shovel, crane, transit mixer, or any other vehicle designated for the transportation of property to which machinery has been attached, on any Airport roadway for the purpose of utilizing such roadway as a short-cut thoroughfare between any points outside the boundaries of the Airport, unless otherwise directed by a Police Officer, or pursuant to a written permit issued by the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall operate any vehicle on the Airport contrary to posted load or height limits.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Separate crane clearance authorization is required for all vehicles with a height of fifteen (15) feet or higher operating at any Airport. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 108, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-8.8'>Pedestrians.<section prefix='(a)'>No pedestrian shall cross the upper or lower vehicular drives at the Terminal Building, Miami International Airport, except at marked crosswalks.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No pedestrian shall cross any Airport roadway having marked intersection crosswalks, except at such crosswalks.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No pedestrian shall cross or walk upon any other Airport roadway except in conformance with the applicable provisions of Section 30-221 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida, as it may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Every person operating a vehicle on the Airport roadway shall yield the right-of-way to any pedestrian in a marked pedestrian crosswalk. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 109, 3-7-95)</section></section></section></text></law>