<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='2'>Chapter 25 AVIATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Control of vehicular traffic on the air operations area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003078</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25-9. Control of vehicular traffic on the air operations area.<section prefix='25-9.1'>Governing law. The control of all vehicular traffic on the AOA shall be governed by applicable laws of the state and County, and the rules and regulations prescribed herein as enforced by any designated Department representative or law enforcement officer. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 110, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-9.2'>Authority to operate on the air operations area.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall operate or cause to be operated any motor vehicle on the AOA, unless such operation is required on the AOA and is directly related to an aviation activity on the Airport, the business of the Department, or the business of a tenant, an authorized subtenant or other authorized user of the Airport.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall enter upon the AOA at Miami International Airport other than pursuant to subsection 25-2.20 herein, nor shall any person drive a motor vehicle on the AOA without a motor vehicle identification permit as prescribed by subsection 25-9.7 herein, a valid driver's license as prescribed by subsection 25-9.8 herein, and, unless accompanied by a Departmental escort, or else be in possession of a certificate of completion of the AOA driver training course administered or approved by the Department.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Insurance against personal injury and property damage shall be provided in the amounts required by the Department from time to time for individual Airports. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 111, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.3'>Yielding to aircraft. All motor vehicles on the AOA shall yield the right-of-way to aircraft in motion, under all conditions. This requirement shall include vehicles within designated roadways on the AOA. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 112, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-9.4'>Crossing runways and taxiways.<section prefix='(a)'>No person at an Airport with an operating control tower shall operate a motor vehicle beyond the hold bars of an active runway, or (i) closer than one hundred fifty (150) feet from the edge of an active runway, or (ii) closer to an active taxiway than as may be provided in the specific Operational Directives for the Airport, or as may subsequently be required by regulations, without first having received clearance to proceed from the control tower.</section><section prefix='(b)'>During periods when a control tower is shut down or at Airports without an operations control tower, no person shall operate a motor vehicle beyond the hold bars of an active runway, or closer to an active taxiway stated in the specific Operational Directives for the Airport, or as may subsequently be required by regulations, without first determining that no aircraft are approaching and transmitting his or her intentions on the appropriate common traffic advisory frequency (C.T.A.F.). Movement across said runway or taxiway shall then be made expeditiously. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 113, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.5'>Operations near aircraft. No person, other than the operator of an aircraft servicing vehicle for that aircraft, shall operate a motor vehicle on the AOA at Miami International Airport so as to pass within twenty (20) feet of a parked aircraft, unless traveling on a marked interior service road, or contrary to published vehicle operating procedures, including but not limited to specific routes or zones marked on pavement or regulatory signs. In the case of an aircraft being loaded or unloaded at ground level, on the Terminal Apron no vehicle shall be operated between said aircraft and the Terminal concourses while passengers are enplaning or deplaning. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 114, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-9.6'>Two-way radio requirements. The operator of a motor vehicle requiring clearance to operate on or across an active taxiway or runway at an Airport with an operating control towner shall maintain direct two-way radio contact with the control tower, or in the event a two-way radio is inoperable or unavailable, shall operate said vehicle only under the escort of an authorized motor vehicle equipped with a two-way radio in contact with the control tower. This requirement shall not apply, however, to operators of vehicles authorized by the Department to receive preestablished visual signals from the control tower, or to operators of vehicles following preestablished special procedures of the Department which have been approved by the Federal Aviation Administration. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 115, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-9.7'>Motor vehicle identification permits.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall operate a motor vehicle on the AOA at Miami International Airport without an official motor vehicle identification permit issued pursuant to an Operational Directive of the Department, as defined in subsections 25-9.7(b), (c), and (d), and without company identification conspicuously displayed thereon.</section><section prefix='(b)'>An AOA regular vehicle permit may be issued for each motor vehicle authorized by the Department to operate on the AOA at Miami International Airport on a regular, continuing basis and may be renewed annually or for such longer period as may be determined by the Department. Such permit shall be permanently affixed to the upper center of the windshield, or where there is no windshield, to the driver's side of the vehicle or to such other place on the vehicle as designated by the Department. The driver of a vehicle for which an AOA regular vehicle permit has been issued shall at all times comply with the terms of the permit as established by the Department, which terms shall include the requirement that an AOA driver's certificate be obtained from the Department as a condition of entry on the AOA by such driver, in accordance with Section 25-9.2(b) of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>An AOA temporary vehicle permit may be issued for temporary, or limited access for each motor vehicle used on the AOA at Miami International Airport for prime contractors and others engaged in construction or other activities for or approved by the Department. This permit shall be conspicuously displayed on the motor vehicle to which it is issued. Unless operating within a designated construction area, any motor vehicle bearing such permit shall, at all times while on the AOA, be under escort by an authorized escort vehicle, unless otherwise authorized by the Department.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An AOA temporary vehicle permit may be issued for a limited area and time for motor vehicles which require occasional or "one-time" access to a specific location on the AOA at Miami International Airport to make authorized pick-ups or deliveries. This permit shall be issued at the discretion of the Department and shall be obtained only at Department-controlled AOA gates to AOA upon clearance by an Airport tenant or by other authorized personnel, and is valid only for the length of time indicated thereon. It shall be returned to an access gate at or prior to the expiration of the allotted time. This permit shall be conspicuously displayed on the motor vehicle to which it is issued. Any motor vehicle bearing such permit shall, at all times while on the AOA, be under escort, unless otherwise authorized by the Director.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All motor vehicle identification permits shall remain the property of the Department, and are not transferable. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 116, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.8'>Driver's license. No person shall drive a motor vehicle on the AOA, unless such individual carries on his person at all times a currently valid operator's license for the type vehicle being operated, issued in accordance with federal law or statutes of the State of Florida; provided however, that the Department may require by Operational Directive that operators of specific types and classes of equipment operated on the AOA must obtain operator's licenses for the type of vehicle involved, even though operator's licenses may not then be required for such type of vehicle by state or federal laws. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 117, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-9.9'>Designated vehicular routes. No person shall operate a motor vehicle on the air operations area, except operators of emergency vehicles proceeding in response to an alarm or Department vehicles in the performance of individual duties, unless such person operates on established vehicular routes only. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-9.10'>Speed limits and traffic control.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall operate any motor vehicle, other than an emergency vehicle proceeding in response to an alarm, on the air operations area at a speed in excess of twenty (20) miles per hour, except as otherwise posted.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall operate any motor vehicle on the air operations area (including the service drives within the Terminal Building at Miami International Airport) in violation of any traffic-control device. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.11'>Reckless driving. No person shall operate a motor vehicle on the air operations area in a reckless manner, so as to indicate a willful or wanton disregard for the safety of persons or property. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-9.12'>Careless driving. No person shall operate a motor vehicle on the air operations area in a careless manner, which is other than in a careful and prudent manner, having regard for the width, grade, curves, corners, traffic and use of roadways, weather conditions and all other attendant circumstances, so as not to endanger the life, limb or property of any person. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-9.13'>Vehicle and equipment condition and safety requirements. No person shall operate a motor vehicle or equipment on the AOA unless such vehicle or equipment is in good operating condition and repair for a unit of its type and is equipped with at least the following safety equipment in fully operable condition:<section prefix='(a)'>Motor vehicle lights:<section prefix='(1)'>All motor vehicles operated on the AOA, except motor vehicles designed for only one (1) headlight and except tow tugs and other specialized ramp equipment designed with only taillights, shall be equipped with two (2) headlights and one or more red taillights and brake lights.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All headlights and taillights shall be kept lighted between the hours of sunset and sunrise and at all times when passing through unlighted or poorly lighted areas.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any motor vehicle, other than emergency vehicles, operating on runways or taxiways of the AOA shall display an amber overhead flashing or rotating light at all times while so operating; provided, however that between the hours of sunrise and sunset a motor vehicle not so equipped may so operate if such vehicle displays a checkered flag approved by the Department. The use of red or blue flashing or rotating lights shall be limited to emergency vehicles only.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All motor vehicle lights shall be of sufficient brilliance to assure their capability of being seen, but not so as to temporarily blind others.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All baggage and cargo carts shall be equipped with reflectors or fluorescent tape material, two (2) each on the front, the rear and both sides of the cart. The reflectors shall be standard truck types. If fluorescent tape is used, each piece shall have a reflective surface of not less than fourteen (14) square inches. Reflectors or tape on the front and front sides shall be amber and on the rear and rear sides shall be red.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Motor vehicle brakes:<section prefix='(1)'>All motor vehicles operating on the AOA shall be equipped with a properly functioning braking system, suitable for the specific type of equipment being operated.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The operator of a motor vehicle on the AOA shall test the brakes of such vehicle upon approaching an aircraft within such distance as necessary to avoid a collision with such aircraft in the event of brake failure.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Motor vehicle windows and mirrors:<section prefix='(1)'>Every motor vehicle operating on the AOA shall be equipped with at least one mirror, so adjusted that the operator of such vehicle shall have a clear view of the road behind for a distance of at least two hundred (200) feet. Exceptions to this requirement are to be requested through the Director, and if justified, authorization will be granted on an individual basis.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The windshields and other windows of a motor vehicle operating on the AOA shall be free of cracks, blisters, discoloration or any other defect causing distortion or obstruction of the vision of the operator thereof.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The use or placing of posters, stickers, signs or other objects on the windshield or other windows of a motor vehicle operating on the AOA, other than those required by the Department or by law, is prohibited.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The vision of the operator of a motor vehicle on the AOA shall not be obstructed by an extended superstructure or load. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 118—120, 3-7-95)</section></section></section><section prefix='25-9.14'>Emergency vehicles. Upon the approach of a Police, ambulance, Fire Department, or other emergency vehicle giving an audible or visual signal, each person operating another motor vehicle on the AOA shall immediately yield the right-of-way to such vehicle, until the emergency vehicle has stopped or passed, unless otherwise directed by an Airport law enforcement officer. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 121, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-9.15'>Occupants of motor vehicles. No person shall, while on the Airport, ride on the running board of a moving motor vehicle, stand up in the body of a moving motor vehicle, ride on the outside of the body of a moving motor vehicle, or ride on such a vehicle with his arms or legs protruding from the body of the vehicle, unless required to do so in the performance of his duties. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-9.16'>Tugs and trailers.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall operate a tug, trailer, or other motor vehicle, on the AOA, towing a train of baggage or cargo carts in excess of five (5) carts or sixty (60) feet long, unless specifically authorized in writing by the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall operate a baggage cart, container dolly, semi-trailer or any other type of trailer on the AOA unless it is equipped with proper brakes so that when disengaged from a towing vehicle, propeller slipstreams, jet blasts, or wind will not cause it to come free-rolling.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall tow any equipment unless such equipment has engaged positive locking couplings.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall store any tugs, cargo and baggage carts on the AOA, when not in use, except in storage areas designated by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 122, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.17'>Traffic control. Any person operating a motor vehicle on the AOA shall obey all posted regulatory signs, special signs, pavement markings and traffic signals, and all instructions by the control tower, a designated Department employee, or a law enforcement officer. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 123, 3-7-95)</section><section prefix='25-9.18'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall park any motor vehicle or motorized or other equipment on the AOA in areas other than those designated or authorized by the Department, nor in any manner contrary to any posted regulatory signs, traffic-control devices or pavement markings.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall park a motor vehicle or motorized or other equipment on the AOA as to interfere with the use of a facility by others or prevent the passage or movement of aircraft, emergency vehicles or other motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall park a motor vehicle or motorized or other equipment on the AOA in such a manner as to interfere with or prevent an aircraft fueling vehicle from being readily driven away from such aircraft in the event of an emergency. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 124, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.19'>Motor vehicle accidents.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person operating a motor vehicle on the AOA which is involved in an accident resulting in injury to any person or damage to any property, shall<section prefix='(1)'>Immediately stop such vehicle at the scene of such accident or as close thereto as possible,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notify the Metro-Dade Police Department and an authorized representative of the Department, and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Then return to and remain at the scene of the accident until he has fulfilled the requirements of subsection 25-9.19(b). The vehicle shall be stopped and parked during these events so as to minimize any obstructions to aircraft and other vehicles.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person operating a motor vehicle on the AOA which is involved in an accident, as defined in subsection 25-9.19(a) and the owner of such vehicle, if other than the operator thereof, shall make a full report of such accident to the Metro Dade Police Department, and to an authorized representative of the Department as soon after the accident as possible, including the names and addresses of the individuals involved, the registration and license number of the vehicle or vehicles involved, and such other information relevant to the accident on request of any law enforcement officer investigating the same; and the operator of any such motor vehicle involved in such accident shall, upon request, exhibit such licenses, registration or other documents relevant to such accident or the persons or property involved to any law enforcement officer investigating the same.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In the event a law enforcement officer investigating an accident pursuant to subsection 25-9.19(b) has reason to believe that a mechanical failure in a vehicle or equipment involved in accident was or may have contributed to the cause of such accident, said law enforcement officer may impound such vehicle or equipment until such time that a mechanical failure can be ruled out as causing or contributing to the cause of the accident. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, §§ 125, 126, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.20'>Service and repair of motor vehicles.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall service, clean, repair, maintain, or overhaul any motor vehicle or motorized or other equipment on the AOA except for immediate minimum repairs required to remove said vehicle from AOA because of a breakdown, or as otherwise approved or authorized by lease or Operational Directive of the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall fuel a motor vehicle or motorized equipment on the AOA in any areas other than those established by the Department, or contrary to any procedures which are established by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 127, 3-7-95)</section></section><section prefix='25-9.21'>Tampering with motor vehicles. No person shall move, interfere with, or tamper with any motor vehicle, or put into operation the engine of any motor vehicle, or take or use any motor vehicle part, instrument or tool, without the authorization of the owner. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75)</section><section prefix='25-9.22'>Contractor's access and operations on the air operations area.<section prefix='(a)'>Access to and egress from the site of construction located on the AOA by motor vehicles, cranes and other equipment belonging to or under the supervision of an Airport contractor shall be gained only via routes, through gates, and at such times as may be established or approved by the Department. Request for access to such sites shall be made to the Department a minimum of twenty-four (24) hours in advance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Construction equipment shall be operated and stored within the AOA, in accordance with procedures established or approved by the Department. (Ord. No. 75-113, § 2, 12-2-75; Ord. No. 95-41, § 128, 3-7-95)</section></section></section></text></law>