<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='2'>Chapter 25A PUBLIC HEALTH TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25A-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Designated facilities and transfer of property in trust.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003081</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25A-2. Designated facilities and transfer of property in trust.<section prefix='(a)'>Designated facilities. The Trust, acting through its governing body as hereinafter defined, shall be responsible for the operation, maintenance and governance of the following facilities which are hereby declared to be "designated facilities" as that term is defined and used in Chapter 73-102, Laws of Florida 1973:<section>Jackson Memorial Hospital and all related facilities and real and personal property used in connection therewith either presently existing or which may come into existence in which Miami-Dade County has a legal interest and which are located within the area bounded by NW 15 Avenue on the west, NW 20 Street on the north, NW 7 Avenue on the east, and NW 14 Street on the south; and all facilities and real and personal property which the Trust may acquire pursuant to the terms of this chapter.</section></section><section>By resolution, the Board of County Commissioners may designate additional facilities or declassify and remove from the jurisdiction of the Trust facilities which have previously been designated.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Transfer of property in trust. Pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, the Trust shall have possession and operating control of, but not title to, all real property within the meaning of "designated facilities," as that term is defined by this chapter. Title to all items of personal property within the meaning of "designated facilities," as that term is defined by this chapter, shall be transferred to the Trust to be held in trust pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, provided however, that the Trust shall be empowered to sell or otherwise lawfully dispose of such personal property.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-69, ยง 2, 7-30-73; Ord. No. 91-63, ยง 1, 6-18-91)</history></law>