<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='2'>Chapter 25A PUBLIC HEALTH TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25A-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Supporting services.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003085</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25A-6. Supporting services.<section>Excepts as otherwise provided by this chapter, the Trust shall be authorized to develop and implement the supporting services systems necessary for carrying out the Trust's responsibilities. Such supporting systems shall include but shall not be limited to budgeting and accounting, liability coverage, quality assurance and utilization management, risk management functions related to care and safety of patients and all others within designated facilities, printing, delinquent account collections, information and computer services, architectural design and construction support services, security, physical maintenance, purchasing and materials management, and legal services. Supporting services may also be purchased from individuals or organizations or obtained from the County in a manner consistent with the method of County funding of the Trust. Before obtaining any supporting services from a source other than Miami-Dade County, the Trust shall determine the availability, cost advantage, and management advantage of obtaining such services from the County on a fee-for-service basis.<section prefix='(a)'>Purchasing and materials management. The Trust shall develop procedures for purchasing supplies, equipment and services and for managing materials and shall implement such procedures.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Security and legal services. From the effective date of this chapter, the Trust shall continue to utilize the services of the County with regard to security and legal services.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-69, ยง 6, 7-30-73; Ord. No. 91-63, ยง 1, 6-18-91)</history></law>