<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='2'>Chapter 25A PUBLIC HEALTH TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25A-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties of the Trust.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003083</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25A-4. Powers and duties of the Trust.<section>In connection with its responsibilities for the operation, maintenance, and governance of designated facilities, the Trust, acting through its governing body, shall be authorized to exercise such powers and shall be required to perform such duties as are hereinafter provided.<section prefix='(a)'>Power to act. The Trust shall be empowered to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to contract and be contracted with, and to have an official seal and alter the same. This provision shall not be construed to in any way affect the laws relating to governmental immunity.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Health care delivery policies.<section prefix='(1)'>Planning for designated facilities. The Trust shall annually develop and recommend to the County Commission policies for the admission of hospital patients, the determination of the indigent status of patients and health care delivery in the designated facilities of the Trust, including primary, secondary and tertiary health care. The Trust shall also develop and recommend to the County Commission long range plans in five-year intervals for the delivery of health care services in designated facilities of the Trust.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Countywide planning. The Trust shall have no responsibility for countywide healthcare planning and such planning shall be the responsibility and within the jurisdiction of the Miami-Dade County Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning, provided however that the operation, maintenance and governance of and planning for the Trust designated facilities wherever situated within Miami-Dade County shall be and remain the sole responsibility of the Trust, subject to the Board of County Commissioners' power to designate additional facilities or to declassify and remove from the jurisdiction of the Trust facilities which have previously been designated.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Submittal of planning recommendations for designated facilities. The Trust shall formally present its annual recommendations for health care delivery in its designated facilities at an annual, joint meeting to be called by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners and to be held between the Commission and the Trust no later than July 1st of each year.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Compliance. The Trust shall comply with the health care policies established by the Board of County Commissioners. When the Commission establishes or changes policies relating to hospital admissions or medical indigency, it shall,in order to avoid the promulgation of unfunded mandates, through the County Manager and Chief Executive Officer of the Trust, identify in consultation with the Trust, an appropriate source of funding necessary to carry out such policies.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Contracts. Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, the Trust, as an agent and instrumentality of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be authorized to act for Miami-Dade County in the performance and enforcement of all contracts pertaining to designated facilities and existing on the effective date of this chapter, such contracts as are properly within the powers and duties of the Trust.<section>The contractual powers of the Trust shall be subject to the following limitations:</section><section prefix='(1)'>The Trust shall not, without the prior approval of the Board of County Commissioners, enter into or amend any contract which shall require the expenditure of funds in excess of the amounts appropriate in the contractual services category of the section of the County budget pertaining to the operation of the Trust.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Trust shall not, without prior approval of the County Commission, enter into or alter any contract the effect of which is to change the contractual relationship between Miami-Dade County and the University of Miami as set forth in the contract between the University and the County entered into on December 18, 1952, and as amended from time to time. The original Basic Affiliation Agreement between the Trust and Florida International University shall be ratified by the Board of County Commissioners. Subsequent to ratification, the Trust shall not, without prior approval of the County Commission, enter into or alter any contract the effect of which is to change the contractual relationship with Florida International University as set forth in the Basic Affiliation Agreement and as amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Trust shall not, without prior approval of the County Commission, enter into or alter any contract the effect of which is to change substantially health care delivery policies established by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Trust shall not be authorized to enter into a contract with any labor union or other organization representing employees without first having obtained the approval of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>It is specifically provided that contracts and amendments thereto executed by the Trust, or other obligations incurred by the Trust, shall not be binding upon Miami-Dade County. In the event that the Trust shall be revoked, obligations of the Trust shall only be enforceable against Miami-Dade County to the extent that such obligations would have been enforceable with regard to personal property which was in the possession of the Trust and with regard to business income which would have come into the possession of the Trust had the Trust not been revoked.</section><section>The Trust shall comply with the formal bid requirements of(D) of the Charter of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and for such purpose the term "Board" as used in(D) shall be construed to be "Board of Trustees" and the term "manager" shall be construed to be "Chief Executive Officer of the Trust."</section><section>For all competitively bid contracts in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) for the construction, alteration, and/or repair, including painting or decorating of "designated facilities" that are public buildings or public works, the Trust shall comply with the provisions of of the Code, as same may be amended from time to time, and the administrative procedures adopted pursuant thereto.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Property. The Trust shall have the authority to purchase or otherwise obtain title in its own name to personal property and shall be authorized to sell or otherwise lawfully dispose of personal property. The Trust shall subject to prior approval of the County Commission be authorized to purchase or otherwise obtain real property, the title to which shall be vested in Miami-Dade County and the possession and operating control of which shall be held in Trust for Miami-Dade County under the provisions of this chapter.<section>The Trust shall not be authorized to sell, convey, mortgage, or otherwise impair or encumber the title to real property, provided however, that the Trust shall be authorized to lease real property either as lessee or lessor for any number of years and upon any terms and conditions. The leasing of any real property by the Trust as lessor shall be in accordance with the requirements of Section 125.35, Florida Statutes.</section><section>The Trust shall not, without having previously obtained the approval of the Commission, destroy, replace, or abandon real property. The Trust shall be authorized to maintain and repair designated facilities and may alter, modify, or made additions to designated facilities whenever such changes are necessary for the proper operation and maintenance of such facilities.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Personnel. The Trust shall be empowered to appoint, remove, and suspend employees or agents of the Trust, to fix their compensation, and to adopt personnel and management policies, subject to Board of County Commissioners approval or disapproval. Absent any action by the Board of County Commissioners, personnel and management policies established by the Board of Trustees shall be considered final. Employees who were initially County employees and reclassified as Trust employees as the result of the original enactment of Chapter 25A shall be entitled to continue their participation in either the State and County Officers and Employees Retirement System or the Florida Retirement System or both such retirement systems. The Trust shall assure employees a process of appeal with regard to disciplinary or other official action.<section prefix='[(1)'>Reserved.]</section><section prefix='(2)'>Labor agreements. The County Labor Relations Office and the County Personnel Department shall be permitted to participate in the negotiation of labor agreements with organizations representing Trust employees, however, the Board of Trustees and the management of designated facilities shall be authorized to assume the primary role in such negotiations.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Classified service of the Public Health Trust; exceptions therefrom. The classified service of the Trust shall comprise all positions in the Trust service existing on May 1, 1975, or thereafter established, except the following:<section prefix='(a)'>President, Senior Vice-Presidents, Division Directors, Administrative Director of Patient Care Services and their immediate assistants, and all secretaries to the foregoing.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Patients employed in designated facilities.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Persons employed in a professional or scientific capacity to make or conduct a temporary and specific inquiry, investigation or examination on behalf of or by the authority of the Trust.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Trust attorneys and assistants.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Persons who are jointly employed by the Trust and any institute of higher learning.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Residents, interns and students in designated facilities.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Employees of those programs or parts thereof which are supported or funded from federal, charitable or foundation sources and which are designated by resolution of the Board of Trustees on the recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer of the Trust.</section><section>Employment within the classified service category shall be based on standards and qualifications approved by appropriate Trust staff and the Chief Executive Officer of the Trust.</section></section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Appointment of medical staff and approval of bylaws. The Trust shall appoint the staff of physicians to practice in designated facilities and shall require that the bylaws, rules, and regulations of the medical staff of such facilities be submitted to the Board of Trustees for approval. Such bylaws, rules, and regulations shall be in accordance with the standards of all relevant accrediting organizations.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Rates and charges. The Trust, in compliance with applicable law, shall be empowered to establish rates and charges for those persons using the facilities of or receiving care or assistance from the Trust and to collect money pursuant to such rates and charges. Rates and charges shall be based upon the following factors: Costs of services and supplies rendered, the prevailing rates and charges of health care facilities in the community, the goal of minimizing the dependence upon tax revenues and maximizing the availability of health care provided by designated Trust facilities.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Acceptance of gifts. The Trust shall have the authority to accept gifts of money, services, or personal property. All such gifts may be subject to such rules, conditions and terms as the Trust may determine. Subject to the prior approval of the Commission, the Trust may accept gifts of real property, the title of which shall be in Miami-Dade County. All gifts shall be held in trust pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.<section>When accepting gifts of services and personal property that are "in kind," including for construction projects and related architectural, engineering, design and landscaping services, the Trust shall be exempt from all competitive bidding requirements and other programs otherwise mandated by the Code of Miami-Dade County for Public Health Trust contracts, provided additional costs, if any, are funded by a not-for-profit organization whose primary purpose is to support the activities of the Trust. An "in kind" donation is one in which the donor itself, or through an entity controlled by the donor, provides the personal property or performs the services.</section><section>In addition, in order to attract private funding for construction projects that are not in kind and that the Trust would either not otherwise undertake or would have to postpone, the Trust may accept from a not-for-profit organization whose primary purpose is to support the activities of the Trust gifts of construction projects, including the building, renovating, retrofitting, restoration, painting, altering or repairing of any Trust facility, and all services and personal property related to such construction projects, provided that each donation of such a construction project shall not exceed five million dollars ($5,000,000) and is fully funded by such not-for-profit organization. All gifts of such construction projects shall be exempt from all competitive bidding requirements and other programs otherwise mandated by the Code of Miami-Dade County for Public Health Trust contracts, provided that the not-for-profit and the contractors on the construction project agree to be bound by public records law to the same extent as a Trust contractor providing such personal property or services. The not-for-profit organization shall file a report with the Public Health Trust and Board of County Commissioners every six (6) months documenting its activities pursuant to this paragraph.</section><section>The Trust by rule or contract shall implement procedures to comply with state law requirements mandating competitive bidding for construction projects and assure that donations of specific construction projects meet all lawful requirements and Trust standards of responsibility.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Intergovernmental cooperation. The Trust shall have the authority to cooperate with and contract with any government agency or instrumentality, federal, state, county, or municipal. The operating relationship between the Trust and Miami-Dade County shall be set forth in an annual agreement the purpose of which shall be to implement applicable provisions of this chapter. The Chief Executive Officer of the Trust and the County Manager shall meet for the purpose of negotiating an annual operating agreement. Such negotiating shall take place prior to September 1 of each year so that the Board of Trustees and Board of County Commissioners may approve the agreement in September of the applicable year.<section>There shall be a Trust/Miami-Dade County Annual Operating Agreement Committee (the "Trust/County Committee"). The Trust's Chief Executive Officer shall submit his recommendations regarding the Annual Operating Agreement between the Trust and the County to the Trust/County Committee for its review and approval. The Trust/County Committee shall make recommendations regarding the Annual Operating Agreement to the Board of Trustees. The Trust/County Committee shall consist of seven (7) voting members including the Chairperson of the Public Health Trust, the Chief Executive Officer of the Public Health Trust, three (3) Trustees appointed by the Chairperson of the Public Health Trust, the Mayor, and the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners. The County Manager shall simultaneously submit the agreement to the Commission for its approval.</section></section><section prefix='(j)'>Compliance with law and Commission directives. The Trust shall comply with all laws and regulations of the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County, including but not limited to the laws relating to the expenditure of funds and the keeping of records and inventories and the operation and governance of health care facilities. The Trust shall also comply with any Commission directive to the Trust, as set forth from time to time by resolution of the Commission. A resolution adopting a directive that undoes or modifies action of the Board of Trustees or any of its committees shall require an affirmative vote of two-thirds () of those Commissioners then in office.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Establishment of alternative health care delivery systems. The Trust shall be empowered to establish, participate in and/or contract with alternative health care delivery systems, including but not limited to prepaid health care plans.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Funding and support of primary health care facilities. The trust shall establish criteria and standards for the provision of financial and programmatic support of primary health care facilities operating within Miami-Dade County. The trust shall also formulate criteria and standards for the establishment of new primary health care facilities within the County.<section prefix='(1)'>Any funding allocated to the primary health care facilities complying with the established criteria and standards shall be allocated regardless of whether the trust owns or controls the facilities.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any funding by the trust for the purpose of capital expenditures shall be allocated from the trust's Funded Depreciation Account. Any funding by the trust for the purpose of operating expenditures shall be allocated from the trust's general operating funds.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any primary health care facility which does not comply with the criteria and standards established by the trust shall not be eligible for any funding from the trust or Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section prefix='(m)'>Office of Internal Auditor, Public Accountability and Information. The Trust shall create an Office of Internal Auditor, Public Accountability and Information ("Office of Internal Audit"). The purpose of the Office of Internal Audit shall be to (i) provide internal auditing functions, (ii) act as the central depository for public information relating to public record requests, (iii) review and account for any and all relationships between the Public Health Trust and private entities, and (iv) interface and coordinate with and serve as the Trust's liaison to the Miami-Dade County Office of Inspector General. The Office of Internal Audit shall report directly to the Chairperson of the Trust. This Office through the Chief Executive Officer shall make monthly written reports to the Board of Trustees at its regular meetings. The written reports shall also be disseminated to the Mayor, Board of County Commissioners, County Manager, the Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning, the Commission Auditor, and Miami-Dade Office of Inspector General. The Chief Executive Officer of the Trust shall develop written policies and procedures for the organization and operation of the Office of Internal Audit and submit the same to the Board of Trustees for approval. Upon the Trust's creation of the Office of Internal Audit, the Trust shall do all things necessary or required to effectuate and merge all existing internal auditing functions into this Office and to provide sufficient funding and staffing.</section></section><section prefix='(n)'>Trust Funding of Service Providers that are Foundations and Non-Profit Entities. Except as otherwise provided by this Chapter, the Trust shall not pay or provide funding to foundations or non-profit entities unless such funding is provided or paid based on a cost reimbursement methodology. The contract between the Trust and the foundation or non-profit service provider shall obligate the foundation or non-profit to receive funding on the basis of cost reimbursement methodology, including proper submission of documentation to support reimbursement and appropriate use of public funds and further obligate the foundation or non-profit entity to segregate all funds received from the Trust to ensure that the funds at no time are commingled with the funds of the foundation or non-profit entity. Without limiting any other provisions of the Code, the Miami-Dade Office of Inspector General and the County shall at all times be empowered to conduct audits of any contract between the Trust and foundations or non-profit entities. The Trust shall submit quarterly reports to the Commission committee of jurisdiction for the Trust regarding the funds reimbursed as provided in this section. Such quarterly reports shall include, but not limited to, the amount of expenditures reimbursed by the Trust for each foundation or non-profit entity for each month of the quarter reported, the categories of expenditures reimbursed, the balance of funding remaining under the contract, and such other matters as directed by the Chairperson of the Commission committee of jurisdiction to be included in the quarterly report.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-69, § 4, 7-30-73; Ord. No. 75-103, § 1, 11-4-75; Ord. No. 77-84, § 1, 11-15-77; Ord. No. 82-67, § 3, 7-20-82; Ord. No. 84-65, § 2, 7-17-84; Ord. No. 85-67, § 1, 9-18-85; Ord. No. 89-90, § 1, 9-26-89; Ord. No. 91-63, § 1, 6-18-91; Ord. No. 92-45, § 6(b), 6-2-92; Ord. No. 92-76, § 1, 7-21-92; Ord. No. 93-41, § 1, 5-18-93; Ord. No. 94-197, § 1, 11-1-94; Ord. No. 94-210, § 1, 11-15-94; Ord. No. 95-151, § 1, 9-14-95; Ord. No. 98-40, § 1, 3-31-98; Ord. No. 03-182, § 4, 9-9-03; Ord. No. 07-166, § 1, 11-6-07; Ord. No. 10-28, § 1, 5-4-10; Ord. No. 10-54, § 3, 9-21-10; Ord. No. 11-29, § 2, 5-3-11; Ord. No. 11-40, § 2, 7-7-11; Ord. No. 11-43, § 1, 7-7-11)</history></law>