<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='2'>Chapter 25A PUBLIC HEALTH TRUST</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25A-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Financial support for the Public Health Trust.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003084</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25A-5. Financial support for the Public Health Trust.<section>The Trust shall establish a fiscal year which coincides with that of Miami-Dade County, and the County shall provide the Trust with financial support pursuant to the official County budget. The Trust shall timely submit to the Board of County Commissioners a Trust budget request pertaining to operating and capital expenditures, which request shall not be implemented until approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of Trustees shall consider and approve its budget request at special meeting of the Board of Trustees to be held in the Commission Chambers. At the special meeting, the only item to be considered shall be the Trust budget request contemplated by this section to be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners. At such special meeting, the Board of Trustees shall hold a public hearing on its budget request. The Board of Trustees shall adopt the budget request by a majority vote of the full Board of Trustees.</section><section>The Trust budget request shall be prepared on official County budget forms in a format prescribed by the County Manager, shall be reviewed in a manner similar to that in which requests of other County departments are reviewed, and shall be incorporated in the proposed budget and timely submitted to the Commission each year. The methods by which Miami-Dade County shall provide financial support to the Trust shall be as hereinafter described. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to prohibit the Trust from submitting to the Commission supplemental budget results which, if approved by the Commission, shall constitute amendments to the official County budget.<section prefix='(a)'>Funding. The Trust shall develop for each fiscal year accounting, budgeting, and financial management systems which will enable Miami-Dade County to provide the Trust, pursuant to the official County budget, with funding to be utilized for the cost of services and supplies provided to medically indigent persons as defined in the annual operating agreement between the Trust and Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Spending of bond proceeds, issuance of new bonds, and borrowing of money. The Trust shall not be empowered to make expenditures of any monies derived from the sale of bonds by Miami-Dade County unless the Trust shall have been specifically authorized by the Board of County Commissioners to make such expenditures. The Trust shall be permitted to request the County Commission to effectuate the issuance of bonds, and to permit the Trust to borrow money by submitting to the Commission a duly enacted resolution of the Board of Trustees. The Commission shall consider any such resolution requesting the issuance of bonds or for the Trust to borrow money, however, the Commission shall be under no obligation to take affirmative action upon such requests.</section><section prefix='(c)'>General financial provisions. The County shall convey to the Trust all accounts receivable pertaining to the designated facilities, and the Trust shall be subject to, assume the liability for, and be authorized to pay all accounts payable pertaining to the designated facilities. The Trust shall have the authority to establish necessary banking accounts in its own name and to make cash disbursements. The Trust shall make an annual report and an audited accounting to Miami-Dade County for all receipts and disbursements of money during each fiscal year, which accounting shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners no later than ninety (90) days subsequent to the close of such fiscal year and which accounting shall be in a manner consistent with and in a format pursuant to that prescribed by the County Manager.<section>Upon request, the Trust shall within thirty (30) days submit to the Board of County Commissioners a full financial report, including but not limited to, operating statistics such as admissions, occupancy rate, revenue and expenses, and a narrative outlining the achievements and problems, if any, of the Trust during the preceding quarter. On a quarterly basis, the Trust through its Chief Financial Officer or designee shall collect and provide to the Board of County Commissioners for its analysis and approval specific patient and health service data elements including, but not limited to, data regarding (i) number of patients served, (ii) patient demographics and patient origin/zip code information, (iii) patient diagnosis, (iv) services rendered, (v) patient charges by service category, (vi) lengths of stay and patient visits, (vii) payment source, (viii) site of service and (ix) such other data elements requested by the Commission or agreed upon by the Trust and the Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning.</section><section>Prior to March 31st of each year, the Trust shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners via a special meeting of the Board of County Commissioners in chambers a report to the Board of County Commissioners and the public that reflects the results of its annual audit for the prior fiscal year performed by the Trust's external auditor. At least seven (7) days prior to the special meeting, the Trust shall hand deliver copies of the audit by the Trust's external auditor to the Mayor, Chairperson and members of the Board of County Commissioners, the County Manager, Office of Countywide Healthcare Planning and Office of Inspector General.</section><section>The Internal Auditor of Miami-Dade County shall at all times have the right to audit all records of the Trust, and the external auditor of the County, at the direction of the Board of County Commissioners, shall be empowered to audit all records of the Trust.</section><section>The Board of County Commissioners shall, after examining the Trust's annual report and accounting, determine whether there is net income, exclusive of County payments for services rendered, at the end of the fiscal year. The Board of County Commissioners may then appropriate such net income into the County's general revenues or leave such net income with the Trust for continued use in effecting the public purposes of the Trust; provided, however, in the event the Commissioners decide to leave such income with the Trust, the Commissioners shall still retain the right to withdraw such income at any future time.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-69, § 5, 7-30-73; Ord. No. 78-54, § 1, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 91-63, § 1, 6-18-91; Ord. No. 98-40, § 1, 3-31-98; Ord. No. 03-182, § 4, 9-9-03; Ord. No. 11-29, § 3, 5-3-11)</history></law>