<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00049' order_by='00049' level='2'>Chapter 25B PARKS AND RECREATION GENERALLY</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. STANDARDS FOR ACCEPTANCE OF CONVEYANCES USED FOR SCENIC OUTDOOR RECREATIONAL OR PARK PURPOSES OR COVENANTS NOT TO USE LAND FOR OTHER THAN SUCH PURPOSES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25B-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Provisions of conveyance of development right or covenant.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003092</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25B-13. Provisions of conveyance of development right or covenant.<section>The conveyance of the development right or covenant shall expressly provide the following:<section prefix='(a)'>That the County through its authorized agents shall have the right, upon written notification to the owner, to inspect the premises at a reasonable time to determine whether the land is being used or maintained in the manner promised by the owner and as permitted by this article. Where a determination is made by the County after such inspection that some curative action on the land is necessary in order to preserve the terms of the covenant or conveyance, the County shall notify the owner in writing by certified mail, return receipt requested, of the particular curative action to be taken and the reasons therefor. The owner shall have the right to appeal such proposed action to the Board by filing a written objection with the Clerk of the Board within thirty (30) days after receipt of the written notification of proposed curative action and reasons therefor.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That land used for outdoor recreational or park purposes under this article shall be open to the general public.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That the owner shall indemnify and hold Miami-Dade County harmless from any and all liability or claims arising out of the public access to the land permitted by the above subsection (b).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-33, ยง 3, 5-21-75; Ord. No. 79-105, ยง 1, 12-4-79)</history></law>