<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00049' order_by='00049' level='2'>Chapter 25B PARKS AND RECREATION GENERALLY</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SAFE NEIGHBORHOOD PARKS ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25B-21</section_number>
<catch_line>Definition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003100</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25B-21. Definition.<section>As used in this article, the following terms mean:</section><section>means all direct expenses incurred in administering the development and completion of any of the projects authorized and approved under the terms of this article. Administrative costs shall not include those administrative expenses incurred in the everyday operation of any not-for-profit organization and public agency, which administer a project funded pursuant to this article.</section><section>means beaches open to use by all of the residents of the County.</section><section>means those funds raised, primarily through ad valorem taxes, fees and transfers, that are used to account for the general operations of the County or municipal governments and all transactions which are not accounted for in other funds or account groups.</section><section>means an environmentally sensitive area usually containing a natural forest community, freshwater or coastal wetland and managed to maintain and enhance biological values.</section><section>means any legally incorporated not-for-profit organization created under the laws of the State of Florida (the "State") and designated as a tax exempt entity by the United States Internal Revenue Service, which has among its purposes the provision of park and recreation services, gang prevention and intervention, tree-planting, or the conservation and preservation of lands for park, natural areas, scenic, historic, or open spaces.</section><section>mean those areas of public land set aside for aesthetic, educational, recreational, or cultural use by the citizens of the County.</section><section>means the Miami-Dade County Park and Recreation Department.</section><section>means an agency or agencies or administrative division or divisions of the United States government, the State of Florida, the County, or any municipality within the County.</section><section>mean those facilities that are managed by a public agency or agencies that focus their programming on cultural, historical, educational and recreational activities.</section><section>means a park owned or operated by the Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Division of Recreation and Parks.</section><section>means the separate interest bearing account into which proceeds of the bond program, as outlined in this article, shall be deposited.</section><section>means Unincorporated Municipal Service area of the County, for which the County provides municipal services.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-115, ยง 2, 7-16-96)</history></law>