<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00049' order_by='00049' level='2'>Chapter 25B PARKS AND RECREATION GENERALLY</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. STANDARDS FOR ACCEPTANCE OF CONVEYANCES USED FOR SCENIC OUTDOOR RECREATIONAL OR PARK PURPOSES OR COVENANTS NOT TO USE LAND FOR OTHER THAN SUCH PURPOSES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25B-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003097</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25B-18. Definitions.<section>The following terms whenever used in this article shall have the following meanings unless a different meaning is clearly indicated by the context:<section prefix='(a)'>Outdoor recreational or park purposes includes, but is not necessarily limited to, boating, golfing, swimming, horseback riding, and historical or scenic sites, and applies only to land which is open to the general public.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Qualified as environmentally endangered means land which has unique ecological characteristics, rare or limited combinations of geological formations, or features of a rare or limited nature constituting a habitat suitable for fish, plants, or wildlife, and which, if subject to development or conservation restrictions, would be consistent with the conservation, recreation, open space, and, if applicable, coastal protection elements of the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan; archaeological or scientific sites of lands subject to regulation by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Regulation or by the United States Army Corps of Engineers and defined as submerged lands by said respective agency. Examples of land qualified as environmentally endangered under this section are vegetative areas containing mangrove forests, hammock and tree islands, pinelands, wetlands, and native cypress forests.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Development right is the right of the owner of the fee interest in the land to change the use of the land.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Conservation restriction means a limitation on a right to the use of land, for purposes of conserving or preserving land or water areas predominantly in their natural, scenic, open or wooded condition, retaining such areas as suitable habitat for fish, plants or wildlife, or maintaining existing land uses by prohibiting or limiting:<section prefix='(1)'>Construction or placing of buildings, roads, signs, billboards or other advertising, utilities, or other structures on or above the ground.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Dumping or placing of soil or other substance or material such as landfill, trash, waste, or unsightly or offensive materials.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Planting, removal or destruction of trees, shrubs or other vegetation.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Excavation, dredging, or removal of loam, peat, gravel, soil, rock or other material substance in such a manner as to affect the surface.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Surface use, except for purposes that permit the land or water area to remain predominantly in its natural condition.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Activities detrimental to drainage, flood control, water conservation, erosion control, soil conservation, or fish and wildlife habitat preservation.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any other act or use detrimental to the preserving or conserving of such areas for the purposes stated herein.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Present use is the manner in which the land is utilized on January first of the year in which the assessment is made.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Board is the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Covenant is a covenant running with the land.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Owner shall mean the owner or, if more than one (1) owner, the owners who have the fee simple title to the land. If the minimum contiguous area referred to above is under fee simple ownership of more than one (1) owner, then such owners may jointly submit a conveyance or covenant to meet the minimum area requirements herein.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Land shall mean a land or water area.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-33, ยง 8, 5-21-75; Ord. No. 79-105, ยง 1, 12-4-79)</history></law>