<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00049' order_by='00049' level='2'>Chapter 25B PARKS AND RECREATION GENERALLY</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SAFE NEIGHBORHOOD PARKS ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25B-23</section_number>
<catch_line>Administration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003102</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25B-23. Administration.<section prefix='(a)'>The Citizens' Oversight Committee. A Citizens' Oversight Committee ("Committee") will be formed to oversee the disbursement of the proceeds from the sale of the bonds. The Committee will have thirteen (13) members; one (1) residing in each of Miami-Dade County's thirteen (13) commission districts. Members of the Committee shall be residents of Miami-Dade County who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, integrity, responsibility and business or professional ability and experience or interest in the fields of recreation, conservation of natural resources or land use planning. The Committee, as defined below, will be comprised of members who are representative of the geographic, ethnic, racial and gender make-up of the County. The Committee shall be automatically dissolved as of October 18, 2010, ("Dissolution Date"). After the Dissolution Date, all duties or responsibilities of the Committee shall be handled administratively by the Mayor or Mayor's designee until all available funds have been expended.<section prefix='(1)'>Selection. Each member of the Board of County Commissioners shall appoint one representative to the Committee. Each representative shall reside in the appointing commissioner's district.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Term. The Committee members shall serve two-year terms, and may be reappointed. The terms shall be staggered, with the representatives of the evenly-numbered districts scheduled for replacement or reappointment after the first year. Members of the Committee shall not be compensated for their services. Notwithstanding Section 2-11.38.2, Committee members may be reappointed for more than eight (8) consecutive years without a two-year hiatus.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Powers and duties. The Committee shall have the following powers and duties:<section prefix='(i)'>To oversee the deposit and disbursement of the bond proceeds in accordance with the terms of this article;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>To issue solicitations for all grants, to evaluate, disqualify, and rank challenge grant proposals, and to recommend the award of grants in accordance with the terms of this article;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>To identify funding to reimburse the County for the reasonable costs of providing staff to the Committee, in the process of the oversight and grant management of this article, which funding may include amounts available under this Bond program if the costs of staffing are related to individual projects authorized by this article;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>To promulgate rules consistent with this article for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities;</section><section prefix='(v)'>To perform such other functions as are set forth for the Committee in this article.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Deposit of bond proceeds. All proceeds of the sale of the bonds shall be delivered to the Director of the Finance Department of Miami-Dade County who shall deposit those proceeds in the Trust Account, not to be commingled with other funds of the County, to be disbursed solely for the purposes set forth in this article. Miami-Dade County, itself or through independent auditors, shall have the right at all times to audit the books and records of the Committee.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Staff. The County Manager and the County Attorney shall provide to the Committee adequate staff and support services to enable the Committee to carry out its duties and responsibilities.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-115, ยง 4, 7-16-96; Ord. No. 06-70, ยง 1, 5-9-06; Ord. No. 09-09, ยง 1, 1-22-09; Ord. No. 10-79, ยง 3, 11-4-10)</history></law>