<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00050' order_by='00050' level='2'>Chapter 25C PAYMENT OF COSTS OF HOSPITAL CARE, TREATMENT AND MAINTENANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25C-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Perfection of lien; notice of filing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003115</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25C-4. Perfection of lien; notice of filing.<section>In order to perfect such lien, the executive officer or agent of a hospital, before, or within ten (10) days after, any such person shall have been discharged from such hospital, shall file in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court or the county in which such hospital shall be located, a verified claim in writing setting forth the name and address of such patient, as it shall appear on the records of such hospital, the name and location of such hospital, and the name and address of the executive officer or agent of such hospital, the dates of admission to and discharge of such patient therefrom, the amount claimed to be due for such hospital care, treatment and maintenance and, to the best knowledge of the person signing such claim, the names and addresses of all persons, firms or corporations claimed by such ill or injured person or by the legal representative of such person, to be liable on account of such illness or injuries; such claimant shall also, within one (1) day after filing of such claim or lien, mail a copy thereof by registered mail, postage prepaid, to each person, firm or corporation so claimed to be liable on account of such illness or injuries, at the address so given in such statement. The filing of such claim shall be notice thereof to all persons, firms or corporations who may be liable on account of such illness or injuries, whether or not they are named in such claim or lien, and whether or not a copy of such claim shall have been received by them.</section></section></text><history>(Ch. 27032, ยง 2, Laws 1951)</history></law>