<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00050' order_by='00050' level='2'>Chapter 25C PAYMENT OF COSTS OF HOSPITAL CARE, TREATMENT AND MAINTENANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>25C-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Validity of release or satisfaction of claims against third parties as to lienholder's rights in those claims.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003117</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 25C-6. Validity of release or satisfaction of claims against third parties as to lienholder's rights in those claims.<section>No release or satisfaction of any action, suit, claim, counterclaim, demand, judgment, settlement or settlement agreement, or of any of them, shall be valid or effectual as against such lien unless such lienholder shall join therein or execute a release of such lien.</section><section>Any acceptance of a release or satisfaction of any such cause of action, suit, claim, counterclaim, demand or judgment and any settlement of any of the foregoing in the absence of a release or satisfaction of the lien referred to in this Act [chapter] shall prima facie constitute an impairment of such lien; and the lienholder shall be entitled to an action at law for damages on account of such impairment, and in such action may recover from the one (1) accepting such release or satisfaction or making such settlement the reasonable cost of such hospital care, treatment and maintenance. Satisfaction of any judgment rendered in favor of the lienholder in any such action shall operate as a satisfaction of the lien. Any action by the lienholder shall be brought in the court having jurisdiction of the amount of the lienholder's claim and may be brought and maintained in the county wherein the lienholder has his, its or their residence or place of business. If the lienholder shall prevail in such action, the lienholder shall be entitled to recover from the defendant, in addition to costs otherwise allowed by law, all reasonable attorneys' fees and expenses incident to the matter.</section></section></text><history>(Ch. 27032, ยง 4, Laws of 1951)</history></law>