<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00051' order_by='00051' level='2'>Chapter 26 PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. PROGRAMMING PARTNERS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>26-23</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003127</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 26-23. Definitions.<section>As used in this article, the following terms shall mean:<section prefix='A.'>Community-based Organization (CBO) shall refer to any not-for-profit agency, group, organization, society, association, partnership or individual whose primary purpose is to provide a community service to improve or enhance the well-being of the community of Miami-Dade County at large or to improve or enhance the well-being of certain individuals within this community who have special needs.</section><section prefix='B.'>Community Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually of 30-100 acres in size with mixed passive and active recreational facilities.</section><section prefix='C.'>Concession Rights shall refer to a Programming Partner's privilege to engage in the trade of certain goods, such as food and drink, in compliance with their IRS status in order to raise funds for the operations of its programs.</section><section prefix='D.'>County Park and Recreation Facility shall refer to any public park land and the recreational facilities, thereon, owned and/or operated by the Department. The following park classifications: Natural Area Preserves, Greenways, Neighborhood parks and mini-parks, by definition are considered passive use areas not usually suited for on-site program development and therefore they are exempt from this article.</section><section prefix='E.'>Department shall refer to the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department.</section><section prefix='F.'>Development Rights shall refer to a Programming Partner's privilege to raise funds or provide services to plan, design and construct capital improvements on County Park and Recreation Facilities so long as any improvements are in accordance with the host Facility's approved general plan, and all capital improvements are authorized through the appropriate Department procedures.</section><section prefix='G.'>District Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually of 200 to 500 acres in size with intensive active, user-based recreational facilities.</section><section prefix='H.'>Exclusive Use shall refer to a Programming Partners' serving as the sole provider of recreational programming services at a County Park and Recreation Facility.</section><section prefix='I.'>Metropolitan Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually of 200-plus acres in size that incorporate activities based upon the natural and cultural resources of the park.</section><section prefix='J.'>Non-Exclusive Use shall refer to a Programming Partners' sharing time and facility usage with other recreational programming service providers at a County Park and Recreation Facility.</section><section prefix='K.'>Not-For-Profit Program Service Provider(s) shall refer to any legally incorporated not-for-profit organization created under the laws of the State of Florida (the State) and designated as a tax-exempt entity by the United States Internal Revenue Service, which has among its purposes the provision of youth, athletic, senior, adult, cultural, environmental, conservation and/or recreational services.</section><section prefix='L.'>Programming shall refer to recreational or cultural activities or services provided to County Park and Recreation Facilities through either a Programming Partner or the Department.</section><section prefix='M.'>Programming Partners Agreement or Programming Partnership Agreement shall refer to the executed contract for services between the Programming Partner and the Department approved and authorized as outlined in the Administrative Order.</section><section prefix='N.'>Programming Partner(s),
                        Partner(s) or Partnering Organization(s) shall refer to any Not-For-Profit Program Service Provider that is selected by the Department under this article and accompanying Administrative Order to provide programs in County Park and Recreation Facilities.</section><section prefix='O.'>Public Park Purpose shall refer to the use of County Park and Recreation Facilities for aesthetic, educational, recreational or cultural use, which promote personal, social, environmental and economic benefits to the County community.</section><section prefix='P.'>Recreational Outcomes shall refer to the measurable recreational or educational programming goals and objectives the Programming Partner seeks to achieve as a condition of its agreement with the Department.</section><section prefix='Q.'>Request For Programming Proposals (RFPP) means a formal written solicitation prepared and issued for the purpose of seeking sealed responses from prospective proposers by a date and time certain as established by the County.</section><section prefix='R.'>Single Purpose Park shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities, usually between five and fifteen acres in size, that are devoted to a single recreational function.</section><section prefix='S.'>Special Activity Areas shall refer to the park classification, as established in accordance with the guidelines of Miami-Dade County's adopted CDMP, for staffed County Park and Recreation Facilities of no set size, that incorporate activities based upon the natural or cultural resources of the park.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-137, ยง 3, 7-23-02; Ord. No. 09-27, ยง 1, 4-7-09)</history></law>