<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00051' order_by='00051' level='2'>Chapter 26 PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. PROGRAMMING PARTNERS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>26-21</section_number>
<catch_line>Findings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003125</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 26-21. Findings.<section>The Board finds that:<section prefix='A.'>The purposes described in the Whereas clauses [of the ordinance from which this article derives] are incorporated into the body of this article by reference. This article shall hereafter be known as the "Programming Partners Ordinance" and referred to herein as this article.</section><section prefix='B.'>To fulfill the goal of the Recreation and Open Space Element of the CDMP Objective 4C, Section ii, the Department stipulates that it shall work with community-based organizations, non-profit youth service organizations, foundations, facility support societies and other special interest groups to expand opportunities for private, non-profit investment in park improvements and recreational programming.</section><section prefix='C.'>County procurement processes primarily govern the purchase of goods and services through specifications and competitive bidding, and are managed through the Department of Procurement Management. As Programming Partners selection criteria are based on elements other than price, the standard procurement process should not apply, and Programming Partners shall become a distinct and unique process.</section><section prefix='D.'>This Article creates a process to identify and select qualified Programming Partners to assist the Department in providing recreational and cultural programming services. Selection is based on an organization's ability to successfully fulfill specific, mutually agreed upon Recreational Outcomes that meet community needs.</section><section prefix='E.'>Based upon these findings, the Board concurs that a fair and standard process for the recruitment, selection, agreement and evaluation of Not-For-Profit Program Service Providers be implemented.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-137, ยง 1, 7-23-02; Ord. No. 09-27, ยง 1, 4-7-09)</history></law>