<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00051' order_by='00051' level='2'>Chapter 26 PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. PROGRAMMING PARTNERS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>26-27</section_number>
<catch_line>Administration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003131</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 26-27. Administration.<section>By implementing order, procedures for the advertisement, selection, and award of all agreements with Programming Partners shall be established. The implementing order shall be consistent with this article. The Department shall administer the Programming Partners process, which shall include at a minimum:<section prefix='A.'>Recruitment Procedures for new Partners;</section><section prefix='B.'>Measures for Existing Partners;</section><section prefix='C.'>Criteria for Selection;</section><section prefix='D.'>Partnership Agreement Types and Authorizations;</section><section prefix='E.'>Required Information and Reporting;</section><section prefix='F.'>Criteria for Performance Monitoring;</section><section prefix='G.'>Measures to Address non-Performing Partners;</section><section prefix='H.'>Procedures for Partnership Renewal;</section><section prefix='I.'>Requirements for Participation in Fee Reduction/Scholarship Program;</section><section prefix='J.'>Requirements for Background Checks of Volunteers;</section><section prefix='K.'>Approval of Programming Partners Fees and Charges Schedules;</section><section prefix='L.'>Mandatory Training Programs;</section><section prefix='M.'>Opportunities for Recognition;</section></section><section>All Requests for Proposals for Programming Partners (RFPP) shall be prepared and issued by the Department. The Department shall receive and open such proposals, evaluate each proposal for responsiveness and qualifications, rank all proposals and shall make recommendations to the entity authorized by the Administrative Order to make the selection of award for a Programming Partner, as set forth herein. The type of agreement executed and level of authority for approval will be based upon the program purpose, use, term and amount of operating revenue and/or capital investment provided by the Programming Partner.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-137, ยง 7, 7-23-02; Ord. No. 09-27, ยง 1, 4-7-09)</history></law>