<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00051' order_by='00051' level='2'>Chapter 26 PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. THE SHANNON MELENDI ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>26-39</section_number>
<catch_line>Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department employees and volunteers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003143</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 26-39. Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department employees and volunteers.<section prefix='A.'>Upon adoption of this ordinance [Ord. No. 08-07], the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall secure a nationwide criminal background check of all existing employees and volunteers whose primary duties require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. In addition, the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall secure a nationwide criminal background fingerprint check prior to employing, or allowing to volunteer, a person whose primary duties would require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. This nationwide criminal background fingerprint check shall be conducted through the Florida Department of Law Enforcement.</section><section prefix='B.'>Every three (3) years thereafter, the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall secure nationwide criminal background checks for existing employees and volunteers whose primary duties require physical presence on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. These nationwide criminal background checks shall be conducted by a Professional Background Screener and shall include a report as to whether each employee or volunteer is located on the National Sex Offender Public Registry, and a comprehensive report and analysis, obtained from two independent databases/sources, on the nationwide criminal history of such employee or volunteer.</section><section prefix='C.'>Any employee or volunteer of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department who:<section prefix='(1)'>Has been convicted of a violent felony or conspiracy to commit a violent felony within the past five (5) years; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Has been convicted of a felony involving the trafficking of a controlled substance within the past (5) years; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Has two (2) or more convictions for a violent felony, for conspiracy to commit a violent felony, or involving the trafficking of a controlled substance; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Is a sexual offender or a sexual predator; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Has failed to provide the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department with proof of United States citizenship or legal immigration status in the United States,</section></section><section>shall be prohibited from working or volunteering on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. All employees and volunteers of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall submit to the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department an affidavit affirming that no work or volunteer duties will be performed on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County in violation of this subsection and that any arrest will be reported to his/her employer within forty-eight (48) hours of such arrest.</section><section prefix='D.'>The Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall maintain copies of the results of the criminal background checks required by this section for a period of three (3) years from the date they were secured. The Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall maintain the affidavits required by Section 26-39.C. and shall maintain copies of the proof of United States citizenship or legal immigration status until the person is no longer an employee or volunteer.</section><section prefix='E.'>Every employee and volunteer of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department shall wear, in a conspicuous and visible manner, an identification badge that contains his/her photograph and full name while working or volunteering on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County, except when in costume and during a performance. The identification badge shall be of a size, design, and format approved by the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department.</section><section prefix='F.'>Penalties and Enforcement.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be unlawful for any volunteer of the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department to volunteer on park property owned or operated by Miami-Dade County in violation of Section 26-39</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any volunteer who shall violate a provision of Section 26-39, or who shall knowingly or willingly provide false or erroneous information to the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department, or fail to comply therewith, or with any of the requirements thereof, shall upon conviction thereof in the County Court, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any volunteer who violates or fails to comply with Section 26-39 may be subject to civil penalties in accordance with Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-07, ยง 2, 1-10-08)</history></law>