<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00051' order_by='00051' level='2'>Chapter 26 PARK AND RECREATION DEPARTMENT RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. THE SHANNON MELENDI ACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>26-37</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003141</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 26-37. Definitions.<section>As used in this article the following terms shall have the following meanings:<section prefix='A.'>Community-based Organization (CBO) shall refer to any not-for-profit agency, group, organization, society, association, partnership, or individual whose primary purpose is to provide a community service to improve or enhance the well-being of the community of Miami-Dade County at large or to improve or enhance the well-being of certain individuals within this community who have special needs.</section><section prefix='B.'>Child Event Worker shall refer to any full-time or part-time employee, agent, volunteer, independent contractor, or employee or volunteer of an independent contractor of a carnival or fair that hosts amusement rides in a park owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. The following persons shall be exempted from this definition:<section prefix='(1)'>Law enforcement personnel;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Emergency or fire rescue personnel;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Persons conducting deliveries; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Military recruitment personnel.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Conviction shall refer to a determination of guilt of a criminal charge which is the result of a trial or the entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld.</section><section prefix='D.'>Park vendor shall refer to any full-time or part-time employee, agent, volunteer, independent contractor, or employee or volunteer of an independent contractor that has a contract with, or permit from, Miami-Dade County to rent or sell food, beverages, sporting equipment, or any other goods or services in a park owned or operated by Miami-Dade County. The following persons and events shall be exempted from this definition:<section prefix='(1)'>Law enforcement personnel;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Emergency or fire rescue personnel;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Persons conducting deliveries;</section><section prefix='(4)'>International or national sporting events;</section><section prefix='(5)'>One-day events; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Carnivals, festivals, trade shows, and fairs that do not host amusement rides.</section></section><section prefix='E.'>Professional Background Screener shall refer to any person, company, organization or agency which, for monetary fees, dues, or on a not-for-profit basis, regularly engages in whole or in part in the practice of researching and assembling criminal history information on specific persons for the purpose of furnishing criminal history reports to third parties.</section><section prefix='F.'>Programming Partner shall refer to any Not-For-Profit Program Service Provider that is selected by the Department under Article II of this chapter and the accompanying Administrative Order to provide programs in County Park and Recreation Facilities.</section><section prefix='G.'>Sexual Offender shall include any individual who meets the criteria of a "sexual predator" as defined in Section 775.21(4) of the Florida Statutes, or a "sexual offender" as defined in Section 943.0435 of the Florida Statutes, or who is listed on the National Sex Offender Public Website owned or operated by the United States Department of Justice.</section><section prefix='H.'>Violent felony shall refer to the following felonies: arson; sexual battery; robbery; kidnapping; aggravated child abuse; aggravated abuse of an elderly person or disabled adult; aggravated assault with a deadly weapon; murder; manslaughter; aggravated manslaughter of an elderly person or disabled adult; aggravated manslaughter of a child; unlawful throwing, placing, or discharging of a destructive device or bomb; armed burglary; aggravated battery; or aggravated stalking.</section><section prefix='I.'>Volunteer shall refer to any individual performing volunteer duties for a CBO, for a Programming Partner, for the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department as a child event worker, or as a park vendor for more than three (3) days in any six (6) month period. Students volunteering in order to fulfill high school graduation requirements shall be exempted from this definition.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-07, ยง 2, 1-10-08)</history></law>