<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00052' order_by='00052' level='2'>Chapter 26A SANITARY NUISANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>26A-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Sanitary nuisances generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003145</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 26A-2. Sanitary nuisances generally.<section prefix='(a)'>Definition. A sanitary nuisance is the commission of any act, by an individual, municipality, organization or corporation, or the keeping, maintaining, propagation, existence or permission of anything, by an individual, municipality, organization or corporation, by which the health or life of an individual, or the health or life of individuals, may be threatened or impaired or by which or through which, directly or indirectly, disease may be caused.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Presumption of nuisance injurious to health. The following conditions existing, permitted, maintained, kept or caused by any individual, municipal organization or corporation, governmental or private, shall constitute prima facie evidence of maintaining a nuisance injurious to health:<section prefix='(1)'>Untreated or improperly treated human waste, garbage, offal, dead animals or dangerous waste materials from manufacturing processes harmful to human or animal life and air pollutants, gases and noisome odors which are harmful to human or animal life.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Improperly built or maintained septic tanks, water closets or privies.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The keeping of diseased animals dangerous to human health.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Unclean or filthy places where animals are slaughtered.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The creation, maintenance or causing of any condition capable of breeding flies, mosquitoes or other arthropods capable of transmitting diseases, directly or indirectly to humans.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Any other condition determined to be a sanitary nuisance as defined in this chapter.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 65-19, §§ 2, 3, 4-6-65)</history></law>