<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00056' order_by='00056' level='2'>Chapter 27 SWIMMING POOLS, PUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>27-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Procedure for obtaining.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003160</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 27-3. Same—Procedure for obtaining.<section prefix='(a)'>Application. All applications for certificates of competency shall be made and filed with the Department of Public Health. The Department of Public Health shall prescribe the form of application and make such investigation concerning all applications filed as it shall deem necessary.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Issuance of certificate. A certificate of competency shall be issued by the Department of Public Health to all applicants of good moral character who shall first present to the Health Department satisfactory evidence of successful or satisfactory completion of a short course in the care, maintenance and operation of swimming pools and bathing places, and have the required amount of experience in public pool operation.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Short course given under supervision. The Health Department shall at least once each year give a short course in the care, maintenance and operation of public bathing places and pools. The Health Department may from time to time approve certain qualified groups or organizations to give the short courses and in that event, said short courses shall be under the sponsorship, direction and supervision of the Health Department. Successful or satisfactory completion of the short course with an approved organization or group sponsored and approved by the Health Department shall likewise entitle an applicant to a certificate of competency as set forth in subsection (b) of this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Time limit and revocation of certificate. A certificate of competency issued pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be valid until revoked for cause by the Health Department, but violation of any applicable provisions of the Florida State Sanitary Code, Chapter XX, as amended, shall be deemed prima facie grounds for revocation of a certificate of competency.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Temporary permits. For one (1) year from the effective date of this chapter, the Health Department shall issue temporary permits in lieu of certificate of competency to all applicants of good moral character in order that such persons shall have sufficient time and opportunity to comply with this chapter and satisfactorily complete the short course. All temporary permits shall become null and void on the date herein specified or upon unsatisfactory completion of the short course, whichever shall occur first. Pool operators of newly completed pools may be issued a temporary certificate if necessary for a period not to exceed one (1) year in order that such person shall have sufficient opportunity to become certified. Upon ex-piration of the temporary certificate, the pool operator must become certified or the pool owner must obtain a certified operator.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Certification of some present pool operators. Any person who has heretofore completed a short course sponsored by the Florida Swimming Pool Operators Association, a nonprofit organization, and the Department of Public Health and presently holds a valid certificate of satisfactory completion therefrom, shall be certified as competent under this chapter.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Fees. A fee not exceeding ten dollars ($10.00) may be charged by the Health Department for processing applications and issuing certificates.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Exemption for experienced swimming pool operators. Anything herein to the contrary notwithstanding, any person furnishing satisfactory proof to the Public Health Department that he has been engaged continuously in the occupation of public swimming pool operator in the County, for at least five (5) years immediately prior to the effective date of this chapter, shall not be required to attend or take any short course of instruction, and a certificate of competency shall be issued to such person, provided he possesses good moral character, and provided he satisfactorily passes a special examination given by the Public Health Department covering the practical aspects of public swimming pool care, maintenance and operation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-36, § 4, 9-9-58; Ord. No. 59-6, § 1, 3-31-59)</history></law>