<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00056' order_by='00056' level='2'>Chapter 27 SWIMMING POOLS, PUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>27-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Fees; exemption.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003163</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 27-6. Fees; exemption.<section prefix='(a)'>Authorized; amounts. In addition to and not limited by the fees set out in Section 27-3(g) of this chapter, the Dade County Department of Public Health is hereby authorized and directed to collect the following annual fees for permitting of swimming pools under the provisions of Chapter 514, Florida Statutes, and Chapter 10D-5, Florida Administrative Code:<section prefix='(1)'>Pools up to 20,000 gallons, per annum$ 50.00</section><section prefix='(2)'>Pools in excess of 20,000 gallons and up to 50,000 gallons, per annum75.00</section><section prefix='(3)'>Pools in excess of 50,000 gallons, per annum100.00</section><section prefix='(4)'>Swimming pools having, in addition to the principal structure set forth above, a wading or therapeutic pool that is part of the bathing area shall be assessed an additional annual permit fee of10.00</section></section><section>All permit applicants for swimming pools permitted under Chapter 514, Florida Statutes, and under the provisions of this section, shall be required to pay the above-noted permit fees upon original application for a permit or upon expiration of their existing permit and prior to the issuance of any new permit.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Exemption of governmentally owned and operated swimming pools. Governmentally owned and operated swimming pools are hereby exempt from the payment of the fees as established in this section, provided that the appropriate supervisor of each swimming pool shall furnish and deliver to the Miami Branch Laboratory, Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, on or before the tenth day of each and every month, a bacteriological water sample in a container approved by the Department of Health, and that said pools shall be subject to not less than one (1) inspection per year by the Dade County Department of Public Health. Failure to comply with this provision shall result in the imposition of a fee as provided herein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-73, § 1, 7-20-76; Ord. No. 77-85, § 1, 12-6-77)</history></law>