<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='2'>Chapter 28 SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Building permits, issuance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003177</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28-11. Building permits, issuance.<section>No building permit shall be issued for construction of any improvements on a parcel that was not legally created in compliance with these regulations except permits for a construction trailer or sale office trailer, permanent buildings to be used as single family home and townhouse models, entrance features, perimeter walls, lift stations and multi-family residential, commercial and industrial buildings, may be issued if the developer complies with the following requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>For construction trailer or trailer used as sales office: No permits will be approved until at least a tentative plat has been approved and the Public Works Department has reviewed and permitted paving and drainage plans. In addition, no permit shall be issued unless the trailer complies with the Department of Environmental Resources Management's requirements for providing potable water and sanitary facilities.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For permanent buildings to be used as single family or townhouse models:<section>Permits for models not to exceed 25 percent of the total number of lots will be approved when:</section><section prefix='(1)'>The tentative plat has been approved by the Plat Committee and is current.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Paving and drainage plans have been approved.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All the Department of Environmental Resources Management's requirements, including the approval of Water and Sewer extension plans are complied with.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A letter signed by the property owner has been submitted to the Supervisor, Platting Section, requesting the construction of models prior to final plat recording. The letter shall include the number of models being requested (only one (1) of each single family model will be allowed, or only one (1) of each model townhouse building) together with the lot and block numbers for each such model. The letter shall state that the owner understands and agrees that the model home, or homes, shall not be occupied until the plat is recorded in the public records and that the penalty for violation of this occupancy prohibition shall be the demolition of the model. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall release and hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature and kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. The Supervisor, should he/she approve the models, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No certificate of completion shall be issued for any model until after the final plat is recorded except that a Temporary Certificate of Completion may be issued by the Planning and Zoning Department.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Entrance features, perimeter wall and lift station permits may be issued after tentative plat approval by the Plat Committee and receipt of a letter to the Supervisor, Platting Section, signed by the property owner requesting the permit prior to final plat recording and releasing and holding Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature or kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. The Supervisor should he/she approve the request, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.</section><section prefix='(d)'>For multi-family residential, commercial, and industrial buildings; tentative plat.<section prefix='(1)'>The tentative plat has been approved by the Plat Committee and is current.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building permits may be issued, on only one site, lot or tract, until the proposed final plat for the subdivision in which the structure, or structures, is to be located has been listed on an agenda for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Paving and drainage plans (if required) shall have been approved by the Public Works Department.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A letter, signed by the property owner, has been submitted to the Supervisor, Platting Section, requesting the permit prior to final plat recording. The letter shall state the proposed lot and block or tract for such permit, and the owner's acknowledgment and agreement that no certificate of occupancy or use will be sought or issued for the structure, or structures, until after the final plat is recorded. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall release and hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature or kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. The Supervisor, should he/she approve the request, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No certificate of occupancy or use for the subject structure, or structures, will be issued until the plat is recorded.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The issuance of the building permit shall not modify or affect the concurrency capacity of the underlying tentative plat in any way.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>For multi-family residential commercial, and industrial buildings; waiver of plat.<section prefix='(1)'>The waiver of plat has been recommended for approval by the Plat Committee.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building permits may be issued, on only one parcel, until the proposed waiver of plat for the subdivision in which the structure, or structures, is to be located has been listed on an agenda for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Paving and drainage plans and a bond in lieu of the immediate construction of any improvements (if required) shall have been approved by the Public Works and Waste Management Department.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A letter, signed by the property owner, has been submitted to the Supervisor, Platting Section, requesting the permit, or permits, prior to the waiver of plat approval by the Board of County Commissioners. The letter shall state the proposed parcel for such permit, or permits, and the owner's acknowledgment and agreement that no certificate of occupancy or use will be sought or issued until after the waiver of plat is approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall release and hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature or kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to waiver of plat approval. Should the Supervisor approve the request, a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section shall be placed in the plat file.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No certificate of occupancy or use for the subject structure, or structures, will be issued until the waiver of plat is approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The issuance of the building permit, or permits, shall not modify or affect the concurrency capacity of the waiver of plat in any way.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>For Permanent Buildings to be used as Single Family or Townhouse Production Homes:<section>Permits for single family or townhouse production homes will be approved when:</section><section prefix='(1)'>The tentative plat has been approved or the waiver of plat has been recommended for approval by the Plat Committee and is current.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Paving and Drainage plans have been approved. A bond in lieu of the immediate construction of any improvements (if required) shall have been approved by the Public Works and Waste Management Department for any waiver of plat.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All DERM requirements, including the approval of Water and Sewer Extension plans are complied with.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The proposed final or waiver of plat for the subdivision in which the production homes are to be located has been listed on an agenda for approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A letter, signed by the property owner, has been submitted to the supervisor, Platting Section, requesting approval of production homes prior to final plat recording, or waiver of plat approval by the Board of County Commissioners. The letter shall state that the owner understands and agrees that the production home shall not be occupied until the plat is recorded in the public records, or the waiver of plat has been approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records, and that the penalty for violation of this occupancy prohibition shall be the demolition of the production home. The letter shall also state that the owner agrees and shall hold Miami-Dade County, its employees and agents, harmless from any and all liability and causes of action of whatsoever nature and kind for and as a result of the issuance of building permits and any construction prior to final plat approval and recordation. or the waiver of plat has been approved by the Board of County Commissioners and the resolution is recorded in the public records. The Supervisor, should he/she approve the models, will send a copy of the owner's letter to the Zoning Processing Section to be placed in the plat file.</section><section prefix='(6)'>No certificate of completion shall be issued for any production home until after the final plat is recorded except that a Temporary of Certificate of Completion may be issued by the Planning and Zoning Department.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-6, ยง 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 03-94, ยง 1, 4-22-03; Ord. No. 12-41, ยง 2, 6-5-12)</history></law>