<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='2'>Chapter 28 SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Construction plan.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003182</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28-16. Construction plan.<section prefix='(a)'>Preparation. The subdivider, or his engineer, shall confer with the appropriate agencies to determine the standards and specifications which will govern the proposed improvements. The subdivider shall submit complete construction plans prepared by an engineer and/or surveyor, as the case may be, registered in the State of Florida for the entire development of the area for which application to plat has been submitted, together with the complete and accurate contour map using U.S.C. and G.S. datum, to the appropriate agencies for their review and approval. The construction plans shall include the complete design of required sanitary sewer system, water supply system, storm drainage system and the street system for the entire area to be subdivided. Due consideration shall be given to the problems that may be created by the subdivision of adjacent lands, especially as pertains to drainage in order that conformance with the overall drainage plan will be obtained. The subdivider shall do no construction work until his completed construction plans have been approved by the appropriate agencies. Reasonable time must be allotted for the proper study of the plans submitted.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Construction of improvements; employing engineer. After approved construction plans have been filed and approved, the subdivider may construct the required improvements, subject to obtaining the required permits from the appropriate agencies.</section><section>On plats within the unincorporated areas of the County the Director of the Department of Public Works, and if sewerage and water systems are involved, the Director of the Department of Public Health shall be notified in advance of the date that such construction shall be commenced. Construction shall be performed under the supervision of the appropriate agencies and shall at all times be subject to inspection by these agencies. However, this in no way shall relieve the subdivider and his engineer of close field supervision and final compliance with the approved plans and specifications.</section><section>Where deemed necessary, in accordance with the County's manual of public works construction, the appropriate agencies may require the subdivider to employ a registered engineer for complete supervision of the construction or installation of the improvements involved, and may require progress reports and final certificate of the construction or installation from such engineer. The appropriate agencies shall establish detailed regulations governing the inspections to be furnished by the developer or his engineer and may refuse to accept work which has been done without proper inspection. No construction work shall be undertaken prior to obtaining the required permits.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Acceptance of improvements. When construction is complete in accordance with the approved plan and specifications and complies with the provisions of these regulations, the subdivider shall obtain written final approval and acceptance from the appropriate agencies.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Bond in lieu of immediate construction. In lieu of immediate construction of improvements, the subdivider may file with the governing body a cash bond or letter of credit in an amount approved by the plat division and a company approved by the governing body or the department authorized by them, to insure the County the actual satisfactory completion of construction of proposed improvements within a period of not more than one (1) year from the date of such bond. The bond for the installation of sidewalks may be a separate bond. Provisions shall be made for extension of all such bonds, such extension to be commensurate with the progress of the development. Provisions shall also be made for reduction of such bonds, such reduction to be commensurate with the percentage of improvements constructed in the subdivision concerned. This bond shall also include a maintenance provision for two (2) years covering drainage and for one (1) year covering all other improvements by the subdivider. The amount to be included for maintenance shall be outlined in the manual of public works construction. Bonds shall be subject to cancellation, reduction or renewal only by the governing body upon written certification of the plat division of the appropriate agency.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-6, ยง 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 94-51, ยง 3, 3-17-94)</history></law>