<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='2'>Chapter 28 SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Drainage.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003179</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28-13. Drainage.<section prefix='(a)'>Master plan and manual of public works construction. The developer shall plan all drainage for his subdivision in accordance with the master plan entitled, "County Water-Control Plan," recorded in Plat Book 64, page 114 and in accordance with the flood criteria map, recorded in Plat Book 53, pages 68, 69, and 70, or as such plan and map may be changed or modified. The drainage plans shall be subject to approval of the Public Works Department for compliance with such plan.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Permit to construct or alter drainage ways. No individual, partnership, or corporation shall construct, deepen, widen, fill, reroute, or alter any existing drainage way, ditch, drain, or canal without first obtaining a written permit from the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management. Plans for all such work shall comply with the manual of public works construction of the County's Public Works Department, and all such work shall be done under the supervision and subject to the approval of the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management. Rights-of-way for all such drainage works and maintenance thereof as prescribed by the manual of public works and construction and the County water control plan, must be dedicated to the use of the public, such dedication to be made prior to any such construction or alteration if so required by the County's Public Works Department and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Rights-of-way and easements. Whenever any drainage way, stream, or surface drainage course is located or planned in any area that is being subdivided, the subdivider shall dedicate such stream or drainage course and an adequate right-of-way necessary for maintenance, future expansion and other purposes along each side of such stream or drainage course as is determined by uniform standards prescribed by the manual of public works construction.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Storm water. Adequate provision shall be made for the disposal of storm water subject to standards prescribed in the manual of public works construction.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Contour map and drainage of adjacent areas. A contour map shall be prepared for the area comprising the subdivision and such additional areas as may be required by the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management, necessary to include all watersheds which drain into or through the property to be developed, provided that this map of the adjacent areas may be prepared from existing maps or other data available to and acceptable by the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management. The design for drainage of the subdivision must be adequate to provide for drainage of adjacent water shed areas, and design of drainage structures must provide for drainage of adjacent water sheds after complete development of the total area. Where ditches and canals are required, rights-of-way shall be provided for future needs in accordance with uniform standards proscribed in the County's manual of public works construction. Provided, however, that the developers may be permitted by the County's Department of Public Works and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management to excavate or open, or construct necessary drainage ways and structures only of sufficient capacity to provide for existing drainage needs whenever the developed or undeveloped status of adjacent water sheds may so warrant as determined by the County's Department of Public Works, and/or the County's Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Off-site drainage. Off-site drainage shall be mutually coordinated by and between the subdivider, and the plat division of the appropriate authority.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-6, ยง 1, 2-1-77)</history></law>