<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='2'>Chapter 28 SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Plats and platting—Recording; exceptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003167</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28-4. Plats and platting—Recording; exceptions.<section>Whenever land is subdivided a plat must be recorded, except that the recording of a plat will not be required if:<section prefix='(1)'>The subdivision involved consists only of the dedication of a road, highway, street, alley or easement and due to unusual conditions and circumstances the plat division of the appropriate authority finds that it is not necessary that a plat be recorded. In lieu of the recording of a plat, the dedication may be required by deed, and may be subject to compliance with such conditions as may be deemed appropriate under the particular circumstances, such as improvements of sidewalks, streets, or drainage facilities and the acceptance of the dedication by the governing body. Posting of bond may be required.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The land to be subdivided is to be divided into no more than six (6) parcels and because of (a) unusual conditions created by ownership or development of adjacent lands, or (b) the isolation or remoteness of the land concerned in relation to other platted or improved lands, or (c) improvements and dedications existing on the land substantially in accordance with the requirements of this chapter, it is determined by the plat division of the appropriate authority that waiving of the requirement for platting would not conflict with the purpose and intent of this chapter. In lieu of platting the plat division of the appropriate authority may require any dedications, reservations, or improvements required in connection with platting under this chapter, including the posting of a performance and maintenance bond, as may be necessary to carry out the intent and purpose of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The resubdivision of land heretofore platted is of such unusual size or shape, or is surrounded by such development or unusual conditions as may be determined by the plat division of the appropriate authority to justify the waiving of the requirement for recording a plat. In lieu of the recording of a plat, such conditions may be imposed as may be deemed necessary and appropriate to preserve the public interest.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A parcel of land conveyed by a recorded warranty deed that is dated prior to January 1, 1958, the effective date of this code; provided, however, that the parcel may be diminished in size as a result of a public dedication of any portion of that parcel.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 81-6, § 1, 1-20-81; Ord. No. 03-94, § 1, 4-22-03)</history></law>