<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='2'>Chapter 28 SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28-4.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Procedure for waiver of plat.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003168</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28-4.1. Same—Procedure for waiver of plat.<section prefix='(a)'>To determine if the waiving of the requirement for platting would not conflict with the purpose and intent of this chapter, and the exceptions contained in Section 28-4 are applicable, a waiver of plat survey shall be submitted by the property owner.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A waiver of plat application shall be submitted, signed by the owner and notarized on the form prescribed by the plat division of the appropriate authority.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The waiver of plat survey shall be prepared by a land surveyor registered in the State of Florida and shall bear the embossed seal of the land surveyor.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The waiver of plat survey shall include the following items, unless waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority:<section prefix='(1)'>Legal description of the parent tract.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Legal description of each parcel to be created.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Location of property lines, existing easements, buildings, watercourses and other essential features.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The location of any existing sewers and water mains, or any underground or overhead utilities, culverts and drains on the property to be subdivided.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Location, names and present widths of existing and proposed streets, highways, easements, building lines, alleys, parks and other open public spaces and similar facts regarding property immediately adjacent.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Date of field survey, north point and graphic scale.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The width and location of all streets or other public ways proposed by the developer.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The proposed lot lines with dimensions.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Existing ground elevations of the property and extending not less than twenty-five (25) feet beyond the boundaries of property.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Existing easements or restrictions shown on underlying plat shall be shown.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The location of all buildings, swimming pools, slabs, fences and other permanent structures on the adjacent properties that would be nonconforming with the creation of this division of land.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>The property owner shall pay such fees as may be prescribed for checking the waiver of plat and investigating such matters concerning it as may be required.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The property owner shall submit a current opinion of title from any attorney authorized to practice law in this State with the submittal of the waiver of plat application.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Prior to the approval of the waiver of plat the property owner shall submit appropriate documentation showing the consent of any mortgage holders to the adoption of the waiver of plat.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Certification from the County that all taxes and assessments have been paid on the land within the proposed waiver of plat or receipted tax bills prior to the approval of the waiver of plat.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The property owner shall pay clerk's fees for the recordation of the governing body's resolution that approved the waiver of plat.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The property owner shall comply with all the County's Plat Committee requirements within 60 days of the recommendation for approval by the County's Plat Committee. If the property owner fails to comply with said requirements within the time prescribed, the Chief of Public Works and Waste Management's Land Development Division, or designee, shall notify the property owner that the recommendation for approval of the waiver of plat is rescinded.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-18, § 1, 3-6-79; Ord. No. 82-71, § 2, 7-20-82; Ord. No. 12-41, § 1, 6-5-12)</history></law>