<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='2'>Chapter 28 SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Procedure for platting.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003172</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28-7. Same—Procedure for platting.<section prefix='(A)'>Preliminary conference. The subdivider or his engineer, or land surveyor, prior to the preparation of the tentative plat, may informally seek the advice of the plat division of the appropriate authority in order that he may become familiar with the subdivision requirements and with the provisions of the master plan affecting the territory in which the proposed subdivision is located.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Tentative plat. The tentative plat shall show on a map all of the facts and data required by the various departments to determine whether the proposed layout of the land in the subdivision is satisfactory from the standpoint of public interest.<section prefix='(1)'>The following information shall be part of the tentative plat unless waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority.<section prefix='(a)'>Proposed subdivision name and identifying title and the name of the city, if any, in which the subdivision is located, and the section, township and range.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Location of property lines, existing easements, buildings, watercourses, elevations, permits and other essential features.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The names of all subdivisions immediately adjacent.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The location of any existing sewers and water mains, or any underground or overhead utilities, culverts and drains on the property to be subdivided.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Location, names and present widths of existing and proposed streets, highways, alleys, parks and other open public spaces and similar facts regarding property immediately adjacent.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The width and location of any street or other public ways or places shown upon the official map or the master plan, within the area to be subdivided, and the width and locations of all streets or other public ways proposed by the developer.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Date of field survey, north point and graphic scale.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Legal description and plan of proposed layout made and certified by a Florida-licensed land surveyor.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The proposed lot lines with approximate dimensions and in the case of odd or irregularly shaped lots, suggested location of building setback lines.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Where the tentative plat submitted covers only a part of the subdivider's entire holding, a master tentative plat of the prospective future street system of the unsubdivided part will be required, and the street system of the unsubmitted part will be considered in the light of adjustments and connection with the street system of the plat submitted.</section><section prefix='(k)'>A plat application signed by the owner and notarized on the form prescribed by the plat division of the appropriate authority.</section><section prefix='(l)'>The numbering of all lots, blocks and the lettering of all tracts shall be shown on the tentative plat. All lots or tracts shall be numbered or lettered progressively. All blocks shall be progressively numbered except that blocks in numbered additions bearing the same name shall be numbered consecutively throughout the several additions.</section><section prefix='(m)'>A location map at the scale of one (1) inch equals three hundred (300) feet showing existing and proposed rights-of-way.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The following information shall be submitted in addition to the tentative plat if requested by the plat division of the appropriate authority.<section prefix='(a)'>The names of owners of record of immediately adjacent property.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any changes in the use, height, area and density districts or other regulations under Chapter 33, Zoning, applicable to the area to be subdivided, and any boundaries of such districts, affecting the tracts; all parcels of land proposed to be dedicated to public use and the conditions of such dedications.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Typical cross-section of the proposed grading and roadways or sidewalks and topographic conditions.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Location of closest available subdivision or public water supply system.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Location of closest available subdivision or public sewage disposal system.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Provisions for collecting and discharging surface drainage.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Preliminary designs of any bridges or culverts which may be required.</section><section prefix='(h)'>A boundary survey.</section><section prefix='(i)'>If required by these regulations or if proposed by the subdivider, the proposed location of any type of sidewalks, street lighting standards and species of street trees, the location of curbs, gutters, water mains, sanitary sewers and storm drains and the sizes and types thereof, the character, width and depth of pavement and sub-base, and the location of manholes and basins and underground conduits.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The boundaries of proposed permanent utility easements over or under private property. Such easements shall provide satisfactory access to an existing public highway or other public open space shown upon the layout. Permanent drainage easements shall also be shown.</section><section prefix='(k)'>All dimensions affecting public rights-of-way and proposed dedication of the public rights-of-way shall be established by a registered surveyor and shown on the grading and drainage plan accompanying approved and valid tentative plats when said plan is submitted for approval, with the same degree of accuracy as, and identical to, the corresponding dimensions shown on the final plat.</section><section prefix='(l)'>A copy of owners' deed or a current opinion of title from any attorney authorized to practice law in the State.</section></section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Filing copies of tentative plat and plat application. The subdivider shall file such copies as may be required of the tentative plat with the plat division of the appropriate authority, together with the plat application. All tentative plats filed shall be reviewed for approval weekly, or at the regular meeting of the plat division, and the tentative plats should be filed at least ten (10) days in advance of the meeting at which approval is sought.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Checking and investigating. The subdivider shall pay such fees as may be prescribed by ordinance for checking the tentative plat and investigating such matters concerning it as may be required by law and this chapter.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Approval of tentative plat. On plats that lie within the unincorporated areas of the County, copies of the tentative plat shall be distributed by the Department of Public Works to the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Department of Florida Health and to such other departments as may be necessary. Tentative approval shall confer upon the subdivider the right for a nine months period from the date of approval that the terms and conditions under which the tentative approval was granted will not be changed if the final plat is in accordance with the tentative approval.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Appeal of the County's plat division decision. Decisions of the County's plat division may be appealed within 14 (fourteen) days to the Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee as defined in Section 33-303.1(B) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida; and appeals of the Executive Council's decision shall be by application for variance from Chapter 28 (Section 28-19) or, if applicable, by appeal of administrative decision pursuant to Section 33-314(C)(1) Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The fourteen-day appeal period provided herein shall commence on the day after notification that the plat division has taken action on the particular matter, such notification to be given by the division through the posting of a short, concise statement of the action taken on a conspicuous bulletin board that may be seen by the public at reasonable times and hours in the office of the Public Works Department. Where the fourteenth day falls on a weekend or legal holiday the appeal period shall be deemed to extend through the next business day.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 78-12, § 2, 3-21-78; Ord. No. 82-71, § 3, 7-20-82; Ord. No. 89-10, § 8, 2-21-89; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 18, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-123, § 2, 9-21-99; Ord. No. 99-147, § 1, 10-19-99; Ord. No. 02-259, § 1, 12-3-02)</history></law>