<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='2'>Chapter 28 SUBDIVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Final plat.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003173</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28-8. Same—Final plat.<section prefix='(a)'>Conformity to tentative plat. The final plat shall have incorporated all changes or modifications as required to make the tentative plat conform to the requirements of this chapter. Otherwise it shall conform to the tentative plat, and it may constitute only that portion of the approved tentative plat which the subdivider proposed to record and develop at the time, provided that such portion conforms with all requirements of this chapter and meets with the approval of the various departments concerned.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Preparation. The final plat shall be prepared by a land surveyor registered in the state. The final plat shall be clearly and legibly drawn, to a sheet size of thirty (30) inches by thirty-six (36) inches and to a scale of sufficient size to be legible, with letters and numbers to be no smaller than one-eighth () of an inch in height. The final plat, insofar as preparation is concerned, shall comply with all applicable regulations and State laws dealing with the preparation of plats.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Contents.<section prefix='(1)'>Name of the subdivision. The plat shall have a title or name. If the plat be a town, city or village, the full name of such town, city or village must appear as the title or name of the plat subdivision. If the land platted be an addition to or a subdivision of a town, city or village already platted, then the title of the plat shall include, with the name of such addition or subdivision, the name of the town, city or village, as the case may be, and section, township and range of which such platted land is a subdivision, or to which it is an addition. The terms "Town," "City," "Village" or any other term suggesting a municipal corporation, shall not appear in the title or name of any plat which includes any property in the unincorporated area. The plat division of the appropriate authority shall disapprove any name or title which he may find to be sufficiently similar to the name of any existing town, city, village or municipal corporation, or the name similar to any previously approved plat in the incorporated or unincorporated areas of the County which may cause confusion as to the status or the location of any platted property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Deed description. Description written on map or plat. There shall be written or printed upon the plat a full and detailed description of the land embraced in the map or plat showing the township and range in which such lands are situated and the section and part of sections platted and a location sketch showing the plat's location in reference to the closest centers of each section embraced within the plat. The description must be so complete that from it, without reference to the plat, the starting point can be determined and the outlines run. If a subdivision of a part of a previously recorded plat is made, the previous lots and blocks to be resubdivided shall be given. If the plat be a resubdivision of the whole of a previously recorded plat, the fact shall be so stated. Vacation of previously platted lands must be accomplished in the manner provided by law.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Names of adjacent subdivisions.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Names or numbers and width of streets immediately adjoining plat.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All plat boundaries.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Bearings and distances to the nearest established street lines, section corners or other recognized permanent monuments which shall be accurately described on the plat.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Municipal, township, County or section lines accurately tied to the lines of the subdivision by distance and bearing.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Accurate location of all monuments.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Length of all arcs, radii, internal angles, points of curvature and tangent bearings.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Where lots are located on a curve or when side lot lines are at angles less than eighty-seven (87) degrees or more than ninety-three (93) degrees, the width of the lot at the front building setback line shall be shown.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The name or numbering and right-of-way width of each street or other right-of-way shown on plat.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The numbering of all lots and blocks shown on the plat. All lots shall be numbered either by progressive numbers, or in blocks progressively numbered, except that blocks in numbered additions bearing the same name shall be numbered consecutively throughout the several additions. Excepted parcels must be marked "not part of this plat."</section><section prefix='(13)'>Plat restrictions to restrict type and use of water supply; type and use of sanitary facilities; use and benefits of water areas and other open spaces and odd-shaped and substandard parcels; resubdivision of parcels as "platted," and restrictions of similar nature.</section><section prefix='(14)'>All areas reserved or dedicated for public purposes. No strip or parcel of land shall be reserved by the owner, unless the same is sufficient in size and area to be of some practical use or service.</section><section prefix='(15)'>The dimensions of all lots and angles or bearings.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Minimum building setback lines where required by ordinance.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Location, dimension and purpose of any easements.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Certification by a registered surveyor to the effect that the plat represents a survey made by him, and that all monuments shown thereon actually exist, and that their location is correctly shown.</section><section prefix='(19)'>An acknowledgment by the owner of his adoption of the plat, and of the dedication of streets and other public areas and the consent of any mortgage holders to such adoption and dedication. If existing right-of-way is to be closed, purpose of closing must be stated on the plat.</section><section prefix='(20)'>The signature and seal of the governing body. On plats within the unincorporated areas of the County, the signature of the Director of Public Works, the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Clerk and Mayor and, in his absence, the Chairman of the County Commission. Provided, however, that where property is being replatted the signatures of the governing body shall be affixed or denied pursuant to the procedures established in Section 177.101, Florida Statutes (1971), unless the vacation of prior plats has previously been validly accomplished.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Other data required with plat.<section prefix='(1)'>Restrictive covenants desired by the developer so long as they do not violate existing ordinances. Restrictive covenants shall be required covering the same restrictions included in subsection (c)(13) of this section; restrictions controlling building lines, establishment and maintenance of buffer strips and walls, and restrictions of similar nature.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The surveyor shall show on the face of the plat (or shall certify on a separate sheet, not to be recorded in the public records) the Florida State Plane Coordinates (current readjustment) of at least two (2) of the permanent reference monuments shown on the plat. This requirement may be waived by the plat division of the appropriate authority if (A) any portion of the land encompassed by the plat is more than one (1) mile from the nearest station shown on the list on file in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department's Survey Office, as updated; or (B) all stations within one (1) mile of the plat have been lost. A copy of the certified corner record (as defined in Section 177.503 Florida Statutes (1993)), for the corners used shall be provided with the final plat.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Current opinion of title from any attorney authorized to practice law in this State.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Certification from the city and County that all taxes and assessments have been paid on the land within the proposed subdivision or receipted tax bills.</section><section prefix='(5)'>If a zoning change is involved, certification from the appropriate agency shall be furnished indicating that the change requested has been approved and is in effect, and that the size of lots and other features shown on the plat conform to all zoning requirements. Signing of the final plat by the director of that agency shall constitute such certification.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Clerk's fees for recording the plat.</section><section prefix='(7)'>On plats within municipalities certification from the appropriate agency shall be submitted to the County's plat division certifying that all required improvements within the public right-of-way have been completed or that the municipality is holding sufficient bond for the completion of the improvements. The certification shall also state that the plat appears to conform to all of the requirements of this chapter. The County's plat division shall review certification from the appropriate agency within forty-five (45) days of the acknowledged receipt of the plats. Failure of the County to act on said plats within forty-five (45) days of the acknowledged receipt of the plat shall be deemed an approval of the plat.</section><section prefix='(8)'>No plat shall be entitled for recording in the Clerk's office until the plat is signed by the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Works, certifying that the plat appears to conform to all of the requirements of this chapter. A certification of the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Works need not appear if the plat division of the appropriate authority submits an affidavit to the Clerk stating that the County has not acted on said plat within forty-five (45) days of the acknowledged receipt of the subject plat.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-6, § 1, 2-1-77; Ord. No. 94-51, § 1, 3-17-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 18, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-123, § 2, 9-21-99)</history></law>