<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='2'>Chapter 28A SEAPORT SECURITY AND OPERATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28A-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Freight security.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003195</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28A-9. Freight security.<section>No person shall operate or use any vehicle or motor vehicle in the area of cargo operations or other restricted area to transport freight of any kind without an identification permit. All such persons must have a written pickup or delivery order pertaining to each vehicle or motor vehicle to be loaded or unloaded in the ACO or other restricted area. The aforesaid pickup or delivery order shall be a bill of lading or an order form or on a letterhead of the firm owning the freight or of the agent of the owner of the freight. Such order must be signed by an officer of the company or person authorized to sign such an order. Said order must describe the freight, the amount to be loaded, the vessel and the bill of lading numbers and marks, if any, on the freight. Any person not having such written order shall not enter the area of cargo operations or other restricted area. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section><section>No person shall knowingly allow any freight from the port to be loaded or carried aboard a vessel unless it is properly documented and manifested as freight to be loaded on that vessel. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section><section></section><section prefix='(a)'>Whenever any shortage or suspected shortage is discovered as to any freight, an official company representative or company supervisor in charge of the freight or its movement at the time of the discovery of such shortage shall immediately notify the Miami-Dade Police Department. Such official company representative shall be responsible for giving all pertinent information concerning such freight or movement to the investigating Law Enforcement Officer and shall render all reasonable assistance to the officer.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The official company representative or supervisor in charge of the cargo at the time the shortage is discovered shall, within twenty-four (24) hours from the time of discovery, complete an original and five (5) copies of the "Preliminary Cargo Security Incident Report" form available in the office of the Director. The original report shall be forwarded to the Miami-Dade Police Department. The remaining copies shall be distributed as indicated on the form.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All Port of Miami stevedore permit holders shall, if they have knowledge, immediately notify the Miami-Dade Police Department of the arrival or scheduled arrival of any shipment by land or water at the port of any firearms, weapons, destructive devices, explosives, or electric weapons or devices, as defined in Section 790.001, Florida Statutes, or any hazardous material, as defined in 49 U.S.C. 1802. Notification shall occur with the receipt of the freight by the stevedore with actual knowledge of its contents, or with the receipt by the stevedore of the freight manifest revealing the nature of the freight, whichever occurs first. Failure of any Port of Miami stevedore permit holder to notify the Miami-Dade Police Department as required herein shall constitute a violation of Chapter 28A of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 95-200, § 1, 11-7-95; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97; Ord. No. 98-78, § 7, 6-2-98)</section><section></section><section>Section 709 of the Port of Miami Tariff No. 10 is hereby amended and restated as follows:<section>All vehicles which use the Seaport Department's Vehicle Examination Facility for the purpose of being inspected or processed by U.S. Customs, in accordance with Public Law 98-673 or otherwise, will be assessed a usage fee in the amount of $7.50 per vehicle, which shall be collected by the Seaport Department. (Ord. No. 95-200, § 1, 11-7-95; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section></section><section></section><section>Two dollars and fifty cents ($2.50) of every seven dollars and fifty cents ($7.50) collected by the seaport pursuant to section 28A-9.4 of this chapter shall be allocated to the Miami-Dade County Multi-Agency Auto Theft Task Force for purposes of enhancing security at, and interdicting the flow of stolen motor vehicles through the Port of Miami. (Ord. No. 95-200, § 1, 11-7-95; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section></section></text></law>