<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='2'>Chapter 28A SEAPORT SECURITY AND OPERATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>28A-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Identification permit for vehicles and motor vehicles.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003190</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 28A-4. Identification permit for vehicles and motor vehicles.<section>Any person employed at the port on a permanent basis and driving a motor vehicle onto port premises and all persons owning, leasing, or operating one (1) or more vehicles or motor vehicles operating on the port and entering into or departing from the ACO or a restricted area (other than cruise vessel passengers engaged in vessel embarkation or disembarkation) shall obtain and maintain a current identification permit for each vehicle from the Department. Such permit may be a numbered decal reflecting the authorization to enter into the ACO or restricted area. Application for such permit must be accompanied by copies of the vehicle registration, certificate of insurance and the applicant's driver's license, as well as the driver's license of all anticipated operators of such vehicle or motor vehicle. The completed application for such permit (one (1) for each vehicle or motor vehicle) shall be submitted in duplicate on a form designed by Miami-Dade County. The owner or operator of such vehicle shall cause the permit to be permanently affixed to the vehicle or motor vehicle for which the permit was issued, and in a manner and place specified by the Director, so that it shall be plainly visible. Such permits shall be renewed by the vehicle or motor vehicle owner in a manner prescribed by the Director, annually before its expiration. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section><section></section><section prefix='(a)'>A temporary limited identification permit, in the form of a pass, may be issued by the Director to the operator of a vehicle or motor vehicle for occasional or one-time access to a specific area within the area of cargo operations or restricted area or for a vehicle or motor vehicle engaged in construction activities within the port and approved by the Director. An owner of such vehicle shall obtain a permit at the Director's office or at the area of cargo operations upon approval by the Director. When issued it shall identify the vehicle or motor vehicle operator, operator's address, operator's driver's license number and issuing state and be valid only for the area designated, parking area (if any) and duration stamped on its face. The owner and operator of such vehicle shall cause it to be plainly visible at all times on the vehicle or motor vehicle to which it is issued. The permit shall be returned at the control gate when departing from the area of cargo operations or restricted area or at the Director's office when departing from other portions of the port.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A record of such temporary permits shall be maintained at the control gate. Any vehicle or motor vehicle operator who enters or who operates a vehicle or motor vehicle within the area of cargo operations more than five (5) times during a four-week period on a temporary permit may be denied a temporary identification permit and be required to obtain a permanent identification permit therefor. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section><section>The owner, as defined in subsection 28A-2.1(16), shall report, in writing, to the Director or the office where the identification permit was originally processed, certain changes in the data on any application for a temporary, permanent, or construction vehicle, or motor vehicle permit within thirty (30) days of any of the following changes, namely:<section prefix='(1)'>New vehicle license plate (tag or decal) number;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any change in data on vehicle registration certificate or driver's license of applicant;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Sale or other disposition of the registered vehicle, including the name and address of the transferee of any interest therein;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Change of vehicle color, motor or title number;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Loss or damage to permanent, temporary or construction vehicle or motor vehicle permit;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Change of regularly assigned place of employment;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Change of applicant's employer; or</section><section prefix='(8)'>Change in home address or business address of owner of the registered vehicle.</section></section><section>Failure to report such changes by an owner or operator within ten (10) days of the change will result in the suspension of the current vehicle identification permit and shall cause operator's access to area of cargo operations or restricted area to be revoked until the change information is furnished. False statements in the change information shall be a violation of. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section><section></section><section prefix='(a)'>All owners and operators of commercial vehicles or motor vehicles operated or used within the port shall comply with Section 8A-276, Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Before any leased vehicle or motor vehicle is authorized entry into the area of cargo operations or any restricted area, the operator thereof upon demand by the Director or Department employee or any Law Enforcement Officer shall comply with Section 28A-4 hereof and shall also present a legible copy of the agreement authorizing the use of the said vehicle by the operator or his employer. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section><section></section><section prefix='(a)'>Any taxicab licensed pursuant to Section 31-82 of the County Code and for which a permit issued under Section 31-93(d) of the County Code is current and valid shall have the right to transport persons and their baggage from the Port of Miami.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Except for taxicabs as set forth in (a) above, no person shall transport another person or baggage by mini-bus, bus, passenger van, limousine, or any other passenger motor vehicle, or courtesy vehicle from the port, or engage in commercial activity on the port, without a valid permit issued by the Director and payment of any fee established in the Port of Miami Terminal Tariff.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It shall be unlawful for the operator of any motor vehicle to park in the ACO or any restricted area or in any loading zone for any longer period than is necessary to load or discharge persons or baggage.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall operate a motor vehicle contrary to posted signs.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No person shall solicit or engage in the rental car business on the port without a valid permit issued by the Director and payment of any fee established in the Port of Miami Terminal Tariff.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Nothing contained herein shall be construed to authorize the operation of a passenger motor vehicle or courtesy vehicle in violation of any other provisions of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, specifically including but not limited to Chapter 31. (Ord. No. 78-65, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 81-85, § 4, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 88-116, § 2, 12-6-88; Ord. No. 97-161, § 1, 9-23-97)</section></section></text></law>