<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. DISCRETIONARY SALES SURTAX AUTHORIZED BY SECTION 212.055(1), FLORIDA STATUTES (1999).</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-117</section_number>
<catch_line>Exemption from Sales Surtax.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003292</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-117. Exemption from Sales Surtax.<section>All exemptions applicable to the discretionary sales surtax contained in Chapter 212, Florida Statutes are hereby incorporated herein as the same may be amended and supplemented from time to time including, but not limited to, the following:<section prefix='1.'>The tax on any sales amount above five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) on any item of tangible personal property and on long-distance telephone service shall not be subject to the sales surtax. For purposes of administering the five thousand dollar ($5,000.00) limitation of an item of tangible personal property, if two (2) or more taxable items of tangible personal property are sold to the same purchaser at the same time and, under generally accepted business practice or industry standards or usage, are normally sold in bulk or are items that, when assembled, comprise a working unit or part of a working unit, such items must be considered a single item for purposes of the five thousand dollar ($5,000.00) limitation when supported by a charge ticket, sale slip, invoice, or other tangible evidence of a single sale or rental. The limitation provided in this subsection does not apply to the sale of any other service.</section><section prefix='2.'>The sale at retail, the rental, the use, the consumption; the distribution, and the storage to be used or consumed in this state of the following are hereby specifically exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article.<section prefix='(1)'>Exemptions; General groceries.<section prefix='(a)'>There are exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article food and drinks for human consumption except candy. Unless the exemption provided by Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, for school lunches, for meals to certain patients or inmates, for meals provided by certain nonprofit organizations, or for food or drinks sold through vending machines pertains, none of such items of food or drinks means:<section prefix='1.'>Food or drinks services, prepared, or sold in or by restaurants; drugstores; lunch counters; cafeterias; hotels; amusement parks; racetracks; taverns; concession stands at arenas, auditoriums, carnivals, fairs, stadiums, theaters, or other like places of business; or by any business or place required by law to be licensed by the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, except bakery products sold in or by pastry shops, doughnut shops, or like establishments for consumption off the premises;</section><section prefix='2.'>Foods and drinks sold ready for immediate consumption from vending machines, pushcarts, motor vehicles, or any other form of vehicle;</section><section prefix='3.'>Soft drinks, which include, but are not limited to, any nonalcoholic beverage, any preparation or beverage commonly referred to as a "soft drink," or any noncarbonated drink made from milk derivatives or tea, when sold in cans or similar containers. The term "soft drink" does not include: natural fruit or vegetable juices or their concentrates or reconstituted natural concentrated fruit or vegetable juices, whether frozen or unfrozen, dehydrated, powdered, granulated, sweetened or unsweetened, seasoned with salt or spice, or unseasoned; coffee or coffee substitutes; tea except when sold in containers as provided herein; cocoa; products intended to be mixed with milk; or natural fluid milk;</section><section prefix='4.'>Foods or drinks cooked or prepared on the seller's premises and sold ready for immediate consumption either on or off the premises, excluding bakery products for off-premises consumption unless such foods are taxed under Subsection 1 or Subsection 2; or</section><section prefix='5.'>Sandwiches sold ready for immediate consumption.</section><section>For the purposes of this section, "Seller's premises" shall be construed broadly, and means, but is not limited to, the lobby, aisle, or auditorium of a theater, the seating, aisle, or parking area of an arena, rink, or stadium; or the parking area of a drive-in or outdoor theater. The premises of a caterer with respect to catered meals or beverages shall be the place where such meals or beverages are served.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Food or drinks not exempt under Section (a) shall be exempt, notwithstanding that Section, when purchased with food coupons or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children vouchers issued under authority of federal law.<section prefix='2.'>This section is effective only while federal law prohibits a state's participation in the federal food coupon program of Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children if there is an official determination that state or local sales taxes are collected within that state on purchases of food or drinks with such coupons.</section><section prefix='3.'>This section shall not apply to any food or drinks on which federal law shall permit sales taxes without penalty, such as termination of the state's participation.</section><section prefix='4.'>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department of Revenue shall make refunds or allow credits to a distributor equal to the fee imposed and paid under Section 403.7197 on containers purchased by consumers with food coupons or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children vouchers issued under authority of federal law.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Exemptions; Medical.<section prefix='(a)'>There shall be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article any product, supply, or medicine dispensed in a retail establishment by a pharmacist licensed by the state, according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a prescriber authorized by law to prescribe medicinal drugs; hypodermic needles; hypodermic syringes; chemical compounds and test kits used for the diagnosis or treatment of human disease, illness, or injury; and common household remedies recommended and generally sold for internal and external use in the cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of illness or disease in human beings, but not including cosmetics or toilet articles, notwithstanding the presence of medicinal ingredients therein, according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue. There shall also be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article artificial eyes and limbs; orthopedic shoes; prescription eyeglasses and items incidental thereto or which become a part thereof; dentures; hearing aids; crutches; prosthetic and orthopedic appliances; and funerals. In addition, any items intended for one-time use which transfer essential optical characteristics to contact lenses shall be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article, however, this exemption shall apply only after one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) of the sales surtax imposed by this article on such items has been paid in any calendar year by a taxpayer who claims the exemption in such year. Funeral directors shall pay tax on all tangible personal property used by them in their business.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For the purposes of this subsection:<section prefix='1.'>Prosthetic and orthopedic appliances means any apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment used to replace or substitute for any missing part of the body, to alleviate the malfunction of any part of the body, or to assist any disabled person in leading a normal life by facilitating such person's mobility. Such apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment shall be exempted according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a physician licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466, Florida Statutes, or according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue.</section><section prefix='2.'>Cosmetics means articles intended to be rubbed, poured, sprinkled, or sprayed on, introduced into, or otherwise applied to the human body for cleaning, beautifying, promoting attractiveness, or altering the appearance and also means articles intended for use as a compound of any such articles, including, but not limited to, cold creams, suntan lotions, makeup, and body lotions.</section><section prefix='3.'>Toilet articles means any article advertised or held out for sale for grooming purposes and those articles that are customarily used for grooming purposes, regardless of the name by which they may be known, including, but not limited to, soap, toothpaste, hair spray, shaving products, colognes, perfumes, shampoo, deodorant, and mouthwash.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Chlorine shall not be exempt from the tax imposed by this article when used for the treatment of water in swimming pools.</section><section prefix='(d)'>This subsection shall be strictly construed and enforced.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-68, ยง 1, 6-22-99)</history></law>