<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. ONE HALF OF ONE PERCENT CHARTER COUNTY TRANSIT SYSTEM SALES SURTAX AUTHORIZED BY SECTION 212.055(1) FLORIDA STATUTES (2001)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-122.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Exemption from Sales Surtax.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003298</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-122.1. Exemption from Sales Surtax.<section>All exemptions applicable to the discretionary sales surtax contained in Chapter 212, Florida Statutes are hereby incorporated herein as the same may be amended and supplemented from time to time including, but not limited to, the following:<section prefix='1.'>The sales amount above $5,000 on any item of tangible personal property shall not be subject to the surtax. However, charges for prepaid calling arrangements, as defined in Section 212.05(1)(e)1.a. Fla. Stats., shall be subject to the surtax. For purposes of administering the $5,000 limitation of an item of tangible personal property, if two or more taxable items of tangible personal property are sold to the same purchaser at the same time and, under generally accepted business practice or industry standards or usage, are normally sold in bulk or are items that, when assembled, comprise a working unit or part of a working unit, such items must be considered a single item for purposes of the $5,000 limitation when supported by a charge ticket, sale slip, invoice, or other tangible evidence of a single sale or rental.</section><section prefix='2.'>The sale at retail, the rental, the use, the consumption, the distribution, and the storage to be used or consumed in this state of the following are hereby specifically exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article.<section prefix='(1)'>Exemptions; General Groceries.<section prefix='(a)'>Food products for human consumption are exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For the purpose of this article, as used in this subsection, the term "food products" means edible commodities, whether processed, cooked, raw, canned, or in any other form, which are generally regarded as food. This includes, but is not limited to, all of the following:<section prefix='1.'>Cereals and cereal products, baked goods, oleomargarine, meat and meat products, fish and seafood products, frozen foods and dinners, poultry, eggs and egg products, vegetables and vegetable products, fruit and fruit products, spices, salt, sugar and sugar products, milk and dairy products, and products intended to be mixed with milk.</section><section prefix='2.'>Natural fruit or vegetable juices or their concentrates or reconstituted natural concentrated fruit or vegetable juices, whether frozen or unfrozen, dehydrated, powdered, granulated, sweetened or unsweetened, seasoned with salt or spice, or unseasoned; coffee, coffee substitutes, or cocoa; and tea, unless it is sold in a liquid form.</section><section prefix='3.'>Bakery products sold by bakeries, pastry shops, or like establishments that do not have eating facilities.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The exemption provided by this subsection does not apply:<section prefix='1.'>When the food products are sold as meals for consumption on or off the premises of the dealer.</section><section prefix='2.'>When the food, products are furnished, prepared, or served for consumption at tables, chairs, or counters or from trays, glasses, dishes, or other tableware, whether provided by the dealer or by a person with whom the dealer contracts to furnish, prepare, or serve food products to others.</section><section prefix='3.'>When the food products are ordinarily sold for immediate consumption on the seller's premises or near a location at which parking facilities are provided primarily for the use of patrons in consuming the products purchased at the location, even though such products are sold on a "take out" or "to go" order and are actually packaged or wrapped and taken from the premises of the dealer.</section><section prefix='4.'>To sandwiches sold ready for immediate consumption on or off the seller's premises.</section><section prefix='5.'>When the food products are sold ready for immediate consumption within a place, the entrance to which is subject to an admission charge.</section><section prefix='6.'>When the food products are sold as hot prepared food products.</section><section prefix='7.'>To soft drinks, which include, but are not limited to, any nonalcoholic beverage, any preparation or beverage commonly referred to as a "soft drink," or any noncarbonated drink made from milk derivatives or tea, when sold in cans or similar containers.</section><section prefix='8.'>To ice cream, frozen yogurt, and similar frozen dairy or nondairy products in cones, small cups, or pints, popsicles, frozen fruit bars, or other novelty items, whether or not sold separately.</section><section prefix='9.'>To food prepared, whether on or off the premises, and sold for immediate consumption. This does not apply to food prepared off the premises and sold in the original sealed container, or the slicing of products into smaller portions.</section><section prefix='10.'>When the food products are sold through a vending machine, pushcart, motor vehicle, or any other form of vehicle.</section><section prefix='11.'>To candy and any similar product regarded as candy or confection, based on its normal use, as indicated on the label or advertising thereof.</section><section prefix='12.'>To bakery products sold by bakeries, pastry shops, or like establishments that have eating facilities, except when sold for consumption off the seller's premises.</section><section prefix='13.'>When food products are served, prepared, or sold in or by restaurants, lunch counters, cafeterias, hotels, taverns, or other like places of business.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>As used in this subsection (1), the term:<section prefix='1.'>"For consumption off the seller's premises" means that the food or drink is intended by the customer to be consumed at a place away from the dealer's premises.</section><section prefix='2.'>"For consumption on the seller's premises" means that the food or drink sold may be immediately consumed on the premises where the dealer conducts his or her business. In determining whether an item of food is sold for immediate consumption, there shall be considered the customary consumption practices prevailing at the selling facility.</section><section prefix='3.'>"Premises" shall be construed broadly, and means, but is not limited to, the lobby, aisle, or auditorium of a theater; the seating, aisle, or parking area of an arena, rink, or stadium; or the parking area of a drive-in or outdoor theater. The premises of a caterer with respect to catered meals or beverages shall be the place where such meals or beverages are served.</section><section prefix='4.'>"Hot prepared food products" means those products, items, or components which have been prepared for sale in a heated condition and which are sold at any temperature that is higher than the air temperature of the room or place where they are sold. "Hot prepared food products," for the purposes of this subsection, includes a combination of hot and cold food items or components where a single price has been established for the combination and the food products are sold in such combination, such as a hot meal, a hot specialty dish or serving, or a hot sandwich or hot pizza, including cold components or side items.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Food or drinks not exempt under paragraphs (a), (b), (c), and (d) shall be exempt, notwithstanding those paragraphs, when-purchased with food coupons or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children vouchers issued under authority of federal law.<section prefix='2.'>This paragraph (e) is effective only while federal law prohibits a state's participation in the federal food coupon program or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children if there is an official determination that state or local sales taxes are collected within that state on purchases of food or drinks with such coupons.</section><section prefix='3.'>This paragraph (e) shall not apply to any food or drinks on which federal law shall permit sales taxes without penalty, such as termination of the state's participation.</section></section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Exemptions medical.<section prefix='(a)'>There shall be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article any medical products and supplies or medicine dispensed according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a prescriber authorized by law to prescribe medicinal drugs; hypodermic needles; hypodermic syringes; chemical compounds and test kits used for the diagnosis or treatment of human disease, illness, or injury; and common household remedies recommended and generally sold for internal and external use in the cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of illness or disease in human beings, but not including cosmetics or toilet articles, notwithstanding the presence of medicinal ingredients therein, according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Health, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue. There shall also be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article artificial eyes and limbs; orthopedic shoes; prescription eyeglasses and items incidental thereto or which become a part thereof; dentures; hearing aids; crutches; prosthetic and orthopedic appliances; and funerals. In addition, any items intended for one-time use which transfer essential optical characteristics to contact lenses shall be exempt from the sales surtax imposed by this article, however, this exemption shall apply only after $100,000 of the sales surtax imposed by this article on such items has been paid in any calendar year by a taxpayer who claims the exemption in such year. Funeral directors shall pay tax on all tangible personal property used by them in their business.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For the purposes of this subsection (2):<section prefix='1.'>"Prosthetic and orthopedic appliances" means any apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment used to replace or substitute for any missing part of the body, to alleviate the malfunction of any part of the body, or to assist any disabled person in leading a normal life by facilitating such person's mobility. Such apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment shall be exempted according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a physician licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466, Florida Statutes, or according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Health, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue.</section><section prefix='2.'>"Cosmetics" means articles intended to be rubbed, poured, sprinkled, or sprayed on, introduced into, or otherwise applied to the human body for cleaning, beautifying, promoting attractiveness, or altering the appearance and also means articles intended for use as a compound of any such articles, including, but not limited to, cold creams, suntan lotions, makeup, and body lotions.</section><section prefix='3.'>"Toilet articles" means any article advertised or held out for sale for grooming purposes and those articles that are customarily used for grooming purposes, regardless of the name by which they may be known, including, but not limited to, soap, toothpaste, hair spray, shaving products, colognes, perfumes, shampoo, deodorant, and mouthwash.</section><section prefix='4.'>"Prescription" includes any order for drugs or medicinal supplies written or transmitted by any means of communication by a duly licensed practitioner authorized by the laws of the state to prescribe such drugs or medicinal supplies and intended to be dispensed by a pharmacist. The term also includes an orally transmitted order by the lawfully designated agent of such practitioner. The term also includes an order written or transmitted by a practitioner licensed to practice in a jurisdiction other than this state, but only if the pharmacist called upon to dispense such order determines, in the exercise of his or her professional judgment, that the order is valid and necessary for the treatment of a chronic or recurrent illness. The term also includes a pharmacist's order for a product selected from the formulary created pursuant to Sec. 465.186 Fla. Stats. A prescription may be retained in written form, or the pharmacist may cause it to be recorded in a data processing system, provided that such order can be produced in printed form upon lawful request.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Chlorine shall not be exempt from the tax imposed by this article when used for the treatment of water in swimming pools.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Lithotripters are exempt.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Human organs are exempt.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Sales of drugs to or by physicians, dentists, veterinarians, and hospitals in connection with medical treatment are exempt.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Medical products and supplies used in the cure, mitigation, alleviation, prevention, or treatment of injury, disease, or incapacity which are temporarily or permanently incorporated into a patient or client by a practitioner of the healing arts licensed in the state are exempt.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The purchase by a veterinarian of commonly recognized substances possessing curative or remedial properties which are ordered and dispensed as treatment for a diagnosed health disorder by or on the prescription of a duly licensed veterinarian, and which are applied to or consumed by animals for alleviation of pain or the cure or prevention of sickness, disease, or suffering are exempt. Also exempt are the purchase by a veterinarian of antiseptics, absorbent cotton, gauze for bandages, lotions, vitamins, and worm remedies.</section><section prefix='(i)'>X-ray opaques, also known as opaque drugs and radiopaque, such as the various opaque dyes and barium sulphate, when used in connection with medical X rays for treatment of bodies of humans and animals, are exempt.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Parts, special attachments, special lettering, and other like items that are added to or attached to tangible personal property so that a handicapped person can use them are exempt when such items are purchased by a person pursuant to an individual prescription.</section><section prefix='(k)'>This subsection (2) shall be strictly construed and enforced.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-116, ยง 1, 7-9-02)</history></law>