<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE V. TOURIST DEVELOPMENT ROOM TAX</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-51</section_number>
<catch_line>Levy and imposition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003224</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-51. Levy and imposition.<section prefix='(a)'>There shall be levied and imposed throughout the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida, except within the municipal limits of Miami Beach, Bal Harbour and Surfside: (1) a tourist development room tax; (2) a professional sports franchise facility tax; and (3) a homeless and spouse abuse tax. The tourist development room tax shall be imposed at a rate of two (2) percent, and the professional sports franchise facility tax shall be imposed at a rate of one (1) percent, of each whole and major fraction of each dollar of the total rental charged every person who rents, leases or lets for consideration any living quarters or accommodations in any hotel, apartment hotel, motel, resort motel, apartment, apartment motel, rooming house, mobile home park, recreational vehicle park, or condominium for a term of six (6) months or less. When receipt of consideration is by way of property other than money, the tax shall be levied and imposed on the fair market value of such nonmonetary considerations. An oral lease, payable weekly, monthly or otherwise, shall not be subject to the tax where the tenant occupies a residential unit located in a facility in which the residential units are leased primarily as permanent residences. Living quarters or accommodations which are exempt according to the provisions of Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, shall also not be subject to the tax.</section><section prefix='(b)'>There shall also be levied and imposed throughout the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida, except within the municipal limits of those municipalities presently imposing a municipal resort tax pursuant to Chapter 67-930, Florida Statutes, a tourist development surtax at a rate of two (2) percent of each whole and major fraction of each dollar of the total amount charged every person for the purchase of food, beverages or alcoholic beverages in any hotel or motel. When receipt of consideration is by way of property other than money, the tax shall be levied and imposed on the fair market value of such nonmonetary consideration.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to the tourism development room tax, the professional sports franchise facility tax and the tourism development surtax, there shall be levied and imposed throughout the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, except within the municipal limits of those municipalities presently imposing a municipal resort tax pursuant to Chapter 67-930, Florida Statutes, a homeless and spouse abuse tax. The homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be imposed at the rate of one (1) percent on each whole and major fraction of each dollar charged every person for the purchase of food, beverages or alcoholic beverages in establishments that are licensed by the State of Florida to sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises, except hotels and motels. The tax shall not apply to: (1) any item sold by the package for off premises consumption; (2) sales of food, beverages or alcoholic beverages in establishments licensed by the state to sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises which during the previous calendar year, calculated from July 1 until the following June 30, had gross annual revenues of four hundred thousand dollars ($400,000.00) or less; (3) food, beverage and alcoholic beverage sales in any veterans, fraternal, or other chartered or incorporated club licensed under Section 565.02(4), Florida Statutes; and (4) all sales or transactions which are exempt from the state sales tax.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The tourist development room tax, the professional sports franchise facility tax, the tourist development surtax, and the homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be in addition to any other tax imposed pursuant to Chapter 212, Florida Statutes, and in addition to all other taxes, fees and the considerations for the rental or lease of living quarters or accommodations as described in Section 29-51(a), or for the purchase of food, beverages and alcoholic beverages from the establishments described in Section 29-51(b).</section><section prefix='(e)'>The tourist development room tax and the professional sports franchise facility tax shall be charged by the person receiving the consideration for the lease or rental, and it shall be collected from the lessee, tenant or customer at the time of payment of the consideration for such lease or rental. The tourist development surtax and the homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be charged by the person receiving the consideration for the food, beverages or alcoholic beverages, and it shall be collected at the time of payment for such food, beverage or alcoholic beverage.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-62, § 1, 10-4-78; Ord. No. 84-88, § 1, 11-6-84; Ord. No. 90-33, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 90-116, § 1, 10-16-90; Ord. No. 93-75, § 1, 7-27-93)</history></law>