<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE V. TOURIST DEVELOPMENT ROOM TAX</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-54</section_number>
<catch_line>Disposition of revenues; review of expenditures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003232</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-54. Disposition of revenues; review of expenditures.<section prefix='(a)'>Tourist development room tax.<section prefix='(1)'>Collections received by the Tax Collector from the tourist development room tax, less costs of administration, are to be deposited in the "Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Trust Fund," herewith established, and used in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Plan, which provides for the allocation of funds as follows:<section prefix='1.'>To fund the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau (sixty (60) percent less the following amounts, the allocation of which shall be made by the Board of County Commissioners after receipt of the recommendations of the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Council: (i) $550,000.00 in 1993-94; (ii) $575,000.00 in 1994-95; and (iii) $600,000.00 in 1995-96 and each year thereafter.) Funds allocated pursuant to the recommendations of the Tourist Development Council shall be for the tourism purposes described in the following subparagraph 2.</section><section prefix='2.'>To promote Miami-Dade County tourism by sponsoring tourist-oriented culture, cultural and special events such as visual and performing arts including theater, concerts, recitals, opera, dance, art, exhibitions, festivals and other tourist-related activities. (Twenty (20) percent). In determining expenditures from the twenty (20) percent portion of this allocation the County Commission may consider the recommendations of the Miami-Dade County Cultural Affairs Council.</section><section prefix='3.'>To promote tourism, to fund tourist-related facilities as allowed by law, and to fund tourist-oriented events located within the municipal boundaries of the City of Miami, as determined by the Board of the County Commissioners and for fiscal year 2012-13, to finance within the County beach park facilities or beach improvement, maintenance, renourishment, restoration, and erosion control, including shoreline protection, enhancement or cleanup, as those uses relate to the physical preservation of the beach or shoreline, or for any other uses within the County's boundaries permitted by law. (Twenty (20) percent).</section><section prefix='4.'>To use as a secondary pledge to pay debt service on bonds issued to finance the construction, reconstruction, or renovation of professional sports franchise facilities (the "Professional Sports Franchise Facilities Tax Revenue Bonds"), if and only to the extent that the primary pledge of revenues are not sufficient to pay amounts due on said Professional Sports Franchise Facilities Tax Revenue Bonds.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The duties of the Tourist Development Council shall be described in the enabling act [Section 125.0104, Florida Statutes] and in Ordinance No. 78-28 [Sections 2-248 through 2-253.1] passed by the Board of County Commissioners on April 4, 1978. The Council shall also, from time to time, make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners for the effective operation of the special projects or uses of the tourist development room tax revenue and may perform such other duties or functions as may be prescribed by ordinance or resolution.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Tourist Development Council shall continuously review expenditures of revenues from the Tourist Development Trust Fund and shall receive at least quarterly expenditure reports from the Board of County Commissioners or the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. Expenditures which the Council believes to be unauthorized shall be reported to the Board of County Commissioners and the Florida Department of Revenue. The County Commissioners and the Florida Department of Revenue shall review the Council's findings and take appropriate administrative or judicial action to ensure compliance with this article and the provisions of Section 125.0104, Florida Statutes.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Professional sports franchise facility tax. Collections received by the Tax Collector from the professional sports franchise facility tax, less costs of administration, shall be used to pay debt service on bonds issued to finance the construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a professional sports franchise facility.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Tourist development surtax. Collections received by the Tax Collector from the tourist development surtax, less costs of administration, are to be deposited to the Miami-Dade County Tourist Development Surtax Trust Fund, herewith established, and disbursed in the following manner:<section prefix='(1)'>The proceeds of the tourist development surtax shall be allocated to the Countywide Convention and Visitors Bureau which, by interlocal agreement and contract with the County, has been given primary responsibility for promoting the County and its constituent cities as a destination site for conventions, trade shows, and pleasure travel.<section prefix='(a)'>All tax proceeds allocated to the Convention and Visitors Bureau shall be used only for the following purposes:<section prefix='(i)'>To promote and advertise tourism in the State of Florida and nationally and internationally; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>To fund convention bureaus, tourist bureaus, tourist information centers and news bureaus, either as County agencies or by contract with the Chambers of Commerce or similar associations in the County.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The County shall regulate by separate agreement with the Convention and Visitors Bureau the manner in which the tax proceeds shall be distributed to the Convention and Visitors Bureau, the specific purposes for which the proceeds shall be expended, and the manner in which the County shall review the administration of tax proceeds by the Convention and Visitors Bureau.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>In the event the County is no longer a party to an interlocal agreement and contract with a Countywide Convention and Visitors Bureau, the County shall allocate directly the proceeds of the tax for the purposes described in subsection (b)(1)(a)(i) and (ii).</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Homeless and spouse abuse tax.<section prefix='(1)'>The County adopts as its controlling policy and plan for addressing the needs of persons who have become or are about to become homeless, the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan prepared by the Miami-Dade County Task Force on the Homeless, attached as exhibit A. This plan shall govern the expenditure of that portion of the homeless and spouse abuse tax dedicated to assisting the homeless.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All funds collected by the Tax Collector from the homeless tax shall be placed into the Homeless Tax Trust Fund and used in the following manner:<section prefix='a.'>For the first twelve (12) months funds placed into the Homeless Tax Trust Fund shall be used by the County to assist persons who have become or are about to become homeless only in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Community Homeless Plan.</section><section prefix='b.'>Thereafter not less than fifteen (15) percent of the funds generated by the homeless and spouse abuse tax shall be made available for the construction and operation of a spouse abuse emergency treatment and shelter facility.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>During the existence of the homeless and spouse abuse tax, Miami-Dade County shall continue to contribute each year at least eighty-five (85) percent of the average annual aggregate general fund expenditures devoted to operating homeless shelter services in the two (2) fiscal years preceding the effective date of this Ordinance No. 93-75.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-62, § 3(C), (D), 10-4-78; Ord. No. 90-33, § 8, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 90-116, § 6, 10-16-90; Ord. No. 92-138, § 1, 11-5-92; Ord. No. 93-75, § 4, 7-27-93; Ord. No. 94-02, § 1, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 06-57, § 1, 4-27-06; Ord. No. 12-74, § 25, 9-20-12)</history></law>