<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE X. PROPERTY TAX EXEMPTIONS IN ENTERPRISE ZONES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-85</section_number>
<catch_line>Application procedures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003266</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-85. Application procedures.<section>Any person, firm, or corporation which desires an economic ad valorem tax exemption pursuant to this article shall file a written application on a form prescribed by the Office of Community and Economic Development (OCED) for said exemption either on or before February first of the year in which new or additional real or tangible personal property is first subject to ad valorem assessment. Such application shall be filed with the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The application shall request the adoption of an ordinance granting the applicant an exemption pursuant to this article and shall include the following information:<section prefix='(a)'>The name and location of the new or expanding business.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The description of the improvements to real property for which an exemption is being requested, the cost of such improvements, and the date of commencement and completion of construction of such improvements.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A description of the tangible personal property for which an exemption is requested, the cost of such property, and the date when such property was or is to be purchased.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A copy of the building plans.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A copy of the building permit, if available.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Proof, to the satisfaction of the Board of County Commissioners, that the application is a new business or an expansion of an existing business, as defined in this article.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Other information deemed necessary by the Board of County Commissioners. The applicant shall pay a reasonable nonrefundable fee for the time and work involved in processing the application.<section>Should a proposal to build a new business or expand an existing one be modified after the Board of County Commissioners has agreed to grant it an exemption, the decision to grant said exemption may continue to apply to the modified proposal, only if the Board of County Commissioners determines that there were extenuating circumstances that justified the modification to the original proposal.</section><section>In the event the reasons for the modification are deemed to be unsatisfactory the exemption shall be withdrawn and the business duly informed. The business, upon notification of the withdrawal of the exemption, shall have the right to appeal to the Board of County Commissioners for the reinstatement of the exemption.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Proof that property taxes are current.</section></section><section>The property appraiser shall report the following information to the Board:<section prefix='(i)'>The total revenue available to the County for the current fiscal year from ad valorem tax sources;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Any revenue lost to the County for the current fiscal year by virtue of exemptions previously granted under this article;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>An estimate of the revenue which would be lost to the County during the current fiscal year if the exemption applied for were granted had the property for which the exemption is requested otherwise been subject to taxation;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>A determination as to whether the property for which an exemption is requested satisfies the eligibility requirements of a new business or an expansion of an existing business, as defined herein, which determination shall also be affixed to the face of the application.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-27, ยง 3, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 96-74, ยง 2, 5-21-96)</history></law>