<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE X. PROPERTY TAX EXEMPTIONS IN ENTERPRISE ZONES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-86</section_number>
<catch_line>Enactment of ordinance granting each exemption.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003267</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-86. Enactment of ordinance granting each exemption.<section>After receipt of the report from the County Manager, the Board of County Commissioners, at its discretion may grant a tax exemption by ordinance as authorized herein.</section><section>The ordinance granting an exemption shall be enacted in the same manner as any other Miami-Dade County ordinance and shall include the following:<section prefix='(a)'>The name and address of the new or expanding business to which the exemption is granted;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The total amount of revenue available to the County from ad valorem tax sources for the current fiscal year, the total amount of revenue foregone by the County for the current fiscal year by virtue of economic development ad valorem tax exemptions currently in effect, and the estimated revenue foregone by the County for the current fiscal year attributable to the exemption of the business named in the ordinance as a new business or expansion of an existing business as defined herein;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The period of time for which the exemption will remain in effect and the expiration date of the exemption; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>A finding that the business named in the ordinance meets the requirements of Section 196.012(15) or (16), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A finding that the business property tax bills are current.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-27, ยง 3, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 96-74, ยง 2, 5-21-96; Ord. No. 06-68, ยง 4, 5-9-06)</history></law>