<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE X. PROPERTY TAX EXEMPTIONS IN ENTERPRISE ZONES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-82</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003263</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-82. Definitions.<section>For the purposes of this article, the following terms are defined as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Enterprise zone means an area either designated pursuant to Section 290.005 [Florida Statutes] and approved by the Office of Tourism, Trade and Economic Development pursuant to Section 290.0065, Florida Statutes, or authorized to be an enterprise zone pursuant to Section 290.0055, Florida Statutes, and approved by the Office of Tourism, Trade and Economic Development pursuant to Section 290.0065, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>New business means any commercial or industrial business, excluding residential developments, located in an enterprise zone that begins operations on a site clearly separate from any other commercial or industrial operation owned by the same business and which creates five (5) or more new jobs to employ five (5) or more additional full-time employees at such location.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Expanding business or expansion of an existing business means any commercial or industrial business, excluding residential developments, located in an enterprise zone that increases operations on a site co-located with a commercial or industrial operation owned by the same business and which creates five (5) or more new jobs to employ five (5) or more additional full-time employees at such location.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-27, ยง 3, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 96-74, ยง 2, 5-21-96; Ord. No. 06-68, ยง 2, 5-9-06)</history></law>