<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE X. PROPERTY TAX EXEMPTIONS IN ENTERPRISE ZONES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-81</section_number>
<catch_line>Authority to grant the exemptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003262</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-81. Authority to grant the exemptions.<section>Pursuant to the terms of this article, the Board of County Commissioners at its discretion is hereby authorized to grant by ordinance ad valorem tax exemptions to new and expanding businesses located within the enterprise zones, as defined herein, except to businesses located in the terminals of the Miami International Airport and except for real property improvements in any community redevelopment area; however, the Board of County Commissioners may grant ad valorem tax exemptions for the tangible personal property of new and expanding businesses in a community redevelopment area located within the enterprise zone in any community redevelopment area. Applications to the County for the tax exemption on tangible personal property from businesses located in municipal CRAs shall require the prior approval of the CRA Board and the governing body of the municipality in which the business is located prior to being submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for consideration. The Board of County Commissioners may also commit to grant an exemption based on presentation of substantive proposals that indicate serious intent to build a new business or expand an existing business within an enterprise zone, provided however, that the improvements to real property are made or the tangible personal property are added or increased on or after the day of the ordinance granting the exemption is adopted. The commitment by the Board to grant an exemption based on plans and proposals is contingent on the business completing the indicated improvements in substantially the same form and extent as presented.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-27, § 3, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 89-119, § 2, 11-21-89; Ord. No. 91-75, § 2, 7-9-91; Ord. No. 93-139, § 1, 12-14-93; Ord. No. 96-74, § 2, 5-21-96; Ord. No. 06-68, § 1, 5-9-06)</history></law>