<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Homestead exemption for low-income senior citizens who are long-term residents.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003210</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-9. Homestead exemption for low-income senior citizens who are long-term residents.<section prefix='(a)'>In accordance with Article VII, Section 6(d)(2), Florida Constitution, and Section 196.075, Florida Statutes, any person who meets the following criteria shall be entitled to make application for an additional homestead exemption for the amount of the assessed value of the property:<section prefix='(1)'>Has the legal or equitable title to real estate located within Miami-Dade County with a just value of less than $250,000.00,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Has maintained thereon the permanent residence of the owner for at least 25 years,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Has attained the age of 65, and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Has a household income that does not exceed the income limitations set forth in state law, which is currently $27,030.00 and adjusted annually.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The exemption set forth in subsection (a) above shall be in addition to and shall not replace the additional $50,000.00 senior citizen homestead exemption adopted pursuant to Ordinance No. 07-70 and codified at Section 29-8</section><section prefix='(c)'>Every person claiming the additional homestead exemption pursuant to subsection (a) above must file an application therefore with the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser no later than March 1 of each year for which such exemption is claimed. Such application shall include a sworn statement of household income for all members of the household and shall be filed on a form prescribed by the Florida Department of Revenue. On or before June 1 of each such year every applicant must file supporting documentation with the Property Appraiser. Such documentation shall include copies of all federal income tax returns, wage and earning statements, and such other documentation as required by the Property Appraiser, including documentation necessary to verify the income received by all of the members of the household for the prior year.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Failure to file the application and sworn statement by March 1 or failure to file the required supporting documentation by June 1 of any given year shall constitute a waiver of the additional exemption privilege for that year.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding subsections (c) and (d) above, if the Property Appraiser, pursuant to Section 196.011(9), Florida Statutes, requests that this Board waive the requirement that an annual application and income statement be made for renewal of the exemption provided in Section 196.075, F.S., then after an initial application for exemption has been made and the exemption is granted pursuant to Section 196.075, subsection (c) and (d) shall not apply and the requirement that an annual renewal application or Income Statement be submitted to the Property Appraiser for exemption of property within the County shall be waived except in the circumstances set forth below. Timely annual application together with the required Income Statement for exemption shall be required whenever:<section prefix='(1)'>Property exempted on the assessment roll of the immediately preceding tax year is sold or otherwise disposed of,</section><section prefix='(2)'>The ownership changes in any manner,</section><section prefix='(3)'>The applicant ceases to use the property as his or her homestead, or</section><section prefix='(4)'>The status of the owner changes so as to change the exempt status of the property, as provided in Section 196.011(9)(a), F.S.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>This additional exemption shall be available commencing with the 2013 tax roll and shall continue with all subsequent tax rolls. The Property Appraiser may begin accepting applications and sworn statements for the year 2013 tax roll as soon as the appropriate forms are available from the Department of Revenue.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Commencing January 1, 2013, and each January 1 thereafter, the annual income limitation applicable to this section shall be adjusted annually as provided in state law and shall be applicable as of January 1 of each year.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The Clerk of the Board shall file a copy of Ordinance No. 13-01 in the appropriate books and records, and within 30 days of the effective date of that ordinance, transmit a copy to the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-01, ยง 1, 1-23-13)</history></law>