<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. COUNTY TRANSIT SYSTEM SALES SURTAX</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-92</section_number>
<catch_line>Transactions deemed to have occurred in Miami-Dade County.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003273</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-92. Transactions deemed to have occurred in Miami-Dade County.<section>For the purpose of this article, a transaction shall be deemed to have occurred in Miami-Dade County when:<section prefix='(a)'>The dealer is located in Miami-Dade County, delivery is made to a location within Miami-Dade County or to a location within a County also imposing the surtax, and the sale includes tangible personal property, except as otherwise provided herein; provided, that the sale of any motor vehicle or mobile home of a class or type which is required to be registered in this State or in any other state shall be deemed to have occurred only in the County identified as the residence address of the purchaser on the registration or title document for such property;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The event for which an admission is charged is located in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The consumer of utility or wired television services is located in Miami-Dade County, or the telecommunication services are provided to a location within Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(d)'>The user of any aircraft or boat of a class or type which is required to be registered, licensed, titled, or documented in this State or by the United States Government imported into Miami-Dade County for use, consumption, distribution, or storage to be used or consumed in Miami-Dade County is located in Miami-Dade County, however, it shall be presumed that such items used outside Miami-Dade County for six (6) months or longer before being imported into the County were not purchased for use in Miami-Dade County. The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to the use or consumption of such items upon which a like tax of equal or greater amount has been lawfully imposed and paid outside Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(e)'>The purchaser of any motor vehicle or mobile home of a class or type which is required to be registered in this State is a resident of Miami-Dade County as determined by the address appearing on or to be reflected on the registration document for such property;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any motor vehicle or mobile home of a class or type which is required to be registered in this State is imported from another state into Miami-Dade County by a user residing therein for the purpose of use, consumption, distribution, or storage in Miami-Dade County, however, it shall be presumed that such items used outside Miami-Dade County for six (6) months or longer before being imported into the County were not purchased for use in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The real property which is leased or rented is located in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(h)'>The transient rental transaction occurs in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(i)'>The delivery of any aircraft or boat of a class or type which is required to be registered, licensed, titled, or documented in this State or by the United States Government is to a location in Miami-Dade County; however, the provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to the use or consumption of such items upon which a like tax of equal or greater amount has been lawfully imposed and paid outside the County;</section><section prefix='(j)'>The dealer owing a use tax on purchases or leases is located in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(k)'>The delivery of tangible personal property other than that described in paragraphs (d), (e), or (f) is made to a location outside Miami-Dade County, but the property is brought into Miami-Dade County within six (6) months after delivery, in which event, the owner must pay the surtax as a use tax; or</section><section prefix='(l)'>A Florida manufacturer or wholesaler sells tangible personal property to a dealer who is located outside Miami-Dade County, but delivers the property within Miami-Dade County to a customer of the dealer, in which event the dealer must collect and remit the surtax.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-15, ยง 1, 3-6-90)</history></law>