<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='2'>Chapter 29 TAXATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. COUNTY HEALTH CARE SURTAX</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>29-96</section_number>
<catch_line>Surtax rate, limitations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003277</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 29-96. Surtax rate, limitations.<section>The surtax rate shall be one-half percent of the amount of taxable sales and taxable purchases representing such transactions. However:<section prefix='(a)'>The tax on any sales amount above five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) on any item of tangible personal property and on long distance telephone service shall not be subject to the surtax;</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the case of utility, telecommunication, or television system program services billed on or after the effective date of any such surtax, the entire amount of the tax for utility, telecommunication, or television system program services shall be subject to the surtax. In the case of utility, telecommunication, or television system program services billed after the last day the surtax is in effect, the entire amount of the tax on said items shall not be subject to the surtax;</section><section prefix='(c)'>In the case of written contracts which are signed prior to the effective date of any such surtax for the construction of improvements to real property or for remodeling of existing structures, the surtax shall be paid by the contractor responsible for the performance of the contract.</section></section><section>The contractor may apply for one (1) refund of any such surtax paid on materials necessary for the completion of the contract. Any application for refund shall be made no later than fifteen (15) months following initial imposition of the surtax in that County. The application for refund shall be in the manner prescribed by the Department of Revenue by rule.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-64, ยง 1, 6-18-91)</history></law>