<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>ARTICLE 3. ELECTIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>3.01</section_number>
<catch_line>ELECTION AND COMMENCEMENT OF TERMS OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000017</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 3.01. ELECTION AND COMMENCEMENT OF TERMS OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS.<section prefix='A.'>The election of the Commissioners from even-numbered districts shall be held in 1994 and every four years thereafter and the election of Commissioners from odd-numbered districts shall be held in 1996 and every four years thereafter at the time of the state primary elections.</section><section prefix='B.'>A candidate must receive a majority of the votes cast to be elected. Effective with the election for County Commission in 2004, if no candidate receives a majority of the votes cast there will be a runoff election at the time of the general election following the state primary election between the two candidates receiving the highest number of votes. Should a tie result, the outcome shall be determined by lot.</section><section prefix='C.'>Except as otherwise provided in this Charter, beginning with the elections in 2004, the terms of office of the Mayor and County Commissioners shall commence on the second Tuesday next succeeding the date of the general election in November.</section><section prefix='D.'>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Charter, effective with the term of Mayor scheduled to commence in October, 1996, no person shall be elected as Mayor for more than two consecutive four-year terms. Neither service as Mayor or County Commissioner prior to the terms scheduled to commence in October, 1996, nor service of a partial term subsequent to October, 1996, shall be considered in applying the term limitation provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='E.'>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Charter, effective with the term of Commissioners scheduled to commence in 2012, no person shall be elected as Commissioner for more than two consecutive four-year terms. No term of service as a Commissioner commencing prior to 2012 shall be considered a part of or counted toward the two term limit.</section></section></text></law>