<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>ARTICLE 3. ELECTIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>3.04</section_number>
<catch_line>QUALIFICATIONS AND FILING FEE.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000020</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 3.04. QUALIFICATIONS AND FILING FEE.<section prefix='A.'>All candidates for the office of Mayor or County Commissioner shall qualify with the Clerk of the Circuit Court no earlier than the 84th day and no later than noon on the 70th day prior to the date of the election at which he is a candidate in the method provided by law or ordinance, and shall pay a filing fee of $300. All filing fees shall be paid into the general funds of the county.</section><section prefix='B.'>Notwithstanding the foregoing, a person who seeks to qualify as a candidate for the office of Mayor or County Commissioner and who meets the petition requirements of this section is not required to pay the filing fee required by this section or any other qualifying fee required by the state (collectively the "Qualifying Fee"). A candidate who seeks to qualify without paying the Qualifying Fee must obtain the number of signatures of voters in the geographical area represented by the office sought equal to at least 1 percent of the total number of registered voters of that geographical area, as shown by the compilation by the Supervisor of Elections for the immediately preceding general election. Signatures may not be obtained until the candidate has filed the appointment of campaign treasurer and designation of campaign depository pursuant to state law. The format of the petition shall be prescribed by the Supervisor of Elections and shall be used by candidates to reproduce petitions for circulation. Each petition must be submitted before noon of the 28th day preceding the first day of the qualifying period for the office sought to the Supervisor of Elections. The Supervisor shall check the signatures on the petitions to verify their status as voters in the geographical area represented by the office sought. No later than the 7th day before the first day of the qualifying period, the Supervisor of Elections shall certify the number of valid signatures. The Supervisor of Elections shall determine whether the required number of signatures has been obtained and shall notify the candidate. If the required number of signatures has been obtained, the candidate shall be eligible to qualify pursuant to this section without paying the Qualifying Fee.</section></section></text></law>