<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-218</section_number>
<catch_line>Obedience to signal indicating approach of train.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003330</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-218. Obedience to signal indicating approach of train.<section prefix='(1)'>Whenever any person driving a vehicle approaches a railroad grade crossing under any of the circumstances stated in this section, the driver of such vehicle shall stop within fifty (50) feet but not less than fifteen (15) feet from the nearest rail of such railroad, and shall not proceed until he can do so safely. The foregoing requirements shall apply when:<section prefix='(a)'>A clearly visible electric or mechanical signal device gives warning of the immediate approach of a railroad train;</section><section prefix='(b)'>A crossing gate is lowered or when a human flagman gives or continues to give a signal of the approach or passage of a railroad train;</section><section prefix='(c)'>A railroad train approaching within approximately one thousand five hundred (1,500) feet of the highway crossing emits a signal audible from such distance and the railroad train, by reason of its speed or nearness to the crossing, is an immediate hazard;</section><section prefix='(d)'>An approaching railroad train is plainly visible and is in hazardous proximity to the crossing.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>No person shall drive any vehicle through, around or under any crossing gate or barrier at a railroad crossing while the gate or barrier is closed or is being opened or closed.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>