<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-210.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Consumption of alcohol or possession of open containers of alcohol prohibited in motor vehicles.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003322</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-210.1. Consumption of alcohol or possession of open containers of alcohol prohibited in motor vehicles.<section prefix='(a)'>No person in any motor vehicle shall consume any alcoholic beverage or have in his or her possession any open container containing any alcoholic beverage while the motor vehicle is upon a street or highway in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>This section shall not apply to any business passenger on a bus or motor vehicle being operated by a duly licensed chauffeur in the course of the chauffeur's ongoing business or employment of providing passenger transportation. Furthermore, this section shall not apply to any open container in a refrigerator in the living area of a house trailer.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any violation of this section shall be punishable as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For a first offense, by a fine of not less than twenty-five dollars ($25.00) and not more than two hundred dollars ($200.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed ten (10) days, or by both.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For a second offense, by a fine of not less than fifty dollars ($50.00) and not more than two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed ten (10) days, or by both.</section><section prefix='(3)'>For each subsequent offense, by a fine of not less than seventy-five dollars ($75.00) and not more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for a term not to exceed thirty (30) days, or by both.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 86-26, ยง 5, 4-1-86)</history></law>