<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-269</section_number>
<catch_line>Stopping, standing or parking outside of municipalities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003388</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-269. Stopping, standing or parking outside of municipalities.<section prefix='(1)'>Upon any highway outside of a municipality, no person shall stop, park or leave standing any vehicle, whether attended or unattended, upon the paved or main traveled part of the highway when it is practical to stop, park, or so leave the vehicle off such part of the highway; but in every event an unobstructed width of the highway opposite a standing vehicle shall be left for the free passage of other vehicles and a clear view of the stopped vehicle shall be available from a distance of two hundred (200) feet in each direction upon the highway.</section><section prefix='(2)'>This section shall not apply to the driver or owner of any vehicle which is disabled, while on the paved or main traveled portion of a highway, in such manner and to such extent that it is impossible to avoid stopping and temporarily leaving the disabled vehicle in such position, or to passenger-carrying buses temporarily parked while loading or discharging passengers or stopped for any purpose reasonably necessary for the safety or comfort of the passengers or operator where highway conditions render such parking off the paved portion of the highway hazardous or impractical.</section><section prefix='(3)'>(a)Whenever any police officer finds a vehicle standing upon a highway in violation of any of the foregoing provisions of this section, the officer is authorized to move the vehicle, or require the driver or other persons in charge of the vehicle to move the same, to a position off the paved or main traveled part of the highway.<section prefix='(b)'>Whenever any police officer finds a vehicle unattended upon any bridge or causeway or in any tunnel, or on any public highway, where the vehicle constitutes an obstruction to traffic, the officer is authorized to provide for the removal of the vehicle to the nearest garage or other place of safety, cost of such removal to be a lien against the motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any vehicle moved under the provisions of this chapter which is a stolen vehicle shall not be subject to the provisions hereof unless the moving authority has reported to the Florida Highway Patrol the taking into possession of the vehicle within twenty-four (24) hours of the moving of the vehicle.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 72-78, ยง 1, 10-31-72)</history></law>