<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-292</section_number>
<catch_line>Stopping, standing or parking prohibited in specified places.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003412</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-292. Stopping, standing or parking prohibited in specified places.<section prefix='(1)'>Except when necessary to avoid conflict with other traffic, or in compliance with law or the directions of a police officer or official traffic control device, no person shall:<section prefix='(a)'>Stop, stand or park a vehicle:<section prefix='1.'>On the roadway side of any vehicle stopped or parked at the edge or curb of a street;</section><section prefix='2.'>On a sidewalk;</section><section prefix='3.'>Within an intersection;</section><section prefix='4.'>On a crosswalk;</section><section prefix='5.'>Between a safety zone and the adjacent curb or within thirty (30) feet of points on the curb immediately opposite the ends of a safety zone, unless the Division of Road Operations of the Department of Transportation indicates a different length by signs or markings;</section><section prefix='6.'>Alongside or opposite any street excavation or obstruction when stopping, standing, or parking would obstruct traffic;</section><section prefix='7.'>Upon any bridge or other elevated structure upon a highway, causeway or within a highway tunnel, where parking is not provided for thereon;</section><section prefix='8.'>On any railroad tracks;</section><section prefix='9.'>On a bicycle path;</section><section prefix='10.'>At any place where official traffic control devices prohibit stopping;</section><section prefix='11.'>On the roadway side of any vehicle stopped or parked at the edge or curb of a street.</section><section prefix='12.'>At any place where disabled access is provided, including but not limited to: an access aisle adjacent to an accessible parking space, curb ramp, ramp, or accessible path of travel such as sidewalks and bicycle paths. Any violation of this section shall result in a fine of one hundred fifty dollars ($150.00).</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Stand or park a vehicle, whether occupied or not, except momentarily to pick up or discharge a passenger or passengers:<section prefix='1.'>In front of a public or private driveway;</section><section prefix='2.'>Within fifteen (15) feet of a fire hydrant;</section><section prefix='3.'>Within twenty (20) feet of a crosswalk at an intersection;</section><section prefix='4.'>Within thirty (30) feet upon the approach to any flashing signal, stop sign or traffic control signal located at the side of a roadway;</section><section prefix='5.'>Within twenty (20) feet of the driveway entrance to any fire station and on the side of a street opposite the entrance to any fire station within seventy-five (75) feet of said entrance (when property sign-posted);</section><section prefix='6.'>On an exclusive bicycle lane;</section><section prefix='7.'>At any place where official traffic control devices prohibit standing.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Park a vehicle, whether occupied or not, except temporarily for the purpose of, and while actually engaged in, loading or unloading merchandise or passengers:<section prefix='1.'>Within fifty (50) feet of the nearest rail of a railroad crossing, or bridge;</section><section prefix='2.'>At any place where official signs prohibit parking.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>No person shall move a vehicle not lawfully under his control into any such prohibited area or away from a curb such a distance as is unlawful.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 84-19, ยง 7, 3-6-84; Ord. No. 07-137, ยง 1, 10-2-07)</history></law>