<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-204</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003314</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-204. Enforcement.<section>The enforcement of the traffic laws of this State is vested as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>State.<section prefix='(a)'>The Division of Florida Highway Patrol of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles has authority to enforce all of the traffic laws of this State on all the streets and highways thereof and elsewhere throughout the State wherever the public has a right to travel by motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Florida Public Service Commission has authority to enforce on all the streets and highways of this State all laws applicable within its authority.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Counties. The sheriff's office of each of the several counties of this State shall enforce all of the traffic laws of this State on all the streets and highways thereof and elsewhere throughout the County wherever the public has the right to travel by motor vehicle within the respective counties.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Municipalities. The Police Department of each chartered municipality shall enforce the traffic laws of this State on all the streets and highways thereof and elsewhere throughout the municipality, wherever the public has the right to travel by motor vehicle within the respective municipalities; provided, however, nothing in this act shall affect any law, general, special or otherwise, in effect on the effective date of this act relating to "hot pursuit" without the boundaries of the municipality.</section></section><section>Anything in this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding, no municipal police officer shall have any power or jurisdiction to issue summons or make arrests on the Palmetto Expressway. The Sheriff's Department and the Florida Highway Patrol shall have exclusive jurisdiction in respect to the enforcement of traffic regulations on the Palmetto Expressway.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>