<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-283</section_number>
<catch_line>Required position and method of turning at intersections; exception for buses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003402</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-283. Required position and method of turning at intersections; exception for buses.<section>The driver of a vehicle intending to turn at an intersection shall do so as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Both the approach for a right turn and a right turn shall be made as close as practicable to the right-hand curb or edge of the roadway.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The driver of a vehicle intending to turn left at any intersection shall approach the intersection in the extreme left-hand lane lawfully available to traffic moving in the direction of travel of such vehicle, and, after entering the intersection, the left turn shall be made so as to leave the intersection in a lane lawfully available to traffic moving in such direction upon the roadway being entered. A person operating a bicycle intending to turn left in accordance with this section shall be entitled to the full use of the lane from which such a turn may legally be made. Whenever practicable the left turn shall be made in that portion of the intersection to the left of the center of the intersection.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In addition to the method of making a left turn described in subsection (2), a person operating a bicycle intending to turn left shall have the option of following the course described hereafter: The rider shall approach the turn as close as practicable to the right curb or edge of the roadway. After proceeding across the intersecting roadway, the turn shall be made as close as practicable to the curb or edge of the roadway on the far side of the intersection. Before proceeding, the bicyclist shall comply with any official traffic control device or police officer regulating traffic on the highway along which he intends to proceed.</section><section prefix='(4)'>This section shall not apply to the owner or operator of any bus where the size of the bus renders impossible strict compliance with the requirements of this section.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The State, County and local authorities in their respective jurisdictions may cause official traffic control devices to be placed within or adjacent to intersections and thereby require and direct that a different course from that specified in this section be traveled by vehicles turning at an intersection. When such devices are so placed, no driver of a vehicle shall turn a vehicle at an intersection other than as directed and required by such devices.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 72-78, ยง 2, 10-31-72; Ord. No. 84-19, ยง 6, 3-6-84)</history></law>