<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-214</section_number>
<catch_line>Unlawful use of license; driving while license revoked, suspended; penalty.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003326</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-214. Unlawful use of license; driving while license revoked, suspended; penalty.<section prefix='(a)'>Unlawful use. It shall be unlawful for any person:<section prefix='(1)'>To display, or cause or permit to be displayed, or have in his possession, any cancelled, revoked, suspended, fictitious, or fraudulently altered operator's or chauffeur's license.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To lend his operator's or chauffeur's license to any person or knowingly permit the use thereof by another.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To display, or represent as one's own, any operator's or chauffeur's license not issued to him.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To fail to surrender to the Florida Department of Public Safety, as defined in and provided by Chapters 321 and 322, Florida Statutes, upon lawful demand, any operator's or chauffeur's license which has been suspended, revoked or cancelled.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To use a false or fictitious name in any application for an operator's or chauffeur's license, or to knowingly make a false statement, or to knowingly conceal a material fact, or otherwise commit a fraud in any such application.</section><section prefix='(6)'>To permit any unlawful use of an operator's or chauffeur's license issued to him.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>(1)Suspended or revoked license. It shall be unlawful and an offense for any person whose operator's or chauffeur's vehicle license or driving privilege as a nonresident, has been cancelled, suspended or revoked as provided by the laws of this State, to drive any vehicle upon the streets, roadways, rights-of-way or highways within this County while such license or privileges is cancelled, suspended or revoked.<section prefix='(2)'>Restricted license. It is unlawful for any person to operate a motor vehicle in any manner in violation of the restrictions imposed in a restricted license issued to him.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Penalty. Every person who is convicted of a violation of any provision of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment in the County Jail not to exceed sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>