<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-215</section_number>
<catch_line>Obedience to and effect of traffic laws.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003327</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-215. Obedience to and effect of traffic laws.<section prefix='(1)'>Provisions of act referring to vehicles upon the highways; exceptions. The provisions of this chapter shall apply to the operation of vehicles, bicycles and the movement of pedestrians upon all State maintained highways, County maintained highways and municipal streets and alleys and wherever vehicles have the right to travel.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Required obedience to traffic laws. It is unlawful for any person to do any act forbidden or to fail to perform any act required in this chapter. It is unlawful for the owner, or any other person, employing or otherwise directing the driver of any vehicle to require or knowingly to permit the operation of such vehicle upon a highway in any manner contrary to law.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Obedience to Police and Fire Department officials. No person shall willfully fail or refuse to comply with any lawful order or direction of any police officer, or member of the Fire Department at the scene of a fire, who is invested by law or ordinance with authority to direct, control, or regulate traffic.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Public officers and employees to obey act; exceptions.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this chapter applicable to the drivers of vehicles upon the highways shall apply to the drivers of all vehicles owned or operated by the United States, Florida, or any County, city, town, district, or any other political subdivision of the State, subject to such specific exceptions as are set forth in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Unless specifically made applicable, the provisions of this chapter except those contained in Sections 30.210—30.212 shall not apply to persons, teams, motor vehicles, and other equipment while actually engaged in work upon the surface of a highway but shall apply to such persons and vehicles when traveling to or from such work.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Authorized emergency vehicles.<section prefix='(a)'>The driver of an authorized emergency vehicle, when responding to an emergency call or when in the pursuit of an actual or suspected violator of the law or when responding to but not upon returning from a fire alarm, may exercise the privileges set forth in this section, but subject to the conditions herein stated.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The driver of an authorized emergency vehicle, except when otherwise directed by a police officer, may:<section prefix='1.'>Park or stand, irrespective of the provisions of this chapter;</section><section prefix='2.'>Proceed past a red or stop signal or stop sign, but only after slowing down as may be necessary for safe operation;</section><section prefix='3.'>Exceed the maximum speed limits so long as he does not endanger life or property;</section><section prefix='4.'>Disregard regulations governing direction or movement or turning in specified directions, so long as he does not endanger life or property.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The foregoing provisions shall not relieve the driver of an authorized emergency vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for the safety of all persons, nor shall such provisions protect the driver from the consequences of his reckless disregard for the safety of others.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, § 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>