<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-295</section_number>
<catch_line>Disabled persons, exemption from payment of parking fees; issuance of identification stickers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003415</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-295. Disabled persons, exemption from payment of parking fees; issuance of identification stickers.<section prefix='(1)'>Neither Miami-Dade County nor any city, town or any agency thereof shall exact any fee for parking on the public streets or highways or in any metered parking space from any person who has suffered the amputation of one (1) or both legs or who has suffered the loss of the use of one (1) or both legs as a consequence of paralysis or other permanent disability and who is licensed to operate a motor vehicle in Florida.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No penalty shall be imposed upon any such disabled person for parking on the street or highways or in a metered space for a longer period of time than other persons are permitted to park on such streets or highways or in such metered space; provided, persons not so disabled using the vehicle of a disabled person with a sticker for their own use shall not have the privileges of this section.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Upon the application of any such disabled person, the Tax Collector of the County in which the disabled person applies for his automobile license plate shall issue to such person a certificate showing that the disabled person is entitled to the immunities provided in this section and a sticker reflecting the disability, which sticker shall be displayed upon the lower right-hand portion of the windshield of the motor vehicle of such disabled person.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Department is authorized and empowered to make any necessary rules and regulations to carry out the purposes of this section and to provide the necessary procedure for assuring that all applicants meet the qualifications prescribed in this section.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Department shall prescribe the form of the application, the certificate and the design of a distinctive identifying sticker and the Department shall supply such applications, certificates and stickers to the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Department shall prescribe the fee to be paid by the applicant for the certificate and sticker but the fee shall not exceed fifty cents ($0.50). The Department shall, in its discretion, determine at what intervals the certificate and sticker shall be renewed.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The fee, as set by the Department, shall be collected by the Miami-Dade County Tax Collector from the applicant at the time the certificate and sticker are issued and all such fees so collected shall be paid over to the Department and used to defray the expenses of carrying out the purposes of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>