<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-206</section_number>
<catch_line>Form of traffic citations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003316</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-206. Form of traffic citations.<section prefix='(1)'>Every traffic enforcement agency in this County shall provide in appropriate form traffic tickets containing notices to appear which shall be issued in books with citations in quadruplicate and meeting the requirements of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The chief administrative officer of every such traffic enforcement agency shall be responsible for the issuance of such books and shall maintain a record of every such book and each ticket contained therein issued to individual members of the traffic enforcement agency and shall require and retain a receipt for every book so issued. Provided, however, that the issuance of such books shall not conflict with any rules of procedure for municipal traffic courts adopted by the State Supreme Court.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All prosecution on any charge involving any violation of this chapter or upon a charge of a violation of any law regulating the control of traffic upon the highways of the County shall be by a uniform traffic ticket substantially as hereinafter set forth:</section><section>UNIFORM TRAFFIC TICKETAND COMPLAINT</section><section>Case No. Docket No.  Page No. State of S.S. No.// County of COMPLAINT-AFFIDAVIT City Village Township of</section><section>in the Court of //</section><section>THE UNDERSIGNED BEING DULY SWORN, UPON HIS OATH DEPOSES AND SAYS:</section><section>On // the day of //19, at a.m.p.m.</section><section>Name</section><section>  Last  (Please print)  First  Middle</section><section>Street</section><section>City-State</section><section>Age Birth date // Race Sex Ht. Wt.</section><section>Driver's License No.</section><section>Kind   Number</section><section>Vehicle License No. State Yr.</section><section>Make Style Color</section><section>Upon a public highway, name at (location)</section><section></section><section>DID UNLAWFULLY (PARK) (OPERATE) IN THE CITY, VILLAGE, TOWNSHIP, COUNTY AND STATE AFORESAID AND DID THEN AND THERE COMMIT THE FOLLOWING OFFENSE:</section><section>Following too closely Failure to yield</section><section>Other violations:</section><section>in violation of Sec. of</section><section>State Statute Local Ordinance in such case made and provided.</section><section>Parking: Overtime Double parking</section><section>Meter No. Prohibited Expired</section><section>(Describe) Other</section><section>parking violation</section><section><section>Slippery pavement Rain Snow Ice</section><section>Darkness Night Fog Snow</section><section>Other traffic</section><section>present Cross Oncoming Pedestrian Same direction</section><section>Caused person to dodge Pedestrian Driver Just missed accident</section></section><section><section>PD PI Fatal Ped.</section><section>Vehicle Hit fixed object</section><section>Right angle Head on</section><section>Sideswipe Rear end</section><section>Ran off roadway</section><section>Intersection</section></section><section><section>Business Industrial School Residential Rural</section></section><section><section>2 lane 3 lane</section></section><section>4 lane 4 lane divided</section><section>THE UNDERSIGNED FURTHER STATES THAT HE HAS JUST AND REASONABLE GROUNDS TO BELIEVE, AND DOES BELIEVE, THAT THE PERSON NAMED ABOVE COMMITTED THE OFFENSE HEREIN SET FORTH CONTRARY TO LAW. SWORN TO AND SUBSCRIBED BEFORE THIS DAY OF //, 19</section><section></section><section>(name and title)</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, § 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>