<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-221</section_number>
<catch_line>Pedestrian obedience to traffic control devices and traffic regulations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003333</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-221. Pedestrian obedience to traffic control devices and traffic regulations.<section>A pedestrian shall obey the instructions of any official traffic control device specifically applicable to him unless otherwise directed by a police officer.<section prefix='(1)'>Pedestrians shall be subject to traffic control signals at intersections as provided in Section 30-281, but at all other places pedestrians shall be accorded the privileges and shall be subject to the restrictions stated in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where sidewalks are provided, no pedestrian shall, unless required by other circumstances, walk along and upon the portion of a roadway paved for vehicular traffic.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Where sidewalks are not provided, any pedestrian walking along and upon a highway shall, when practicable, walk only on the shoulder on the left side of the roadway in relation to the pedestrian's direction of travel, facing traffic which may approach from the opposite direction.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No person shall stand in the portion of a roadway paved for vehicular traffic, for the purpose of soliciting a ride, employment or business from the occupant of any vehicle.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No person shall stand on or in proximity to a street or highway for the purpose of soliciting the watching or guarding of any vehicle while parked or about to be parked on a street or highway.</section><section prefix='(6)'>When traffic control signals are not in place or not in operation the driver of a vehicle shall yield the right-of-way, slowing down or stopping if need be to so yield, to a pedestrian crossing the roadway within a crosswalk when the pedestrian is upon the half of the roadway upon which the vehicle is traveling, or when the pedestrian is approaching so closely from the opposite half of the roadway as to be in danger; provided that any pedestrian crossing a roadway at a point where a pedestrian tunnel or overhead pedestrian crossing has been provided shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles upon the roadway.</section><section prefix='(7)'>No pedestrian shall suddenly leave a curb or other place of safety and walk or run into the path of a vehicle which is so close as to constitute an immediate hazard.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Whenever any vehicle is stopped at a marked crosswalk or at any unmarked crosswalk at an intersection to permit a pedestrian to cross the roadway, the driver of any other vehicle approaching from the rear shall not overtake and pass such stopped vehicle.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Every pedestrian crossing a roadway at any point other than within a marked crosswalk or within an unmarked crosswalk at an intersection shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles upon the roadway.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Between adjacent intersections at which traffic-control signals are in operation, and which are two hundred fifty (250) feet apart, or less, pedestrians shall not cross at any place except in a marked crosswalk.</section><section prefix='(11)'>No pedestrian shall, except in a marked crosswalk, cross a roadway at any other place than by a route at right angles to the curb or by the shortest route to the opposite curb.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Pedestrians shall move, whenever practicable, upon the right half of crosswalks.</section><section prefix='(13)'>No pedestrian shall cross a roadway intersection diagonally unless authorized by official traffic control devices, and, when authorized to cross diagonally, pedestrians shall cross only in accordance with the official traffic control devices pertaining to such crossing movements.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Notwithstanding other provisions of this chapter, every driver of a vehicle shall exercise due care to avoid colliding with any pedestrian or any person operating a bicycle and shall give warning when necessary and shall exercise proper precaution upon observing any child or any obviously confused or incapacitated person.</section><section prefix='(15)'>No pedestrian shall enter or remain upon any bridge or approach thereto beyond the bridge signal, gate, or barrier after a bridge operation signal indication has been given. No pedestrian shall pass through, around, over, or under any crossing gate or barrier at a railroad gate crossing or bridge while such gate or barrier is closed or is being opened or closed.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 78-38, ยง 1, 6-6-78; Ord. No. 84-19, ยง 2, 3-6-84)</history></law>