<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-263</section_number>
<catch_line>Bicycle regulations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003375</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-263. Bicycle regulations.<section prefix='(1)'>Every person operating a bicycle shall have all of the rights and all of the duties applicable to the driver of any other vehicle under this chapter, except as to special regulations in this chapter, and except as to provisions of this chapter which by their nature can have no application.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A person operating a bicycle shall not ride other than upon or astride a permanent and regular seat attached thereto.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No bicycle shall be used to carry more persons at one (1) time than the number for which it is designed or equipped, except that an adult rider may carry a child securely attached to his person in a backpack or sling.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No person riding upon any bicycle, coaster, roller skates, sled or toy vehicle shall attach the same or himself to any vehicle upon a roadway. This section shall not prohibit attaching a bicycle trailer or bicycle semitrailer to a bicycle, if that trailer or semitrailer has been designed for such attachment and solely for carrying cargo.</section><section prefix='(5)'>(a)Every person operating a bicycle upon a roadway at less than the normal speed of traffic at the time and place and under the conditions then existing shall ride as close as practicable to the righthand curb or edge of the roadway except under any of the following situations:<section prefix='(1)'>When overtaking and passing another bicycle or vehicle proceeding in the same direction.</section><section prefix='(2)'>When preparing for a left turn at an intersection or into a private road or driveway.</section><section prefix='(3)'>When reasonably necessary to avoid conditions, including but not limited to fixed or moving objects, parked or moving vehicles, bicycles, pedestrians, animals, surface hazards, or substandard width lanes that make it unsafe to continue along the righthand curb or edge. For purposes of this section, a "substandard width lane" is a lane that is too narrow for a bicycle and another vehicle to travel safely side-by-side within the lane.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person operating a bicycle upon a one-way highway with two (2) or more marked traffic lanes may ride as near the lefthand curb or edge of such roadway as practicable.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Persons operating bicycles upon a roadway shall not ride more than two (2) abreast except on paths or parts of roadways set aside for the exclusive use of bicycles. Persons riding two (2) abreast shall not impede traffic when traveling at less than the normal speed of traffic at the time and place and under the conditions then existing and shall ride within a single lane.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any person operating a bicycle shall keep at least one (1) hand upon the handlebars.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Every bicycle in use between sunset and sunrise shall be equipped with a lamp on the front exhibiting a white light visible from a distance of at least five hundred (500) feet to the front and a lamp on the rear exhibiting a red light visible from a distance of six hundred (600) feet to the rear, except that a red reflector meeting the requirements of this section may be used in lieu of the red light. A bicycle or its rider may be equipped with lights or reflectors in addition to those required by this section.</section><section prefix='(9)'>No parent of any minor child and no guardian of any minor ward shall authorize or knowingly permit any such minor child or ward to violate any of the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A person propelling a bicycle by human power upon and along a sidewalk, or across a roadway upon and along a crosswalk, shall have all the rights and duties applicable to a pedestrian under the same circumstances.<section prefix='(11)'>(a)A person operating a bicycle upon and along a sidewalk, or across a roadway upon and along a crosswalk, shall yield the right-of-way to any pedestrian and shall give any audible signal before overtaking and passing such pedestrian.<section prefix='(b)'>A person operating a bicycle upon and along a sidewalk, or across a roadway upon and along a crosswalk, shall follow all posted regulatory signs governing the use of bicycles in these areas.</section></section></section><section prefix='(12)'>No person upon roller skates, or riding in or by means of any coaster, toy vehicle, or similar device, shall go upon any roadway except while crossing a street or a crosswalk and when so crossing such person shall be granted all rights and shall be subject to all of the duties applicable to pedestrians.</section><section prefix='(13)'>This section shall not apply upon any street while set aside as a play street authorized herein or as designated by State, County or municipal authority.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 84-19, ยง 5, 3-6-84; Ord. No. 93-65, ยง 1, 6-15-93)</history></law>