<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-299</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of municipal and County speed zones.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003419</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-299. Establishment of municipal and County speed zones.<section prefix='(1)'>Municipal speed. The maximum speed within any municipality is thirty (30) miles per hour in the daytime or nighttime. Provided that a municipality may set speed zones altering such speed, both as to maximum and minimum, after investigation determines such a change is reasonable and in conformity to criteria promulgated by the Department of Transportation, except no changes shall be made on State highways, connecting links or extension thereof which shall be changed only by the Department of Transportation.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Speed on County roads. The maximum speed on any County maintained road is: In any business or residence district, thirty (30) miles per hour in the daytime or nighttime; on any other part of a County road not a business or residence district, as set forth in Section 30-300. Provided that the Board of County Commissioners may set speed zones altering such speeds, both as to maximum and minimum, after investigation determines such a change is reasonable and in conformity to criteria promulgated by the Department of Transportation, except that no such speed zone shall permit a speed of more than sixty-five (65) miles per hour.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Posting of speed limits. All speed zones shall be posted with clearly legible signs. No change in speeds from thirty (30) miles per hour or from those established in Section 30-300 shall take effect until the zone is posted by the authority changing the speed pursuant to this section and Section 30-298. All signs which limit or establish speed limits, maximum and minimum, shall be so placed and so painted as to be plainly visible and legible in daylight or in darkness when illuminated by headlights.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Penalty. Violation of the speed limits established pursuant to this section shall be punished as set forth in Section 30-208</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>