<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-329</section_number>
<catch_line>Lamps on parked vehicles.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003451</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-329. Lamps on parked vehicles.<section prefix='(1)'>Every vehicle shall be equipped with one (1) or more lamps which, when lighted, shall display a white or amber light visible from a distance of one thousand (1,000) feet to the front of the vehicle, and a red light visible from a distance of one thousand (1,000) feet to the rear of the vehicle. The location of the lamp or lamps shall always be such that at least one (1) lamp or combination of lamps meeting the requirements of this section is installed as near as practicable to the side of the vehicle which is closest to passing traffic.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whenever a vehicle is lawfully parked upon a street or highway during or between sunset and sunrise and in the event there is sufficient light to reveal persons and vehicles within a distance of one thousand (1,000) feet upon such street or highway, no lights need be displayed upon such parked vehicle.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Whenever a vehicle is parked or stopped upon a roadway or shoulder adjacent thereto outside of a municipality, whether attended or unattended, during the hours between sunset and sunrise and there is insufficient light to reveal any person or object within a distance of one thousand (1,000) feet upon such highway, the vehicle so parked or stopped shall be equipped with and shall display lamps meeting the requirements of subsection (1).</section><section prefix='(4)'>Any lighted head lamps upon a parked vehicle shall be depressed or dimmed.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>