<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-399</section_number>
<catch_line>Issuance of identification cards to licensed secondhand dealers; authorized use on uninspected used motor vehicles; revocation, penalties; legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003564</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-399. Issuance of identification cards to licensed secondhand dealers; authorized use on uninspected used motor vehicles; revocation, penalties; legislative intent.<section prefix='(a)'>The County is hereby authorized to issue plasticized identification cards to secondhand dealers holding valid current unrevoked secondhand dealers' licenses issued by the State Motor Vehicle Commission in accordance with the provisions of Section 320.27, Florida Statutes. The cards shall be in the form prescribed by the County, and shall be issued to the dealers upon presentation to the County of the said secondhand dealers' licenses. The cards shall be issued in the name of the dealer as stated on said license and shall be nontransferable.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The identification cards shall expire on December thirty-first of each year; however, each card shall automatically and without notice expire at the time the dealer's license expires or is revoked or suspended.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each licensed dealer is entitled to have additional cards issued to him, but in no event shall the dealer possess at any one (1) time more than five (5) valid unexpired cards for each license he holds under Section 320.27, Florida Statutes. The fee for the issuance of each card is one dollar and fifty cents ($1.50). Any card that has been defaced, mutilated, or is illegible, is invalid, and upon presentation of such card to the County, the dealer may be issued a new card in substitution therefor upon payment of the fee.</section><section prefix='(d)'>When the dealer has in his possession a used motor vehicle which has not been inspected, or which does not bear a valid and unexpired certificate of inspection, said dealer or his agent may, by prominently and visibly displaying a valid unexpired identification card in the rear window of said vehicle, drive the vehicle on the public streets of Miami-Dade County; (1) from the point within this County where the dealer first takes possession of the vehicle to the dealer's place of business or to a garage or shop for repairs or to an authorized motor vehicle inspection station, (2) from the dealer's place of business to a garage or shop for repairs or to said inspection station, and (3) from a garage or shop for repairs to the dealer's place of business or to said inspection station. Any other use of said identification card is unauthorized.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Upon determination by the County that a dealer or his agent has been using an identification card in an unauthorized manner, the County may revoke said card and all other cards issued to said dealer by giving notice of revocation to the dealer by certified mail, and all cards issued to said dealer must be surrendered to the County forthwith.</section><section prefix='(f)'>It shall be unlawful and a violation of this section to display an invalid or expired or revoked card, or to use a card in an unauthorized manner, or to do any act forbidden by this section, or to fail to perform any act required by this section. All violations are punishable as provided for in Section 30-403</section><section prefix='(g)'>Nothing in this section shall be construed to relieve the dealer and his agent from the duty of complying with the provisions of Section 30-33. The provisions and penalties of this section are not intended to and shall not be construed as changing, modifying, amending, repealing, superseding or conflicting with any provisions or sections of the Florida Statutes, but shall be construed as supplemental and additional thereto and not as a substitute therefor.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>