<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-396</section_number>
<catch_line>Fees for inspection and reinspection.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003561</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-396. Fees for inspection and reinspection.<section>A fee of three dollars ($3.00) shall be charged at the time of inspection of all vehicles. When any vehicle is inspected subsequent to the time required by Chapter 325, Florida Statutes, an additional delinquent fee of one dollar ($1.00) shall be charged. Of the amounts collected, one dollar and fifty cents ($1.50) shall be retained by the inspecting agency for the inspection of each passenger motor vehicle, and each motorcycle or similar vehicle; and two dollars ($2.00) shall be retained by the inspecting agency for the inspection of each vehicle for hire, motor bus, truck and truck trailer. Proper counts of the type of vehicles inspected shall be kept and made available to the County at all times. The balance of the funds collected, including all of the delinquent fees above-described, shall be remitted by the fifteenth of the month following to the County and held by it in trust for those purposes for which this fund may be lawfully expended, such expenditures to be disbursed in accordance with the County Manager's reports of May 6 and May 9, 1968, and as may be otherwise provided by the County Commission from time to time through ordinance after public hearing. The County Manager shall forward to the State Department of Public Safety all said delinquent fees in accordance with the provisions of Section 325.24, Florida Statutes.</section><section>All fees shall be paid by the owner of the vehicle, or his agent, at the time of inspection.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>