<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-333</section_number>
<catch_line>Spot lamps and auxiliary lamps.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003455</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-333. Spot lamps and auxiliary lamps.<section prefix='(1)'>Spot lamps. Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two (2) spot lamps and every lighted spot lamp shall be so aimed and used that no part of the high intensity portion of the beam will strike the windshield, or any window, mirror, or occupant of another vehicle in use.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Fog lamps. Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two (2) fog lamps mounted on the front at a height not less than twelve (12) inches nor more than thirty (30) inches above the level surface upon which the vehicle stands and so aimed that when the vehicle is not loaded none of the high intensity portion of the light to the left of the center of the vehicle shall at a distance of twenty-five (25) feet ahead project higher than a level of four (4) inches below the level of the center of the lamp from which it comes. Lighted fog lamps meeting the above requirements may be used with lower head lamp beams as specified in Section 30-337(1)(b).</section><section prefix='(3)'>Auxiliary passing lamps. Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two (2) auxiliary passing lamps mounted on the front at a height not less than twenty-four (24) inches nor more than forty-two (42) inches above the level surface upon which the vehicle stands. The provisions of Section 30-337 shall apply to any combination of head lamps and auxiliary passing lamps.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Auxiliary driving lamps. Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two (2) auxiliary driving lamps mounted on the front at a height not less than sixteen (16) inches nor more than forty-two (42) inches above the level surface upon which the vehicle stands. The provisions of Section 30-337 shall apply to any combination of head lamps and auxiliary driving lamps.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>