<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-369</section_number>
<catch_line>Transportation of explosives, flammables, radioactive materials, etc., generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003491</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-369. Transportation of explosives, flammables, radioactive materials, etc., generally.<section prefix='(1)'>Any vehicle used for transporting any explosives as a cargo or part of a cargo upon the highways, roads or streets of this County shall be marked or placarded on the front, both sides and the rear, with the word "EXPLOSIVES" in letters not less than six (6) inches high or in lieu thereof shall conspicuously display upon an erect pole a red flag, not less than five hundred forty (540) square inches in area with the word "EXPLOSIVES" thereon in white letters not less than six (6) inches high. Any vehicle used for transporting any flammable liquids as a cargo or part of a cargo upon the highways, roads or streets of this County shall be marked or placarded on each side and the rear with the word "GASOLINE," other name of fuel or flammable liquid carried or other applicable wording in letters of such height as required by rules and regulations made and promulgated by the Department of Insurance. Every such vehicle shall be equipped with not less than two (2) fire extinguishers, filled and ready for immediate use, and placed at a convenient point on the vehicle so used. Any vehicle used for transporting any radioactive material as a cargo or part of a cargo upon the highways, roads or streets of this County but not regulated as to such transportation by federal authority shall be marked or placarded with such words and symbols of identification as may be prescribed by the regulations of the Department of Insurance. The Department of Insurance is authorized in accordance with Chapter 633, F.S., to make and promulgate such additional rules and regulations governing the transportation of explosives, flammable liquids, and other dangerous articles, including radioactive materials, by vehicles upon the highways, roads and streets as it shall deem advisable for the protection of the public, and all such rules and regulations shall have the full force and effect of law, provided that, as to radioactive materials, it shall promulgate rules and regulations no less restrictive than those imposed by federal authority for similar interstate transportation.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The provisions of subsection (1) shall not be applicable to the transporting of liquefied petroleum gas. The rules and regulations applicable to the transporting of liquefied petroleum gas on the highways, roads or streets of this County shall be only those made and promulgated by the Department of Insurance under Chapter 527, F.S.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>