<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-342</section_number>
<catch_line>Revocation of certificate of approval on lighting devices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003464</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-342. Revocation of certificate of approval on lighting devices.<section prefix='(1)'>When the Department has reason to believe that an approved lighting device as being sold commercially does not comply with the requirements of this chapter, it may, after giving thirty (30) days' previous notice to the person holding the certificate of approval for such device in this State, conduct a hearing upon the question of compliance of the approved device. After the hearing the Department shall determine whether the approved device meets the requirements of this chapter. If the device does not meet the requirements of this chapter it shall give notice to the person holding the certificate of approval for such device in this State.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If at the expiration of ninety (90) days after such notice the person holding the certificate of approval for the device has failed to satisfy the Department that the approved device as thereafter to be sold meets the requirements of this chapter, the Department shall suspend or revoke the approval issued therefor until or unless such device is resubmitted to and retested by an authorized testing agency and is found to meet the requirements of this chapter, and may require that all said devices sold since the notification following the hearing be replaced with devices that do comply with the requirements of this chapter. The Department may at the time of the retest purchase in the open market and submit to the testing agency one (1) or more sets of such approved devices, and if the device upon retest fails to meet the requirements of this chapter, the Department may refuse to renew the certificate of approval of such device.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>