<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-372</section_number>
<catch_line>Inspection of school buses; physical requirements of drivers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003496</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-372. Inspection of school buses; physical requirements of drivers.<section prefix='(1)'>(a)All motor vehicles, other than private passenger automobiles and school buses with a seating capacity of less than twenty-four (24) pupils, which are used primarily for the transportation of pupils to school, but which are not operated by or under the purview of the State or a political subdivision thereof or under a franchise issued by a municipality or the Public Service Commission, shall comply with the requirements for school buses of Chapter 234, F.S.<section prefix='(b)'>For the purposes of this section the term "school" includes all public and private nursery, pre-elementary, elementary, secondary, and college level schools.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>(a)Every bus with a seating capacity of less than twenty-four (24) pupils shall be equipped with the following:<section prefix='1.'>Nonleaking exhaust system;</section><section prefix='2.'>First aid kit;</section><section prefix='3.'>Fire extinguisher;</section><section prefix='4.'>Unbroken safety glass on all windows;</section><section prefix='5.'>Inside rear view mirror capable of giving the driver clear view of motor vehicles approaching from the rear; and</section><section prefix='6.'>Seats securely anchored.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Such vehicles shall be covered by liability insurance to protect pupils being transported.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Such vehicles shall transport no more passengers than they are equipped to seat.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to drive a private school bus over any street in Miami-Dade County without first having obtained a chauffeur's registration from the CSD pursuant to Chapter 31, Article V of this Code.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All school buses and all motor vehicles covered by subsection (1) shall be inspected annually by the Department, and when found satisfactory for safe operation shall display on the vehicle a current certificate of inspection.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Department shall promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary to effect the purposes of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 94-15, ยง 2, 1-20-94)</history></law>