<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-300</section_number>
<catch_line>Unlawful speed.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003420</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-300. Unlawful speed.<section prefix='(1)'>No person shall drive a vehicle on a highway at a speed greater than is reasonable and prudent under the conditions and having regard to the actual and potential hazards then existing. In every event, speed shall be controlled as may be necessary to avoid colliding with any person, vehicle, or other conveyance or object on or entering the highway in compliance with legal requirements and the duty of all persons to use due care.</section><section prefix='(2)'>(a)On all highways except those provided for in paragraph (b), the maximum speed limits for motor vehicles of less than eight thousand (8,000) pounds and motor vehicles designed for carrying passengers shall be:<section prefix='1.'>Thirty (30) miles per hour in business or residential districts.</section><section prefix='2.'>Sixty-five (65) miles per hour during the daytime at other locations on the highway.</section><section prefix='3.'>Sixty (60) miles per hour during the nighttime at other locations on the highway.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On all highways which are outside of business and residential districts and which have at least four (4) lanes divided by a median strip at least twenty (20) feet wide and on all highways which comprise a part of the national system of interstate and defense highways, the maximum speed limits for motor vehicles of less than eight thousand (8,000) pounds and motor vehicles designed for carrying passengers shall be seventy (70) miles per hour during the daytime and sixty-five (65) miles per hour during the nighttime.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The maximum speed limits for motor vehicles of more than eight thousand (8,000) pounds or any combination of vehicles, except as provided in paragraph (d), shall be:<section prefix='1.'>Thirty (30) miles per hour in business or residential districts.</section><section prefix='2.'>During daytime, sixty-five (65) miles per hour on highways provided for in paragraph (b) and sixty (60) miles per hour on other highways.</section><section prefix='3.'>During nighttime, sixty (60) miles per hour on highways provided for in paragraph (b) and fifty-five (55) miles per hour on other highways.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>The maximum speed limit for motor vehicle towing house trailers shall be:<section prefix='1.'>Thirty (30) miles per hour in business or residential districts.</section><section prefix='2.'>During daytime, sixty (60) miles per hour on highways provided for in paragraph (b) and fifty-five (55) miles per hour on other highways.</section><section prefix='3.'>During nighttime, fifty-five (55) miles per hour on highways provided for in paragraph (b) and fifty (50) miles per hour on other highways.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>The minimum speed on all highways which comprise a part of the national system of interstate and defense highways and having not less than four (4) lanes, shall be forty (40) miles per hour.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>No school bus shall exceed the maximum speed limit of fifty-five (55) miles per hour on highways which form a part of the national interstate system or on any expressway or limited access four-lane road or when involved in interCounty travel on highways outside of municipalities with respect to extracurricular activities authorized by the School Board, forty (40) miles per hour on the highways outside of municipalities of which are not a part of the national system of interstate highways, or twenty-five (25) miles per hour in any business or residential district.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The driver of every vehicle shall, consistent with the requirements of subsection (1), drive at an appropriately reduced speed when:<section prefix='(a)'>Approaching and crossing an intersection or railway grade crossing;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Approaching and going around a curve;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Approaching a hill crest;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Traveling upon any narrow or winding roadway; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any special hazard exists with respect to pedestrians or other traffic, or by reason of weather or highway conditions.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>No person shall drive a motor vehicle at such a slow speed as to impede or block the normal and reasonable movement of traffic, except when reduced speed is necessary for safe operation or in compliance with law.</section><section prefix='(6)'>No person shall operate any motor-driven cycle at nighttime at a speed greater than thirty-five (35) miles per hour unless such motor-driven cycle is equipped with a headlamp or lamps which are adequate to reveal a person or vehicle at a distance of three hundred (300) feet ahead.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>