<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-309</section_number>
<catch_line>Reregistration of certain motor vehicles not conforming with Section 30-307.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003429</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-309. Reregistration of certain motor vehicles not conforming with Section 30-307.<section>Any motor vehicles or combination of vehicles which conformed to the requirements of motor vehicle laws relative to weights and sizes prior to the enactment of Chapter 25342, Laws of Florida, 1949, which are now registered and continue to reregister yearly for operation in this State, and due to their peculiar construction and design may not, in the opinion of the Department, be made to conform to the axle spacing requirements of Section 30-199 without excessive expenses may be continued in operation for the life of the vehicle, subject to all safety and operational requirements of law, without being made to conform to the axle spacing requirements of provided that such vehicles or combination of vehicles shall be limited to a total gross load, including weight of vehicle, of twenty thousand (20,000) pounds per axle plus scale tolerances and shall not exceed five hundred fifty (550) pounds per inch width tire surface. Such vehicles equipped with more than three (3) axles shall not exceed a gross weight, including the weight of the vehicle and scale tolerances of seventy thousand (70,000) pounds provided such gross weight shall not exceed twenty thousand (20,000) pounds per axle and five hundred fifty (550) pounds per inch width of tire surface plus scale tolerances. Such reregistration may be made only by the Department and shall show that the license is a specially issued one. Dump trucks, concrete mixing trucks, fuel oil and gasoline trucks designed and constructed for special type work or use need not be registered as required herein, but shall meet the requirements of this section as to load limits. Any vehicle violating the weight provisions of this section shall be penalized as provided in.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>