<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-360</section_number>
<catch_line>Certain vehicles to carry flares or other devices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003482</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-360. Certain vehicles to carry flares or other devices.<section prefix='(1)'>No person shall operate any truck, bus or truck-tractor, or any motor vehicle towing a house trailer, upon any highway outside an urban district or upon any divided highway at any time between sunset and sunrise unless there is carried in such vehicles the following equipment except as provided in subsection (2).<section prefix='(a)'>At least three (3) flares or three (3) red electric lanterns or three (3) portable red emergency reflectors, each of which shall be capable of being seen and distinguished at a distance of not less than six hundred (600) feet under normal atmospheric conditions at nighttime. No flare, fusee, electric lantern or warning flag shall be used for the purpose of compliance with the requirements of this section unless such equipment is of a type which has been submitted to the Department and approved by it. No portable reflector unit shall be used for the purpose of compliance with the requirements of this section unless it is so designed and constructed as to be capable of reflecting red light clearly visible from all distances within six hundred (600) feet to one hundred (100) feet under normal atmospheric conditions at night when directly in front of lawful lower beams of head lamps, and unless it is of a type which has been submitted to the Department and approved by it.</section><section prefix='(b)'>At least three (3) red-burning fusees unless red electric lanterns or red portable emergency reflectors are carried.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>No person shall operate at the time and under conditions stated in subsection (1) any motor vehicle used for the transportation of explosives, any cargo tank truck used for the transportation of flammable liquids or compressed gases, or any motor vehicle using compressed gas as a fuel unless there is carried in such vehicle three (3) red electric lanterns or three (3) portable red emergency reflectors meeting the requirements of subsection (1), and there shall not be carried in any such vehicle any flares, fusees or signal produced by flame.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No person shall operate any vehicle described in subsections (1) or (2) upon any highway outside of an urban district or upon a divided highway at any time when lighted lamps are not required by Section 30-317 unless there is carried in such vehicle at least two (2) red flags, not less than twelve (12) inches square, with standards to support such flags.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>