<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-388.32</section_number>
<catch_line>Penalty for violation of article.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003547</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-388.32. Penalty for violation of article.<section prefix='(a)'>Violations of this article shall be punishable by the fine indicated below:</section><section>Schedule of Parking Fines and Costs</section><section prefix='(b)'>Reduced fine schedule for persons pleading guilty by mail: Upon a finding that it will further the interests of justice and promote judicial economy, the Chief Judge may, by administrative order, reduce the fines prescribed in subsection (a) of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Except as set forth in subsection (a), above, Section 30-447, and Section 30-292, all violations of ordinances and statutes regulating, prohibiting or otherwise controlling the parking of motor vehicles shall be punished by a fine not to exceed thirty dollars ($30.00), plus the surcharge provided in subsection (g) and, after thirty (30) days, the imposition of late penalties in the amount of twenty-three dollars ($23.00) to be distributed in accordance with this chapter, unless otherwise provided by ordinance, statute, or administrative order of the Chief Judge.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In addition to the fines and costs referred to in subsection (a), upon a finding of guilty after trial, the Court shall assess court costs against the guilty party.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Chief Judge may, by administrative, order, designate and specially set aside five dollars ($5.00) for each assessment of costs referred to in subsection (a) for the establishment of a Parking System Trust Fund and a Court Facility Trust Fund. Three dollars ($3.00) shall be placed in the Parking System Trust Fund and the remaining two dollars ($2.00) shall be placed in the Court Facility Trust Fund. The Chief Judge and the Clerk of the Court may authorize expenditure to these funds for maintenance and enhancement of the Parking Violations Bureau and court facilities.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Clerk of the Courts may designate and specially set aside four dollars ($4.00) for each assessment of costs referred to in subsection (a) for the establishment of the Clerk's Service Enhancement Trust Fund which shall be used for the maintenance and enhancement of the functions of the Clerk.</section><section prefix='(g)'>A surcharge of four dollars ($4.00) is imposed on parking fines and monies collected shall be placed in the School Crossing Guard Trust Fund as authorized by Section 316.660(4)(c), Florida Statutes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, § 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 81-62, § 2, 6-2-81; Ord. No. 86-7, § 2, 2-4-86; Ord. No. 90-72, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 94-183, § 9, 9-21-94; Ord. No. 01-64, § 2, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 03-70, § 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 07-137, § 2, 10-2-07)</history></law>