<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-301</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of school speed zones, enforcement; designation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003421</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-301. Establishment of school speed zones, enforcement; designation.<section prefix='(1)'>School zone speed limit shall be fifteen (15) miles per hour for all public and private schools, except high schools, which shall be individually studied for determination of appropriate speed limit, when designated by the appropriate traffic control devices as stipulated in Sections 30-301(2), (3), and (4) below. Such speed limit shall be in force only during those times thirty (30) minutes before and thirty (30) minutes after the times necessary and corresponding to the periods of time when pupils are arriving at and leaving regularly scheduled school sessions.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Permanent signs designating school zones and school zone speed limits shall be uniform in size and color, and shall have the times during which the restrictive speed limit is enforced clearly designated thereon. The Department of Transportation shall establish adequate standards for the signs.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Portable signs designating school zones and school zone speed limits shall be uniform in size and color. Such signs shall be erected on the roadway only during those hours when pupils are arriving at and leaving regularly scheduled school sessions. The Department of Transportation shall establish adequate standards for the signs.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Nothing herein shall prohibit the use of automatic traffic control devices for the control of vehicular and pedestrian traffic at school crossings in lieu of permanent or portable school zone signs. The Department of Transportation shall establish standards for automatic flashing signals.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 88-63, ยง 1, 7-5-88)</history></law>