<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-389.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Withholding of license tag or revalidation sticker.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003554</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-389.5. Withholding of license tag or revalidation sticker.<section prefix='(a)'>The Clerk of the Court or the Parking Violations Bureau shall supply the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles monthly with a magnetically encoded computer tape reel or cartridge, which is machine readable by the installed computer system at the Department, listing tags of persons who have three (3) or more outstanding parking violations or any outstanding violations of Sections 316.1955 or 316.1956, Florida Statutes, or Section 30-447 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, regulating parking in spaces designated for use by disabled persons.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the name of an applicant for vehicle registration appears on the list referred to in subsection (a), no license plate or revalidation sticker shall be issued until such person's name no longer appears on said list or until he/she presents a receipt from the Clerk showing that such parking fines have been paid.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Tax Collector and the Clerk of the Court shall be entitled to receive monthly, as costs for implementing and administering this section, ten (10) percent of the civil penalties and fines recovered from said persons. If the Tax Collector has private tag agents, such tag agents shall be entitled to receive a pro rata share of the amount paid to the Tax Collector, based upon the percentage of license plates and revalidation stickers issued by such tag agent compared to the total issued within the County.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The authority to issue license plates of any private agent who issues any license plate or revalidation sticker contrary to the provisions of this subsection may be revoked after notice and hearing as provided in Chapter 120, Florida Statutes and existing County ordinances.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 86-7, ยง 5, 2-4-86; Ord. No. 89-124, ยง 1, 12-5-89; Ord. No. 90-72, ยง 2, 7-24-90)</history></law>