<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-332</section_number>
<catch_line>Lamps, reflectors and emblems on farm tractors, farm equipment and implements of husbandry.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003454</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-332. Lamps, reflectors and emblems on farm tractors, farm equipment and implements of husbandry.<section prefix='(1)'>Every farm tractor and every self-propelled unit of farm equipment or implement of husbandry manufactured or assembled after January 1, 1972 shall be equipped with vehicular hazard warning lights visible from a distance of not less than one thousand (1,000) feet to the front and rear in normal sunlight, which shall be displayed whenever any such vehicle is operated upon a highway.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Every farm tractor and every self-propelled unit of farm equipment or implement of husbandry manufactured or assembled after January 1, 1972, shall at all times, and every other such motor vehicle shall at all times mentioned in Section 30-317 be equipped with lamps and reflectors as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>At least two (2) head lamps meeting the requirements of Sections 30-337 and 30-339</section><section prefix='(b)'>At least one (1) red lamp visible when lighted from a distance of not less than one thousand (1,000) feet to the rear mounted as far to the left of the center of the vehicle as practicable.</section><section prefix='(c)'>At least two (2) red reflectors visible from all distances within six hundred (600) feet to one hundred (100) feet to the rear when directly in front of lawful lower beams of head lamps.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Every combination of farm tractor and towed farm equipment or towed implement of husbandry shall at all times mentioned in Section 30-317 be equipped with lamps and reflectors as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>The farm tractor shall be equipped as required in subsections (1) and (2).</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the towed unit or its load extends more than four (4) feet to the rear of the tractor or obscures any light thereon, the unit shall be equipped on the rear with at least two (2) red reflectors visible from all distances within six hundred (600) feet to one hundred (100) feet to the rear when directly in front of lawful lower beams of head lamps.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the towed unit of such combination extends more than four (4) feet to the left of the center line of the tractor, the unit shall be equipped on the front with an amber reflector visible from all distances within six hundred (600) feet to one hundred (100) feet to the front when directly in front of lawful lower beams of head lamps. This reflector shall be so positioned to indicate, as practicable, the extreme left projection of the towed unit.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>The two (2) red reflectors required in the foregoing subsections shall be so positioned as to show from the rear, as nearly as practicable, the extreme width of the vehicle or combination carrying them. Provided that all other requirements are met, reflective tape or paint may be used in lieu of the reflectors required by subsection (3).</section><section prefix='(5)'>Every farm tractor and every self-propelled unit of farm equipment or implement of husbandry designed for operation at speeds not in excess of twenty-five (25) miles per hour shall at all times be equipped with a slow moving vehicle emblem mounted on the rear except as provided in subsection (6).</section><section prefix='(6)'>Every combination of farm tractor and towed farm equipment or towed implement of husbandry normally operating at speeds not in excess of twenty-five (25) miles per hour shall at all times be equipped with a slow moving vehicle emblem as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Where the towed unit or any load thereon obscures the slow moving vehicle emblem on the farm tractor, the towed unit shall be equipped with a slow moving vehicle emblem. In such cases, the towing vehicle need not display the emblem.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Where the slow moving vehicle emblem on the farm tractor unit is not obscured by the towed unit or its load, then either or both may be equipped with the required emblem but it shall be sufficient if either has it.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The emblem required by subsections (5) and (6) shall comply with current standards and specifications of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers approved by the Department.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>