<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-388.15</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking prohibited for certain purposes.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003529</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-388.15. Parking prohibited for certain purposes.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall park a vehicle upon any road, street or public right-of-way, including the sidewalk and swale, located within unincorporated Miami-Dade County, except outside the urban development boundary, for the purpose of:<section prefix='(1)'>Displaying such vehicle for sale.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Greasing, or repairing such vehicle, except repairs necessary in an emergency.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Displaying advertising.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Selling merchandise from such vehicle except in a duly established market place, or when so authorized or licensed under the ordinances of this County.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Storage, or as junkage or dead storage for more than twenty-four (24) hours.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>All violations of this section shall be punishable by a fine of one hundred dollars ($100.00) for the first vehicle on a first offense and five hundred dollars ($500.00) per vehicle for each additional vehicle and any repeat violation of this section. Any vehicle in violation of this section shall be towed if not removed immediately by the owner. Any vehicle that the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department or his/her designee deems to pose a serious threat to the public health, safety, or welfare and is in violation of this section shall be towed if not removed within twenty-four (24) hours by the owner. (Vehicle owners will be responsible for all fines, towing fees, storage fees, and any administrative and enforcement fees that result from the enforcement of this section.) The County may lien the vehicle and any real property owned by the violator in Miami-Dade County until all fines, enforcement costs, and administrative costs are paid by the violator.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71; Ord. No. 95-211, ยง 2, 11-21-95; Ord. No. 01-86, ยง 3, 5-8-01; Ord. No. 03-70, ยง 1, 4-8-03)</history></law>