<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-390</section_number>
<catch_line>Inspection of vehicles; required; exceptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003555</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-390. Inspection of vehicles; required; exceptions.<section prefix='(a)'>Every motor vehicle registered or required to be registered within the State of Florida when operated within this County or stopped upon any street or highway within this County shall at all times display a current approved certificate which shall be placed on the vehicle indicating that it has been inspected in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 325, Florida Statutes, and Chapter 30, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and has been found to comply with the standards and requirements of these laws for safety equipment.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, every law enforcement officer of this County shall recognize any current official inspection sticker affixed to any motor vehicle from another state, and vehicles operating under a Certificate of the Interstate Commerce Commission or Florida Public Service Commission subject to United States Department of Transportation safety regulations are exempt from displaying a Florida official inspection sticker; provided they have attached or displayed a valid certificate number issued by the Interstate Commerce Commission or Florida Public Service Commission.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It is unlawful for any person to drive, operate, stop or park, or for the owner to cause or knowingly permit to be driven, operated, stopped or parked on any public street, road, highway, or on any parking lot or facilities owned or operated by any governmental unit within this County, any motor vehicle which is required under the laws of the State or as required by this article to be inspected, unless such motor vehicle has been inspected and has attached thereto, in proper position, a valid and unexpired certificate of inspection.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>