<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-388</section_number>
<catch_line>Creation of emergency vehicle zones.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003514</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-388. Creation of emergency vehicle zones.<section prefix='(a)'>On application of the owner or lessor of real property and payment of the fee established in accordance with subsection (e) of this section, the County Manager or authorized designee(s) shall inspect the grounds of any shopping center, shopping mall, parking lot or parking garage and determine whether there are areas within such shopping center, shopping mall, parking lot or parking garage which should be kept free of parked motor vehicles in order to facilitate access to buildings by authorized emergency vehicles as defined in Section 316.003, Florida Statutes. When making this determination, the Manager or authorized designees shall consider the following factors:<section prefix='(1)'>The number of people who frequent the property;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The accessibility of the property by authorized emergency vehicles;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The frequency of calls for emergency services at the property;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The need for accessibility to buildings by tenants, vendors and persons making deliveries to the property; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>Official acts of County and municipal zoning and planning boards and agencies which relate to the property.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Manager, or authorized designee(s), upon determining that there are areas within a shopping, center, shopping mall, parking lot or parking garage, which should be kept free of parked vehicles in order to facilitate access to building by authorized emergency vehicles, shall discuss the matter with the owner or lessee of the property, and if there is no objection, order that the owner or lessee of the property erect emergency vehicle zone signs in accordance with subsection (d) of this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The owner or lessee of a shopping center, shopping mall, parking lot or parking garage who has made application to the County Manager or authorized designee(s) pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may withdraw the application at any time by notifying the County Manager or authorized designee in writing of the withdrawal of the application.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Areas in which parking is to be prohibited pursuant to this section shall be conspicuously posted with signs advising motorists that parking is prohibited. The County Manager or authorized representative may designate the form of the sign to be used; provided, however, that nothing herein shall prohibit the County Manager or designee from authorizing the continued use of nonconforming signs which were in place when the property was inspected pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All signs erected or allowed by subsection (d) of this section shall be installed and maintained by the property owner or lessee of the property.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The County Manager may, by administrative order, establish a fee for inspection of property and establishment of emergency vehicle zones pursuant to this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 83-23, ยง 1, 5-3-83)</history></law>