<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-310.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Maximum height, length and width of vehicles; projecting loads.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003431</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-310.1. Maximum height, length and width of vehicles; projecting loads.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall drive, move, stop or park, and no owner shall cause or knowingly permit to be driven, moved, stopped or parked on any street of this County and vehicle or vehicles of a size or weight or gross loaded weight exceeding the maximum limitations specified in the laws of the State as to such size, weight, or gross loaded weight unless such person or owner is authorized to drive, stop, park such vehicle of a size or weight exceeding the maximum by special permit of the Department of Transportation on State highways as provided by the laws of the State, or by special permit issued by the Director, Public Works Department, as provided in subsection (e).</section><section>The provisions of this section shall not apply to fire apparatus, road machinery or to implements of husbandry temporarily moved upon a street.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The load upon any vehicle operated alone, or the load upon the front vehicle of a combination of vehicles shall not extend beyond the front wheels of such vehicle or the headlamp lenses of such vehicle, provided that the part of any load projecting ahead of the rear of the cab, or driver's compartment shall be so loaded as not to obscure the vision of the driver to the front or either side.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Whenever the load upon any vehicle or any projection on any vehicle extends to the rear four (4) feet or more, beyond the bed or body of such vehicle, there shall be displayed at the extreme rear end of the load or projection at the times specified in Section 30-310.2, red light or lantern plainly visible from a distance of at least five hundred (500) feet to the sides and the rear. The red light or lantern required under this section shall be in addition to the red rear light required upon every vehicle. At any other time there shall be displayed at the extreme rear end of such load a red flag or cloth not less than sixteen (16) inches square.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In no event shall a load project for a distance of more than ten (10) feet from the rear of the vehicle except as hereinafter permitted.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Director, Public Works Department, is authorized to permit the movement of vehicles having a greater width, height, length or having a load of greater length as hereinabove specified in this section upon application to his office for such special permission.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Schedule of permit fees for the movement of oversize and overweight vehicles. The Miami-Dade County Public Works Department shall charge and collect permit fees for the movement of oversize and overweight vehicles and fees for equipment and personnel at the rates established by separate administrative order which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Agencies of federal, State, County and municipal governments may obtain permits for movement of oversize/overweight vehicles without paying the fees set forth in subsection (f). Nongovernmental firms or individuals doing work for such governmental agencies may obtain trip permits for the movement of oversize/overweight vehicles without paying the fees set forth in subsection (f) if the movement for which the permit is sought is part of the work being done by the nongovernmental firm or individual for the governmental agency. The Director, Public Works Department, shall, through standard procedures established by him for that purpose, determine the existence or nonexistence of facts entitling a permittee to the fee exemption provided by this subsection.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The permittee shall be responsible for the repair of any damage to property resulting from the move. Upon notification from the Public Works Department, the permittee shall make arrangements for the expeditious repair of such damage. In case the permittee fails to repair the damage within fifteen (15) days, the County shall make such repairs and the permittee shall be liable for all costs incurred. No permit shall be issued for any person or firm who has failed to make the required repairs or who has failed to reimburse the County for such repairs until such repairs or reimbursements are made.</section><section prefix='(j)'>All moving contractors requesting permits for the movement of any load exceeding the limits established by this section or by other sections of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall maintain at all times with an insurance company authorized to do business in the State of Florida, the limits of insurance required by any applicable law or authority having jurisdiction, but no less than bodily injury liability insurance in the minimum amounts of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) for one (1) person and one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) for more than one (1) person in any one (1) accident, and property damage insurance in the minimum amount of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) for any one (1) accident including damage to public rights-of-way. Certificates signed by a qualified agent of the insurer shall be filed with the Public Works Department showing the type of policy issued, the policy number, name of the insurer, amount and effective date of the policy and any other pertinent information requested by the County.</section><section prefix='(k)'>All proceeds collected by the Public Works Department under terms of this section shall be forthwith transmitted to the Director, Finance Department, who shall deposit said proceeds in the general fund.</section><section prefix='(l)'>The Director, Public Works Department, shall make and prescribe such rules and regulations reasonably necessary and appropriate for the proper administration of the provisions of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 72-25, ยง 1, 5-2-72; Ord. No. 85-18, ยง 1, 4-2-85)</history></law>