<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-323</section_number>
<catch_line>Certain lights prohibited; exceptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003445</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-323. Certain lights prohibited; exceptions.<section prefix='(1)'>No person shall drive or move or cause to be moved any vehicle or equipment upon any highway within this State with any lamp or device thereon showing or displaying a red or blue light visible from directly in front thereof except for certain vehicles hereinafter provided.</section><section prefix='(2)'>It is expressly prohibited for any vehicle or equipment, except police vehicles, to show or display blue lights.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vehicles of the fire department, fire patrol, including vehicles of volunteer firemen as permitted under Section 30-376 and ambulances as authorized under this chapter are permitted to show or display red lights. Wreckers, mosquito control fog and spray vehicles, emergency vehicles of governmental departments or public service corporations may show or display amber lights when in actual operation or a hazard exists provided they are not used going to and from the scene of operation or hazard without specific authorization of a law enforcement officer or law enforcement agency. Further, escort vehicles will be permitted to show or display amber lights when in actual process of escorting over-dimensioned equipment, material, or buildings as authorized by law. School buses may show and display lights as provided in Chapter 234, F.S.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Road or street maintenance equipment, road or street maintenance vehicles, road service vehicles and mail carrier vehicles may show or display amber lights when in operation or a hazard exists.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All lighting equipment heretofore referred to shall meet all requirements as set forth in Section 30-341</section><section prefix='(6)'>Flashing lights are prohibited on vehicles except as a means of indicating a right or left turn, or to change lanes, or to indicate the vehicle is lawfully stopped or disabled upon the highway, or except that the lamps authorized in subsections (1), (2), (3) and (4) shall be permitted to flash.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Subsection (1) shall not apply to police, fire, or authorized emergency vehicles while in performance of their necessary duties.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>