<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-325</section_number>
<catch_line>Mounting of reflectors, clearance lamps and side marker lamps.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003447</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-325. Mounting of reflectors, clearance lamps and side marker lamps.<section prefix='(1)'>Reflectors when required by Section 30-362 shall be mounted at a height not less than twenty-four (24) inches and not more than sixty (60) inches above the ground on which the vehicle stands, except that if the highest part of the permanent structure of the vehicle is less than twenty-four (24) inches the reflector at such point shall be mounted as high as that part of the permanent structure will permit.<section prefix='(a)'>The rear reflectors on a pole trailer may be mounted on each side of the bolster or load.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any required red reflector on the rear of a vehicle may be incorporated with the tail lamp, but such reflector shall meet all the other reflector requirements of this chapter.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Clearance lamps shall, so far as is practicable, be mounted on the permanent structure of the vehicle in such a manner as to indicate the extreme height and width of the vehicle. Provided, that when rear identification lamps are required and are mounted as high as practicable, rear clearance lamps may be mounted at optional height and when the mounting of front clearance lamps results in such lamps failing to indicate the extreme width of the trailer, such lamps may be mounted at optional height but must indicate, as near as practicable, the extreme width of the trailer. Clearance lamps on truck tractors shall be located so as to indicate the extreme width of the truck tractor cab. Clearance lamps and side marker lamps may be mounted in combination provided illumination is given as required herein with reference to both.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>