<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-368</section_number>
<catch_line>Safety of vehicle; inspection.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003490</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-368. Safety of vehicle; inspection.<section>It is a violation of this chapter for any person to drive or move, or for the owner to cause or knowingly permit to be driven or moved, on any highway any vehicle or combination of vehicles which is in such unsafe condition as to endanger any person, or which does not contain those parts, or is not at all times equipped with such lamps and other equipment in proper condition and adjustment as required in this chapter, or which is equipped in any manner in violation of this chapter, or for any person to do any act forbidden, or fail to perform any act required, under this chapter.<section prefix='(1)'>Any police officer may at any time, upon reasonable cause to believe that a vehicle is unsafe or not equipped as required by law, or that its equipment is not in proper adjustment or repair, require the driver of the vehicle to stop and submit the vehicle to an inspection and such test with reference thereto as may be appropriate.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In the event the vehicle is found to be in unsafe condition or any required part or equipment is not present or is not in proper repair and adjustment, the officer may give written notice to the driver. Said notice shall require that the vehicle be placed in safe condition and its equipment in proper repair and adjustment within a period of forty-eight (48) hours.</section><section prefix='(3)'>It is unlawful to operate any vehicle on any of the streets or highways which is required under the laws of this State or any political subdivision thereof to be inspected, unless the vehicle has been inspected and has attached thereto, in proper position, a valid and unexpired certificate of inspection as required.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>