<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-304</section_number>
<catch_line>Maximum width, height, length.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003424</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-304. Maximum width, height, length.<section prefix='(1)'>The total outside width of any vehicle or the load thereon shall not exceed ninety-six (96) inches, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No vehicle shall exceed a height of thirteen (13) feet six (6) inches, inclusive of load carried thereon.</section><section prefix='(3)'>(a)No vehicle shall exceed a length of forty (40) feet extreme overall dimension, inclusive of front and rear bumpers, and load carried thereon; provided, that any vehicle in excess of thirty-five (35) feet, except buses, shall have not less than three (3) axles. No combination of vehicles coupled together shall consist of more than two (2) units and no such combination of vehicles shall exceed a total length of fifty-five (55) feet, inclusive of load carried thereon; provided, that automobile tow-away or drive-away operations, transporting new or used trucks may use what is known to the trade as saddle mounts, provided the overall length shall not exceed fifty-five (55) feet and in no instance may more than two (2) saddle mounts be towed.<section>Provided, combinations of vehicles up to five (5) in number will be authorized for the sole purpose of collecting refuse and transporting same to the dump by vehicles and combinations of vehicles provided that such vehicles or combination of vehicles shall be covered in such manner that refuse transported therein shall not spill from the vehicle, where they otherwise comply with the provisions of this law and only use the State roads to the extent necessary to collect and dispose of refuse.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Tour trains and similar operations which have been continuously conducted for one hundred twenty (120) days prior to the date this act becomes law shall also be authorized hereunder, subject to the length and other restrictions imposed by law, not in conflict with the provisions of this act.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>The load upon any vehicle operated alone, or the load upon the front vehicle of a combination of vehicles, shall not extend more than three (3) feet beyond the front wheels of the vehicle or the front bumper of the vehicle if it is equipped with a bumper.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The length limitation imposed by this section shall not apply to fire apparatus, to vehicles operated in the daytime when transporting poles, pipes, machinery or other objects of a structural nature which cannot readily be dismembered, nor to such vehicles transporting such objects operated at night by a public utility when required for emergency repair of public service facilities or properties, when operated under special permit as hereinafter provided for, but in respect to such night transportation every such vehicle and the load thereon shall be equipped with a sufficient number of clearance lamps on both sides and marker lamps upon the extreme ends of any projecting load to clearly mark the dimensions of the load.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>