<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-362</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional equipment required on certain vehicles.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003484</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-362. Additional equipment required on certain vehicles.<section>In addition to other equipment required in this chapter, the following vehicles shall be equipped as herein stated under the conditions in.<section prefix='(1)'>On every bus or truck, whatever its size, there shall be the following: On the rear, two (2) reflectors, one (1) at each side, and one (1) stop light.</section><section prefix='(2)'>On every bus or truck eighty (80) inches or more in overall width, in addition to the requirements in subsection (1):<section prefix='(a)'>On the front, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On the rear, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side.</section><section prefix='(c)'>On each side, two (2) side marker lamps, one (1) at or near the front and one (1) at or near the rear.</section><section prefix='(d)'>On each side, two (2) reflectors, one (1) at or near the front and one (1) at or near the rear.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>On every truck tractor:<section prefix='(a)'>On the front, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On the rear, one (1) stop light.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>On every trailer or semitrailer having a gross weight in excess of three thousand (3,000) pounds:<section prefix='(a)'>On the front, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On each side, two (2) side marker lamps, one (1) at or near the front and one (1) at or near the rear.</section><section prefix='(c)'>On each side, two (2) reflectors, one (1) at or near the front and one (1) at or near the rear.</section><section prefix='(d)'>On the rear, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side, also two (2) reflectors, one (1) at each side, and one (1) stop light.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>On every pole trailer in excess of three thousand (3,000) pounds gross weight:<section prefix='(a)'>On each side, one (1) side marker lamp and one (1) clearance lamp which may be in combination to show to the front, side and rear.</section><section prefix='(b)'>On the rear of the pole trailer or load, two (2) reflectors, one (1) at each side.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>On every trailer, semitrailer, and pole trailer weighing three thousand (3,000) pounds gross, or less: On the rear, two (2) reflectors, one (1) on each side. If any trailer or semitrailer is so loaded, or is of such dimensions as to obscure the stop light on the towing vehicle, then such vehicle shall also be equipped with one (1) stop light.</section><section prefix='(7)'>On every slow-moving vehicle or equipment, any animal-drawn vehicle, or any other machinery, designed for use and speeds less than twenty-five (25) miles per hour, including all road construction and maintenance machinery except when engaged in actual construction or maintenance work either guarded by a flagman or a clearly visible warning sign, which normally travels or is normally used at a speed of less than twenty-five (25) miles per hour and which is operated on a public highway:<section prefix='(a)'>A triangular slow-moving vehicle emblem SMV as described in, and displayed as provided in paragraph (b). The requirement of the emblem shall be in addition to any other equipment required by law. The emblem shall not be displayed on objects which are customarily stationary in use except while being transported on the roadway of any public highway of this State.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall adopt such rules and regulations as are required to carry out the purpose of this section. The requirements of such rules and regulations shall incorporate the current specifications for SMV emblems of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>