<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-376</section_number>
<catch_line>Display or use of red lights; motor vehicles of volunteer firefighters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003502</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-376. Display or use of red lights; motor vehicles of volunteer firefighters.<section prefix='(1)'>Privately owned vehicles belonging to the active firefighter members of regularly organized volunteer fire-fighting companies or associations, while en route to scenes of fires or other emergencies, in the line of duty as active firefighter members of regularly organized fire-fighting companies or associations may display or use red lights visible from the front and from the rear of such vehicles, subject to the following restrictions and conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The light may not have a light source greater than fifty (50) candlepower for each light displayed.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Two (2) such red lights may be displayed on each end of the vehicle and such lights shall be of the flasher or revolving type.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The red lights shall consist of a lamp with a red lens and shall not consist of an uncolored lens with a red bulb.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The red lights shall not be a part of the regular head lamps or tail lights or turn signal lights displayed on such vehicles.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No inscription of any kind shall appear across the face of the lenses of the red lights.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The lenses of the red lights shall not be less than three (3) inches nor more than eight (8) inches in diameter.</section><section prefix='(g)'>In order for an active volunteer firefighter to display such red light on his vehicle, he must first secure a written permit from the chief executive officers of the fire-fighting organization to use the red lights, and this permit shall be carried by him at all times while the red lights are displayed.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>It is unlawful for any person who is not an active firefighter member of a regularly organized volunteer fire-fighting company or association to display on any motor vehicle owned by him at any time, red lights as described above.</section><section prefix='(3)'>It is unlawful for any active volunteer firefighter to use or display red lights as provided for herein except while en route to scenes of fires or other emergencies in the line of duty.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Any active volunteer firefighter, or any other person who violates any of the provisions of this section, is guilty of a violation and, upon conviction, shall be fined in any sum not less than five dollars ($5.00) and no more than twenty-five dollars ($25.00), and shall be dismissed from membership of the fire-fighting organization by the chief executive officers thereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>