<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-377</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking meters; determining zones; installation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003503</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-377. Parking meters; determining zones; installation.<section prefix='(a)'>Authority of Traffic Director. The Traffic Director is hereby authorized to determine and designate metered parking zones, and to install and maintain upon any of the streets or parts of streets as many parking meters as necessary in said metered parking zones, where it is determined that the installation of parking meters shall be necessary to aid in the regulation, control and inspection of the parking of vehicles. The parking meters may be of whatever type as determined by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Length of spaces. Parking meter spaces shall be approximately twenty-two (22) feet in length.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Installation of meters. The Traffic Director shall cause to be fastened to the curb or sidewalk bordering upon each of said parking metered spaces, at or near the front or forward end of each such space, a parking meter.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Condition of meter; indicator. Each such parking meter shall be maintained in good working order and shall be equipped with an indicator showing the length of time which will elapse before the indicator shall show a violation, and the meter shall operate the time shown by such indicator before showing a violation.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Deposit of coin. Permission to park in the adjoining parking metered space shall be granted for the length of time indicated upon the deposit of a sum as required and indicated on the meter for such space.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>