<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-388.31.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking prohibited for display for sale.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003546</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-388.31.1. Parking prohibited for display for sale.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall park a vehicle upon a public or private street, public right-of-way, parking lot, vacant lot, or private property for the principal purpose of displaying such vehicle or other personal property thereon for sale or rental in violation of the zoning provisions of Chapter 33 of this Code or the applicable licensing provisions of Florida Law, unless said property is properly zoned for that type of business at that location and the vendor is duly licensed to transact such business at that location.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Police officers, Code Enforcement Officers, or such other persons designated by the County Manager, shall be authorized to have the vehicle towed to a garage designated or maintained by the County or a County contracted towing company.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All violations of this section shall be punishable by a fine of one hundred dollars ($100.00) for the first vehicle on a first offense and five hundred dollars ($500.00) per vehicle for each additional vehicle and any repeat violation of this section. Any vehicle in violation of this section shall be towed if not removed immediately by the owner. (Vehicle owners will be responsible for all fines, towing fees, storage fees, and any administrative and enforcement fees that result from the enforcement of this section.) The County may lien the vehicle and any real property owned by the violator in Miami-Dade County until all fines, enforcement costs, and administrative costs are paid by the violator.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-81, ยง 3, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 01-86, ยง 4, 5-8-01)</history></law>