<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-370.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Child safety alarm devices for vehicles transporting children for licensed day care centers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003494</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-370.1. Child safety alarm devices for vehicles transporting children for licensed day care centers.<section prefix='(a)'>Definition. For purposes of this section, "Day Care Center" means any licensed building or shelter in which custodial care is rendered to six (6) or more children age five (5) or younger in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Child Safety Alarm. On or after December 1, 2012, all vehicles used by or on behalf of a licensed Day Care Center for the transportation of children must be equipped with a child safety alarm device that prompts the driver to inspect the vehicle for children and passengers upon vehicle shut-off. The device must be properly maintained in working order at all times.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Designated Department. The Miami-Dade Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement Department ("Department") shall develop and adopt standards for the installation and performance of such devices.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Violation.<section prefix='A.'>On or after December 1, 2012, it shall be unlawful for any Day Care Center to transport a child in a vehicle that is not equipped with a child safety alarm device properly maintained in working order that prompts the driver to inspect the vehicle for children and passengers upon vehicle shut-off. Violations shall be enforced through and in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Director of the Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement Department is authorized to file any action in a court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this ordinance and to seek appropriate remedies. In any such action the Department shall be entitled to recover its reasonable costs in the enforcement of this ordinance including reasonable attorney fees.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-03, ยง 1, 1-24-12)</history></law>