<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-476.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Denial, revocation and suspension of licenses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003614</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-476.1. Denial, revocation and suspension of licenses.<section>The Director may deny, revoke, or suspend a license issued pursuant to the provisions of this article if the Director determines that the applicant or licensee has:<section prefix='(a)'>Violated any provision of this article, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Misrepresented or concealed a fact on the application, renewal application or replacement application for a license, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Aided or abetted a person who has not obtained a license to evade or avoid the provisions of this article, or</section><section prefix='(d)'>Engaged in any conduct as part of the performance of a contract for service which constitutes fraud, or</section><section prefix='(e)'>Violated any condition, limitation, or restriction of a license imposed by the Director, or</section><section prefix='(f)'>Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the trade or business of towing or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this article, or</section><section prefix='(g)'>Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation, written assurance of compliance, or any other lawful order of the Director, or</section><section prefix='(h)'>Was convicted of a violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(i)'>In addition to the foregoing, a license issued pursuant to this article shall be automatically suspended without a hearing when the CSD shall receive written notification that the licensee's officer, director or partner, or any other stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of the licensee or of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate partner of a partnership licensee, has been convicted of a felony as listed in Section 30-463(b)(9) or of three (3) misdemeanors after receiving a license. In addition to such suspension, the CSD shall forthwith initiate a hearing as hereinafter specified to consider revocation of such license. A licensee whose license has been suspended under this provision shall be entitled to reinstatement of his or her license upon proof that:<section prefix='(1)'>After a felony conviction, the licensee's civil rights have been restored or that the licensee otherwise qualifies for restoration of rights under Section 940.05, Florida Statutes; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>After a conviction of any other criminal offense, that the person convicted has successfully completed all sentences of incarceration, probationary periods, required rehabilitation activities, and payment of all fines and penalties imposed in connection with such criminal offense.</section></section></section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a license by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to this section, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-176, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>