<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-481</section_number>
<catch_line>Appeals from actions, decisions or determinations of the director; judicial review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003619</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-481. Appeals from actions, decisions or determinations of the director; judicial review.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any action, decision or determination of the Director pursuant to this article may request an administrative hearing before a hearing officer to appeal the action, decision or determination of the Director which resulted in the grievance. Appeal by administrative hearing of the action, decision or determination complained of shall be accomplished by filing a written request with the Director within fifteen (15) days after the date of the action, decision or determination complained of, a written notice of appeal which shall set forth the nature of the action, decision or determination to be reviewed and the basis for the administrative hearing. A timely request for administrative hearing shall be scheduled and heard by a Hearing Officer pursuant to Section 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section. The Hearing Officer shall set the matter for hearing on the earliest practicable regularly scheduled hearing date or as soon as possible, but no sooner than ten (10) days after the request has been filed and shall cause notice of the hearing to be served upon the aggrieved party by first class mail. The notice may include, but not be limited to, the applicable Sections of 8CC-6(b)(2) through (9) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The Hearing Officer shall hear and consider all relevant facts in accordance with the procedures set forth in Sections 8CC-6(e), (f), (g), (i), (j), (k), (l), (m)(2), and (n) of the Code of Miami-Dade County (any reference in these sections to Inspector shall mean "Director" and to violator shall mean "the person filing the appeal", and may affirm, modify or reverse the action, decision or determination appealed from. The decision of the Hearing Officer shall constitute final administrative review and no rehearing shall be permitted. Nothing herein shall be construed to prevent or prohibit the Director from instituting any civil or criminal action or proceeding authorized by this article at any time.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director, the Miami-Dade County Consumer Advocate, or any person regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action. The words "action," "decision" and "determination" as used herein shall not include the filing or institution of any action, conference or proceeding by the Director in any court or otherwise. Customers shall not be deemed to be persons regulated by this article for the purposes of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-176, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>