<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-464</section_number>
<catch_line>Issuance of license; renewal.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003600</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-464. Issuance of license; renewal.<section prefix='(a)'>The Director is empowered to issue licenses to applicants which have met the standards and requirements for a towing license, and to promulgate rules, regulations and procedures for the application, issuance and revocation of such licenses.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director shall review and investigate each application for a towing license and shall reject any application that is not properly filed or is incomplete or untrue in whole or in part, or which fails in any way to meet the requirements of subsection (c) of this section. An incomplete application shall be considered to be abandoned if an applicant fails to complete his or her application within sixty days from the date that the application was filed with the Director. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No towing license shall be issued to an applicant or renewed unless the applicant has completed the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Filed with the Director a true, correct and complete application on the form prescribed by the CSD, including all proofs of required insurance.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Paid the initial, renewal or late application fee, as applicable.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Submitted to a background investigation resulting in a determination by the Director that:<section prefix='a.'>Neither the applicant, nor any officer, director or partner of the applicant, nor any stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having a beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate applicant or of a corporate general partner of a partnership applicant, has a currently suspended license, has had its license revoked by action of the Director within two (2) years of the date of application, or has outstanding and unsatisfied civil penalties imposed on account of violations of this article.</section><section prefix='b.'>Neither the applicant, nor any officer, director or partner of the applicant, nor any stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having a beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate general partner of a partnership applicant, has been convicted of one (1) or more of the felonies listed in Section 30-463(b)(9) within the preceding five (5) years; or that three (3) misdemeanors have been committed within the thirty-six (36) month period preceding the date of application as described in subsection 30-463(b)(9), unless the civil rights of such individual or applicant have been restored or that such person has successfully completed all sentences of incarceration, probationary periods, required rehabilitation activities and payment of all fines and penalties imposed. For applicants requesting renewal, the Director may only consider crimes committed after the date the applicant obtained his or her license, unless such crimes were not previously disclosed in the original application.</section><section prefix='c.'>Each corporate or partnership applicant is qualified under the laws of Florida to do business under the trade name or names under which it has applied for a license.</section><section prefix='d.'>No fraud or willful or knowing misrepresentation or false statement was made in the application.</section><section prefix='e.'>No judgment against the applicant arising out of the activity of recovery, towing or removing a vehicle or providing storage in connection therewith remains unsatisfied, unless a stay or reversal of the judgment is procured through the courts.</section><section prefix='f.'>That there be no outstanding warrants of arrest against the applicant nor any officer, director or partner of the applicant nor any stockholder owning, holding, controlling or having a beneficial interest in five (5) percent or more of the issued and outstanding stock of a corporate general partner of a partnership applicant.</section><section prefix='(3)'>There are no (i) unpaid civil penalties; (ii) unpaid administrative costs of hearing; (iii) unpaid County investigative, enforcement, testing, or monitoring costs; or (iv) unpaid liens, any or all of which are owed to Miami-Dade County pursuant to the provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Each towing license shall be on a form prescribed by the CSD and shall be signed by the Director. Each towing license shall contain, at a minimum, the name and address of the applicant, the dates the license remains in effect unless suspended or revoked, and a statement of such additional terms and conditions, restrictions and limitations as were authorized in the application and approval process. Violation of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a license shall be a violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All initial towing licenses shall be effective from their date of issuance to the date of birth of the applicant, if the applicant is a sole proprietor, and in the case of a corporation or partnership, from the date of formation of the legal entity. The fee for the initial application shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Commission. The CSD shall, for each initial application, prorate the fee from the date of its issuance to the date of birth or date of formation of the applicant, whichever is the case.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Prior to the expiration of the initial towing license or expiration of the annual license, whichever is the case, an applicant may apply for an annual towing license. As a part of the renewal process, the original application shall be updated and verified by the applicant on forms prescribed by CSD. Renewal applications shall also include such financial information as CSD shall deem necessary to consider the continued appropriateness of maximum fees established pursuant to Section 30-476. Each updated renewal application shall be submitted at least sixty (60) days prior to expiration of the current initial or annual license and shall be accompanied by a fee which shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager approved by the Commission. All renewal application fees shall be deposited with original application fees and other charges and fees under this article in a separate Miami-Dade County fund and shall be used exclusively to accomplish the purposes of this article. The amount of the renewal fee shall be reasonably related to the cost of the services and regulation provided, and shall be in addition to any other fees or charges required by this article. All annual towing licenses which are not renewed shall automatically expire upon the one (1) year anniversary of the date of issuance and all recovery, towing, removing and storage services permitted thereunder shall cease immediately. The Director shall deny each renewal application that is not timely, is not properly filed, is incomplete, is untrue in whole or in part, is unaccompanied by the required fee, or results in a determination by the Director that the applicant has failed to satisfy the requirements of subsection (c)(3) of this section.</section><section prefix='(g)'>A license issued or renewed pursuant to the provisions of this article shall not be transferable, nor shall the ownership structure of the licensee be so modified as to constitute a change in the control or ownership of the license, without the prior written approval of the Director.</section><section prefix='(h)'>There shall be no numerical limit on licenses issued pursuant to the provisions of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 89-105, § 1, 11-7-89; Ord. No. 89-128, § 1, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>