<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. PARKING SPACES FOR DISABLED PERSONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-442</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking spaces provided by governmental agencies for certain disabled persons.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003589</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-442. Parking spaces provided by governmental agencies for certain disabled persons.<section prefix='(a)'>Miami-Dade County and each municipality within Miami-Dade County, and each agency, instrumentality and authority thereof, having jurisdiction over street parking or publicly owned and operated parking facilities shall provide a minimum number of specially designated and marked motor vehicle parking spaces for the exclusive use of those severely physically disabled individuals who have permanent mobility problems that substantially impair their ability to ambulate and who have been issued an exemption entitlement parking permit pursuant to Section 316.1958, Florida Statutes, or Section 320.0848, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The following minimum number of such parking spaces shall be provided:<section prefix='(1)'>One (1) space in the immediate vicinity of a building which houses a governmental entity or a political subdivision, including, but not limited to, State office buildings and courthouses, if no parking for the public is provided on the premises of such building;</section><section prefix='(2)'>One (1) space for each one hundred fifty (150) metered on-street parking spaces; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>For publicly maintained and operated parking facilities intended for public use and not subject to paragraph (1), the number of parking spaces for disabled persons as set forth in the following table:<section>However, when parking spaces are leased at such publicly maintained and operated parking facilities, the number of parking spaces for disabled persons shall be increased or decreased on demonstrated and documented need. A minimum of four (4) parking spaces for disabled persons shall be provided at a physical restoration rehabilitation center or a hospital.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Such parking spaces shall be designed and located as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>All spaces shall have accessible thereto a curb-ramp or curb-cut, when necessary to allow access to the building served, and shall be located so that users will not be compelled to wheel behind parked vehicles.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Diagonal or perpendicular parking spaces shall be a minimum of twelve (12) feet wide.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Parallel parking spaces shall be located either at the beginning or end of a block or adjacent to alley entrances. Curbs adjacent to such spaces shall be of a height which will not interfere with the opening and closing of motor vehicle doors.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Each such parking space shall be prominently outlined with paint and posted with a permanent above-grade sign of a color and design approved by the Department of Transportation, bearing the international symbol of accessibility and the caption "PARKING BY DISABLED PERMIT ONLY." In addition, each such parking space shall be provided with a sign stating "TOW-AWAY ZONE AND FINE UP TO $250.00."</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-39, ยง 1, 6-16-87)</history></law>