<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-463</section_number>
<catch_line>Application for towing license; fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003599</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-463. Application for towing license; fees.<section prefix='(a)'>Every application for a towing license shall be in writing, signed and verified by the applicant, and filed with the CSD together with an investigative, processing fee, or late fee as applicable, established by administrative order of the County Manager approved by the Commission. That application fee shall be deposited in a separate Miami-Dade County fund and shall be used exclusively to accomplish the purposes of this article. The amount of the application fee shall be reasonably related to the cost of the services and regulation provided. The statements contained in the application shall become a part of the towing license and may be modified only in accordance with the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Every application for a towing license shall be on a form prescribed by the CSD and shall contain all the information required by that form, including but not limited to:<section prefix='(1)'>Sufficient information to identify the applicant, including but not limited to, full legal name, date of birth or of formation of legal entity, telephone numbers, and all business and residence addresses. If the applicant is a corporation, the foregoing information shall also be provided for each corporate officer, director, resident agent and shareholder. If the applicant is a partnership, the foregoing information shall also be provided for each general and each limited partner. Post office box addresses shall not be accepted.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Documentation demonstrating that all corporate or partnership applicants are qualified to do business under the laws of Florida.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Photocopy of the occupational license of the applicant.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Photocopy of the certificate of use and occupancy of the applicant, indicating authorization for the business use of the applicant, for each business address located in unincorporated Miami-Dade County and identified in the application.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A list of all persons with any ownership interest in the applicant who have previously been denied a license.</section><section prefix='(6'>Any trade name under which the applicant operates, intends to operate, or has previously operated, and a description of proposed, existing and previous towing vehicles' colors and markings.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A description of the applicant's management plan, which shall include but not be limited to the following: location and description of all places of business, a description of all existing towing vehicles and equipment, a description of the plan and facilities for maintaining towing vehicles and equipment, a system for handling complaints and accidents, insurance coverage, and a description of any communication system.</section><section prefix='(8)'>A description of nonconsent tower services proposed to be provided, including but not limited to days and hours of operation and types of towing and storage services to be provided.</section><section prefix='(9)'>A record of all outstanding warrants of arrest; all misdemeanors committed within the preceding thirty-six (36) month period; and felonies of which the applicant has been convicted within the last five (5) years preceding the date of the application involving: criminal homicide; kidnapping; a sexual offense; an assaultive offense; robbery; burglary; arson; fraud; theft if the offense was committed against a person with whom the applicant came in contact with while engaged in the services regulated by this section; public indecency; possession of a weapon; and a violation of any laws regarding controlled substances.<section>Individual applicants shall obtain their fingerprints and photographs from the Miami-Dade Police Department and provide them with the application and, where civil rights have been restored or periods of incarceration or probation have been completed, as is further described in subsections(e)(1) and (2) below, provide such information with the application. In the case of a corporate or partnership applicant, all such information shall be provided by all corporate officers and directors, or partners, as the case may be, and by all stockholders who own, hold or control five (5) percent or more of issued and outstanding stock in the corporation or beneficial interest therein, and by all officers and directors of any corporate general partners of a partnership and by stockholders who own, hold or control five (5) percent or more of issued and outstanding stock in a corporate general partner, or beneficial interest therein.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Proof of insurance as required in Section 30-465 of this article.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The signature of each individual applicant, the signature of the president or vice-president of a corporate applicant, and the signature of all the general partners of a partnership applicant.</section><section prefix='(12)'>An agreement on the part of the applicant to abide by the provisions of this article, ordinances of municipalities having jurisdiction and Miami-Dade County, and the laws of the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(13)'>It shall be a violation of this section to fail to report to CSD any material change pertaining to the information supplied by the applicant or licensee for his or her license, including, but not limited to, changing the location of any of the applicant's place(s) of business.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Each nonconsent tower who applies for a license shall provide with his or her application for a license a listing of all of his or her existing or proposed rates and charges in a format approved by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Such additional information about the nonconsent tower applicant as the Director may deem appropriate.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-184, § 1, 10-17-95; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>