<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-476</section_number>
<catch_line>Maximum immobilization, nonconsent towing and storage rates for providing immobilization or tow services at the request of property owners or police agencies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003613</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-476. Maximum immobilization, nonconsent towing and storage rates for providing immobilization or tow services at the request of property owners or police agencies.<section prefix='(a)'>The Commission shall by resolution, establish maximum rates for providing immobilization, recovery, nonconsent towing, removal and storage services at the request of a police agency, or a property owner or authorized representative, without the prior consent of the vehicle owner or other authorized person in control of the vehicle. The rates established shall be uniform throughout Miami-Dade County, both in incorporated and unincorporated areas, except where municipalities pursuant to Sections 125.0103 and 166.043, Florida Statutes, have established differing maximum rates for their jurisdictions. From time to time, the maximum rates established by the Commission may be altered, revised, increased or decreased.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Persons who provide nonconsent towing services shall not charge in excess of the maximum allowable rates established by the Commission. No person providing services pursuant to this section shall charge any type of fee other than the fees for which the Commission has established specific rates.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to the maximum rates that may be charged by persons providing services pursuant to this section, the County shall charge an administrative fee of $15 for each vehicle that is recovered, towed, removed, or stored at the request of the Miami-Dade County Police Department. Any administrative fee charged and collected on behalf of the County by a person providing services at the County's request is hereby ratified and confirmed. All administrative fees, as described above, imposed before the effective date of this ordinance are ratified, validated, and confirmed in all respects, from the date any such fee was charged, billed, or collected.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 99-70, § 1, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 03-165, § 1, 7-22-03; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>