<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-478</section_number>
<catch_line>Scope of article.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003616</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-478. Scope of article.<section>The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive regulations applicable to the immobilization, recovery, towing and removal of vehicles in Miami-Dade County and all storage provided therewith; except that, " Nonconsent Towing Without the Prior Consent of the Vehicle Owner or Duly Authorized Driver of Vehicle," Section "Requirements for Providing Nonconsent Tow Services at Request of Property Owners," Section "Requirements for Property Owners Requesting Nonconsent Tows From Property," and "Requirements for immobilizing vehicles without prior consent of vehicle owner or duly authorized driver of vehicle," shall not apply in any municipality that has adopted and maintains in effect ordinances or regulations governing the same matters. Except as provided by this section, the regulations established by this article shall be applicable throughout Miami-Dade County both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries, and shall not be subject to modification by any municipality. The provisions of this article shall not apply to the immobilization of a motor vehicle by a governmental agency, or person acting at the direction of a governmental agency, when such immobilization is authorized by a court order. Except as provided by this section, all municipal ordinances or resolutions contrary to this article are hereby superseded and rescinded.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, ยง 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 99-70, ยง 1, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 03-176, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>