<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-468</section_number>
<catch_line>Manifest or trip records.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003604</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-468. Manifest or trip records.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith unless the person providing such service shall maintain in his or her possession a manifest or trip sheet which shall include but not be limited to the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>Name of the licensee and of the natural person physically providing the service.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Decal number of the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier used to provide the service.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Date and time that the service was requested.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Name, address and telephone number of the person requesting the service.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Date and time that the service was initiated.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Location at which the service originated.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Destination to which the vehicle being provided the service is taken.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Description of the vehicle being provided the service, including make, model, year, color, vehicle identification number and State license plate number, if any.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Description of services provided.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Cost(s) for the service(s) provided.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Any and all "load and offload" charges, including the name, badge number, and agency of the officer on the scene who approved these additional charges.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Date and time that the vehicle was delivered to the storage facility.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Each manifest or trip record shall be immediately available for inspection by police officers or by personnel authorized by the CSD to perform enforcement duties, at any time during the period of recovery, towing or removal of a vehicle.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each licensee shall maintain for no less than three (3) years the original of each manifest or trip record. No person providing the service shall destroy, mutilate, alter or deface any manifest or trip record prior to the expiration of three (3) years without written approval of the CSD. All manifests and trip records shall be available for inspection by personnel authorized by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, ยง 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, ยง 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, ยง 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 03-176, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>