<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-422</section_number>
<catch_line>Traffic intersection safety and traffic infraction detectors.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003587</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-422. Traffic intersection safety and traffic infraction detectors.<section prefix='(1)'>Purpose and intent. The purpose of this ordinance is to implement the Mark Wandall Traffic Safety Act, Chapters 2010-80 and 2010-163, Laws of Florida (HB 325 and HB 5501), as such may be amended from time to time (hereinafter the "Mark Wandall Traffic Safety Act" or the "Act"), in order to promote, protect and improve the health, safety and welfare of individuals and protect property in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Scope of regulation and applicability. The provisions of this section shall apply to and be enforced in only the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Use of Traffic Infraction Detectors. Miami-Dade County hereby exercises its authority pursuant to the Mark Wandall Traffic Safety Act to use traffic infraction detectors within the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County to enforce the Uniform Traffic Code of the State of Florida. The Mayor or designee is authorized to implement the provisions and requirements of the Act consistent with the specifications established by the Florida Department of Transportation, as such may be amended from time to time. The County is expressly authorized to use traffic infraction detectors to enforce red light signal violations pursuant to sections 316.074(1) and 316.075(1)(c)1., Florida Statutes, when a driver fails to stop at a traffic signal on streets and highways within the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. The provisions of this ordinance shall not otherwise prohibit a law enforcement officer from issuing a traffic citation to a driver for a red light signal violation in accordance with Chapters 316 and 318, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Right turn on red enforcement by traffic infraction detectors prohibited. Traffic infraction detectors shall not be used to enforce red light signal violations when a driver is making a right turn where such turns are permissible. This subsection shall not otherwise prohibit a law enforcement officer from issuing a traffic citation to a driver for a right turn violation in accordance with Chapters 316 and 318, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Traffic infraction enforcement officers. The Mayor or designee is authorized to designate traffic infraction enforcement officers to administer the County's red light camera program pursuant to the Mark Wandall Traffic Safety Act, as such may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Notice and appeals. Notification of a violation of the Mark Wandall Traffic Safety Act and appeals shall be provided as set forth in the Act, as such may be amended from time to time. The notice expressly shall advise the registered owner of the vehicle that he or she has a right to review the photographic or electronic images or streaming video evidence.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Penalties. A violation of the Mark Wandall Traffic Safety Act and section 30-422 shall be punishable as set forth in the Act, as such may be amended from time to time. The Act currently sets the fine at one hundred fifty-eight dollars ($158.00) per violation.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Signage and public awareness campaign. The Mayor or designee is directed to:<section prefix='i.'>Prior to installation of a traffic infraction detector at an intersection, install signage at the intersection indicating that traffic infraction detectors may be in use; and</section><section prefix='ii.'>No less than 30 days before traffic infraction detectors are installed, conduct a public awareness campaign related to traffic infraction detectors and red light safety.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>Permits for installation of traffic infraction detectors by municipalities on county roads and infrastructure. The Mayor or designee shall develop a policy for approval by this Board consistent with the Act setting the requirements for municipalities to acquire permits from the County to install traffic infraction detectors, including any applicable fees:<section prefix='i.'>On County roads within or adjacent to cities; and</section><section prefix='ii.'>On County traffic signal mast arms and other county infrastructure.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Revenue. Revenue realized by the County pursuant to the Act, once all associated costs have been paid and distributions made as required by the Act, shall supplement the unincorporated municipal service area (UMSA) budget. This provision shall be subject to annual appropriation by the Board.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Reporting. The Mayor or designee shall submit a report by October 1, 2012, and annually thereafter, to both the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles or its successor state department (DHSMV) and this Board detailing the results of using traffic infraction detectors and the procedures for enforcement for the preceding state fiscal year. The information submitted must include statistical data and information required by the DHSMV to complete the report required by the Mark Wandall Traffic Safety Act.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-01, ยง 1, 1-20-11)</history></law>