<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-467</section_number>
<catch_line>Decals; vehicle standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003603</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-467. Decals; vehicle standards.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or to store it in connection therewith unless the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier used to provide such service displays in the lower left corner of the front window a current decal issued by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director is authorized to issue current licensee decals for each separate towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier, upon application by the licensee and completion of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Inspection of vehicle records by personnel authorized by the CSD to determine ownership, or first-party lease held by the licensee, of the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Inspection by personnel authorized by CSD to assure that the non-governmentally owned towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier clearly displays on the front of the tow truck or car carrier body, the towing license number in letters at least three (3) inches high; and on the driver and passenger sides of the vehicle and/or doors, the licensee's name in letters at least three (3) inches high; and in letters at least one (1) inch high, the licensee's principal address and telephone number.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Inspection by personnel authorized by CSD to ascertain that the towing vehicle has the equipment required by rules to be promulgated by CSD and that such equipment is operable. If an inspection of the towing vehicle does not reveal that it meets the minimum ratings for the vehicle's class specifications, as contained in Section 30-461(22), the licensee must furnish the CSD a sworn statement that the towing vehicle meets the applicable minimum ratings.</section><section prefix='(4)'>An application form completed by the licensee and approved by the Director which correctly indicates the year, make, model and vehicle identification number of the towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Payment of a CSD decal fee set at an amount reasonably related to the costs of providing the services under this section. Such costs shall be set by administrative order of the County Manager approved by the Commission, and deposited and used in the same manner as other fees and charges under this article.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Decals shall be issued in numerical order, and each decal issued shall display its assigned number. Decals shall be issued with the initial license and shall be renewable annually in the same manner as original application is made.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The decal for each towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier shall be affixed by personnel authorized by the CSD, shall remain the property of the County, and shall at all times by displayed and available for inspection by any police officer or by personnel authorized by the CSD to perform enforcement duties.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 89-105, § 2, 11-7-89; Ord. No. 89-128, § 2, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>