<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-461</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003597</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-461. Definitions.<section>For the purposes of this article, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(1)'>Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(1.5)'>Consent Tower shall mean a person who tows a motor vehicle with the consent of the vehicle owner.</section><section prefix='(2)'>County Manager shall mean the chief executive officer and head of the administrative branch of County government as provided in Article 3 of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>CSD shall mean the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Decal shall mean an identifying sticker issued by the Director and appropriate for display in the lower left corner of the front window of a towing vehicle or equipment or car carrier used by a person licensed under this article.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Director shall mean the CSD Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Express instruction shall mean a clear, definite and explicit request:<section prefix='(a)'>Made in writing by a police officer to immobilize, recover, tow, remove or store a specific and individual vehicle which is disabled or abandoned or parked without authorization, or whose operator is unable or unwilling to remove the vehicle;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Made in writing by a property owner or duly authorized agent of the property owner to immobilize, recover, tow, remove or store a specific and individual vehicle parked without permission of the property owner; however, such property owner or agent shall not be the person requested to immobilize, recover, tow, remove or store the vehicle or an employee or agent thereof; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Made by telephone, in person or in writing by a vehicle owner or the authorized driver to recover, tow, remove or store a specific and individual vehicle which is in the lawful control of the vehicle owner or authorized driver requesting the towing service. The foregoing notwithstanding, where the property owner is a government entity, the property owner or an employee or agent thereof, may be the same person requested to recover, tow, remove or store the vehicle.</section><section>Every request made in writing or in person must indicate the date and time of the instruction and must be signed by the police officer, the property owner or agent, or the vehicle owner or authorized driver in the presence of the person providing the requested service. Every request made by telephone must also be documented with the date and time of the call.</section></section><section prefix='(6.5)'>Immobilization, immobilize or immobilizing, also known as boot or booting, shall mean the act of placing, on a parked vehicle, a mechanical device that is designed to be attached to the wheel or tire so as to prohibit its usual manner of movement.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Industry shall mean the business of recovering, towing or removing vehicles and providing such vehicle storage services as may be associated therewith.</section><section prefix='(8)'>License shall mean the certificate or document which allows a person to engage in Miami-Dade County in the activity of recovering, towing, removing and storing of vehicles for compensation. As used in this article, "license" shall not mean a municipal occupational license or a County occupational license.</section><section prefix='(8.5)'>Nonconsent Tower shall mean persons who perform "Police Directed Tows" or "Private Property Impounds" as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Operate shall mean to provide for compensation the services of recovering, towing or removing vehicles and any vehicle storage services associated therewith.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Operator shall mean any person who provides for compensation the services of recovering, towing, or removing vehicles and any vehicle storage services associated therewith.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Person shall mean any natural person, firm, partnership, association, corporation or other entity of any kind whatsoever.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Personnel authorized by the CSD shall mean enforcement personnel authorized by the Director and presenting valid identification.</section><section prefix='(12.5)'>Police Directed Tow shall mean the removal and storage of wrecked or disabled vehicles at the direction of police/law enforcement from an accident scene or the removal and storage of vehicles in the event the owner or operator is incapacitated, unavailable, or otherwise does not consent to the removal of the vehicle, excepting, however, all incidents of Private Property Impounds as herein defined.</section><section prefix='(12.6)'>Private Property Impound shall mean towing or removal of a vehicle, without the consent of the vehicle's owner or operator, as such is authorized by Section 715.07, Florida Statutes, as may be amended, when that vehicle is parked on private real property.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Property owner shall mean that person who exercises dominion and control over real property, including but not limited to the legal titleholder, lessee, designated representative of a condominium association or any person authorized to exercise a share dominion and control over real property; however, "property owner" shall not mean or include a person providing towing services within the purview of this article. The foregoing notwithstanding, all government entities providing their own towing services may be property owners for purposes of this article.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Recover shall mean to take possession of a vehicle and its contents and to exercise control, supervision and responsibility over it.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Regulation shall mean a rule set forth in this article, the violation of which is sufficient grounds for fines; suspension or revocation of a towing license; civil damages, court costs and attorneys fees; and specified criminal penalties.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Remove shall mean to change the location of a vehicle by towing it.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Revoke shall mean to annul and make void the license of a person engaged in the business of providing towing services.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Store shall mean to place and leave a towed vehicle at a location where the person providing the towing service exercises control, supervision and responsibility over the vehicle. The storage facility must be securely fenced or locked for the protection of vehicles and property.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Tow shall mean to haul, draw or pull along a vehicle by means of another vehicle equipped with booms, car carriers, winches or similar equipment.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Trade name shall mean any name under which a person, corporation, partnership, association, firm or any other entity operates its business.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Vehicle shall mean an automobile, truck, bus, trailer, semitrailer, truck tractor semitrailer combination, recreational unit primarily designed as temporary living quarters which either has its own motive power or is mounted on or drawn by another vehicle, or any other mobile item using wheels and being operated on the roads of Miami-Dade County, which is used to transport persons or property and is propelled by power other than muscular power; provided, however, that the term does not include bicycles, mopeds, traction engines, road rollers or vehicles which run only upon a track.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Wrecker class shall mean the type of towing vehicle, equipment or apparatus used to recover, tow or remove vehicles. The wrecker classes shall be distinguished as follows:</section></section><section></section><section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, § 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, § 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 99-70, § 1, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 03-176, § 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>