<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-462</section_number>
<catch_line>Towing license required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003598</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-462. Towing license required.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith or to cause or permit any other person for compensation to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith, or to advertise or offer to recover, tow or remove a vehicle or provide storage in connection therewith, without first obtaining and maintaining a current and valid license pursuant to the provisions of this article; provided, however, that a property owner without a license may cause or permit the removal of a vehicle from his or her property in accordance with the provisions of this article. The provisions of this ordinance do not apply to persons who use a towing vehicle to transport their vehicles purely for personal, family, household or recreational use.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Nothing in this article shall be construed to prohibit the discharge or storage of a vehicle lawfully recovered, towed or removed in another County and lawfully transported into Miami-Dade County; nor shall anything in this article be construed to prohibit a vehicle owner or his authorized agent from requesting the services of a towing business not regularly doing towing business in Miami-Dade County, to remove the owner's vehicle to a location outside Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Nothing in this article shall be construed to prevent a natural person from working in an employment relationship for another person holding a valid license under this article; however, any person who is an independent contractor and not an employee of a licensed person is also subject to all the requirements and provisions of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, ยง 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, ยง 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, ยง 1, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-184, ยง 1, 10-17-95)</history></law>