<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-417</section_number>
<catch_line>Specific duties of Traffic Director.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003582</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-417. Specific duties of Traffic Director.<section>The Traffic Director is hereby authorized to:<section prefix='(1)'>Through streets. Designate streets or parts of said streets, as through streets.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Stop streets and stop signs. Determine and designate intersections where a particular hazard exists upon other than through streets and to determine whether vehicles shall stop at one (1) or more entrances to any such intersection, and shall cause to be erected a stop sign at every place where he shall find a stop required, except at those intersections which are controlled by automatic signals or other traffic-control devices. Every stop sign erected pursuant to this chapter shall be a standard sign adopted by the State Department of Transportation.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Crosswalks. Designate by appropriate devices, marks or lines upon the surface of the roadway, within the jurisdiction of this County, crosswalks at those places where he shall find that there is particular danger to pedestrians crossing the roadway, and when he shall further find that the existence of a crosswalk will reduce that danger.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Safety zones. To establish safety zones of such kind and character and at such places where he shall find that there is particular danger to pedestrians, and which are consistent with State law, and where he shall find that the existence of a safety zone will reduce that danger.</section><section prefix='(5)'>One-way streets, roadways and alleys; signs. To designate one-way streets, roadways and alleys, and whenever the Traffic Engineer designates any one-way street, roadway, or alley, he shall cause to be placed signs giving notice thereof, and no such regulation shall be effective unless such signs are in place. Signs indicating the direction of lawful traffic movement shall be placed at every intersection where movement of traffic in the opposite direction is prohibited.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Marking traffic lanes. Require the marking of lanes upon the roadway of any street where he shall find that a regular alignment of traffic is necessary in the interest of safety and efficiency, or at such places as he may find to be advisable, consistent with the traffic regulations of this County and State law.</section><section prefix='(7)'>All-night parking. Prohibit all-night parking, and to cause to be erected signs giving notice thereof, upon any street or portion thereof, whenever in his opinion such prohibition is necessary or advisable in the interest of public safety.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Play streets. Declare and to establish, whenever he shall find that the public safety and convenience are best served thereby, any street or part thereof a play street, and to have placed appropriate signs and barricades enclosing the roadway indicating and helping to protect the same. Whenever authorized signs and barricades are erected enclosing any street or part thereof as a play street, no person shall drive a vehicle upon any such street or portion thereof.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Signs, signals and devices; specifications. Designate traffic-control signs, signals, lane markings and other devices and shall determine the hours and days during which any traffic-control device shall be in operation or be in effect. In all respects all traffic-control signs, signals and devices shall conform to the manual and specifications as approved by the State Department of Transportation. All signs and signals required hereunder for a particular purpose shall be uniform as to type and location throughout the County. All traffic-control devices so erected and not inconsistent with the provisions of State law or this chapter shall be official traffic-control devices.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Emergency and experimental regulations; testing. Make all regulations necessary to make effective the provisions of the traffic ordinance of this County and to make and enforce temporary or experimental regulations, consistent with this chapter, to cover emergencies or special conditions. No such regulations shall be effective and in force until and unless adequate signs, signals or other notices are erected, clearly indicating said regulation. No such temporary experimental regulation shall remain in effect for more than ninety (90) days. The Traffic Director may test traffic-control devices under actual conditions of traffic.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Angle parking. Shall determine the location of angle parking zones.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Prohibit parking on left side of one-way street. Prohibit the standing or parking of vehicles upon the left-hand side of any one-way street and to erect signs giving notice thereof.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Permit parking on one-way streets. Determine when standing or parking may be permitted upon the left-hand side which include two (2) or more separate roadways and to cause to be erected signs giving notice thereof.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Restrict parking in hazardous places. Designate by proper signs, places in which the stopping or parking of vehicles would create an especially hazardous condition or would cause unusual delay to traffic.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Curb loading zones. Determine the location of passenger and freight curb loading zones and shall place and maintain appropriate signs indicating the same and stating the hours during which the provisions of this section are applicable.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Truck routes, designating. Designate certain streets as truck routes to be used for the expeditious and convenient movement of farm tractors, trailers, semi-trailers, trucks and other commercial vehicular traffic and shall give notice thereof by means of appropriate signs placed along such streets.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Bus stops, taxi stands, etc. Establish bus stops, bus stands, taxicab stands, and stands for other passenger common-carrier motor vehicles on the public streets, in such places and in such numbers as he shall determine to be of the greatest benefit and convenience to the public. Every such bus stop, bus stand, taxicab stand, or other stand shall be designated by appropriate signs.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Prohibited parking. Designate certain streets where parking shall be prohibited at all times, may designate certain places where parking shall be prohibited at all times and shall cause to be erected signs giving notice thereof.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Limited parking. Cause to be erected signs in each block limiting the parking time on certain streets and giving notice thereof.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Bicycles on sidewalks. Cause to be erected signs on any sidewalk or street prohibiting the riding of bicycles thereon by any person, and when such signs are in place no person shall disobey the same.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-94, ยง 1, 12-21-71)</history></law>