<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE IIA. PARKING SPACES FOR PERSONS TRANSPORTING YOUNG CHILDREN AND STROLLERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-450</section_number>
<catch_line>Penalty for misuse of specially marked parking spaces.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003595</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-450. Penalty for misuse of specially marked parking spaces.<section>It is unlawful for any person to stop, stand, or park a vehicle within any parking space designated for persons transporting young children and strollers, unless such vehicle displays a parking permit decal issued pursuant to administrative order, and such vehicle is transporting a child aged two (2) years or less; provided, however, physically handicapped and/or disabled persons displaying a valid handicapped parking permit shall be permitted to utilize parking spaces designated for persons transporting young children and strollers. Whenever a law enforcement officer or a parking enforcement specialist finds a vehicle in violation of this section, that officer or enforcement specialist shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Have the vehicle in violation removed to any lawful parking space or facility or require the operator or other person in charge of the vehicle immediately to remove the unauthorized vehicle from the parking space. Whenever any vehicle is removed by a law enforcement officer, parking enforcement specialist, or agency to a storage lot, garage, or other safe parking space, the cost of such removal and parking shall be a lien against the vehicle, or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Charge the motor vehicle owner in violation with a noncriminal traffic infraction.<section prefix='(a)'>Whenever evidence shall be presented in any court of the fact that any automobile, truck, or other vehicle was found to be parked in a specially designated parking space in violation of this section, it shall be prima facie evidence that the vehicle was parked and left in the space by the person, firm, or corporation in whose name the vehicle is registered and licensed according to the records of the Division of Motor Vehicles.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Violators of this article shall be punished by the maximum fine for a non-moving violation pursuant to Chapter 318, Florida Statutes.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-104, ยง 2, 6-7-94; Ord. No. 98-108, ยง 2, 7-21-98)</history></law>