<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE IIA. PARKING SPACES FOR PERSONS TRANSPORTING YOUNG CHILDREN AND STROLLERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-449</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003594</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-449. Parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers.<section>Parking spaces specifically designed for persons transporting young children under the age of three (3) and strollers, shall be required for all uses other than single-family, duplex, townhouse or multifamily; provided, however, industrial zoned properties shall not be required to comply with this section. Such baby stroller parking spaces shall be provided as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Quality of specially designated parking spaces:</section><section prefix='(b)'>Location of parking spaces. Such spaces shall be located as closely as possible to parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons; provided however, parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons shall take precedence. Where no parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons have been provided, parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers shall be located on the shortest accessible route of travel from adjacent parking to an accessible entrance.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Signage and markings. All parking spaces reserved for persons transporting young children and strollers shall be prominently outlined with green paint and posted with an approved permanent above-ground sign which shall conform to the figure entitled "Baby Stroller Parking Sign" hereby incorporated in this section. The bottom of the sign must be at least five (5) feet above grade when attached to a building, or seven (7) feet above grade for a detached sign.</section></section><section><section prefix='(d)'>Parking permit required. Such parking spaces shall only be utilized by parking permit holders as specified in Section 30-450 of this Code and only when the permit holder is transporting a young child and a stroller; provided, however, physically handicapped and/or disabled persons displaying a valid handicapped parking permit shall be permitted to utilize parking spaces designated for persons transporting young children and strollers.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-104, ยง 2, 6-7-94; Ord. No. 96-161, ยง 3, 11-12-96; Ord. No. 98-108, ยง 1, 7-21-98)</history></law>