<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. TOWING OF MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-465</section_number>
<catch_line>Insurance requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003601</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30-465. Insurance requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person for compensation or as part of a regularly conducted business activity to recover, tow, or remove a vehicle or to provide vehicle storage services in connection therewith until that person has filed with the Director and maintains in effect, for each towing vehicle operated by that person, an insurance policy or policies or certificates of insurance which shall indemnify or insure such person for its liability at a minimum:<section prefix='(1)'>For vehicles with a gross vehicle weight of less than eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds: automobile liability insurance covering each vehicle in an amount not less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per person, one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury, and twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) per occurrence for property damage or one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) combined single limit.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For vehicles with a gross vehicle weight of eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds or more, but less than thirty thousand (30,000) pounds: automobile liability insurance covering each vehicle in an amount not less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per person, three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury, and one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for property damage or three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) combined single limit.</section><section prefix='(3)'>For vehicles with a gross vehicle weight of thirty thousand (30,000) pounds or more: automobile liability insurance coverage covering each vehicle in an amount not less than three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per person, five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) per occurrence for bodily injury, and one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for property damage or five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) combined single limit.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>All insurance policies required shall be issued by insurance companies authorized and qualified to do business in the State of Florida. No policy shall be accepted which is of less than six (6) months' duration. Each policy shall contain a provision that the CSD must be notified in writing by mail by the insurance agent/company of any policy changes at least forty-five (45) days prior to the endorsement taking effect or at least ten (10) days prior to cancellation thereof for non-payment of premium, as applicable.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Failure to provide current certificates of insurance or policies or failure to maintain the required coverage for each vehicle shall result in automatic suspension of the towing license, which shall remain in effect until proof of compliance with this section is submitted to the Director and approved.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The insurance requirements of this article shall not apply to governmental entities which are self-insured.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-67, ยง 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 90-29, ยง 1, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 93-130, ยง 1, 11-16-93)</history></law>