<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. SOUTH BEACH REDEVELOPMENT TRUST FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-20</section_number>
<catch_line>Review and approval of master bond indenture or other financing instrument or ordinance or resolution authorizing financing instruments; review of subsequent financing instruments to assure compliance with master indenture.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003647</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-20. Review and approval of master bond indenture or other financing instrument or ordinance or resolution authorizing financing instruments; review of subsequent financing instruments to assure compliance with master indenture.<section>The County Commission shall review and approve the initial master bond indenture or ordinance or resolution authorizing financing instruments and instruments of indebtedness such as bonds or tax anticipation notes as described in Section 163.385, Florida Statutes (1977), as to its provisions relating to refunding, prepayment and redemption, other provisions relating to the governance of financing instruments and instruments of indebtedness, the application of funds necessary to pay costs of necessary residential property acquisition, moving expenses and relocation benefits as provided under the revised redevelopment plan. Subsequent financing instruments or instruments of indebtedness prepared pursuant to the master indenture shall be reviewed by the County Manager and shall be approved unless he determines that the instruments do not conform with the terms of the approved initial master indenture and ordinance or resolution authorizing financing instruments.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-20, ยง 5, 4-4-78; Ord. No. 79-33, ยง 3, 6-5-79)</history></law>