<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. SOUTH BEACH REDEVELOPMENT TRUST FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Incorporation of recitations as to purpose, authority, etc.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003643</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-16. Incorporation of recitations as to purpose, authority, etc.<section>The following recitations [from the preface to Ordinance No. 78-20] are hereby incorporated as a part of this article:<section>the legislature of Florida enacted the Community Redevelopment Act of 1969 during the legislative session held during 1969; and</section><section>all powers arising through the aforesaid enactment were conferred by that enactment upon counties with home rule charters, which counties in turn are authorized to delegate such powers to municipalities within their boundaries when such municipalities wish to undertake redevelopment projects within their respective municipal boundaries; and</section><section>such authorization for counties to delegate such powers to municipalities is contained in Section 163.410, Florida Statutes, which states:</section></section><section>"163.410 Exercise of powers in counties with home rule charters<section>"In counties which have adopted home rule charters, the powers conferred by this part shall be exercised exclusively by the governing body of such County. However, the governing body of any such County which has adopted a home rule charter may, in its discretion, by resolution delegate the exercise of the powers conferred upon said County by this part within the boundaries of a municipality to the governing body of such a municipality. Such a delegation to a municipality shall confer only such powers upon a municipality as shall be specifically enumerated in the delegating resolution. Any power not specifically delegated shall be reserved exclusively to the governing body of the County.;" and</section><section>the City of Miami Beach, acting through its own community redevelopment agency, indicated its wish to undertake a project which will involve the acquisition and redevelopment in accordance with a plan for redevelopment of that portion of Miami Beach known as South Beach and extending from Sixth Street on the north to Government Cut on the south and from the Atlantic Ocean on the east to Biscayne Bay on the west; and</section><section>the redevelopment trust fund will provide payment for the construction, reconstruction or relocation of County facilities made necessary by the redevelopment project; and</section><section>the City of Miami Beach on February 1, 1977, requested the County to adopt a resolution pursuant to the provisions of Section 163.410, Florida Statutes, delegating to the City of Miami Beach all powers then conferred by the statute upon Miami-Dade County, but only with regard to that portion of Miami Beach described in the preceding whereas clause, so that the said municipality could proceed to adopt its plan for redevelopment, and acquire and arrange for the redevelopment of the above described portion of the said City; and</section><section>the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County passed on February 1, 1977, Resolution No. R-88-77, entitled:<section>"RESOLUTION DELEGATING ALL POWERS CONFERRED UPON Miami-Dade COUNTY UNDER THE COMMUNITY REDEVELOPMENT ACT OF 1969 UPON THE CITY OF MIAMI BEACH FOR THE ACQUISITION AND REDEVELOPMENT OF THE SOUTH BEACH AREA WITHIN MIAMI BEACH SUBJECT TO THE IMPLEMENTATION OF THE PLAN PRESENTED TO THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS"; and</section></section><section>the delegation of authority was expressly made subject to the implementation of the redevelopment plan presented that date to the Board of County Commissioners, with any substantial deviation being subject to the subsequent approval of the Board of County Commissioners; and</section><section>a substantial modification of the plan was presented to the Board of County Commissioners on January 17, 1978, and approved by the Board through Resolution No. R-52-78; and</section><section>the 1977 Florida legislature enacted Chapter 77-391, Laws of Florida, amending the Community Development Act of 1969, which is codified as Part III of Chapter 163, Florida Statutes, also known as Sections 163.330 through 163.450, Florida Statutes; and</section><section>the City of Miami Beach approved Resolutions Nos. 77-15283, 77-15291 and 77-15413, adopted on March 2nd, March 30th and August 17th, 1977, respectively, approving modifications to the redevelopment plan of South Beach; and</section><section>Chapter 77-391, Laws of Florida, created Section 163.387, Florida Statutes, permitting the establishment of redevelopment trust funds and the funding of the funds through the deposit in the funds of the increment in the income, proceeds, revenues, and funds of the County and municipality derived from or held in connection with its undertaking and carrying out of community redevelopment projects; and</section><section>the additional redevelopment powers established by Chapter 77-391, Laws of Florida, including the authority to establish and fund a redevelopment trust fund were not delegated to the City of Miami Beach in Resolution No. R-88-77, passed on February 1st, 1977, or in Resolution No. R-52-78, passed on January 17th, 1978; and</section><section>the establishment and funding of the redevelopment trust fund by such tax increment can only be effectuated through an ordinance of the Board of County Commissioners delegating the authority to establish a redevelopment trust fund to the City of Miami Beach; and</section><section>the County is sympathetic to the project envisaged and proposed by the City of Miami Beach which will ultimately involve the expenditure of several hundreds of millions of dollars, which will be financed in part through revenue bonds to be issued by the City of Miami Beach and which is presently to be secured by such revenue sources as are provided by law, including the rents and revenues that individual projects and properties within the area of redevelopment will generate, the sale of properties by the City to individual entrepreneurs for redevelopment, the lease of a number of properties retained in ownership by the City, and revenues generated by increased assessed valuation of property resulting from the completed project; and</section><section>the County desires to increase the viability of the project by delegating the authority to establish a redevelopment trust fund and funding it by the annual tax increment; and</section><section>this Board desires to accomplish the purpose outlined in the memorandum from the County Manager, a copy of which is attached to this ordinance, for the reasons delineated therein; and</section><section>the Board hereby finds that this delegation of power and ensuing appropriation of funds serves a public purpose;</section><section>now, therefore be it ordained by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, [as follows in this article].</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-20, ยง 1, 4-4-78)</history></law>