<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Cooperation by public bodies in carrying out project; limitations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003641</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-14. Cooperation by public bodies in carrying out project; limitations.<section prefix='(a)'>For the purpose of aiding in the planning, undertaking or carrying out of an urban renewal project located within the area in which it is authorized to act, any municipality or public body may, upon such terms, with or without consideration, as it may determine:<section prefix='(1)'>Dedicate, sell, convey or lease any of its interest in any property or grant easements, licenses or other rights or privileges therein to Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Incur the entire expense of any public improvements made in exercising the powers granted in this section;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Do any and all things necessary to aid or cooperate in the planning or carrying out of an urban renewal plan;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Lend, grant or contribute funds to the County;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Enter into agreements (which may extend over any period, notwithstanding any provision or rule of law to the contrary) with the County respecting action to be taken pursuant to any of the powers granted by this chapter, including the furnishing of funds or other assistance in connection with an urban renewal project; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Cause public buildings and public facilities, including parks, playgrounds, recreational, community, educational, water, sewer or drainage facilities, or any other works which it is otherwise empowered to undertake to be furnished; furnish, dedicate, close, vacate, pave, install, grade, regrade, plan or replan streets, roads, sidewalks, ways or other places; plan or replan; zone or rezone any part of the municipality or make exceptions from building regulations; and cause administrative and other services to be furnished to the County. If at any time title to or possession of any urban renewal project is held by any municipality, public body or governmental agency, other than the County, which is authorized by law to engage in the undertaking, carrying out, or administration of urban renewal projects (including any agency or instrumentality of the United States of America), the provisions of the agreements referred to in this section shall inure to the benefit of any such public body or governmental agency and may be enforced by such public body and governmental agency.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Any sale, conveyance, lease or agreement provided for in this section may be made by a municipal or public body without appraisal, public notice, advertisement or public bidding.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For the purpose of aiding in the planning, undertaking or carrying out of an urban renewal project of an urban renewal agency hereunder, the Board may (in addition to its other powers and upon such terms, with or without consideration, as it may determine) do and perform any or all of the actions or things which, by the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, a public body is authorized to do or perform, including the furnishing of financial and other assistance.</section><section prefix='(d)'>For the purposes of this section, or for the purpose of aiding in the planning, undertaking or carrying out of an urban renewal project, the Board may (in addition to any authority to issue bonds pursuant to Section 30A-12) issue and sell its general obligation bonds. Any bonds issued pursuant to this section shall be issued in the manner and within the limitations prescribed by the laws of this State for the issuance and authorization of bonds by the County for public purposes generally except as to constitutional requirements.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-6, ยง 13, 2-9-60)</history></law>