<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. SOUTH BEACH REDEVELOPMENT TRUST FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-17</section_number>
<catch_line>Delegation of authority to establish a redevelopment trust fund to the City of Miami Beach.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003644</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-17. Delegation of authority to establish a redevelopment trust fund to the City of Miami Beach.<section>The authority to create a redevelopment trust fund ("the fund"), as defined in Section 163.387, Florida Statutes, is hereby delegated to the City of Miami Beach pursuant to the provisions of Section 163.410, Florida Statutes, solely with respect to the area known as South Beach, which is generally bounded by Sixth Street on the north, Government Cut on the south, the Atlantic Ocean on the east, and Biscayne Bay on the west, and is legally described in the amended and restated redevelopment plan ("the community redevelopment project area"). This delegation is made subject to the provisions of Resolution No. R-88-77, adopted on February 1, 1977, Resolution No. R-52-78, adopted on January 17, 1978, and Resolution No. R-646-79, adopted on June 1, 1979, and so much therein as has been replaced by Resolution No. R-612-82, adopted on May 4, 1982, and by Resolution No. R-1056-84, adopted on September 4, 1984, and the implementation of the amended and restated redevelopment plan presented to the Board, the prior approval of which plan is hereby affirmed and ratified. This delegation is made so that the City may proceed with the implementation of a plan for redevelopment, and the acquisition of property and redevelopment of the aforesaid area through its municipally created community redevelopment agency.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-20, § 2, 4-4-78; Ord. No. 79-33, § 1, 6-5-79; Ord. No. 82-57, § 1, 6-15-82; Ord. No. 84-73, § 1, 9-18-84; Ord. No. 89-59, § 2, 6-20-89)</history></law>