<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. TASK FORCE ON URBAN ECONOMIC REVITALIZATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-134</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003677</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-134. Powers and duties.<section>The powers and duties of the Task Force shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>To serve in an advisory capacity to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners with respect to all issues affecting urban economic revitalization related to targeted urban areas;</section><section prefix='(b)'>To develop and present to the Mayor and the Board of County Commissioners within ninety (90) to one hundred twenty (120) days from the first meeting of the Task Force, a "Plan" which shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Identify the goals of the Plan and identify specific, focused, achievable economic development projects and/or programs to be carried out wholly or partially within the targeted urban areas,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Delineate the action steps necessary or desirable to accomplish goals of the Plan,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Develop a plan for private sector fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; such plan should (1) identify persons and/or private entities to engage in fundraising to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas and may propose to Miami-Dade County a contract with such persons and/or entities which would establish a public/private partnership, the goal of which would be to benefit Urban Economic Development within targeted urban areas; (2) include a component to involve residents of the targeted urban areas in fundraising in order to promote a sense of community ownership in the economic revitalization of the targeted urban areas, and (3) allow an opportunity for capital investment by residents of the targeted urban areas.</section></section></section><section>In order to develop the Plan, the Task Force shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Review, analyze and evaluate the funding expended in the targeted urban areas for economic development over the past ten (10) years.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Review, analyze and evaluate existing economic development plans and/or studies prepared on behalf of Miami-Dade County and prepared by community development corporations or community based organizations to determine which projects are achievable and feasible, including but not limited to plans and/or studies related to projects such as the Poinciana Industrial Park, the Seventh Avenue Corridor, Northside Shopping Center, the Northwest 183rd Street Shopping Center, the Community Development Bank, the Richmond Heights Old Shopping Center Project, the Perrine/Homestead Avenue Corridor, and the Goulds Shopping Center; provided, such plans or studies shall relate to projects or programs wholly or partially within targeted urban areas;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Review, analyze and evaluate successful Urban Economic Revitalization programs from other major urban areas, including but not limited to programs in Baltimore, Maryland, Harlem, New York; Washington, D.C. and Atlanta, Georgia;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Review, analyze and evaluate the Community and Individual Investment Corporation Guide published by USHUD September, 1996;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Hold community meetings, coordinated by MMAP, to encourage public input in developing a focused, achievable and feasible plan and disseminate information regarding existing programs which aid the urban economic revitalization effort. The community input process utilized in the empowerment zone process may be used as a guide;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Identify new and existing federal, state and local sources of funding, if any, which could provide funding for Urban Economic Revitalization.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>To update the Plan on an annual basis;</section><section prefix='(d)'>To study the feasibility of community based development entities' consolidating and forming alliances which could take advantage of economies of scale and promote efficiency in service delivery; and to recommend incentives to encourage the formation of such consolidations and alliances;</section><section prefix='(e)'>To encourage employment of targeted urban area residents in major downtown developments, such as the Maritime Park Project and the Performing Arts Center;</section><section prefix='(f)'>To encourage and promote the development and growth of the new and existing businesses in the targeted urban areas; and</section><section prefix='(g)'>To review the Office of Community Development's ("O.C.D.'s") recommendations for Miami-Dade County Community Development Block Grant economic development category funding and Community Based Organization Funding, related to economic development, for the purpose of assuring that O.C.D.'s staff recommendations are in accordance with priorities established by the Plan and require O.C.D. to report the dollar amount being spent in targeted urban areas. To the extent the Board expends County Funds for economic development in targeted urban areas, recommendations of the Task Force made pursuant to this subsection shall be accepted and implemented by the Board of County Commissioners, unless the recommendation is disapproved by a two-thirds () vote of the entire membership of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Work with the Mayor to identify and propose to the Board of County Commissioners a dedicated source of funding to implement the Urban Economic Revitalization Plan.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-33, ยง 7, 4-15-97)</history></law>