<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Interest of officials, commissioners or employees in projects; method of disclosing; penalty for failure; holding of other offices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003642</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-15. Interest of officials, commissioners or employees in projects; method of disclosing; penalty for failure; holding of other offices.<section>No public official or employee of Miami-Dade County (or board, agency or commission thereof), and no public official or employee of any municipality in Miami-Dade County, and no employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall voluntarily acquire any personal interest, direct or indirect, in any urban renewal project, or in any property included or planned to be included in any renewal project or in any contract or proposed contract in connection with such urban renewal project. Where such acquisition is not voluntary, the interest acquired shall be immediately disclosed in writing to the Board of County Commissioners and such written disclosure shall be entered upon the official minutes of the County Commission. If any such official, commission or employee presently owns or controls, or owned or controlled within the preceding two (2) years, any interest, direct or indirect, in any property which he knows is included or planned to be included in any contemplated urban renewal project, he shall immediately disclose this fact in writing to the Board of County Commissioners and such written disclosure shall be entered in the official minutes of the County Commission, and any such official, commissioner or employee shall not participate in any action affecting such property. Any disclosure required to be made by this section to the Board of County Commissioners shall be made concurrently to the Director of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. No employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall hold any other public office in Miami-Dade County or any municipality in Miami-Dade County, other than the office or position with respect to the Department of Housing and Urban Development. Any violation of the provisions of this section shall constitute misconduct in office, and shall operate to disqualify such person from further serving as an employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-6, ยง 17, 2-9-60)</history></law>