<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. SOUTH BEACH REDEVELOPMENT TRUST FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-19</section_number>
<catch_line>Obligation to appropriate; duration of obligation; accounting requirements for County increment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003646</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-19. Obligation to appropriate; duration of obligation; accounting requirements for County increment.<section>The County shall annually appropriate to the fund the tax increment due the fund by January first of each year. The County's obligation to annually appropriate to the fund shall commence immediately upon the effective date of this article [April 14, 1978] and continue until all loans, advances and indebtedness incurred as a result of the community redevelopment project and secured by a pledge of the tax increment funding granted by this article, as described in Section 163.385, Florida Statutes, have been paid in full or provision for their payment in full has been made. In no year shall the County's obligation to the fund exceed the amount of that year's tax increment as determined in. In the final year in which existing indebtedness so supported is discharged, only so much of that year's tax increment as is needed to finally discharge that indebtedness shall be advanced by the County into the fund created pursuant to. The County's increment contributions are to be accounted for as a separate revenue within the fund but may be combined with other revenues for the purpose of paying debt service.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-20, § 4, 4-4-78; Ord. No. 79-33, § 2, 6-5-79; Ord. No. 80-26, § 1, 4-8-80; Ord. No. 81-42, § 1, 4-21-81; Ord. No. 82-33, § 1, 4-20-82; Ord. No. 82-106, § 1, 11-2-82; Ord. No. 84-73, § 1, 9-18-84; Ord. No. 86-87, § 2, 11-18-86; Ord. No. 89-59, § 3, 6-20-89)</history></law>