<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. SOUTH BEACH REDEVELOPMENT TRUST FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Appropriation of funds; calculation of increment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003645</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-18. Appropriation of funds; calculation of increment.<section>The County shall annually pay into the fund a sum equal to the increment in the income, proceeds, revenues and funds of the County derived from, or held in connection with, the community redevelopment project area, and the City's undertaking and carrying out of the community redevelopment project plan. The increment shall be determined annually and shall be that amount equal to ninety-five (95) percent of the difference between:<section prefix='(a)'>That amount of general Countywide operating ad valorem taxes levied each year by the County on taxable real property contained within the geographic boundaries of the community redevelopment project area; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>That amount of general Countywide operating ad valorem taxes which would have been produced by the rate upon which the tax is levied each year by or for the County upon the total of the assessed value of the taxable real property in the community redevelopment project area, as shown upon the assessment rolls used in connection with the taxation of such property by the County, last equalized prior to the effective date of the city's Resolutions Nos. 77-15283, 77-15291 and 77-15413, adopted on March 2nd, March 30th and August 17th, 1977, respectively, approving the community redevelopment plan with modifications.</section></section><section>In calculating the increment, the amount of the ad valorem taxes levied based on the Countywide debt service on County bonds and other special purpose taxes shall be totally excluded from the calculation. All increment in this amount shall continue to be used for its voter-approve purpose and shall not be appropriated in any part to the fund.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-20, ยง 3, 4-4-78; Ord. No. 86-87, ยง 1, 11-18-86)</history></law>