<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-11</section_number>
<catch_line>County property exempt from taxes, levy and sale by execution; presumption affecting title of purchasers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003638</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-11. County property exempt from taxes, levy and sale by execution; presumption affecting title of purchasers.<section prefix='(a)'>All property of Miami-Dade County, including funds, owned or held by it for the purposes of this chapter shall be exempt from levy and sale by virtue of an execution, and no execution or other judicial process shall issue against the same nor shall judgment against the County be a charge or lien upon such property; provided, however, that the provisions of this section shall not apply to or limit the right of obligees to pursue any remedies for the enforcement of any pledge or lien given pursuant to this chapter by the County on its rents, fees, grants or revenues from urban renewal projects.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The property acquired or held for the purposes of this chapter is declared to be public property used for essential public and governmental purposes and such property shall be exempt from all taxes of any municipality, the County, the State or any political subdivision thereof; provided, that such tax exemption shall terminate when the County sells, leases or otherwise disposes of such property in an urban renewal area to a purchaser or lessee which is not a public body entitled to tax exemption with respect to such property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any instrument executed by the County and purporting to convey any right, title or interest in any property under this chapter shall be conclusively presumed to have been executed in compliance with the provisions of this chapter insofar as title or other interest of any bona fide purchasers, lessees or transferees of such property is concerned.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-6, §§ 12, 14, 2-9-60)</history></law>