<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—By Director of Housing and Urban Development.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003631</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-5. Same—By Director of Housing and Urban Development.<section prefix='(a)'>The Board of County Commissioners shall exercise all the urban renewal duties, functions and powers enumerated in this chapter, unless the Board by resolution determines that certain powers, duties and functions may best be exercised by the Director of Housing and Urban Development in the public interest. In the event the Board, by resolution, makes such determination, said Director of Housing and Urban Development shall be vested with such powers as shall be specified in said resolution in the same manner as though such powers were conferred on such Director of Housing and Urban Development by the provisions of this chapter. If the Board does not elect to make such determination, the urban renewal project powers enumerated herein shall be exercised by the Board or through such Board, agency or officials as the Board may by resolution determine.</section><section prefix='(b)'>As used in this section, the term urban renewal project powers shall include the rights, powers, functions and duties under this chapter, except the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The power to determine an area to be a slum or blight area or combination thereof and to designate such area as appropriate for an urban renewal project and to hold any public hearings required with respect thereto;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The power to approve urban renewal plans and modifications thereof;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The power to establish a general plan for the County as a whole;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The power to formulate a workable program under Section 30A-8</section><section prefix='(5)'>The power to make the determinations and findings provided for in Section 30A-7, Section 30A-3, and Section 30A-9(d);</section><section prefix='(6)'>The power to issue general obligation bonds;</section><section prefix='(7)'>The power to appropriate funds, to levy assessments, and to exercise other powers provided for in Section 30A-4(h).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-6, § 15, 2-9-60)</history></law>