<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003627</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-1. Definitions.<section>The following terms, wherever used or referred to in this chapter, shall have the following meanings, unless a different meaning is clearly indicated by the context:<section prefix='(a)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(b)'>County shall mean Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Public body shall mean the State or any municipality, township, village, board, commission, authority, district, or any other subdivision or public body of the State.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Board shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Federal government shall include the United States of America or any agency or instrumentality, corporate or otherwise, of the United States of America.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Slum area shall mean an area in which there is a predominance of buildings or improvements, whether residential or nonresidential, which by reason of dilapidation, deterioration, age or obsolescence, inadequate provision for ventilation, light, air, sanitation, or open spaces, high density of population and overcrowding, or the existence of conditions which endanger life or property by fire and other causes, or any combination of such factors, is conducive to ill health, transmission of disease, infant mortality, juvenile delinquency, or crime, and is detrimental to the public health, safety, morals or welfare.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Blighted area shall mean an area which by reason of the presence of a substantial number of slum, deteriorated or deteriorating structures, predominance of defective or inadequate street layout, faulty lot layout in relation to size, adequacy, accessibility or usefulness, insanitary or unsafe conditions, deterioration of site or other improvements, diversity of ownership, tax or special assessment delinquency exceeding the fair value of the land, defective or unusual conditions of title, or the existence of conditions which endanger life or property by fire and other causes, or any combination of such factors, substantially impairs or arrests the sound growth of a municipality, retards the provision of housing accommodations or constitutes an economic or social liability and is a menace to the public health, safety, morals, or welfare in its present condition and use; provided, that if such blighted area consists of open land the conditions contained in the proviso in Section 30A-9(d) shall apply; and provided further, that any disaster area referred to in subsection (g) of Section 30A-9 shall constitute a blighted area.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Urban renewal project may include undertakings and activities of the County in an urban renewal area for the elimination and for the prevention of the development or spread of slums and blight, and may involve slum clearance and redevelopment in an urban renewal area, or rehabilitation or conservation in an urban renewal area, or any combination or part thereof in accordance with an urban renewal plan. Such undertakings and activities may include:<section prefix='(1)'>Acquisition of a slum area or a blighted area or portion thereof;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Demolition and removal of buildings and improvements;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Installation, construction, or reconstruction of streets, utilities, parks, playgrounds, and other improvements necessary for carrying out in the urban renewal area the urban renewal objectives of this chapter in accordance with the urban renewal plan;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Disposition of any property acquired in the urban renewal area (including sale, initial leasing or retention by the County itself) at its fair value for uses in accordance with the urban renewal plan;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Carrying out plans for a program of voluntary or compulsory repair and rehabilitation of buildings or other improvements in accordance with the urban renewal plan; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Acquisition of any other real property in the urban renewal area where necessary to eliminate unhealthful, insanitary or unsafe conditions, lessen density, eliminate obsolete or other uses detrimental to the public welfare, or otherwise to remove or prevent the spread of blight or deterioration, or to provide land for needed public facilities.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Urban renewal area means a slum area or a blighted area or a combination thereof which the Board of County Commissioners designates as appropriate for an urban renewal project.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Urban renewal plan means a plan, as it exists from time to time, for an urban renewal project, which plan (1) shall conform to the general plan for the County as a whole except as provided in Section 30A-9(g); and (2) shall be sufficiently complete to indicate such land acquisition, demolition and removal of structures, redevelopment, improvements, and rehabilitation as may be proposed to be carried out in the urban renewal area, zoning and planning changes, if any, land uses, maximum densities, building requirements, and the plan's relationship to definite local objectives respecting appropriate land uses, improved traffic, public transportation, public utilities, recreational and community facilities, and other public improvements.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Real property shall include all lands, including improvements and fixtures thereon, and property of any nature appurtenant thereto, or used in connection therewith, and every estate, interest, right and use, legal or equitable, therein, including terms for years and liens by way of judgment, mortgage or otherwise.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Bonds shall mean any bonds (including refunding bonds), notes, interim certificates, certificates of indebtedness, debentures or other obligations.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Obligee shall include any bond holder, agents or trustees for any bondholders, or lessor demising to the municipality property used in connection with an urban renewal project, or any assignee or assignees of such lessor's interest or any part thereof, and the federal government when it is a party to any contract with the municipality.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Person shall mean any individual, firm, partnership, corporation, company, association, joint stock association, or body politic; and shall include any trustee, receiver, assignee, or other person acting in a similar representative capacity.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Area of operation shall mean any area within the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Commission shall mean a board, commission, department, division, office, body or other unit of the County or any municipality, other than the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Public officer shall mean any officer who is in charge of any department or branch of the government of the County or any municipality relating to health, fire, building regulations, or other activities concerning dwellings in the County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-6, ยง 18, 2-9-60)</history></law>