<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. SOUTH MIAMI COMMUNITY REDEVELOPMENT AND REVITALIZATION TRUST FUND</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-153</section_number>
<catch_line>County appropriations to Fund.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003685</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-153. County appropriations to Fund.<section>Each taxing authority shall, by January 1st of each year, appropriate to the Fund for so long as any indebtedness pledging increment revenues to the payment thereof is outstanding (but not to exceed thirty (30) years) a sum that is no less than the increment as defined and determined by Section 2 of this ordinance accruing to such taxing authority. In no year shall the County's obligation to the Fund exceed the amount of that year's tax increment as determined pursuant to Section 2 of this ordinance. Beginning with the twentieth year after the date of sale of the initial bonding or indebtedness pledging tax increment funds, no new sale of bonds or indebtedness supported by the County's tax increment may occur nor may existing indebtedness so supported be refunded without amending this Ordinance. The County's obligation to fund the Fund annually shall continue until all loans, advances and indebtedness, if any, and interest thereon, of the Agency incurred as a result of redevelopment in the Redevelopment Area have been paid. The County's increment contribution is to be accounted for as a separate revenue within the Fund but may be combined within other revenues for the purpose of paying debt service. The County must approve the amount, duration of the obligation and the purpose of any bond, note or other form of indebtedness, including advances, pledging or otherwise obligating tax increment funds.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-80, ยง 3, 6-16-98)</history></law>