<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. TASK FORCE ON URBAN ECONOMIC REVITALIZATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-129</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003672</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-129. Definitions.<section>For the purposes of this section the following definitions shall be effective:<section prefix='(1)'>Urban Economic Revitalization means the undertakings and activities of Miami-Dade County and its residents in implementing comprehensive economic development strategies to create jobs, cause an increase in the tax base, and promote business activity in Targeted Urban Areas located in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Targeted urban areas means those geographical areas commonly known as: Liberty City, Model City/Brownsville, Carol City, Goulds, Overtown, Little Haiti, Opa-locka, Richmond Heights, Homestead, Florida City, Coconut Grove, Northwest 27th Avenue Corridor, Northwest 183rd Street Corridor, West Little River, Princeton/Naranja, Leisure City, South Miami, Perrine and the following City of North Miami Districts: 7th Avenue District, Downtown District, West Dixie Highway District and Biscayne Boulevard District. Any geographic locations in Miami-Dade County which are designated by the Federal Government as empowerment zones shall be included in the definition of targeted urban areas at the time of such designation. Maps or street descriptions setting forth the contiguous boundaries of the targeted urban areas, which are more fully described in Exhibit A that is attached to this ordinance [Ord. No. 11-05], are hereby incorporated herein by reference. Exhibit A shall replace any prior maps describing the target urban areas, which are currently on file with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. The Clerk of the Board is directed to file Exhibit A upon the effective date of this ordinance [February 11, 2011].</section><section prefix='(3)'>County funds means funds received by the County from any source, and shall include but not be limited to, general funds, omnibus reserve funds, state or federal grant funds, and any empowerment zone funding granted to Miami-Dade County before and after the effective date of this article</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-33, ยง 2, 4-15-97; Ord. No. 02-39, ยง 1, 3-12-02; Ord. No. 11-05, ยง 1, 2-1-11)</history></law>