<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. TASK FORCE ON URBAN ECONOMIC REVITALIZATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-130</section_number>
<catch_line>Governing body.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003673</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30A-130. Governing body.<section prefix='(a)'>Membership; compensation. The governing body of the Task Force shall be a Board of Directors composed of twenty-three (23) voting members. Members shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Composition. The voting membership of the Board of Directors shall be ethnically, racially, geographically and gender balanced and shall be composed of the following members:<section prefix='(1)'>One (1) member representing the financial or banking community;</section><section prefix='(2)'>One (1) member representing the legal community;</section><section prefix='(3)'>One (1) member nominated by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioner's Committee which has jurisdiction over community and economic development;</section><section prefix='(4)'>One (1) member with a background in public sector budgeting and finance;</section><section prefix='(5)'>One (1) member nominated by the Beacon Council;</section><section prefix='(6)'>One (1) member representing the civic and private sector business community which shall be nominated by the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix='(7)'>One (1) member representing the civic and private sector business community which shall be nominated by the Miami-Dade Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix='(8)'>One (1) member nominated by the Metro-Miami Action Plan Trust</section><section prefix='(9)'>Two (2) members of the Florida Legislature, one (1) from the House and one (1) from the Senate, who were elected from districts which are located, wholly or partially, within a targeted urban areas;</section><section prefix='(10)'>One (1) member nominated by the Urban Bankers Association, Inc.;</section><section prefix='(11)'>One (1) member nominated by the Black Lawyers Association Inc.;</section><section prefix='(12)'>One (1) member nominated by the Black Business Association;</section><section prefix='(13)'>One (1) member nominated by Tools for Change;</section><section prefix='(14)'>One (1) member nominated by a community development organization which allows the community to vote on its Board membership;.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Four (4) members of the Board of County Commissioners whose districts constitute the largest part of the Targeted Urban Areas shall each designate one (1) member of the Task Force who shall be residents of targeted urban areas or who are business owners who have places of business within targeted urban areas.</section><section prefix='(16)'>One (1) member representing the Commercial/Industrial Development Community;</section><section prefix='(17)'>One (1) member nominated by the Coalition of Community Development Corporations;</section><section prefix='(18)'>One (1) member representing the investment banking community;</section><section prefix='(19)'>One (1) member representing the insurance community;</section></section><section>Members of the Board of County Commissioners who were elected from districts which are located, wholly or partially, in the targeted urban areas, shall serve as ex-officio, non-voting advisors to the Task Force. These advisors shall not count towards a quorum.</section><section>Vacancies on the Board of Directors shall be filled in the same manner by which the original members were appointed, with a special emphasis on choosing persons representative of the gender, racial and ethnic composition of the entire community.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-33, ยง 3, 4-15-97)</history></law>