<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='2'>Chapter 30B TRANSIT AGENCY RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30B-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Personal conduct; solicitation of contributions; and distribution of materials.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003696</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30B-7. Personal conduct; solicitation of contributions; and distribution of materials.<section prefix='(1)'>No person shall solicit alms or contributions of money or other articles of value for religious, charitable or any other purpose, or conduct or participate in any speech-making, distributing of pamphlets, books or other written or graphic materials anywhere on the transit system without having delivered a written notice to the Executive Director, or his designee, of the intent to do so at least seven (7) days prior thereto so that the County may be fully informed of the activity proposed and take adequate precautions to protect the public health, safety, welfare and order, to assure the efficient and orderly use of the transit system for its primary purpose and function, and to assure appropriate opportunity for the freedom of expression to others.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The written notice required herein shall state:<section prefix='(a)'>The full name, address (and mailing address if different), telephone number of the person furnishing the notice, and, if an organization, the name, address and telephone number of a responsible local officer thereof and the title of such officer.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The purpose or subject of the proposed activity and a description of the means and methods intended to be used in conducting the same. If the proposed activity includes the solicitation of alms, donations or contributions of money or of other articles of value, the notice shall contain the verified statement of a responsible local officer of the organization furnishing the notice that it is a tax-exempt organization under existing federal laws and regulations and that donations and contributions made to such organization may lawfully be included as charitable deductions on a donor's federal income tax return for the year in which made.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The date, hours and location desired for the proposed activity and the maximum number of persons proposing to participate therein at any one time or period of time, together with a form of identification card, authenticated copies of which shall be displayed on the outer clothing of each individual participating in the particular activity proposed. Such identification cards shall contain the name of the organization furnishing the notice, the legal name of the individual bearing the card, the signature and title of the official of such organization and the date issued.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Persons having given such written notice shall be permitted to conduct their activities in or on the transit system with the number of persons, at the times, for the purpose, in the manner, and with the identification card, all as set forth in their respective written notices subject only to such restrictions as may be prescribed from time to time by the Executive Director or his designee; provided, however, that any such restrictions shall be reasonable and appropriate and shall be prescribed only after a finding by the County that the restrictions are necessary to avoid injury, or the likelihood of injury, to persons or property, or to assure the safe and orderly use of the transit system by the public, and such restrictions shall be applied equally and without discrimination as to all persons who have given such written notice. A copy of any such restrictions and any explanatory diagrammatic attachments shall be furnished those persons affected.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No person, while engaging in the activities provided for herein, shall prevent or interfere with access to or egress from busstops or shelters, faregates, fare card machines, washroom facilities, stairways, escalators, or elevators, nor shall such person in any manner assail, coerce, threaten or physically disturb any member of the public, any County employee, or any other person for any reason, nor shall such activity prevent, impede, interfere with, hamper or curtail the conduct of ordinary business on the transit system. The activities provided for herein shall not intrude upon or take place in any location or area reserved or zoned for a particular use including, but not limited to, washrooms, offices, reception areas, Metrorail and Metromover station platforms, and within any mass transit vehicle. No individual engaged in the proposed activity shall solicit any donation or engage a member of the public as a prospective donee without first identifying the organization he or she represents in connection with such prospective donation.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No person, while engaging in the activities provided for herein, shall affix any matter, written or graphic, to any transit system structure or facility, nor shall any such matter be left unattended at any location anywhere within the transit system.</section><section prefix='(6)'>No person, while engaging in the activities provided for herein, shall sell any material whatsoever to a member of the public, nor shall such person tender or transfer any material whatsoever to a member of the public in return for a fixed sum of money or other specific thing of value agreed upon in advance of such tender or transfer, nor shall such person after the transfer of such material require or demand any sum of money or other specific thing of value including the item transferred, from any member of the public.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The Executive Director or his designee is empowered to restrict, wholly or partially, the activities provided for herein in the event of emergencies, including but not limited to, strikes, accidents, riots, civil disturbances, power failures, hurricanes, or other conditions tending to disrupt the normal operation of the transit system.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-67, ยง 1, 7-17-84)</history></law>