<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='2'>Chapter 30B TRANSIT AGENCY RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30B-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003691</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30B-2. Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>General. Words not specifically defined in this section which relate to transit practices, processes and equipment shall be construed according to their general usage in the transit industry.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>"Commission" or "Board" shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(b)'>"County" shall mean Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>"County Manager" shall mean the County Manager as appointed by the Commission.</section><section prefix='(d)'>"Metro-Dade Transit Agency" or "MDTA" shall mean the agency designated by the County Manager to operate public mass transportation within the county.</section><section prefix='(e)'>"Executive Director" shall mean that person appointed by the County Manager carrying the title Director of the Metro-Dade Transit Agency or his duly authorized representatives.</section><section prefix='(f)'>"Transit system" shall mean all land, facilities, and improvements utilized by Dade County for the provision of public mass transportation services by Metrorail, Metrobus, and Metromover including but not limited to yard and shop, Metrorail and Metromover stations and parking areas, Metrorail guideway including the piers and girders and linear park located thereunder, Metromover guideway and supporting structures, traction power substations, operation and maintenance facilities and buildings, mass transit vehicles, and land located within the "Rapid Transit Zone" (as defined in Section 33C-2 of this Code) except for those rights and areas of said Zone which are leased to private entities for joint development.</section><section prefix='(g)'>"Mass transit vehicle" shall mean Metrobus buses, Metrorail cars, Metromover vehicles operated by or for the County for use by the public. For the purposes of this chapter, private buses, limousines, jitneys and taxicabs shall not be deemed mass transit vehicles.</section><section prefix='(h)'>"Metrorail" shall mean the twenty and five-tenth-mile fixed guideway heavy rail system, and future extensions thereof.</section><section prefix='(i)'>"Metromover" shall mean the one and nine-tenth-mile fixed guideway people mover system, and future extensions thereof.</section><section prefix='(j)'>"Metrobus" shall mean all facilities and equipment of the County bus system.</section><section prefix='(k)'>"Abandon" shall mean to forsake, desert, give up and surrender one's claim or right.</section><section prefix='(l)'>"Authorized" shall mean acting under or pursuant to a written contract, permit authorization or other evidence of right issued by the Board, the County Manager, or the Executive Director.</section><section prefix='(m)'>"Person" shall mean any individual, firm, partnership, corporation, company association, joint stock association, or body politic; and includes any trustee, receiver, committee, assignee or other representative or employee thereof.</section><section prefix='(n)'>"Solicit" or "solicitation" shall mean the request directly or indirectly for money or other thing of value.</section><section prefix='(o)'>"State" shall mean the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(p)'>"Restricted area" shall mean any area of the transit system posted to prohibit entry or to limit entry or access to specific authorized persons.</section><section prefix='(q)'>"Rules and regulations" shall mean the Metro-Dade Transit Agency rules and regulations, as codified in Chapter 30B, Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(r)'>"Park" shall mean to put or leave or let a motor vehicle stand or stop in any location whether the operator thereof leaves or remains in such vehicle when such standing or stopping is not required by traffic controls or conditions beyond the control of the operator.</section><section prefix='(s)'>"Weapon" shall mean any weapon, firearm, explosive, tear gas gun or chemical weapon or device, as those terms are defined by Section 790.00, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(t)'>"Fireworks" shall mean fireworks as defined by Section 791.01, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(u)'>"Explosive" shall mean explosive as defined by Section 790.001, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(v)'>"Paid area" shall mean that portion of a Metrorail or Metromover station beyond the faregate area where only fare-paying passengers are allowed.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-67, ยง 1, 7-17-84)</history></law>