<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='2'>Chapter 30B TRANSIT AGENCY RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30B-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003695</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30B-6. Parking.<section prefix='(1)'>Transit system parking facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall park or leave a vehicle unattended in any transit system parking facility for any purpose other than for a public transit related use, except as may be authorized in writing by the Director of MDTA. No person shall enter or use a transit system parking facility or parking space at such facility contrary to its posted or restricted use. Except when authorized in writing by MDTA, it shall be unlawful for any truck tractor, trailer or semi-trailer as defined in Section 316.003, Florida Statutes, as the same may be amended from time to time, to be parked or left in any transit system parking facility beyond one hour after such facility closes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall park or leave a vehicle unattended in any transit system parking facility or parking space without having positioned said vehicle wholly within a single designated stall or area in such a manner as not to obstruct the proper movement of other vehicles in the parking facility or utilization by other vehicles of driveways or adjacent parking spaces. All vehicles shall park head-in only. Only compact cars shall park in spaces marked "compact cars only." Whenever any police officer finds an unauthorized vehicle parked on transit right-of-way or in other than a marked space, such officer is authorized to provide for removal of the vehicle to the nearest storage lot, garage or other place of safety, cost of such removal to be a lien against the motor vehicle. No vehicle which requires more than one parking space, as defined in Section 33-122 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, may be parked or left unattended in any transit system parking facility without the express written consent of MDTA.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall park or leave a vehicle unattended in any transit system parking facility without having properly secured a required parking ticket or having paid the required parking fee, if any. The parking ticket shall be placed face up on the dashboard inside the vehicle. A monthly decal shall be appropriately placed inside the vehicle on the lower left rear windshield. MDTA will establish one of the following methods for payment at each transit system parking facility:<section prefix='1.'>Electronic Pay/Ticket Issued: Purchase parking ticket at electronic parking ticket machine inside the transit station area, receive parking ticket and surrender parking ticket at exit or pay a parking fee as established by Dade County Ordinance 86-37, and as may be amended from time to time. Failure to display either a parking ticket or a monthly parking permit, or to pay the applicable parking fee before exiting a parking facility utilizing this parking fee collection method shall constitute a violation of this section and shall be subject to the penalties provided in Section 30B-6(3) hereunder.</section><section prefix='2.'>Pay In/Free Out: Pay parking fee to cashier at manned booth upon entrance to parking lot, exit free. Failure to pay the parking fee upon entering the parking facility shall constitute a violation of this section and shall be subject to the penalties provided in Section 30B-6(3) hereunder.</section><section prefix='3.'>Manual Deposit Box: Park in numbered space, pay inside the transit station area at parking deposit box with numbered slot which corresponds to the numbered parking space. Any vehicle parked in a numbered space for which parking fee payment has not been deposited in the corresponding numbered deposit slot inside the station, shall be in violation of this section and shall be subject to the penalties provided in Section 30B-6(3) hereunder.</section><section prefix='4.'>Electronic Deposit Box: Park in numbered space, pay at electronic deposit box inside the transit station area and enter corresponding parking space number. Electronic deposit box records the fee paid for the individual parking space and issues a receipt. Whenever a vehicle is parked in a numbered space for which payment has not been registered in the electronic deposit machine, said vehicle shall be in violation of this section and shall be subject to the penalties provided in Section 30B-6(3) hereunder.</section><section prefix='5.'>Monthly Parking Permit: Parking permit purchased in advance of parking and displayed from the rearview mirror of parked vehicle. This method of parking payment shall be accepted at all transit system parking facilities.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>No person, shall remove or attempt to remove any vehicle from a transit system public parking facility without paying the required parking charge.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Except when authorized by MDTA or the parking facility operator, no person shall remove a parking ticket from a transit system public parking facility parking ticket dispensing machine, other than as an operator of a vehicle entering such facility.</section><section prefix='(f)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to remove a parking ticket from, or to otherwise operate, a transit system parking facility parking ticket dispensing machine, for the purpose of avoiding or enabling another person to avoid payment of a parking fee.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Employee parking areas and facilities. No person shall utilize an employee parking area or facility except as authorized by MDTA.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Parking fines. Violations of this section shall be punishable by the fine indicated below:</section><section prefix='(4)'>Enforcement. The enforcement of this section is vested in the Metro-Dade Police Department throughout Dade County in both the incorporated and the unincorporated areas thereof, in the Police Department of each municipality as to those Metrorail public parking facilities which are located in that municipality, and in parking enforcement specialists who are employed in accordance with Section 316.640, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Form of parking citations. Prosecution for violation of this section shall be by a uniform traffic ticket in the form provided by Section 30-206 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-67, § 1, 7-17-84; Ord. No. 89-82, §§ 1, 2, 9-12-89)</history></law>