<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='2'>Chapter 30B TRANSIT AGENCY RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30B-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Personal activities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003693</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30B-4. Personal activities.<section prefix='(1)'>Impeding or hindering operators of mass transit vehicles. On any mass transit vehicle operated solely within the boundaries of Dade County, it shall be unlawful for any person to impede or hinder the operator of said mass transit vehicle in the performance of his or her duties. No person shall, on any mass transit vehicle operated solely within the boundaries of Dade County, interfere with or disturb the operator of said mass transit vehicle by drinking alcoholic beverages, playing a radio or other instrument, unless said radio or other instrument is connected to an earphone; carry any animals or flammable liquids; display any weapons or firearms; use abusive, insulting or obscene language or gestures with the intent to distract the operator; Board through a rear exit; or refuse to pay the established fare.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Trespassing. It shall be unlawful to trespass on the transit system or to enter any restricted area.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Preservation of property. It shall be unlawful and a violation of this section for any person to deface, destroy, disfigure, injure, blemish, or vandalize any part of the transit system. Prohibited activities shall include, but not be limited to:<section prefix='(a)'>The unauthorized marking of any part of the transit system with spray paint and other marking substances;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The marking of any part of the transit system with graffiti;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The cutting or mutilating of seats on mass transit vehicles; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>The injuring or destruction of any tree, plant or other vegetation located within the transit system.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Obstruction of guideways or tracks. It shall be unlawful to place or cause to be placed any obstruction on Metrorail or Metromover guideways or tracks.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Smoking or spitting.
                   It shall be unlawful for passengers to smoke or spit within any mass transit vehicle or any paid area of a Metrorail or Metromover station.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Drinking or eating. It shall be unlawful to eat or drink, or carry an open container of food or beverage, on any mass transit vehicle or station platform.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Sanitation. It shall be unlawful to dispose of garbage, papers, refuse or other forms of trash within the transit system except in receptacles provided for such purpose. No person shall dump or dispose of any material [except as authorized herein]. No person shall use a comfort station or rest room, toilet or lavatory facility other than in a clean and sanitary manner. No person shall deposit, blow or spread any bodily discharge on any part of the transit system. No person shall place any foreign object in any plumbing fixture.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Abandonment. It shall be unlawful to abandon any vehicle or personal property on any part of the transit system.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Radio playing. It shall be unlawful while on any mass transit vehicle or facility to play any radio, cassette player, or other electronic audio or video playback device or musical instrument unless the sound produced by said device or instrument is played solely through earphones. Said devices and instruments may be played along the linear park underneath the Metrorail guideway provided same is not annoying or a nuisance.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Insulting or obscene language. It shall be unlawful to use any insulting or obscene language on any part of the transit system.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Animals. With the exception of seeing-eye dogs, it shall be unlawful to bring, carry, or transport any animal on a mass transit vehicle or the paid area of any transit system unless said animal is properly boxed or caged for transport. Animals may be permitted to use the linear park underneath the Metrorail guideway provided that they do no damage and cause no nuisance or inconvenience.</section><section prefix='(12)'>False reports or threats. It shall be unlawful to make a false report of conduct on, the operation of, or a threat concerning any portion of the transit system.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Forgery and counterfeit. It shall be unlawful to make, possess, use, offer for sale, sell, barter, exchange, pass, or deliver any forged, counterfeit or falsely altered pass, permit, farecard, transfer, identification card, certificate or other authorization purporting to be issued by or on behalf of the Transit Agency.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Explosives and fireworks. It shall be unlawful to carry, transport or ignite any explosive, fireworks, acid, or flammable liquid anywhere on the transit system.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Refusal to pay fare. It shall be unlawful to refuse to pay the established fare, evade payment of fare, or enter through rear doors or emergency exits of any mass transit vehicle, guideway or facility.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Transfers. It shall be unlawful to alter, abuse or give to another person any transfer or other fare medium, unless expressly authorized by the terms of said transfer or other fare medium.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Train attendant cab. It shall be unlawful for any unauthorized person to enter the train attendant cab of any Metrorail vehicle.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Safety lines. It shall be unlawful for any individual to cross a safety line on a Metrorail or Metromover station platform.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Equipment. It shall be unlawful for any unauthorized individual to operate any transit system equipment located within the transit system except:<section prefix='(a)'>Where such equipment is designed for use by the public; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>When necessary in an emergency situation.</section></section><section prefix='(20)'>Mass transit vehicle doors. It shall be unlawful to interfere with the operation of mass transit vehicle doors.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Passage between Metrorail cars. It shall be unlawful to pass from one (1) Metrorail car to another through the end door of the car, except in an emergency situation.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Bicycles. It shall be unlawful to bring or operate a bicycle on any mass transit vehicle or within the paid area of any Metrorail or Metromover station, except as allowed by MDTA rule and procedures. Bicycles may only be parked in designated areas on the transit system. Bicycles shall not be locked or chained to transit facilities except as allowed by MDTA rules and procedures.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Mopeds or motorized vehicles. No moped or other motorized vehicle shall be operated within the linear park underneath the Metrorail system and guideway.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-67, ยง 1, 7-17-84; Ord. No. 87-76, ยง 2, 11-3-87; Ord. No. 02-170, ยง 1, 9-24-02)</history></law>