<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='2'>Chapter 30B TRANSIT AGENCY RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30B-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Commercial activities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003694</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30B-5. Commercial activities.<section prefix='(1)'>Soliciting or carrying on business. No person, unless duly authorized in writing by MDTA, shall anywhere on the transit system:<section prefix='(a)'>Engage in any business or commercial activity;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Sell, or offer for sale, any merchandise or service;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Solicit any business or trade;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Sing, dance or play any musical instrument.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Commercial photography or recording. No person, unless authorized in writing by MDTA or the County Manager when appropriate under Section 2-11.14 of this Code, shall take still, motion, or sound motion pictures or sound records or recordings of voices or otherwise for commercial, training or educational purposes, other than news coverage anywhere in the transit system.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Building construction and improvements. No person, unless authorized in writing by MDTA, shall construct or cause to be constructed any buildings or structures, including signs, utility connection, or any improvements, modifications, or additions to any such buildings or structures, or any pavings, excavations, removal of oil or fill material anywhere on the transit system.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Advertising. No person, unless authorized in writing by MDTA, shall post or distribute commercial signs, advertisements, literature, circulars, pictures, sketches, drawings, handbills, or any other form of printed or written commercial matter or material anywhere within the transit system.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Vending in public areas. No person shall vend services, including but not limited to amusements and food and beverages, anywhere within the transit system, unless authorized in writing by MDTA.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Signs. No person unless authorized in writing by MDTA, shall construct or install any sign or device anywhere on the transit system.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-67, ยง 1, 7-17-84)</history></law>