<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='2'>Chapter 30B TRANSIT AGENCY RULES AND REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30B-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Applicability and penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003692</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 30B-3. Applicability and penalties.<section prefix='(1)'>Applicability. This chapter applies to all who utilize the transit system.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person violating subsections (2), (5), (6), (7), (9), (10), (11) and (22) of Section 30B-4 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County shall, upon being warned by a Police Officer of Metropolitan Dade County, cease the prohibited activity. If the person continues the prohibited activity after such warning, the police officer may direct the individual to leave the train or to leave the premises of the station. Any individual who does not leave as directed, shall be charged with trespassing and subject to a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both. In lieu of any fine or penalty, the court may order any person convicted of violating any provision of this chapter to participate in transit public service for a minimum of ten (10) hours. Such service may include graffiti removal, cleaning of transit vehicles, and maintenance of transit right-of-way.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For violations of subsections (1), (3), (4), (8), (12), (13), (14), (15), (16), (17), (18), (19), (20), (21), and (23) of Section 30B-4 of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County and for any other provision of this chapter for which another penalty is not specifically provided shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00), or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or both. In lieu of any fine or penalty, the court may order any person convicted of violating any provision of this chapter to participate in transit public service for a minimum of ten (10) hours. Such service may include graffiti removal, cleaning of transit vehicles, and maintenance of transit right-of-way.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to recover compensatory damages, including reasonable costs and expenses, for any damage caused to the transit system.</section><section prefix='(d)'>For violations other than those specified in subsection (a) above, the County may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty for each violation in an amount of not more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) per offense.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The judicial remedies in this section shall be independent and cumulative for the violations to which they are applicable hereunder.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-67, ยง 1, 7-17-84; Ord. No. 87-76, ยง 1, 11-3-87)</history></law>