<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-107</section_number>
<catch_line>Safety regulation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003731</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-107. Safety regulation.<section prefix='(a)'>Adoption; enforcement. The Consumer Services Department (CSD) shall adopt and enforce all safety regulations of the United States Department of Transportation that are applicable to passenger motor carriers and passenger motor carrier vehicles, as required for operation in an urban area. Any operator applying for a certificate or permit requiring or authorizing the use of a specialized or unique vehicle, not contemplated in United States Department of Transportation regulations, shall submit, subject to approval by CSD, safety regulations for each specific type of vehicle as to equipment, operation, maintenance, seating capacity and inspection of such vehicles, consistent with the vehicle manufacturer specifications, which must be submitted by the operator. The CSD shall develop special standards to be applied to motor vehicles older than five (5) model years which are operated as passenger motor vehicles in order to assure that such vehicles are safe.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Vehicle age. No vehicle older than fifteen (15) model years old shall be operated as a passenger motor carrier.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Inspection for compliance. CSD shall provide for semi-annual inspection of each vehicle for compliance with the foregoing standards. The CSD shall provide for annual inspection of each vehicle between and including one (1) and two (2) model years old; CSD shall provide for semi-annual inspection of each vehicle between and including three (3) and four (4) model years old; CSD shall provide for quarterly inspection of each vehicle between and including five (5) and fifteen (15) model years old for compliance with the foregoing standards. CSD shall charge a fee for such inspections. In addition to regular inspections, the CSD may also inspect any passenger motor vehicle at any time. The results of each inspection shall be recorded and a copy provided the operator. Any vehicle failing to meet required safety standards shall not be operated as a passenger motor vehicle until such time as the vehicle satisfactorily passes inspection. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the quarterly inspection of each vehicle between and including five (5) and fifteen (15) model years old to determine compliance with the foregoing vehicle condition standards shall commence on May 1, 1995 and the quarterly inspection of each such vehicle to determine compliance with the foregoing vehicle safety and mechanical standards shall be reduced to semi-annual inspection until July 1, 1998.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, § 8, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 87-11, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 88-118, § 2, 12-6-88; Ord. No. 90-134, § 1, 12-4-90; Ord. No. 92-66, § 3, 7-7-92; Ord. No. 93-85, § 2, 9-7-93; Ord. No. 94-190, § 2, 10-7-94; Ord. No. 95-99, § 2, 6-6-95; Ord. No. 96-186, § 2, 12-17-96)</history></law>