<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-102</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003726</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-102. Definitions.<section>For the purpose of this article, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>Certificate of transportation means the holder thereof may engage in providing the transportation services described thereon.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Chauffeur means a duly licensed driver registered with and authorized by the Consumer Services Department to operate a passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Commission means the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Common carrier means any motor carrier who holds his services out to the public.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Contract carrier means any passenger motor carrier who is not a common carrier and who repeatedly or continuously transports persons for compensation under written contract with one (1) or more persons.</section><section prefix='(f)'>County Manager means the chief executive officer and head of the administrative branch of the County Government as provided in Article 3 of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Director means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department Director.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Fixed route or regular route service means the transportation of persons by a common carrier for compensation on a regular route with a regular schedule between fixed terminals.</section><section prefix='(i)'>For compensation means for money, property, service or anything else of value.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Jitney means any motor vehicle having a maximum seating capacity of fifteen (15) or less, transporting passengers for compensation on a semi-fixed route between fixed terminals not on a fixed schedule basis.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Operate means providing transportation services for compensation utilizing a passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Operator means any person who has been issued a certificate in accordance with the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(m)'>CSD means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Passenger motor carrier or motor carrier means any person owning, controlling, operating or managing any motor vehicle used in the business of transportation of persons for compensation.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Passenger motor vehicle or motor vehicle means any chauffeur-driven motor vehicle engaged in the transportation of persons and their accompanying baggage, if any, for compensation over the public streets, but excludes motor vehicles engaged solely in providing special transportation services for the Miami-Dade Transit Agency pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County. Motor vehicles used to provide special transportation service pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County are subject to regulations contained in Article IV of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Permit means an operating permit authorizing the holder thereof to utilize the motor vehicle described in said permit for the transportation of passengers as authorized by a certificate issued pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Person means any individual, corporation, firm, partnership, limited partnership, association or joint stock association.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Rates or fares means the charges established pursuant to this article for the transportation services provided by an operator.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Registration means a chauffeur's registration authorizing the holder thereof to operate passenger motor vehicles subject to the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Special operations means the transportation of persons in a motor vehicle to a common destination or series of destinations where the person may be charged as an individual or as part of a group, including but not limited to charter, sightseeing, or subscription service, not between fixed terminal or on a regular route.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Street means any public street, avenue, road, boulevard, alley, lane, highway, sidewalk, public park, viaduct or other public place located in the County and established for the use of vehicles.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Public interest means a determination based on the following criteria, that transportation benefits will accrue to the community, transportation services, the public who presently or in the future utilize the passenger motor carrier industry to meet transportation needs, and adopted community development policy and that determination is consistent with the transportation policy statement contained in this article.</section><section prefix='(w)'>Charter service means the transportation of a group of persons pursuant to a common purpose and traveling under a single contract involving the exclusive use of a motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(x)'>Core transit or transit corridor means the area one-fifth () of a mile on each side of the street on which high service level of fixed route or jitney service is being legally provided.</section><section prefix='(y)'>Limited certificate of transportation means the holder thereof may engage in providing transportation services as described in a contract with the Miami-Dade Transit Agency for the provision of transportation services for so long as such contract is in effect.</section><section prefix='(z)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(aa)'>Paratransit services mean any transportation services provided for compensation to passengers with disabilities by motor carriers between specific origins and destinations selected by an individual user at a certain time that is agreed upon by the user and the service provider.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 or the ADA means the civil rights act signed into law on July 26, 1990 as Public Law 101-336, 104 Stat. 327, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>The ADA-defined area of Miami-Dade County means the complementary paratransit service area as required by the ADA or any federal regulations established pursuant to the ADA. The service area includes an area with a width of three-fourths of a mile on each side of each of Miami-Dade County's fixed bus routes and an area consisting of a circle with a radius of three-fourths of a mile around each Metrorail station.</section><section prefix='(dd)'>Paratransit passenger means an individual receiving paratransit services who has a physical or mental impairment as defined by the ADA that substantially limits one (1) or more of the major life activities of such individual, has a record of such impairment or has been regarded as having such impairment.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, § 3, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 85-20, § 1, 4-16-85; Ord. No. 87-11, § 1, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 90-67, § 1, 7-10-90; Ord. No. 91-130, § 1, 1-5-91; Ord. No. 95-42, § 1, 3-7-95; Ord. No. 95-221, § 3, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 02-1, § 1, 1-29-02)</history></law>