<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-115</section_number>
<catch_line>Special provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003739</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-115. Special provisions.<section prefix='(a)'>Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, the provisions of this article shall not be applicable within those municipalities which regulated passenger motor carrier transportation as of July 1, 1974, and such municipalities shall be exempt from this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive regulations applicable to the provision of and operation of passenger motor carrier transportation services in Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding the provisions of any municipal ordinance, resolution or agreement to the contrary, from and after the effective date of this article, no municipality shall authorize, establish, change, alter, amend, or otherwise regulate passenger motor carrier transportation in Miami-Dade County. Regulations established by this article shall be uniform throughout Miami-Dade County both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries. All municipal ordinances or resolutions to the contrary are hereby superseded and rescinded.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any person operating a passenger motor vehicle within Miami-Dade County on February 2, 1981, upon the authority of a valid certificate of public convenience and necessity or other valid permit issued by the Florida Public Service Commission or a valid certificate of public convenience and necessity issued by a municipality within Miami-Dade County regulating passenger motor vehicles, shall, upon proper proof of possession of such authority, be entitled to a Miami-Dade County certificate upon the payment of the fee required in this article, with all existing authority, limitation or restriction of the Public Service Commission or municipal certificate as of February 2, 1981, providing the County certificate shall be limited to the maximum number of vehicles operated in any one (1) month of the previous twelve (12) months prior to February 2, 1981. Holders of municipal certificates shall only be issued a certificate for each vehicle that is not also operating under authority of a Florida [Public] Service Commission certificate. No Miami-Dade County certificate shall be issued in accordance with this section unless same has been applied for no later than fifty (50) days after the effective date of the article, provided that on each certificate applied for, a separate and distinct vehicle meeting the requirements of this article is listed and a proper and timely application and fee is submitted in accordance with this section. A separate and identifiable motor vehicle cannot be used to apply for more than one (1) certificate under this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any person operating a passenger motor vehicle upon the effective date of Ordinance No. 81-17 must make application for a certificate within ten (10) days. Those persons who applied within the time period specified in the first sentence of this subsection (d) shall be issued a Miami-Dade County certificate for those operations specified in the application which have been continuously performed in accordance with the terms and conditions of Sections 31-106 and 31-108 of this article. The County certificate issued hereunder shall not limit the number of vehicles authorized.</section><section prefix='(e)'>On the effective date of this article, the existing rate(s) of operators entitled to the issuance of certificate pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be that rate in effect on February 2, 1981, and said rate may only be changed in accordance with the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Each chauffeur authorized on the effective date of this article by a certificate holder to drive a passenger motor vehicle shall be issued by CSD, at no cost, a temporary ninety-day chauffeur registration upon proof of possession of a valid Florida chauffeur license. Upon expiration of the temporary registration, said chauffeur must fully comply with Section 31-105</section><section prefix='(g)'>Any person operating a passenger motor vehicle designed for carrying ten (10) to twenty-eight (28) passengers, including driver, with an overall length of thirty (30) feet or less engaged solely in intercounty transportation or engaged in intracity transportation routes which intracity routes have been operated continuously from January 1, 1990 through July 1, 1990 in compliance with applicable safety rules and regulations promulgated under Section 316.70 Florida Statutes must make application for a certificate of transportation and pay a two hundred and twenty-five dollar ($225.00) application fee therefor to CSD by August 17, 1990. Those persons who apply and pay the required application fee by August 17, 1990 shall be issued a certificate of transportation for those operations which meet the requirements of the preceding sentence. Appeal of the CSD Director's decision on any application hereunder must be filed with the County Manager within ten (10) days of the issuance of the Director's decision. Such certificate shall be subject to the requirements of Section 31-101; 31-102; 31-103(a), (b), (c)(1)—(3), (8) and (10), and (j) through (o); 31-104; 31-105; 31-106; 31-107; 31-108; 31-110; 31-111; 31-112 and 31-115. A certificate of transportation issued hereunder shall expire July 1, 2010, or ten (10) years after any change in ownership of any such passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Any private passenger motor carrier providing transportation pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County, acting on behalf of the Miami-Dade Transit Agency, shall not be allowed to provide transportation on any route on which Miami-Dade County Metrobus is providing service, when the expressed purpose of such contract is to incorporate private passenger motor carriers into Miami-Dade County's public transportation network.</section><section prefix='(i)'>No person or business entity shall be awarded a contract by Miami-Dade County to provide transportation on more than twenty-five (25) percent of Jitney Transportation Network Service. No business entity shall be awarded a contract by Miami-Dade County to provide transportation on a Jitney Transportation Network Route, if a person with a controlling financial interest in that business entity has a controlling financial interest in another business entity or entities, which provide or have agreed to provide transportation on more than twenty-five (25) percent of the Jitney Transportation Network Service. In the event that an award of a Jitney Transportation Network Route to the lowest bidder would be in violation of this ordinance, such award shall be made to the next lowest bidder, if any award is made.</section><section>These terms used in the preceding paragraph shall have the meanings provided below:<section>means a contract between the County and the operator of a passenger motor carrier to provide transportation on a Jitney Transportation Route, when the expressed aim of such contract is to incorporate private jitneys or other passenger motor carriers into the public transportation system of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>means such transportation route designated by the Miami-Dade Transit Agency on which passenger motor carriers will provide transportation pursuant to a coordinated jitney service contract.</section><section>means the total number of revenue miles on which private passenger motor carriers provide transportation, pursuant to a coordinated jitney service contract.</section><section>means the ownership, directly or indirectly, of ten (10) percent or more of the outstanding capital stock in any corporation or a direct or indirect interest of ten (10) percent or more in a firm, partnership, or other business entity.</section></section><section>The foregoing requirements may be waived by resolution of the County Commission (1) upon a finding that a waiver is in the best interest of Miami-Dade County, and (2) that there are not enough responsive bidders or proposers with whom the County can contract to provide the necessary transportation on Jitney Transportation Network Routes, unless the provisions of this ordinance are waived.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Notwithstanding the vehicle age limit required by Section 31-107(b) of the Code, any properly permitted and inspected passenger motor carrier scheduled for retirement on December 31, 2011, shall be allowed to be operated for an additional one-year period.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, § 16, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 81-46, § 1, 4-19-81; Ord. No. 85-20, § 2, 4-16-85; Ord. No. 87-11, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 90-78, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 93-116, § 1, 11-3-93; Ord. No. 93-117, § 1, 11-3-93; Ord. No. 11-11, § 1, 3-1-11; Ord. No. 11-102, § 1, 12-19-11)</history></law>