<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-101</section_number>
<catch_line>Transportation policy.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003725</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-101. Transportation policy.<section>To assure the development and maintenance of a safe, healthy and efficient passenger transportation system for Miami-Dade County, the Commission, County Manager and County staff, in carrying out the duties and responsibilities prescribed in this article, shall consider the following as being in the public interest:<section prefix='(1)'>Reliance on market forces and on actual and potential competition among all transportation modes, so as to provide transportation services at competitive prices.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Coordination of regulatory decision-making with the transportation improvement plan, and the orderly development of an integrated transportation/transit system for Miami-Dade County so as to ensure the development and maintenance of a transportation/transit system responsive to the needs of the public, in which regulatory decisions are reached fairly and expeditiously, and with consideration of their costs and benefits.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Improvement of motor vehicle safety.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Achievement of County, national and State energy conservation goals.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Reduced concentration of market power, and prevention of unfair, deceptive, predatory or anticompetitive practices.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Reduction of restrictive regulatory barriers to entry into the industry and promotion of equal opportunities.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Promotion of the safety and welfare of the residents and visitors of Miami-Dade County who use the services of passenger motor carriers to meet their transportation needs.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Recognition that a strong, viable, private sector passenger motor carrier industry has a role in efforts to improve transportation mobility.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, ยง 2, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 85-20, ยง 1, 4-16-85)</history></law>