<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-106</section_number>
<catch_line>Financial responsibility or insurance requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003730</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-106. Financial responsibility or insurance requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>No passenger motor carrier vehicle shall be permitted to operate without the operator having first obtained and filed with CSD a certificate of insurance on forms provided by CSD for each vehicle showing automobile liability insurance coverage with limits of liability no less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) for one (1) passenger and one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) for all passengers for injuries or death arising out of any one (1) occurrence, and fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) for damage to property arising out of any one (1) occurrence. Any vehicle with a seating capacity in excess of fifteen (15) shall provide additional minimum limit for injury or death of ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per passenger seat of each vehicle.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The insurance required in this section shall be written by an insurance company authorized to do business in the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The certificate of insurance shall be endorsed to provide for thirty (30) days' notice by registered mail to CSD of any material change, cancellation or expiration. No policy will be accepted for a shorter period than six (6) months.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Unless an operator has furnished CSD with satisfactory evidence of the required insurance coverage prior to the expiration of the thirty (30) days' notice specified in paragraph (c) of this section, or upon a third notice of cancellation within twelve (12) months, the certificate shall be suspended forthwith by the Director and surrendered to CSD pending a hearing to determine whether the said certificate should be revoked.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Operators may comply with these insurance requirements if found to be a qualified self-insurer with minimum limit required by paragraph (a) of this section by the State of Florida. An operator's failure to maintain the requirements of a qualified self-insurer shall be grounds for CSD to take the actions described in paragraph (d) above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, ยง 7, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 87-11, ยง 2, 3-17-87)</history></law>