<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-108</section_number>
<catch_line>Rules for operation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003732</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-108. Rules for operation.<section prefix='(a)'>Color scheme. Each operator shall adopt and use, after approval by the CSD, a distinctive, uniform, and decorative color scheme for all passenger motor carrier vehicles certified pursuant to this article. The CSD shall refuse to approve any proposed color scheme which will infringe upon any color scheme already in use by another operator. No other color scheme shall be employed until approved by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Disposal of personal property. Personal property left by a passenger in any passenger motor vehicle shall, upon its discovery by or delivery to the chauffeur of said vehicle, be reported immediately to and deposited at the operator's office, where a record of the same shall be maintained and the property held for the owner for a period of six (6) months, at the end of which it shall become the property of the finder. The operator shall be responsible for chauffeur compliance with this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Compliance with other legislation. Every operator shall fully comply with all ordinances, rules and regulations of the County and all statutes of the State of Florida applicable to the operation of passenger motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Accessibility of service to the public; accessibility of records for regulatory purposes. Each operator shall maintain and list with CSD a central place of business, where a listed telephone number is operative and where business records and daily manifests set forth herein are kept.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Records required. Each operator shall maintain accurate records of all financial and operating information as may be required by CSD. CSD shall be granted access to these records for the purpose of inspection and/or copying same, upon five (5) days' prior notice. All such records and information shall be confidential except that they will become public records for the purpose of revocation or suspension hearings, or, if required by the Board of County Commissioners, for the purpose of approving or disapproving applications for new certificates or transfers of certificates. Each operator shall annually furnish financial and operating information to CSD on forms and in the manner prescribed by CSD.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Antidiscrimination. No operator or chauffeur shall refuse or neglect to transport to and from any place in the County any orderly person requesting service regardless of race, sex, religion, national origin, age, marital status or handicap, who is willing and able to pay the prescribed fare.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Vehicle numbering system. Each operator shall adopt a vehicle numbering system approved by CSD, which does not conflict with those in use by other operators.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Manifest or trip sheet required. Every operator shall maintain a manifest or trip sheet on a form approved by CSD, which shall include, but not be limited to, the following information on each trip: Name of chauffeur, vehicle number, date, time, origin, destination, number of passengers, and rate of fare. Operators shall not destroy, mutilate, alter or otherwise deface any daily manifests without CSD approval. All manifests shall be available for inspection and/or copying by CSD or any police agency during regular business hours and shall be retained for three (3) years.</section><section prefix='(i)'>[Prohibitions for operators.] No operator shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Knowingly allow or permit any person to operate a passenger motor vehicle while his ability or alertness is so impaired, or is likely to become impaired, through fatigue, illness, or any other cause, as to make it unsafe for him to begin or continue to operate the motor vehicle; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Permit or authorize any chauffeur or other person to operate any passenger motor vehicle without that vehicle's current valid certificate displayed therein; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Operate or permit or authorize anyone else to operate any passenger motor vehicle unless and until that person is issued a chauffeur's registration in accordance with Section 31-105</section></section><section prefix='(j)'>[Vehicle prohibitions.] No operator shall allow vehicles permitted under this article to:<section prefix='(1)'>Stop, stand, park or await employment at a marked taxicab stand.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Display the word(s) "taxicab," "taxi" or "cab" on the vehicle exterior.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Be equipped with a taximeter.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Operate as a taxicab, as defined in the County Code.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>[Separate phone numbers for jitney and taxi service.] No operator shall use for the purpose of advertising or requesting services to be provided under this article telephone number(s) that is used to request or furnish taxicab services.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, ยง 9, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 87-11, ยง 2, 3-17-87)</history></law>