<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-110</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003734</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-110. Enforcement.<section prefix='(a)'>This article shall be enforced by authorized personnel of CSD, and by the Miami-Dade Police Department, and may be enforced by another police agency within Miami-Dade County. CSD shall prepare and distribute to all authorized enforcement agencies an enforcement manual outlining procedures for the detection, reporting and issuance of citations or deficiency reports for violations of this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>CSD shall develop a deficiency or warning system through which operators are given written notice of minor violations and a specified period of time to correct same. For more serious or repeated violations, CSD shall develop a citation form. Authorized personnel will issue citations as official notice of violations. Civil violations by chauffeurs shall be processed under Chapter 8CC of the Code.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Deficiency reports and/or citations shall be issued to the party responsible for the violation as set forth in this article. Any person issued a deficiency report or a citation shall sign and accept it. Notice is given to a chauffeur for a violation involving the vehicle under his control shall be deemed notice to the operator.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Whether a corporation, partnership or association violates any of the provisions of this article, such violation shall be deemed also to be that of the individual officers, directors, partners or agents of such corporation who have personally authorized, personally ordered, or personally done any of the actions constituting in whole or in part such violation, and any such officer, director, partner, or agent may be fined in the same manner and to the same extent as herein provided for the individual.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the Director may secure enforcement of the provisions of this article by any legal action necessary, such as application to any court for injunctive relief or other appropriate relief.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, ยง 17, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 87-11, ยง 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 94-15, ยง 3, 1-20-94)</history></law>