<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-109</section_number>
<catch_line>Rates and fares.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003733</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-109. Rates and fares.<section prefix='(a)'>[Applicability.] The provisions of this section shall be the exclusive method for the establishment of passenger motor carrier rates through Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Rates and fares to be charged. It shall be unlawful for any operator to charge, demand, request or accept any fare other than the rates and fares established pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Methods of establishing rates. Each operator may establish rates and fares under one (1) or both of the following categories:<section prefix='(1)'>Rates and fares:<section prefix='a.'>The operator's initial rate will be that rate or fare proposed in the application for certificate and will become effective upon issuance of the certificate.</section><section prefix='b.'>An operator may change the rate or fare by filing a proposed rate or fare, thirty (30) days prior to its effective date, with CSD. The proposed rate or fare for jitney and fixed route service shall be posted within the passenger compartment section of each vehicle at least fifteen (15) days before it becomes effective.</section><section prefix='c.'>The rate(s) or fare structure for jitney or fixed route service shall be clearly set forth as a schedule of charges based on service elements understandable by the public, posted within the passenger compartment and on the exterior located adjacent to the entrance of each vehicle.</section><section prefix='d.'>Each operator shall post, in the business offices serving the public, a schedule of rates and fares and shall provide information of such rates and fares on request for service.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Contract rates. Each operator may establish through written contract, rates and fares other than the public rates and fares. Such rates and fares shall become effective when the contract is filed with CSD.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, ยง 10, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 87-11, ยง 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 98-105, ยง 1, 7-9-98; Ord. No. 00-139, ยง 1, 11-14-00)</history></law>