<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-111</section_number>
<catch_line>Penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003735</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-111. Penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to any other penalties provided by law, a fine not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100.00) may be imposed for each and every violation of the provisions of this article, provided that violations which result in fines pursuant to this section shall not be the basis for revocation or suspension proceedings except that five (5) or more violations resulting in fines within any twelve-month period shall constitute grounds for revocation or suspension proceedings.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Failure to correct items recorded on a deficiency report by the time of deadline shall cause a citation to be issued for each such item. In the case of chauffeurs, for civil violations a citation shall be issued under Chapter 8CC of the Code.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Except for chauffeurs receiving civil violations, each person issued a citation shall within ten (10) days either satisfy the citation by payment to CSD of the fine stated in subsection (a) hereof or by filing a written request for a hearing on the charges. Failure to do one (1) of the foregoing may result in revocation or suspension proceedings or penalties in accordance with subsection (f) hereof.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Except for chauffeurs receiving civil violations, the hearings specified in subsection (c) hereof shall be within the jurisdiction of the County Court and the Clerk of the Court is hereby empowered to dispose of the case and fines assessed through normal procedure.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Anyone who engages a passenger motor vehicle with intent to defraud the chauffeur or operator shall be in violation of this article and subject to the penalty provided for in subsection (f) hereof.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Violations of Section 31-103 shall be punishable by fines and/or imprisonment as follows: (1) the first such violation shall be punishable by fines of not less than two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) or more than one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) and/or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days; (2) the second such violation shall be punishable by fines of not less than one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or more than five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) and/or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days; and (3) the third and subsequent violation shall be punishable by fines of not less than five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) or more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) and/or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days. Violations of revocation or suspension ordered under Section 31-112 shall be punishable by fines of not less than one hundred dollars ($100.00) or more than five hundred dollars ($500.00) and/or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, § 12, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 87-11, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 92-52, § 1, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 93-77, § 2, 7-29-93; Ord. No. 94-15, § 3, 1-20-94)</history></law>