<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-103</section_number>
<catch_line>Certificate of transportation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003727</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-103. Certificate of transportation.<section prefix='(a)'>Required. From and after the effective date of this article, it shall be unlawful for any person to use, drive or operate or to cause or permit any other person to use, drive or operate any passenger motor carrier vehicle for compensation upon the streets of Miami-Dade County without first obtaining a Miami-Dade County certificate and maintaining it current and valid, pursuant to the provisions of this article, unless specifically excluded from this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Out-of-county origin excepted. Nothing in this article shall be construed to prohibit:<section prefix='(1)'>Discharge within Miami-Dade County of any passenger lawfully picked up in another County and lawfully transported into Miami-Dade County including preticketed round trips originating outside Miami-Dade County which are completed within a single twelve-hour period.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Pick up of a paratransit passenger by a provider of paratransit services that is duly licensed and legally authorized to provide paratransit services in a county adjacent to Miami-Dade County, provided that such county has determined that the passenger is eligible for paratransit services and such passenger is picked up within the ADA-defined area of Miami-Dade County. A paratransit service provider shall not be required to obtain a Miami-Dade County Certificate of public convenience and necessity for such purpose, nor shall a chauffeur of such paratransit vehicle be required to obtain a Miami-Dade County for-hire chauffeur's registration.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Application contents. Every application for a certificate shall be in writing, signed and sworn to by the applicant, and shall be filed with CSD. The statements contained in the application shall become a part of the certificate and may be modified only in accordance with this article. The application shall be on a form provided by CSD and shall contain all information required thereon, including but not limited to:<section prefix='(1)'>Sufficient information to identify the applicant.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The class of transportation service to be authorized under this article, routes, termini, schedules, etc., and a brief description of the kinds of and types of vehicles, seating capacity of the vehicles, seating arrangements, and size and gross weight thereof.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The trade name under which the applicant intends to operate and a description of the proposed vehicle colors, numbers and markings.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The applicant's management plan including but not limited to maintenance facilities, a system for handling complaints and accidents, a driver training program, insurance coverage, and a communication system.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The applicant's proposed service standards, including but not limited to days and hours of operation, and passenger services to be provided.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The applicant's proposed initial public fare and rate structure.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A record of all present and prior transportation business activities of the applicant during the past five (5) years.</section><section prefix='(8)'>A record of all crimes (excluding traffic) of which the applicant has been convicted within five (5) years preceding the date of the application. The applicant shall have his/her fingerprints and photograph taken by the Miami-Dade Police Department.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Two (2) credit references including at least one (1) bank where the applicant maintains an active account.</section><section prefix='(10)'>An investigative and processing fee which shall be nonrefundable.</section><section prefix='(11)'>An agreement on the part of the applicant to conform to and abide by the provisions of this article and the laws of the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The applicant's current financial statement. If the applicant has an existing certified financial statement, the most current certified financial statement is required.</section><section prefix='(13)'>A factual statement indicating the anticipated market to be served and such other pertinent information as the applicant may desire to present to support his application.</section><section prefix='(14)'>A factual statement supporting the economic feasibility of the services proposed to be provided, including estimated ridership, fare revenue, and operating expenses for the first year of operation.</section><section prefix='(15)'>An operational plan for implementing the proposed services.</section><section prefix='(16)'>A factual statement, if applying for jitney or fixed route authority, indicating the economic and ridership effect on any existing sixed route or jitney transportation service providers on the same transit corridor, route or portion thereof.</section><section prefix='(17)'>A factual statement, if applying for jitney or fixed route authority, that the application is consistent with the criteria and factors contained in subsection (g) of this section.</section><section prefix='(18)'>A public notice which shall contain a brief summary of the subject matter of the application including a brief description of the type of service proposed and the geographical area or route(s) to be served.</section><section prefix='(19)'>For transfer applications only, a statement disclosing the terms and conditions of the proposed transfer, including amount of compensation which has been paid or is payable to the transferor and any other consideration given or to be given to the transferor in connection with the transfer of the certificate of transportation; in lieu of the requirements of this paragraph, the applicant for transfer of the certificate of transportation may submit a notarized copy of the purchase contract which contains all information requested by this paragraph.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Application review. The Director shall review and investigate each application and shall reject any application that is not properly filed, incomplete or, where applicable, in conflict with criteria set forth in subsection (g) of this section. Such investigation shall include a Miami-Dade Police Department background check including, but not limited to, past business credit or financial standing and law enforcement records. Application rejection by the Director may be appealed in accordance with Section 31-112(f) of the Code.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Hearing, notices and reports.<section prefix='(1)'>Upon the proper filing of an application under this article for a certificate to provide jitney or fixed route service, or for the transfer or modification thereof, and payment of the required fee, the Director shall give notice to the following: (a) The governing bodies of all affected municipalities within Miami-Dade County; (b) all jitney or fixed route certificate holders; (c) any other person, office or entity requesting notice.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any interested person affected by the proposed operation of jitney or fixed route service who wishes to intervene in the proceeding shall file with the Director and serve upon the applicant a formal protest within twenty (20) days after service of said notice. A person who has not filed a formal protest as provided in this section may not appear as a party in the proceeding. If no written protest is properly filed and served as herein provided, the Commission shall dispose of the application after a public hearing. If one (1) or more protests are properly filed and served as herein provided, the County Manager shall appoint a hearing officer and fix a time for an administrative hearing no later than twenty (20) days after the conclusion of the termination date for filing a protest, and shall serve notice of hearing upon the applicant and all persons who have filed a written protest. The County Manager, by regulations, shall establish the procedures for such hearings.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Director shall submit a report and recommendation on each application to the County Manager. The Director shall base the recommendation on the thoroughness of the application, the competence of the applicant, the criteria contained in subsection (g) where applicable and consideration of the findings of the hearing examiner. The County Manager may require any further investigation or additional information that he deems necessary and shall submit a written report and recommendation to the Commission.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Public hearings. The Commission shall hold at least two (2) public hearings each year if required, to consider and take action upon pending certificate applications and transfer applications. The Clerk of the Board shall provide at least seven (7) days' advance notice of such public hearing. Additionally, if the application is for jitney or fixed route authority, CSD shall provide at least twenty (20) days' advance notice of such public hearings to all applicants and all jitney or fixed route certificate holders by certified mail. In reaching its determination, the Commission shall consider the application, the County Manager's report and recommendation, and matters presented at the public hearing.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Certification criteria and process. The Commission, at the conclusion of the public hearing shall determine if the requested certificate of transportation is consistent with the following public interest criteria.<section prefix='(1)'>That the applicant is fit, willing and able, in accordance with the requirements of this section, to provide the transportation to be authorized by the certificate and is able to comply with this article and regulation of the Commission.</section><section prefix='(2)'>That the transportation to be provided under the requested certificate is consistent with the public interest.</section><section prefix='(3)'>That the proposed transportation service will improve the quality of transportation available to the public.</section><section prefix='(4)'>That, if applying for jitney or fixed route authority, the proposed transportation will not adversely affect the existing transportation system as a whole or future planned transit service as designated in the most current Miami-Dade Transportation Plan. In particular, it shall be deemed not in the public interest to authorize certificates of transportation for service on actual transit or passenger motor carrier corridors where service presently exists at average frequencies of twenty-nine (29) minutes or less and/or where such service will impair special transportation provided by the passenger motor carrier industry. The provisions of the preceding sentence shall not apply when the applicant is applying for a certificate of transportation to provide jitney or fixed route authority and the Commission finds: (1) that the proposed transportation will not adversely affect the existing transportation system as a whole or future planned transit service as designated in the most current Miami-Dade Transportation Plan: (2) the route applied for has been operated by the applicant for at least five (5) years utilizing at least twelve (12) vehicles during 1997 which were issued permits by the CSD; (3) the fixed or jitney route traverses at least five (5) miles on either NW 7th Avenue or NE 2nd Avenue in Miami-Dade County; and (4) the applicant has held a certificate of transportation issued by Miami-Dade County for at least eight (8) years.</section></section><section>The Commission, after such public hearing, by resolution, may authorize or refuse to authorize the certificate as applied for, or may authorize a certificate with such modifications or upon such terms and conditions as in its judgment the public interest may require.</section><section>The County Manager may prescribe rules and regulations consistent with the criteria set forth in subsection (g)(1), (2), (3) and (4) above, for the approval and issuance of emergency temporary certificate. No temporary certificate shall be issued unless the applicant has paid a temporary certificate fee.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Burden of proof. In any proceeding under this section, the applicant shall have the burden of providing all of the prerequisites of the issuance of the certificate except that if a protestant objects on the ground that issuance will adversely affect the existing transportation system or impair essential transportation services being provided by the motor carrier industry then, on that issue, the protestant shall have the burden of proof.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Resolution of approval. CSD shall issue the certificate as authorized by the resolution.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Further requirements. No certificate shall be issued unless the applicant has:<section prefix='(1)'>Paid an annual certificate fee for the right to operate passenger motor vehicles;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Has presented proof of insurance as required by Section 31-106; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Passed all required vehicle inspections.</section></section><section>Failure on the part of the applicant to complete this process within ninety (90) days after notification of approval shall cause the certificate not to be issued and the County's approval to be automatically revoked.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Form of certificate. Each certificate shall be on a form developed by CSD and shall be signed by the Director. Each certificate shall contain, at a minimum, the name and address of the applicant, a statement of the transportation service authorized, the passenger capacity of the vehicles to which it applies, and such additional terms, conditions, provisions, and limitations as were authorized in the approval process. All operators holding certificates which are valid as of the effective date of this amendment shall be issued amended certificates which contain no limit on the number of vehicles authorized thereunder.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Renewal. All certificates shall be renewed before April 1 of each year by payment of an annual certificate fee. All fees provided for in this section shall be in addition to any other license fees or charges and shall not be prorated for fractional parts of a year. All certificates which are not renewed shall automatically expire and all certificate transportation services rendered thereunder shall immediately cease as of April 1.</section><section>On or before March 31 of each year, each operator shall, on application for renewal, certify, on a form provided by CSD, the number of months during the preceding year that he operated and provided the service authorized by his certificate. Failure to certify or to operate for at least eight (8) months during the year period shall result in automatic expiration of the certificate.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Transfer of certificate.<section prefix='(1)'>No certificate issued pursuant to this article may be sold, assigned, transferred or its ownership structure changed or altered so as to result in a change or the possibility of a change in the control of said certificate to another until the proposed sale, assignment, transfer or change in control shall have been approved by the commission. Any transfer of shares or stock or interest of any person or certificate holder so as to cause a change in the directors, officer, shareholders or managers of such person or certificate holder shall be deemed a transfer or assignment as contemplated in this section and subject to the same rules and regulations as any other transfer or assignment.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Commission, in considering the proposed transfer of ownership or control of the certificate, by either direct or indirect means, shall determine, upon evidence submitted by the parties or any other party or person affected by the proposed transfer, whether or not said transfer is contrary to the public interest or if said certificate, in whole or in part, is dormant within the meaning of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Commission may approve said transfer or refuse to approve said transfer upon such terms and conditions or may reasonably alter, restrict or modify the terms and provisions of such transfer where the same may best serve the public interest.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All such applications for approval of transfers shall be filed on forms provided by the Director and shall be accompanied by payment of a nonrefundable transfer investigative and processing fee. Applications for transfers shall be noticed for public hearing before the Commission in the manner provided by this article for new applicants for certificates and the formal approval of the Commission shall be a condition precedent to any such transfer.</section></section><section prefix='(n)'>Modification of certificate. Every application for modification of a certificate shall be in writing, signed and sworn to by the operator and shall be filed together with a modification processing fee. The application shall be on a form provided by CSD, and shall be noticed for hearing before the Commission in the manner as provided for in this article for applications for a certificate and the formal approval of the Commission shall be a precedent to any modification. Modifications of a certificate shall include changes in service standards, route changes in service standards, route extensions, and similar items which enlarge operating authority.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Surrender or abandonment of certificate. An operator may relinquish or abandon all or part of the operating authority provided in such certificate upon written notice to the Director thirty (30) days prior to the effective date of such action, and submission of his certificate. The Director shall, upon his authority, re-issue a certificate containing the residual operating authority unless, in his opinion, the requested changes or the residual authority are not in the public interest, in which case he may institute revocation or suspension procedures.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Limited certificate of transportation. A passenger motor carrier proposing to provide transportation services pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County for the provision of Miami-Dade Transit Agency services, may satisfy the passenger motor carrier certificate requirements by obtaining a limited certificate of transportation. A holder of a limited certificate of transportation must comply with all requirements of the Miami-Dade County Code pertaining to holders of a Certificate of Transportation. Provided, however, that the requirements of Section 31-103(e) pertaining to hearings, notices, and administrative protest procedures and Section 31-103(f) pertaining to advance notice to certificate holders and applicants of the public hearing at which time the limited certificate of transportation is to be considered shall not apply. The limited certificate of transportation shall only authorize provision of transportation services pursuant to such contract for so long as such contract is in effect. A person who is issued a limited certificate of transportation shall not lease or otherwise assign the right to operate under such certificate to any other person.</section><section prefix='(q)'>The amendments to Section 31-103(g)(4) contained in this section shall sunset on July 5, 1999. Notwithstanding the requirements of the prior sentence, any certificate of transportation issued pursuant to an application approved by the Commission prior to June 22, 1999 pursuant to Section 31-103(g)(4) as amended by this section shall remain in full force and effect so long as the certificate holder complies with all applicable provisions of the Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, § 4, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 85-20, § 1, 4-16-85; Ord. No. 87-11, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 88-118, § 2, 12-6-88; Ord. No. 90-67, § 2, 7-10-90; Ord. No. 90-126, § 3, 11-27-90; Ord. No. 95-42, § 2, 3-7-95; Ord. No. 95-221, § 3, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-123, § 1, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-72, § 1, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 02-1, § 1, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 06-21, § 2, 2-7-06)</history></law>