<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PASSENGER MOTOR CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-113</section_number>
<catch_line>Exclusions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003737</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-113. Exclusions.<section>The following passenger motor carriers and/or passenger motor vehicles are exempt from the requirements of this article:<section prefix='(a)'>Ambulances and other vehicles required to be licensed under the provisions of Chapter 401, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Motor vehicles used exclusively in transporting children to and from schools when regulated by a Florida Statute and/or a Miami-Dade County ordinance.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For-hire vehicles with a seating not to exceed eight (8) passengers subject to the provisions of a Miami-Dade County or municipal ordinance.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Motor vehicles used for the transportation of passengers between the vicinity of their respective residences and the vicinity of their respective places of work, when driven by a person traveling between his residence and his place of work in an arrangement commonly known as a "car pool" or a "van pool."</section><section prefix='(e)'>A passenger motor carrier operating pursuant to a valid Interstate Commerce Commission certificate which is providing interstate transportation service within the jurisdiction of the Interstate Commerce Commission. As used in this subsection (e), "interstate transportation service" means the provision of transportation over a route through more than one (1) state. Said interstate transportation service must be substantial, actual and bona fide.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Motor vehicles owned and operated by a governmental unit in a local public transportation system, commonly referred to as a "mass transit" when controlled by a Miami-Dade County ordinance.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Federal, State, County and municipal vehicles when operated by a government employee providing transportation services without compensation.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Motor vehicles used exclusively to provide transportation without compensation and purely incidental to a person's primary business and requiring the performance of substantial services in addition to transportation.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Social service transportation of persons without compensation by private, nonprofit organization subject to State of Florida and/or federal government regulatory and safety standards.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Motor vehicle providing special operations service, contract carrier service or charter service having an overall length in excess of thirty (30) feet or a rated seating capacity in excess of twenty-eight (28) persons.</section><section prefix='(k)'>A passenger motor carrier under contract to Miami-Dade County pursuant to a State statute or County ordinance who has the exclusive right to provide demand ground transportation services at Miami International Airport, and is subject to the safety and insurance requirements of a County ordinance.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Passenger motor carriers operating under authority of a municipal regulatory ordinance adopted prior to July 1, 1974, are exempt from the provisions of this article for those services provided in accordance with their municipal certificate(s).</section><section prefix='(m)'>Motor vehicles owned, operated by or operated under contract with a municipality in a local public transportation system providing circulator service when authorized by an interlocal agreement with Miami-Dade County which has been approved by the Board. As used herein, "circulator service" means the provision of fixed route or semi-fixed route transportation service where at least seventy (70) percent of the route is within one (1) municipality. The interlocal agreement and any certificate of transportation, chauffeur's registration and permit issued to provide circulator service pursuant to an interlocal agreement shall require, among other things, that the municipality, operator, vehicles and chauffeurs comply with safety, mechanical and vehicular standards mandated by the Miami-Dade Transit Agency and the CSD, and any applicable State or Federal requirements. Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, the CSD may administratively issue certificates of transportation to municipalities providing circulator service or to operators under contract with a municipality providing circulator service pursuant to an interlocal agreement with Miami-Dade County. The provisions of Section 31-103(e), (f) and (g)(4) shall not apply when the CSD administratively issues a certificate of transportation pursuant to this paragraph. Where a municipality intends to provide circulator service pursuant to a contract with a third party, said municipality shall give Miami-Dade County the opportunity to submit a bid or proposal to provide that transportation service.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-17, ยง 14, 2-17-81; Ord. No. 95-139, ยง 1, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 97-127, ยง 1, 7-22-97)</history></law>