<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. SPECIAL TRANSPORTATION SERVICE CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-202</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003743</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-202. Definitions.<section>For the purposes of this article, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>Special transportation services certificate of transportation means the holder thereof may engage in providing the special transportation services described thereon and consistent with the terms and restrictions contained in the applicable Miami-Dade County contract relating thereto.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Chauffeur means a duly licensed driver registered with and authorized by the Consumer Services Department to operate a special transportation services vehicle.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Commission means the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Common carrier means any motor carrier who holds his services out to the public.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Special transportation services means any transportation services provided by a motor carrier, for compensation, to passengers with disabilities, including non-ambulatory individuals who use wheelchairs, or individuals who are eligible for Medicaid as determined by the Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, pursuant to a written contract with Miami-Dade County for the provision of Miami-Dade Transit Agency services or pursuant to a written contract with a broker which has a written contract with Miami-Dade County for the provision of Miami-Dade Transit Agency services.</section><section prefix='(f)'>County Manager means the chief executive officer and head of the administrative branch of the County government as provided in Article III of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Director means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department director.</section><section prefix='(h)'>For compensation means for money, property, service or anything else of value.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Operate means providing transportation services for compensation utilizing a special transportation services motor vehicle pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County for the provision of Miami-Dade Transit Agency services.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Operator means any person who has been issued a special transportation services certificate of transportation in accordance with the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(k)'>CSD means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Special transportation services motor carrier or motor carrier means any person owning, controlling, operating or managing any motor vehicle used in the business of providing special transportation services for compensation pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County for the provision of Miami-Dade Transit Agency services.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Permit means an operating permit authorizing the holder thereof to utilize the motor vehicle described in said permit to provide special transportation services to passengers as authorized by a special transportation services certificate issued pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Person means any individual, corporation, firm, partnership, limited partnership, association or joint stock association.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Registration means a chauffeur's registration authorizing the holder thereof to operate passenger motor vehicles subject to the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Street means any public street, avenue, road, boulevard, alley, lane, highway, sidewalk, public park, viaduct or other public place located in the County and established for the use of motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(q)'>MDTA means the Miami-Dade Transit Agency.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Special transportation services motor vehicle means any chauffeur-driven motor vehicle engaged in providing special transportation services to passengers with disabilities, including non-ambulatory individuals who use wheelchairs, or individuals who are eligible for Medicaid as determined by the Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County for the provision of Miami-Dade Transit Agency services.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Sedan means a special transportation services motor vehicle, not equipped with a taximeter, with at least four (4) doors and providing seating accommodations for not more than eight (8) persons, exclusive of driver.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Broker means any person who has entered into a contract with Miami-Dade County to provide specified administrative services only related to the provision of transportation services, for compensation, to passengers with disabilities, including non-ambulatory individuals who use wheelchairs, or individuals who are eligible for Medicaid as determined by the Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Service provider means any person who has entered into a contract with a broker to provide transportation services, for compensation, to passengers with disabilities, including non-ambulatory individuals who use wheelchairs, or individuals who are eligible for Medicaid as determined by the Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Paratransit services means any transportation services provided for compensation to passengers with disabilities by motor carriers between specific origins and destinations selected by an individual user at a certain time that is agreed upon by the user and the service provider.</section><section prefix='(w)'>The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 or the ADA means the civil rights act signed into law on July 26, 1990 as Public Law 101-336, 104 Stat. 327, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(x)'>The ADA-defined area of Miami-Dade County means the complementary paratransit service area as required by the ADA or any federal regulations established pursuant to the ADA. The service area includes an area with a width of three-fourths of a mile on each side of each of Miami-Dade County's fixed bus routes and an area consisting of a circle with a radius of three-fourths of a mile around each Metrorail station.</section><section prefix='(y)'>Paratransit passenger means an individual receiving paratransit services who has a physical or mental impairment as defined by the ADA that substantially limits one (1) or more of the major life activities of such individual, has a record of such impairment or has been regarded as having such an impairment.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-130, ยง 2, 11-5-91; Ord. No. 92-101, ยง 1, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 95-221, ยง 4, 12-5-95)</history></law>