<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. SPECIAL TRANSPORTATION SERVICE CARRIERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-213</section_number>
<catch_line>Special provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003754</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-213. Special provisions.<section>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in this article, the County may enter into a contract with a broker which requires the broker to provide administrative services related to the provision of special transportation services. Such broker shall comply with all provisions of this article pertaining to the provision of special transportation services, including obtaining a certificate of transportation pursuant to this article; provided, however, the broker must contract with a service provider or service providers to provide such transportation and the broker may not be a service provider. A service provider is required to comply with all provisions of this article pertaining to the provision of special transportation services, including obtaining a certificate of transportation pursuant to this article or otherwise complying with(a); provided, however, a written contract in effect between the service provider and the broker shall satisfy the provisions of this article which would require a written contract between the County and the service provider. The special transportation services certificate of transportation issued to a service provider pursuant to this article shall be automatically revoked if MDTA determines that the service provider is in default of its contractual obligations to the broker or the contract between a service provider and the broker to provide special transportation services expires or is terminated.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-101, ยง 2, 9-15-92)</history></law>