<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. GENERAL REQUIREMENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-305</section_number>
<catch_line>Chauffeur's registration—Additional nonemergency medical transportation chauffeur provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003760</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-305. Chauffeur's registration—Additional nonemergency medical transportation chauffeur provisions.<section>Each chauffeur shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Be trained in the correct use of special equipment required for wheelchair and stretcher transport.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the county commission may by a majority vote of the members present authorize the issuance of a nonemergency medical transportation chauffeur's registration to an applicant who does not otherwise meet the requirements of Section 4-45 (and Chapter 31, Article V of the Code) if the applicant can produce evidence sufficient to satisfy the county commission that the applicant: (1) has been paroled into the United States pursuant to 8 United States Code Section 1182(d)(5); (ii) is authorized to work in the United States; (iii) has been convicted of a felony; (iv) has been leading an exemplary life during the two (2) year period prior to application; and (v) is seeking a chauffeur's registration for the purpose of earning an honest livelihood. A chauffeur's registration issued pursuant to Section 4-45 may be renewed (i) upon compliance with the requirements of Section 4-45 (and Chapter 31, Article V of the Code) and with any conditions imposed by the commission, (ii) if the chauffeur's parole into the United States has not expired or been revoked and (iii) if said chauffeur is authorized to work in the United States at the time of renewal. Each chauffeur issued a chauffeur's registration pursuant to Section 4-45 shall immediately notify the CSD if (a) his/her parole into the United States has expired or been revoked, or (b) he/she is no longer authorized to work in the United States. A chauffeur's registration issued pursuant to Section 4-45 shall be revoked upon notice and hearing as provided in Chapter 31, Article V of the Code if the chauffeur is no longer authorized to work in the United States or said chauffeur's parole into the United States has expired or been revoked.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-15, § 5, 1-20-94)</history></law>