<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. GENERAL REQUIREMENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-309</section_number>
<catch_line>Chauffeur's registration—Additional passenger motor carrier requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003764</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-309. Chauffeur's registration—Additional passenger motor carrier requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>The language and testing requirements contained in Section 31-303(d)(2) shall apply to initial and renewal fixed route or jitney service chauffeur applicants, except that said requirements shall not apply to fixed route or jitney service chauffeur applicants whose primary language is other than English. An initial or renewal applicant whose primary language is other than English shall be required to take and pass a separate examination which demonstrates the applicant's ability to communicate in English with emergency personnel and passengers in those situations described in this paragraph which pose immediate danger to the health and welfare of passengers. Such examination shall only test the applicant's ability (1) to notify emergency personnel and communicate with passengers in English in the event of an accident, illness, fire, physical injury or trauma, and (2) to minimally describe in English the nature of the emergency. The examination shall consist of a series of hypothetical emergency situations where the applicant is required to identify and/or articulate certain phrases necessary to notify emergency personnel, communicate with passengers and describe the nature of the emergency.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each initial and renewal fixed route or jitney service chauffeur applicant shall take the one-day course and pass the oral and written exam required in Section 31-303(d)(2) demonstrating the applicant's knowledge of Miami-Dade County traffic regulations, defensive driving techniques and chauffeur responsibilities. For chauffeur registration applicants whose primary language is other than English, said examination shall be administered in Spanish or Creole.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-44, § 1, 6-2-09)</history></law>