<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. GENERAL REQUIREMENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-302</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003757</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-302. Definitions.<section>For purposes of this article the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>CSD means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For-hire company means an entity which is registered with the Consumer Services Department, which shall minimally provide a color scheme, including the trade name, customer lost and found services and a system for handling customer complaints. A for-hire company may among other things also provide communication services, contract services to chauffeurs and contract services for for-hire license holders.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For-hire passenger motor vehicle or for-hire vehicle means any of the following chauffeur-driven vehicles as defined in Chapters 4, 30 or 31 of the Code of Miami-Dade County:<section prefix='(i)'>Taxicab</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Limousine</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Passenger motor carrier vehicle</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Non-emergency medical transportation vehicle</section><section prefix='(v)'>Private school bus</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Special transportation service vehicle</section><section>which engages in the transportation of passengers and their accompanying property for compensation over the public streets of Miami-Dade County which complies with Section 319.23, Florida Statutes, as may be amended from time to time, but excluding ambulances, vehicles used exclusively for the transportation of decedents and persons participating in funeral services, vehicles used solely to provide free transportation services for customers of the business establishment owning said vehicles, and rental or leased vehicles which rental or lease does not include a chauffeur; provided, however, that no vehicle excluded under this definition shall be used on a for-hire basis except as authorized by this chapter.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>PTRD means the Passenger Transportation Regulatory Division.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Solicit means an appeal by bell, horn, whistle, words or gestures for immediate patronage of a for-hire vehicle by a chauffeur or his agent directed at individuals or groups while the person making the appeal is upon the public way or public property, or the vehicle is parked, stopped, standing or moving up the public way or public property.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-15, ยง 5, 1-20-94)</history></law>