<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. GENERAL REQUIREMENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-306</section_number>
<catch_line>Chauffeur's registration—Additional private school bus chauffeur requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003761</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-306. Chauffeur's registration—Additional private school bus chauffeur requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Each chauffeur shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Possess a license issued pursuant to the licensure requirements of Florida Statutes, Chapter 234 and Chapter 6A-3 of the Rules of the Department of Education, as may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Possess a valid American Red Cross Standard First Aid and personal safety course card or its equivalent.</section><section prefix='(b)'>(1) The language and testing requirements contained in Section 31-303(d)(2) shall apply to initial private school bus chauffeur applicants, except that said requirements shall not apply to private school bus chauffeur applicants whose primary language is other than English and who transport students who are fluent in the language spoken by the applicant. An initial applicant whose primary language is other than English and who transports students who are fluent in the language spoken by the applicant shall be issued a separate chauffeur registration; such an applicant shall be required to take and pass a separate examination which demonstrates the applicant's ability to communicate in English with emergency personnel in those situations described in this paragraph which pose immediate danger to the health and welfare of the student(s). Such examination shall only test the applicant's ability (1) to notify emergency personnel in the event of an accident, illness, fire, physical injury or trauma, and (2) to minimally describe in English the nature of the emergency. The examination shall consist of a series of hypothetical emergency situations where the applicant is required to identify and/or articulate certain phrases necessary to notify emergency personnel and describe the nature of the emergency.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each initial private school bus chauffeur applicant shall take the one-day course and pass the oral and written exam required in Section 31-303(d)(2) demonstrating the applicant's knowledge of Miami-Dade County, traffic regulations, defensive driving techniques and chauffeur responsibilities. Each renewal private school bus chauffeur applicant who, in the most recent two-year period, has been found guilty or pled guilty or nolo contendere to two (2) or more moving violations shall be also be required to take the one-day course and pass the oral and written exam required in Section 31-103(d)(2) demonstrating the applicant's knowledge of Miami-Dade County traffic regulations, defensive driving techniques and chauffeur responsibilities. For separate chauffeur registration applicants whose primary language is other than English and who transport students who are fluent in the language spoken by the applicant, said examination shall be administered in Spanish or Creole.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-15, § 5, 1-20-94; Ord. No. 94-139, § 2, 7-12-94: Ord. No. 95-02, § 1, 1-17-95)</history></law>