<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE LIMOUSINES.</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-604</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishing limousine rates.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003769</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-604. Establishing limousine rates.<section>Except as otherwise provided herein, the Commission shall establish minimum rates for luxury limousine sedan, stretch limousine, super-stretch limousines, antique limousines, ancient limousines and collectible limousines operating in Miami-Dade County. Such rates shall be established, altered, amended, revised, increased, or decreased in accordance with the following procedures:<section prefix='(1)'>The CSD, at two-year intervals or upon request of the Commission or the County Manager, shall investigate and prepare a report concerning the existing rates for luxury sedans, ancient limousines, antique limousines, collectible limousines, stretch, and super stretch limousines. Said investigation shall specify the relative changes in the consumer price index over the preceding two-year period and shall quantify what the rates would be if the currently approved minimum limousine rates were adjusted for such change. Such investigation may also consider the financial records of the industry to determine revenues or expenses when requested by the Commission or County Manager.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The CSD's report shall be forwarded to the County Manager who shall prepare a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A public hearing concerning rates shall be scheduled at which time all interested parties shall have an opportunity to be heard. The Commission shall consider the CSD's report, the County Manager's recommendation, and all evidence produced at the hearing and, by resolution, shall determine and set the appropriate rates as may be in the public interest; provided, however, limousine minimum rates shall be no less than three and one-third (3) times the hourly rate of taxicabs.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-139, ยง 1, 11-14-00)</history></law>