<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE LIMOUSINES.</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-613</section_number>
<catch_line>Special provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003778</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-613. Special provisions.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive regulations applicable to the provision of and operation of for-hire motor vehicle transportation services in Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding the provisions of any municipal ordinance, resolution, or agreement to the contrary, from and after the effective date of this article, no municipality shall authorize, establish, change, alter, amend, or otherwise regulate for-hire transportation in Miami-Dade County. Regulations established by this article shall be uniform throughout Miami-Dade County both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries. All municipal ordinances or resolutions to the contrary are hereby superseded and rescinded.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this article, a stretch limousine license holder that has, as of October 1, 2003, been issued a current and valid permit to operate a vehicle that has been categorized by the automobile industry as a sports utility vehicle may continue to operate a sports utility vehicle pursuant to the for-hire license until October 1, 2006 provided that: 1) the stretch limousine license is maintained current and valid; 2) all permits issued pursuant to the for-hire license to operate a sports utility vehicle are continuously operated and maintained current and valid; 3) all sports utility vehicles operated pursuant to the for-hire license meet and comply with all other requirements for a luxury sedan, including, but not limited to, the vehicle standards, vehicle age requirements, inspection frequency and minimum rates for a luxury sedan; and 4) the permit is operated in compliance with the preceding provisions and all requirements of Chapter 31 of the Code. Any change in ownership of the license holder or failure to comply with applicable requirements shall result in automatic revocation of the permit and removal of the sports utility vehicle from service under the stretch for-hire limousine license. A for-hire license holder operating a sports utility vehicle pursuant to this subsection (b) shall not at any time operate any more sports utility vehicles than the number authorized as of October 1, 2003.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Temporary limousine licenses. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the County Manager may prescribe rules and regulations for the approval and issuance of temporary limousine licenses for Super Bowls, summits, political conventions and other major special events of national or international significance, such as nationally televised awards shows, where the event's organizers can demonstrate that the existing supply of limousines is not adequate to meet the needs of the event.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notwithstanding the vehicle age limits required by Section 31-609(b) of the Code, any properly permitted and inspected luxury limousine sedan, stretch limousine, or super-stretch limousine scheduled for retirement on December 31, 2012, shall be allowed to be operated for an additional one-year period.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 03-266, § 1, 12-8-03; Ord. No. 06-112, § 1, 7-6-06; Ord. No. 09-58, § 1, 6-30-09; Ord. No. 11-11, § 1, 3-1-11; Ord. No. 11-102, § 1, 12-19-11; Ord. No. 12-66, § 1, 9-6-12)</history></law>