<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE LIMOUSINES.</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-610</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement of article.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003775</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-610. Enforcement of article.<section prefix='(a)'>This article shall be enforced by authorized personnel of the CSD, the police forces of the various municipalities in Miami-Dade County, and by the Miami-Dade Police Department. When specifically authorized by the Director, this article may be enforced by personnel of the Seaport and Aviation Department when violations occur within their respective boundaries. The CSD shall prepare and distribute to all authorized enforcement personnel an enforcement manual outlining procedures for the detection, reporting, and issuance of citations or deficiency reports for violations of this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The CSD may employ a deficiency or warning system through which operators are given written notice of minor violations and a specified period of time to correct same. Unless otherwise provided, all other violations shall be processed under Chapter 8CC of the Code.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Deficiency reports and citations shall be issued to the party responsible for the violation as set forth in this article. Any person issued a deficiency report or a citation shall sign and accept said report or citation. Notice given to a chauffeur for a violation involving the vehicle under his control shall be deemed notice to the operator.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Whenever a corporation, partnership, or association violates any of the provisions of this article, such violation shall be deemed also to be that of the individual officers, directors, partners, or agents of such corporation who have personally authorized, personally ordered, or personally done any of the actions constituting in whole or in part such violation, and any such officer, director, partner, or agent may be fined in the same manner and to the same extent as herein provided for an individual.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the Director may secure enforcement of the provisions of this article by any legal action necessary, such as application to any court for injunctive relief or other appropriate relief.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-139, ยง 1, 11-14-00)</history></law>