<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE LIMOUSINES.</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-601</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003766</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-601. Definitions.<section>For the purposes of this article, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 or the ADA means the civil rights acts signed into law on July 26, 1990 as Public Law 101-336, 104 Stat. 327, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Applicant means an individual, partnership or corporation which applies for a for-hire license, permit, or chauffeur's registration, pursuant to the provisions of this article. "Applicant" shall also mean an individual, partnership or corporation which makes application, where applicable, to renew or transfer a for-hire license, permit or chauffeur's registration pursuant to the provisions of this article. In the case of partnerships and corporations, "applicant" shall also mean each individual with a partnership interest, each shareholder of the corporation as well as the corporate officers and directors.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Ancient limousine means a luxury motor vehicle as defined in section 320.086(1), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Antique limousine means an antique luxury motor vehicle as defined in section 320.086(2), Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Chauffeur means a duly licensed driver registered with and authorized by the Consumer Services Department to operate a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Chauffeur registration means a registration card issued by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Collectible limousine means a luxury motor vehicle of the age of twenty (20) or more years from the date of manufacture, equipped with an engine and parts of the age of twenty (20) years or more from the date of manufacture.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Commission means the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(i)'>County means Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(j)'>County Manager means the chief executive officer and head of the administrative branch of county government as provided in Article 3 of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(k)'>CSD means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Director means the CSD director or the director's designee.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Fares or Rates means the charges established pursuant to this article to be paid by passengers for the transportation services provided by a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(n)'>For compensation or compensation means for money, property, service, or anything of value, including tips and commissions.</section><section prefix='(o)'>For-hire means driving, operating, or managing a for-hire passenger motor vehicle, and includes all non-revenue producing operations of the passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(p)'>For-hire license means an annual, renewable license issued pursuant to this Article which authorizes the provision of for-hire transportation services and which may expire, be suspended or revoked.</section><section prefix='(q)'>For-hire passenger motor vehicle or limousine means any chauffeur-driven limousine as defined herein which engages in pre-arranged transportation of persons and their accompanying property for compensation over the public streets, but excluding ambulances and nonemergency medical transportation vehicles; vehicles used exclusively for the transportation of decedents and persons participating in funeral services; vehicles used solely to provide free transportation services for customers of the business establishment owning said vehicles; vehicles used solely to provide special transportation services for the Miami-Dade Transit Agency pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County; and rental or leased vehicles which rental or lease does not include a chauffeur; provided, however, that no vehicles excluded under this definition shall be used on a for-hire basis except as authorized by this article. Vehicles used to provide Miami-Dade Transit Agency special transportation services pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County are subject to the regulations contained in Article IV of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Good cause shall mean delay caused by circumstances beyond the control of the applicant.</section><section prefix='(s)'>In service means a for-hire vehicle which is displaying a valid, current operating permit or decal, as applicable, issued by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Lease of a limousine vehicle means a written agreement for the transfer from a lessor to a lessee of the right to possess and use a motor vehicle, meeting the requirements of Chapter 521, Florida Statutes, for a scheduled term exceeding four (4) months.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Limousine means a "luxury limousine sedan," a "stretch limousine," a "super-stretch limousine," an "ancient limousine," an "antique limousine," or a "collectible limousine" and which provides service on a pre-arranged basis only, which is dispatched by its central business location.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Luxury limousine sedan or luxury sedan means a luxury, non-metered vehicle of a wheelbase size smaller than a stretch limousine, as defined by CSD.</section><section prefix='(w)'>Operate means to provide transportation services for compensation regulated by this article utilizing a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(x)'>Operating permit means the valid and current vehicle decal issued to the license holder which authorizes a specific, registered vehicle to operate for-hire and which may expire, be suspended or revoked.</section><section prefix='(y)'>Operator means any person who has been issued a for-hire license.</section><section prefix='(z)'>Out of service means the removal of a for-hire vehicle from operation by removal of a valid, current operating permit and filing with the CSD a CSD form removing the vehicle from service.</section><section prefix='(aa)'>Own means a person who holds the legal title of a motor vehicle; or, in the event a motor vehicle is the subject of a security agreement or lease with an option to purchase with the debtor or lessee having the right to possession, then the debtor or lessee shall be deemed the owner.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>Pre-arranged or pre-arrange means a written or telephone reservation made at least one hour in advance by the person requesting service at the place of business of the for-hire license holder for the provision of limousine service for a specified period of time.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>Passenger means a person utilizing a for-hire limousine for the purpose of being transported to a destination, or a person who is awaiting the arrival of a prearranged for-hire limousine, and does not include the chauffeur.</section><section prefix='(dd)'>Person means any natural person(s), firm, partnership, association, corporation, or other business entity.</section><section prefix='(ee)'>Personnel authorized by the CSD means uniformed enforcement personnel and any other individual authorized by the director.</section><section prefix='(ff)'>Place of business means the specific Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County address where management of for-hire operations is provided and which is zoned for the appropriate business usage and matches the address on a current valid occupational license.</section><section prefix='(gg)'>Solicit means an appeal by bell, horn, whistle, words or gestures by a chauffeur or his or her agent directed at individuals or groups.</section><section prefix='(hh)'>Stage means to stop, park, or otherwise place a limousine vehicle in the loading or curbside area of a hotel, restaurant, shopping center, public sports facility, museum, theater, performing arts center or transportation facility when the limousine vehicle is not engaged in a prearranged, round trip or one way fare. A curbside or loading area shall not include a parking lot.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Street means any public street, avenue, road, boulevard, alley, lane, highway, sidewalk, public park, viaduct, or other public place accessible to the public, located in Miami-Dade County and used by motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(jj)'>Stretch limousine means a sedan cut and stretched a minimum of forty-two (42) inches beyond its standard basis, manufactured to carry between six to eight (6—8) persons, excluding the driver.</section><section prefix='(kk)'>Super-stretch limousine means a luxury vehicle, as defined by CSD, stretched a minimum of one hundred twenty (120) inches beyond its standard basis and manufactured to carry nine (9) or more passengers, including the driver.</section><section prefix='(ll)'>Trade name or doing business as or (d/b/a) name means the county-approved name under which the for-hire license holder may provide for-hire passenger motor vehicle transportation services, and which name shall not duplicate the name of any other license holder.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 03-266, § 1, 12-8-03)</history></law>