<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE LIMOUSINES.</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-609</section_number>
<catch_line>Vehicle standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003774</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-609. Vehicle standards.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to the applicable Federal Motor Vehicle Safety requirements in 49 Code of Federal Regulations, part 571, and Florida Statutes, the following vehicle standards shall apply to all for-hire motor vehicles operated under the provisions of this article. It is the operator's responsibility to insure that each vehicle meets the following standards and minimum inspection requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Brakes within allowable parameters as provided by test equipment readings for stopping effectiveness. There shall be no leaks in lines, hoses, fittings, or parts; hoses shall not be cracked or frayed; there shall be no audible air leaks in air brake system.</section><section prefix='(2)'>License, permit or inspection decals, as applicable, shall be correctly displayed and be clearly visible from the outside of the vehicle;<section prefix='(a)'>Chauffeur registration, operating permit number, rate card, passenger advisory, and any additional information as may be required shall be displayed within the vehicle in accordance with the instructions of the CSD.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Exterior vehicle signage and markings shall be as required by the CSD.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Inside rear-view mirror and a mirror on each side of vehicle.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A functioning speedometer and odometer indicating speed in miles per hour and a functioning odometer indicating distance in miles.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Functioning windows, door handles, and latches. The primary and secondary hood/trunk/rear access door latches shall be fully operable.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A functioning interior light within the passenger compartment. If the light becomes defective, the operator must correct the defect on the very next day or remove the vehicle from service at that time.</section><section prefix='(7)'>An operating air-conditioning system that provides cooled and heated air. If the air-conditioning system becomes inoperable, the vehicle must be removed from service until such system is repaired. Maximum output temperature will be based on a sliding scale chart which takes outside air temperature and relative humidity into account. Output temperature will be taken at center duct with controls set for maximum cooling.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The vehicle exterior must be free of grime, oil, or other substances and free from cracks, breaks, dents and damaged paint that detracts from the overall appearance of the vehicle and that could harm, injure, soil, or impair the passenger or his or her personal belongings.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Equipped with hubcaps or wheel covers, on all four (4) wheels. If not on the vehicle, the operator must put them on the vehicle the next day.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Bumpers/mouldings/guards shall be installed/replaced as originally manufactured except for moldings on side panel doors.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The interior of the trunk, or rear portion of for-hire vehicles, shall be free from dirt, grime, oil, trash, or other material which could soil items placed therein and free of protruding metal or other objects that could damage items placed therein.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The passenger compartment must be clean, free from torn upholstery or floor coverings, damaged or broken seats, and protruding sharp edges. All equipment in the interior of the vehicle shall be safely and adequately secured. There shall be no holes opening to the passenger compartment from the underbody.</section><section prefix='(13)'>A horn which shall be audible.</section><section prefix='(14)'>The driver's vision must be unobstructed on all four (4) sides.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Safe tires no recaps shall be used. Maximum allowable treadwear shall be where tread is level with wear bar, or  inches when measured at three random places in tire tread. The tires shall be inflated to manufacturer's specifications and free of cuts, cracks, bulges or exposed belts.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Front-end and rear-end alignment shall be within allowable parameters as provided by test equipment readings for alignment.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Wiper blades must be able to clean glass when wet and the rubber element shall not be torn, ripped, or loose.</section><section prefix='(18)'>All lights shall be operable including four-way flasher, turn and signal, clearance, warning, marker, brakes, taillight, license plate, backup, and parking light. All lights must be of correct color and properly positioned as required by Florida Statutes and regulations. All dome lights must be operable with lens in place.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Reflectors and lenses shall not be cracked or missing and must be of correct color and properly positioned.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Both low and high beam headlights shall be operable, and within test equipment allowable readings.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Glass shall not be broken or cracked and chips must be capable of being ground out, leaving a smooth, clear finish.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Doors shall be operable with all weather stripping and rubber seals.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Vehicle steering and suspension shall be functional.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Seat belts for all persons transported shall be in place and functional, unless otherwise exempted by regulation.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Limousines shall not display the word(s) "taxicab," "taxi," or "cab" on the vehicle exterior or interior and shall not be equipped with a taximeter.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Vehicle age limits and inspection schedules. Vehicle age limits and frequency of for-hire vehicle inspections are as follows; provided however, that the CSD may inspect a for-hire vehicle at any time:<section prefix='(1)'>Luxury limousine sedans. No luxury limousine sedan initially placed into service shall be older than two (2) model years of age. No luxury limousine sedan that exceeds five (5) model years of age shall be inspected or operated.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Stretch limousines. No stretch limousine initially placed into service shall be older than two (2) model years of age. No stretch limousine that exceeds five (5) model years of age shall be inspected or operated; provided, however, that a luxury sedan vehicle that is either a fifteen (15) or greater model year Rolls Royce, Packard or Mercedes-Benz that has been stretched a minimum of forty-two (42) inches may be operated beyond five (5) model years as long as the vehicle meets the inspection requirements of the Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Super-stretch limousines. No super-stretch limousine initially placed into service shall be older than two (2) model years of age. No super-stretch limousine that exceeds seven (7) model years of age shall be inspected or operated; provided, however, that a luxury sedan vehicle that is either a fifteen (15) or greater model year Rolls Royce, Packard or Mercedes-Benz that has been stretched a minimum of one hundred twenty (120) inches may be operated beyond seven (7) model years as long as the vehicle meets the inspection requirements of the Code.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The limousine vehicle age requirements will be effective one year after adoption of this article. Notwithstanding the vehicle age limits required by Section 31-609(b)(1), (2) and (3) of the Code, no luxury limousine sedan, stretch limousine or super-stretch limousine initially placed into service during 2011 or 2012 shall be older than three (3) model years of age.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Ancient, antique, or collectible limousines are exempt from the vehicle age requirements of this article.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Limousines shall minimally meet the following inspection schedule:<section prefix='(i)'>Limousines one (1) through two (2) model years of age shall be inspected annually;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Limousines three (3) through four (4) model years of age shall be inspected semi-annually;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Limousines five (5) model years of age or more shall be inspected quarterly; provided, however, that ancient or antique limousines shall be inspected semi-annually.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Inspection fees. The CSD shall charge non-refundable fees for inspection and re-inspection of any for-hire vehicle for compliance with the vehicle standards and requirements of this subsection. Inspection results shall be recorded and a copy provided. Any vehicle failing to meet any required vehicle safety standard shall not be operated until it passes a re-inspection.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Display of information identifying vehicle number and company. The operating permit number, fares, or rates, for-hire license holder's name, and business telephone number shall be permanently displayed in the interior of the vehicle in accordance with instructions issued by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Telecommunication devices. Limousines shall be equipped with a two-way radio or cellular telephone.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Vehicles operated pursuant to a luxury limousine sedan license shall be either entirely silver, black, navy or white.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-139, ยง 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 11-77, ยง 2, 10-4-11; Ord. No. 12-66, ยง 1, 9-6-12)</history></law>