<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE LIMOUSINES.</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-602</section_number>
<catch_line>For-hire limousine licenses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003767</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-602. For-hire limousine licenses.<section prefix='(a)'>Prohibition against unauthorized operations. It shall be unlawful for any person to use, drive, or operate or to advertise in any newspaper, airwaves transmission, telephone directory, or other medium accessible to the public that it offers for-hire limousine services or to cause or permit any other person to use, drive, or operate any for-hire limousine vehicle upon the streets of Miami-Dade County without first obtaining a Miami-Dade County for-hire license and maintaining it current and valid pursuant to the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Out-of County origin exception. Nothing in this article shall be construed to prohibit discharge within Miami-Dade County of any passenger lawfully picked up in another County and lawfully transported into Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, (1) Any passenger lawfully picked up in another county, transported to, and discharged at any location within Miami-Dade County, may be picked up at the discharge location and returned to the county of origin as long as the transportation is part of a pre-arranged, round-trip fare pursuant to a written contract, the limousine has complied with all of the regulatory requirements of the other county and the county where the passenger is picked up has adopted a similar provision; and (2) A limousine from another county may pick up a passenger at either the Miami International Airport (MIA) or the Miami-Dade Seaport (Seaport) and transport said passenger directly to the limousine's county of origin as long as the transportation is part of a pre-arranged one-way continuous fare pursuant to a written contract, the passenger arrived at either the MIA or the Seaport, the limousine has complied with all of the regulatory requirements of the other county and the county where the passenger is picked up has adopted a similar provision. Pre-arranged means a written or telephone reservation made at least one hour in advance by the person requesting service at the place of business of the for-hire license holder for the provision of limousine service for a specified period of time. Any limousine that picks up or discharges passengers at either the MIA or the Seaport shall meet the MIA and the Seaport limousine requirements. A copy of the contract shall be in the possession of the chauffeur at all times and shall be made available to enforcement personnel upon request.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Application procedures. Every initial application for a for-hire license, renewal application, transfer, or amendment to a for-hire license shall be in writing, signed and sworn to by the applicant, and shall be filed with the CSD together with an investigative and processing fee which shall be nonrefundable. If the applicant is a corporation, the form shall be signed and sworn to by the president or vice-president, and the corporate secretary shall attest such signature and affix the corporate seal. If the applicant is a partnership, the form shall be signed and sworn to by a general partner. The application shall be on a form provided by the CSD and shall contain all information required thereon, including:<section prefix='(1)'>Sufficient information to identify the applicant, including but not limited to full legal name, and trade name, date of birth, telephone number, and residence address, of the applicant. If the applicant is a corporation, the foregoing information shall be provided for each officer, resident agent, director, and stockholder. If the applicant is a partnership, the foregoing information shall be provided for each partner. As part of such application, the applicant shall also disclose the foregoing information for any person who has any interest (legal, equitable, beneficial or otherwise) in the license. Post office box addresses will not be accepted hereunder. All corporate or partnership applicants shall be organized or qualified to do business under the laws of Florida and shall have a place of business in either Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The class or classes of transportation service which the applicant desires to furnish.<section prefix='(i)'>Limousine service:<section prefix='(a)'>Luxury limousine sedan;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Stretch limousine;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Super-stretch limousine;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Ancient limousine;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Antique limousine;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Collectible limousine.</section></section></section><section prefix='(3)'>A brief description of the kind(s) and type(s) of vehicles, seating capacity, seating arrangements, gross weight, mileage, and number of vehicles proposed to be used.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The names and addresses of at least three (3) residents of the County as references.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The trade name under which the applicant intends to operate and a description, where applicable, of a distinctive uniform and decorative color scheme including placement of numbers and other markings.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A record and proof of all present and prior transportation business activities of the applicant during the past five (5) years.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A record of all crimes to which the applicant has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, or of which the applicant has been found guilty or been convicted, whether or not adjudication has been withheld within the five (5) years preceding the date of the application. The applicant shall have his or her fingerprints and photograph taken by the Miami-Dade Police Department. In the case of a corporate or partnership applicant, this information shall be obtained from all corporate officers and directors or partners, as the case may be. In the case of corporations, the above information shall be obtained from stockholders who own, hold or control five (5) percent or more of the corporation's issued and outstanding stock.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Two (2) credit references including at least one bank where the applicant has an active account. In lieu of the second credit reference, the applicant may submit alternative written evidence of financial trustworthiness.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Where applicable, the contract disclosing the terms and conditions of the proposed transfer, including amount of compensation which has been paid or is payable to the transferor and any other consideration given or to be given to the transferor in connection with the transfer of the for-hire license.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A limousine management service plan which shall include:<section prefix='(a)'>Maintenance facilities and maintenance program for the upkeep of vehicles operating under the for-hire license.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A system for handling complaints, accidents and property left by a passenger in the for-hire motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A central place of business, with a properly listed telephone for receiving all calls relating to for-hire vehicle service and where the operator will maintain the business records and daily manifests as set forth in this article.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A driver training program which the applicant will utilize to ensure quality service.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A proposal for submission of appropriate insurance coverage as required by section 31-608 of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(11)'>A sworn statement signed by the applicant that all the information provided by the applicant is true and correct.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Any additional information as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Investigation of for-hire license applicants. The director shall investigate each application and accompanying required documents and reject any application that is not properly filed or that is incomplete or untrue in whole or in part. The director may approve or deny the issuance of for-hire licenses as specified in this chapter on such terms and conditions as the public interest may require. The director's decision to reject or to deny may be appealed in accordance with this chapter.</section><section>An applicant shall not be eligible for a for-hire license if he/she/it:<section prefix='(1)'>Has misrepresented or concealed a material fact on his, her, or its application;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Is an alien who is not duly authorized to work by the immigration laws or the Attorney General of the United States;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Is a user of alcohol or drugs whose current use would constitute a direct threat to property or the safety of others;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty or been convicted of a felony within the last five (5) years, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, unless his or her civil or residency rights have been restored;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty or been convicted of any crime wherein a for-hire vehicle was employed whether or not adjudication has been withheld;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Has pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty, or been convicted of any felony, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer under § 775.0823, Florida Statutes, or is a habitual violent felony offender under § 775.084, Florida Statutes;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Has violated any condition, limitation, or restriction of a for-hire license imposed by the director or commission where the director deems the violation to be grounds for denial;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the for-hire business or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Has as a stockholder, officer, director, or partner of a corporation or partnership committed an act or omission which would be cause for denying a for-hire license to the officer, director, stockholder, or partner as an individual;</section><section prefix='(10)'>Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation or any other lawful order of the director;</section><section prefix='(11)'>Does not have a place of business located in either Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County, Florida;</section><section prefix='(12)'>Has any unsatisfied civil penalty or judgment pertaining to for-hire operation;</section><section prefix='(13)'>Has had a for-hire license issued by Miami-Dade County revoked;</section><section prefix='(14)'>Has within the last five (5) years plead nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty, or been convicted of any misdemeanor, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, involving moral turpitude relating to sex; or</section><section prefix='(15)'>Has within the last ten (10) years pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, been found guilty, or been convicted, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, of any offense involving trafficking in narcotics. After said ten-year period, such a person shall only be eligible if and when his or her civil or residency rights have been restored.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Conditions for obtaining a for-hire license. No for-hire license shall be issued unless the applicant:<section prefix='(1)'>Has paid an initial or annual license fee;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Has provided an adequate management plan.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Has submitted proof of insurance required by this article;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Has ensured that the for-hire limousine to be operated under the applicant's for-hire license has passed all required vehicle inspections. Failure of the applicant to meet all of the foregoing requirements within forty-five (45) days after notification of conditional approval shall cause the license not to be issued. If the applicant believes he, she or it cannot meet the foregoing requirements within the forty-five-day period, the applicant may, prior to expiration of such forty-five-day period, request in writing a reasonable extension from the director. If the request states good cause for an extension, the director may grant such a reasonable extension as the director finds is in the public interest.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Vehicles authorized to operate under a for-hire license.<section prefix='(1)'>Except for luxury limousine sedans, limousines shall be solely owned or leased by the for-hire license holder. Under no circumstances shall a limousine license holder require a chauffeur to purchase or lease a limousine motor vehicle. This requirement shall become effective one (1) year after the adoption of this article when a new vehicle is placed into service as provided by Section 31-609(b).</section><section prefix='(2)'>The number of vehicles authorized to operate under for-hire license are as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Luxury limousine sedan for-hire license holders shall operate only one vehicle per for-hire license.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Stretch, super-stretch, ancient, antique, or collectible limousine license holders may operate more than one vehicle per license, after each such vehicle has obtained a valid and current operating permit.</section></section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Issuance and replacement of for-hire license.<section prefix='(1)'>Issuance. Each for-hire license shall be on a form developed by the CSD and shall be signed by the director. Each for-hire license shall, at a minimum, contain the name and the business address of the license holder, date of issuance, its expiration date and such additional terms, conditions, provisions, and limitations as were imposed during the approval process.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Replacement. The director may issue a replacement license to any license holder upon application, payment of a nonrefundable replacement fee and presentation of proof or a sworn affidavit that the license has been lost or stolen.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Expiration of and renewal process for for-hire license. For-hire licenses may be issued for such periods as specified in the Administrative Order establishing the fees. The CSD may establish staggered license terms to ease administration of the renewal process. Each renewal shall be submitted no less than thirty (30) days prior to expiration of the current initial or annual for-hire license together with payment of a license fee. As part of the renewal process, the original application shall be updated and verified by the applicant on forms supplied by the CSD. The director shall deny any renewal application that is not timely, is not properly filed, is incomplete, is untrue in whole or in part, or results in a determination by the director that the applicant has failed to satisfy the requirements of subsection 31-602(c), (d) or (e). Renewal applications shall additionally include disclosure of all interests in the for-hire license (legal, beneficial, equitable or otherwise) and a sworn statement as to the number of months which each permitted for-hire vehicle operated during the preceding license year. Appeal of the denial of a renewal application shall be in accordance with this chapter.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Grace period. License holders shall have a grace period of up to thirty (30) days after expiration of their license in which to renew same provided, however, that all operations shall cease on the date of license expiration and the license holder shall also pay a late fee over and above the annual license fee. All for-hire licenses which have not been renewed on or before thirty (30) days after their expiration shall automatically be deemed revoked.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Rules pertaining to change in control of the for-hire license. Except as provided in Section 31-602(n), no for-hire license shall be assigned, transferred, or sold (either outright or under a conditional sales contract). Except as provided in Section 31-602(n), any change in the ownership structure of a corporation or partnership where at least five (5) percent of the shares of said corporation or at least five (5) percent of the partnership interest is assigned, sold or transferred to another shall be deemed a sale and shall immediately terminate the license and a new for-hire license application shall be filed. The for-hire transportation service may continue to operate provided that such application has been filed with the CSD within thirty (30) days of the change in accordance with Section 31-602 and be accompanied by an investigatory and processing fee.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Rules of operation. For-hire license holders shall abide by all rules and regulations applicable to for-hire license holders and shall be subject to the enforcement provisions contained in this chapter and chapter 8CC of the Miami-Dade County Code. A for-hire license holder shall comply with the following regulations:<section prefix='(1)'>Every operator shall collect and file on a daily basis all manifests and trip sheets for each for-hire limousine. The operator shall furnish the forms for each manifest to the chauffeur, which forms shall be approved by the County. Operators shall not destroy, mutilate, alter, or otherwise deface any daily manifests without CSD approval. All manifests shall be available for inspection and copying by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours and shall be retained for one (1) year;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Shall maintain a record of all requests for service for each passenger transport request received by telephone or made in writing or pursuant to a corporate charge account which shall minimally include the following information: name of passenger or corporation requesting service, assigned vehicle number, date and time of service request, service provision, including charge accounts, and origin and destination of each trip. All records must be made available for inspection and copying within one business day of such request by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours and shall be retained for one (1) year;</section><section prefix='(3)'>No for-hire license holder, chauffeur, or any other person shall directly or indirectly provide compensation in any form to any individual or entity or engage in any activity in connection with the payment of compensation, for the right to pick up passengers, or provide limousine service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, or any other business establishment, or public facility. The license or registration of any for-hire license holder, or chauffeur violating this provision shall be subject to suspension for up to six (6) months and/or revocation in accordance with the provisions of Section 31-612 or other appropriate enforcement action as provided in this chapter;</section><section prefix='(4)'>It shall be a violation of this article for any individual or entity to accept compensation in any form, either directly or indirectly, from any passenger service company, for-hire license holder, chauffeur, or any other person for the right to pick up passengers or provide limousine service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, or any other business establishment or public facility;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Each operator shall maintain accurate records of all revenues, all associated expenses, capital expenditures, and other financial and operating information as may be required by the CSD. The revenue records shall include charge account contracts that reflect rates charged to all passengers. The CSD shall be granted access to these records for the purpose of inspection and copying same upon five (5) days prior notice. All such records and information shall be confidential except that they will become public records for the purpose of rate hearings, revocation or suspension hearings. Each operator shall annually furnish financial and operating information to the CSD on forms and in the manner prescribed by the CSD;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Shall maintain a log of all customer complaints;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Shall maintain quarterly vehicle accident records for all vehicles operated in the prior quarter;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Shall hold any personal property deposited in the lost and found facility for a period of six (6) months, at the end of which time the personal property shall become the property of the finder. A record of personal property reported to or deposited at the lost and found facility shall be kept for at least one (1) year;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Comply with applicable federal law, Florida law, and ordinances, rules and regulations of the County applicable to the operation of for-hire vehicles;</section><section prefix='(10)'>Immediately report any change of address;</section><section prefix='(11)'>Maintain all records pertaining to the for-hire operations of a vehicle at the place of business for one year and make same available for inspection during the regular business hours of the license holder. When requested by the CSD, the license holder shall provide copies of the records;</section><section prefix='(12)'>Obtain the operating permit for each for-hire vehicle operated pursuant to authority of the for-hire license and pay all application and vehicle inspection fees;</section><section prefix='(13)'>Not permit or authorize any chauffeur or other person to operate any for-hire vehicle without that vehicle's current valid operating permit being displayed therein;</section><section prefix='(14)'>Not allow any person to operate a for-hire vehicle who is not a Miami-Dade County registered chauffeur;</section><section prefix='(15)'>Not allow or permit any person to operate a for-hire vehicle without current, valid, and sufficient insurance coverage as required in this chapter;</section><section prefix='(16)'>Register and have inspected by CSD all vehicles to be placed into service and all vehicles taken out of service;</section><section prefix='(17)'>Not permit or authorize anyone to drive any for-hire vehicle unless the brakes, steering mechanism, tires, horn, windshield wipers, side and rearview mirrors, and all lighting devices are in good working order, and the vehicle meets all other applicable vehicle standards as set forth in this chapter;</section><section prefix='(18)'>Not allow or permit any person to operate a for-hire vehicle while his or her ability or alertness is so impaired or so likely to become impaired through fatigue, illness, or any other cause, as to make it unsafe for the chauffeur to begin or continue to drive the for-hire vehicle;</section><section prefix='(19)'>Not refuse or neglect to transport or to dispatch to or from any place in the county any orderly person requesting service. Every deaf or hard of hearing person, totally or partially blind person, or physically disabled person shall have the right to be accompanied by a service animal specially trained for the purpose, without being required to pay an extra charge for the service animal;</section><section prefix='(20)'>A limousine for-hire license holder shall be prohibited from leasing a for-hire license to another person or entity, or requiring that a chauffeur pay any amount of compensation for the right to operate the vehicle authorized by the for-hire license;</section><section prefix='(21)'>A limousine for-hire license holder shall, except as provided herein, be prohibited from entering into a written agreement with an existing for-hire limousine license holder or passenger service company as defined in Article II. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a luxury sedan limousine license holder who has been issued three (3) or less luxury sedan limousine licenses may enter into a written agreement with an existing for-hire limousine license holder or passenger service company for the provision of the following services as stated in Section 31-602(c)(10). Under no circumstances shall an existing for-hire limousine license holder or passenger service company require a sedan limousine license holder to purchase any services or goods others than those stated in Section 31-602(c)(10);</section><section prefix='(22)'>Not allow a driver to solicit or pick up passengers other than by prearrangement through a person located at the limousine license holder's place of business;</section><section prefix='(23)'>Disclose to the customer if a vehicle substitution is necessary and provide the customer with an opportunity to cancel a contract based thereon;</section><section prefix='(24)'>Not allow a driver to stage;</section><section prefix='(25)'>A holder of a luxury limousine sedan license, or stretch limousine license, or super stretch limousine license shall provide limousine services with not more than ten (10) percent of the limousine service provided being paid for in cash;</section><section prefix='(26)'>A holder of an ancient, antique or collectible limousine license shall provide limousine service with not more than fifty (50) percent of the limousine service provided being paid for in cash.</section></section><section prefix='(l)'>Responsibility for violations of chapter. The holder of a for-hire license shall be held responsible for any applicable violation of this article arising from the operation of the for-hire vehicle authorized under the holder's for-hire license and shall be subject to the penalties provided in this chapter for any such violation. In addition, his, her, or its license shall be subject to suspension or revocation for any such violation. Charges against or penalties imposed on a for-hire license holder or for-hire chauffeur for the same or related violations shall not relieve the for-hire license holder of responsibility under this article.</section><section prefix='(m)'>As part of the annual renewal of a for-hire license, each operator shall certify on a form provided by the CSD the number of months during the preceding year that he, she, it operated and provided the service authorized by the for-hire license. Failure to operate for at least nine (9) months during the preceding year shall result in automatic revocation of such license. Operations within the thirty-day grace period provided in subsection (i) shall not be counted for purposes of determining compliance with the requirements of the two (2) preceding sentences.</section><section prefix='(n)'>No for-hire limousine luxury sedan license shall be assigned, sold, (either outright or under a conditional sales contract) or transferred without prior County approval. Any change in the ownership structure of a corporation or partnership where at least five (5) percent of the shares of said corporation or at least five (5) percent of the partnership interest is assigned, sold or transferred to another shall be deemed a sale for the purposes of this section. The Director is authorized to approve assignments, sales, or transfers when requested by submission of an application (which discloses the information specified in and is signed and sworn to in accordance with the requirements of subsections (c) and (d) of this section) and payment of a transfer investigative and processing fee and after an investigation and determination, based on the criteria set forth in this section. An assignee, buyer, or transferee shall not begin operating the limousine luxury sedan license during the pendency of the application approval process. If the County approves an application to assign, sell, or transfer a limousine luxury sedan license, the assignor's, seller's, or transferor's limousine luxury sedan license shall be suspended until the County reissues the limousine luxury sedan licenses to the assignee, buyer, or transferee. Provided, however, that the County shall reissue the limousine luxury sedan licenses to the assignee, buyer, or transferee at a cost not to exceed the annual, limousine luxury sedan license renewal fee. Any limousine luxury sedan license issued pursuant to Section 31-603(c)(ii)—(v) shall not be assigned, sold or transferred for a period of five (5) years from the date of issuance, except upon: (1) the sale of the luxury sedan license holder's business within the five-year period; (2) the sale of shares or the corporation or partnership as provided in this subsection; or (3) the transfer of all for-hire luxury sedan licenses by an individual to a person as defined in Section 31-601. No transfer shall be approved that results in a license holder holding or controlling more than thirty (30) percent of the total number of luxury limousine sedan licenses issued by the County. Appeals of the Director's decision shall be made pursuant to the requirements of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(o)'>It shall be unlawful to operate any vehicle as a for-hire motor vehicle without first having obtained a for-hire license and an operating permit specifically relating to said vehicle. The for-hire operating permit shall, at all times, be displayed within the vehicle and shall be available for inspection by any police officer or authorized agent of the CSD.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Conversion of super-stretch limousine certificates of transportation to a limousine for-hire license. Within ninety (90) days after the date of enactment of this article, super-stretch limousine certificate of transportation license holders shall obtain a stretch or super-stretch limousine for-hire license and corresponding operating permit for each vehicle operated thereunder. Such permits shall be obtained pursuant to the provisions of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Rules for existing for-hire limousine licenses. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, any person who converts an existing for-hire limousine license after the date of adoption of this article pursuant to Section 31-603(c)(i) and is providing luxury limousine service may lease the luxury limousine sedan license to a person who meets the requirements of Section 31-602(c) and (d), including payment of the application and investigatory fee, until such license is assigned, sold or transferred as provided in Section 31-602(n).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 09-26, § 1, 4-7-09)</history></law>