<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-76</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibition against compensation for right to pick-up passengers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003706</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-76. Prohibition against compensation for right to pick-up passengers.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any passenger service company, for-hire license holder, chauffeur or operator of any passenger vehicle for hire or any other person directly or indirectly to provide compensation in any form to any individual or entity or engage in any activity in connection with the payment of compensation for the right to pick up passengers or provide for-hire passenger service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, school, hospital, convalescent home, medical clinic or any other business establishment, or public facility. The license, registration or certificate of any passenger service company, for-hire license holder, chauffeur or operator of any passenger vehicle for hire violating this provision shall be subject to suspension up to twelve (12) months for the first violation and shall be subject to revocation for repeat violations in accordance with the provisions of the Code.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be a violation of this article for any individual or entity to accept compensation in any form, either directly or indirectly, from any passenger service company, for-hire license holder, chauffeur or operator of any passenger vehicle for hire or any other person for the right to pick up passengers or provide for-hire passenger service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, school, hospital, convalescent home, medical clinic or any other business establishment or public facility.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-08, ยง 1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 07-149, ยง 1, 10-2-07)</history></law>