<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-88</section_number>
<catch_line>Insurance requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003715</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-88. Insurance requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>No for-hire motor vehicle shall be permitted to operate without the license holder or entity providing passenger services having first obtained and filed with the CSD a certificate of insurance on forms provided by the CSD for each for-hire motor vehicle showing the federal vehicle identification number, a vehicle description and the for-hire license number, and shall list the for-hire license holder, each chauffeur the entity providing passenger services allows to operate the vehicle, the passenger service company, where applicable, and the owner of the vehicle as insureds under an automobile liability insurance policy with limits of liability no less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) per person, and one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) per occurrence for bodily injury, and twenty thousand dollars ($20,000) per occurrence for property damage. Additionally, the certificate of insurance shall specify coverage for complete 24-hour vehicle operations for all drivers who have a Miami-Dade County chauffeur's registration, regardless of where operated or whether engaged in for-hire operations, and shall state the limits of automobile liability and property damage coverage. Failure to provide current certificates of insurance or to maintain appropriate insurance coverage for each for-hire vehicle shall be grounds for revocation of that vehicle's for-hire license.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Scope of insurance. The insurance required in this section shall be issued by an insurer that is a member of the Florida Insurance Guaranty Association. Insurance coverage shall be for a policy term of at least six (6) months. Nothing in the insurance policy or declaration shall permit binders, deductibles, self-insurance or any provision requiring the insured to reimburse the insurance company for claims.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each automobile liability insurance policy shall be endorsed to provide for thirty (30) days' notice by registered mail to the CSD of any material change, cancellation, or expiration. No policy will be accepted for a shorter period than six (6) months.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Unless an operator furnishes the CSD with satisfactory evidence of the required insurance coverage prior to the expiration of the thirty (30) days' notice specified in subsection (c) of this section, or upon a third notice of cancellation within twelve (12) months, the for-hire license shall be suspended forthwith by the Director and surrendered to the CSD pending a hearing to determine whether said for-hire license should be revoked. This automatic suspension requirement will not pertain to a for-hire motor vehicle when its insurer withdraws from Florida and cancels its policies, or when the policy is canceled through no fault of the operator.</section><section prefix='(e)'>From and after one hundred twenty (120) days after the effective date of this section [June 2, 1989], all operators shall comply with the amended requirements of this section.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Examination of Insurance Policy. The CSD reserves the right to require submission of a certified copy of or to examine the original policies of insurance including but not limited to endorsements, amendments, exclusions, riders, any additional contracts between the insured and the insurer and applications to confirm the existence of the required insured coverage.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 87-12, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 88-34, § 3, 5-3-88; Ord. No. 89-44, § 1, 5-23-89; Ord. No. 96-114, § 1, 7-16-96; Ord. No. 98-105, § 1, 7-9-98)</history></law>