<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-81</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003708</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-81. Definitions.<section>For the purposes of this article, the following definitions shall apply:</section><section prefix='(a)'>The ADA-defined area of Miami-Dade County means the complementary paratransit service area as required by the ADA or any federal regulations established pursuant to the ADA. The service area includes an area with a width of three-fourths (¾) of a mile on each side of Miami-Dade County's fixed bus routes and an area consisting of a circle with a radius of three-fourths (¾) of a mile around each Metrorail station.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 or the ADA means the civil rights acts signed into law on July 26, 1990 as Public Law 101-336, 104 Stat. 327, as the same may be amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Applicant means an individual, partnership or corporation which applies for a for-hire license, permit, chauffeur's registration, or a passenger service company registration pursuant to the provisions of this article. "Applicant" shall also mean an individual, partnership or corporation which makes application, where applicable, to renew or transfer a for-hire license, permit, chauffeur's registration or a passenger service company registration pursuant to the provisions of this article. In the case of partnerships and corporations, "applicant" shall also mean each individual with a partnership interest, each shareholder owning at least five (5) percent of the shares of the corporation as well as the corporate officers and directors.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Chauffeur means a duly licensed driver registered with and authorized by the Consumer Services Department to operate a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Chauffeur agreements means the CSD approved form agreements entered into by the chauffeur and the passenger service company and the chauffeur and the for-hire license holder prior to the provision of any for-hire service.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Chauffeur registration means a registration card issued by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Color scheme and markings mean a County-approved decorative vehicle exterior design to be utilized on each vehicle.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Commission means the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(i)'>County means Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(j)'>County Manager means the chief executive officer and head of the administrative branch of county government as provided in Article 3 of the Home Rule Charter of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(k)'>CSD means the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department</section><section prefix='(l)'>Director means the CSD director or the director's designee.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Dispatch means a communication via two-way radio or cellular telephone from a passenger service company to a taxi chauffeur to provide for-hire transportation to a passenger.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Fares or rates means the charges established pursuant to this article to be paid by passengers for the transportation services provided by a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(p)'>For compensation or compensation means for money, property, service or anything of value, including tips and commissions.</section><section prefix='(q)'>For-hire means driving, operating, or managing a for-hire passenger motor vehicle, and includes all non-revenue producing operations of the passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(r)'>For-hire license means an annual, renewable license issued pursuant to this Article which authorizes the provision of for-hire transportation services and which may expire, be suspended or revoked.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Passenger service company means a Florida corporation or partnership created for the purpose of providing passenger services for for-hire taxi operations and providing various services to for-hire license holder(s) and chauffeurs with whom the passenger service company has entered into passenger service agreements.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Passenger service company registration means an annual, renewable registration issued pursuant to this article which grants authority to provide passenger services for for-hire operations and which may expire, be suspended or revoked.</section><section prefix='(u)'>For-hire passenger motor vehicle or for-hire motor vehicle means any chauffeur-driven taxicab as defined herein which engages in the casual and nonrecurring transportation of persons and their accompanying property for compensation over the public streets, but excluding ambulances and nonemergency medical transportation of decedents and persons participating in funeral services, vehicles used solely to provide free transportation services for customers of the business establishment owning said vehicles, vehicles used solely to provide special transportation services for the Metro-Miami-Dade Transit Agency pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County, and rental or leased vehicles which rental or lease does not include a chauffeur; provided, however, that no vehicles excluded under this definition shall be used on a for-hire basis except as authorized by this article. Vehicles used to provide Metro-Miami-Dade Transit Agency special transportation services pursuant to a contract with Miami-Dade County are subject to the regulations contained in Article IV of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Good cause shall mean delay caused by circumstances beyond the control of the applicant.</section><section prefix='(w)'>In service means a for-hire vehicle which is displaying a valid, current operating permit or decal, as applicable, issued by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(x)'>Passenger service agreement means the CSD approved form agreement entered into by the for-hire license holder and the passenger service company prior to any for-hire operation.</section><section prefix='(y)'>MDTA means the Miami-Dade Transit Agency.</section><section prefix='(z)'>Medallion means a plate or decal issued by CSD as the physical evidence of a taxicab license which is affixed to the outside or inside of such taxicab.</section><section prefix='(aa)'>Medallion system means the system which deems a taxicab for-hire license to be intangible property.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>Off Duty means the periodic, temporary cessation of daily for-hire service indicated by a sign placed and visible on the vehicle's front windshield and which shall not be construed to alter the "in service" status of the for-hire vehicle. No for-hire vehicle in operation or awaiting passengers shall display an off-duty sign.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>Operate means to provide transportation services for compensation regulated by this article utilizing a for-hire passenger motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(dd)'>Operating permit means the valid and current vehicle decal issued to the license holder or passenger service company, when applicable, which authorizes a specific, registered vehicle to operate for-hire and which may expire, be suspended or revoked.</section><section prefix='(ee)'>Operator means any person who has been issued a for-hire license and her, his or its agent, where applicable, which shall be a passenger service company.</section><section prefix='(ff)'>Out of Service means the removal of a for-hire vehicle from operation by removal of a valid, current operating permit and filing with the CSD a CSD form removing the vehicle from service.</section><section prefix='(gg)'>Paratransit services means any transportation service provided for compensation to passengers with disabilities by motor carriers between specific origins and destinations selected by the individual user at a certain time that is agreed upon by the user and the service provider.</section><section prefix='(hh)'>Passenger means a person utilizing a for-hire vehicle for the purpose of being transported to a destination, or a person who is awaiting the arrival of a dispatched for-hire vehicle, and does not include the chauffeur.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Person means any natural person(s), firm, partnership, association, corporation, or other business entity.</section><section prefix='(jj)'>Personnel authorized by the CSD means uniformed enforcement personnel and any other individual authorized by the director.</section><section prefix='(kk)'>Place of business means the specific Miami-Dade County address where management of for-hire operations is provided and which is zoned for the appropriate business usage and matches the address on a current valid occupational license.</section><section prefix='(ll)'>Rate card means a card, issued by the CSD, which displays for-hire rates and such other data as the CSD may prescribe.</section><section prefix='(mm)'>Solicit means an appeal by bell, horn, whistle, words or gestures by a chauffeur or his or her agent directed at individuals or groups.</section><section prefix='(nn)'>Street means any public street, avenue, road, boulevard, alley, lane, highway, sidewalk, public park, viaduct or other public place accessible to the public, located in Miami-Dade County and used by motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(oo)'>Street hail means an immediate arrangement made on a street with a taxi chauffeur by a person seeking immediate transportation by taxi.</section><section prefix='(pp)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(qq)'>Taxicab means an eight (8) passenger or less, exclusive of chauffeur, for-hire passenger motor vehicle, which is not a limousine, with at least three (3) doors, designed, constructed, reconstructed and equipped as required in this chapter to provide either street hail or prearranged taxicab service, which is equipped with a taximeter, unless authorized to exclusively operate at a flat rate, and where the route and destination are controlled by the passenger.</section><section prefix='(rr)'>Taxicab stand means the county-approved location on a public right-of-way for awaiting employment which is specifically marked with a taxicab stand sign. "Taxicab stand" also means a location for awaiting employment authorized and provided by the owner of private property.</section><section prefix='(ss)'>Taximeter means any approved mechanical or electronic internally mounted device approved by the CSD and meeting all certifications, tolerances and other technical requirements for taximeters specified in the most recent edition of the National Bureau of Standards Handbook H. 44 published by the U.S. Department of Commerce which automatically records and indicates a charge or fare measured by distance traveled, waiting time, or other traditionally compensable activities or times of taxicab service.</section><section prefix='(tt)'>Trade name or doing business as or (d/b/a) name means the county-approved name under which the for-hire license holder and the passenger service company may provide for-hire passenger motor vehicle transportation services, and which name shall not duplicate the name of any other license holder or passenger service company.</section><section prefix='(uu)'>Two-way dispatch system means a communication system utilizing a two-way radio or cellular telephone by which a dispatcher may communicate with the chauffeurs of all taxicabs during all hours of vehicle operation and in which each for-hire vehicle is equipped with a two-way radio or cellular telephone.</section><section prefix='(vv)'>Waiting employment or awaiting employment means that the vehicle and chauffeur are available and are in proper condition, location, attendance so as to be hired for service.</section><section prefix='(ww)'>Paratransit passenger means an individual receiving paratransit services who has a physical or mental impairment as defined by the ADA that substantially limits one (1) or more of the major life activities of such individual, has a record of such impairment or has been regarded as having such an impairment.</section><section prefix='(xx)'>Accessible vehicle means a vehicle that has been significantly modified and specially equipped with the installation of lifts or other equipment necessary for the transport of disabled persons who use wheelchairs or wheelchair conveyances.</section><section prefix='(yy)'>Wheelchair means those wheeled devices, usable indoors, designed for and used by persons with mobility impairments which do not exceed 30 inches in width and 48 inches in length, measured 2 inches above the ground, and do not weigh more than 600 pounds when occupied.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 82-11, § 2, 2-18-82; Ord. No. 87-12, §§ 1, 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 88-124, § 1, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 91-130, § 1, 11-5-91; Ord. No. 95-221, § 2, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-105, § 1, 7-9-98; Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 03-45, § 1, 3-11-03)</history></law>