<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-85</section_number>
<catch_line>Rules for operation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003712</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-85. Rules for operation.<section prefix='(a)'>Each operator shall adopt and use, after approval by the CSD a uniform and decorative color scheme for all taxicabs licensed pursuant to this article which shall be yellow. The CSD shall refuse to approve any proposed color scheme which is not school bus yellow. License holders shall comply with the uniform color scheme at the time a new vehicle is placed into service. Failure to comply with this section shall be grounds for suspension of all for-hire licenses issued to the operator.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Taxicabs using any designated public stand shall be faced in accordance with applicable traffic regulations. The chauffeur of the taxicab at the head of such file shall accept as a passenger any orderly person who agrees to pay the proper fare; provided, however, that any person shall have the right to select any taxicab regardless of its position in the file. Upon the departure of any taxicab from said file, all vehicles entitled to use the stand shall move forward. No number of taxicabs greater than the maximum allowed shall attempt to use any public vehicle stand. Each waiting taxicab must take a position to the rear of taxicabs already at the stand. All taxicabs parked at any designated public vehicle stand shall be considered to be waiting employment.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Every operator shall fully comply with all ordinances, rules and regulations of the County and all statutes of the State of Florida applicable to the operation of for-hire motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Unless otherwise provided in this article, every operator shall collect and file on a daily basis all manifests and trip sheets for each for-hire motor vehicle. The operator shall furnish the forms for each manifest to the chauffeur, which forms shall be approved by the County. Operators shall not destroy, mutilate, alter or otherwise deface any daily manifests without CSD approval. All manifests shall be available for inspection and copying by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours and shall be retained for one (1) year.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Each operator shall maintain accurate records of all revenues, all associated expenses, capital expenditures, and other financial and operating information as may be required by the CSD. The CSD shall be granted access to these records for the purpose of inspection and copying same upon five (5) days' prior notice. All such records and information shall be confidential except that they will become public records for the purpose of rate hearings, revocation or suspension hearings, or, if required by the Board of County Commissioners, for the purpose of approving or disapproving applications for new for-hire licenses or transfers of for-hire licenses. Each operator shall annually furnish financial and operating information to the CSD on forms and in the manner prescribed by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Any for-hire motor vehicle not waiting employment or actually transporting paying passengers shall prominently display an out-of-service or off-duty sign.</section><section prefix='(j)'>No passenger service company, for-hire license holder, chauffeur or any other person shall directly or indirectly provide compensation in any form to any individual or entity or engage in any activity in connection with the payment of compensation for the right to pick up passengers or provide taxicab service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, or any other business establishment, or public facility. The license or registration of any passenger service company, for-hire license holder or chauffeur violating this provision shall be subject to suspension for up to twelve (12) months for the first violation and shall be subject to revocation for repeat violations in accordance with the provisions of Section 31-91 or other appropriate enforcement action as provided in this article.<section prefix='(2)'>It shall be a violation of this article for any individual or entity to accept compensation in any form, either directly or indirectly, from any passenger service company, for-hire license holder, chauffeur or any other person for the right to pick up passengers or provide taxicab service from any hotel, motel, apartment, restaurant, nightclub, bar, or any other business establishment or public facility.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>Reserved.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 81-29, § 2, 11-17-81; Ord. No. 81-130, § 1, 12-1-81; Ord. No. 87-12, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 98-105, § 1, 7-9-98; Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 07-149, § 1, 10-2-07)</history></law>