<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-84</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties of Consumer Services Department.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003711</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-84. Duties of Consumer Services Department.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to the duties and responsibilities specified in this article, the CSD shall be charged with the following duties and responsibilities:<section prefix='(1)'>Process, investigate and prepare all reports required by this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Investigate and prepare reports on alleged violations of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Enforce the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Attempt to resolve complaints received from any source concerning the industry.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Issue, deny, suspend and revoke all for-hire licenses, passenger service company registrations and chauffeurs' registrations pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, and maintain appropriate files regarding same.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Prepare and conduct or cause to be conducted a training, orientation and apprentice program for chauffeurs and a training and orientation for for-hire license holders and passenger service companies.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Develop and implement, in cooperation with the industry, service expansion and improvements.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Provide technical assistance to the industry.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Create and render technical assistance to a for-hire vehicle advisory group comprised of representatives from consumers, the industry, transportation-related interests, municipalities and public interest organizations.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Develop a standardized reporting technique for operators after consultation with a for-hire vehicle advisory group.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Assign an exclusive number to be displayed on each for-hire vehicle operating in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Provide a system to handle complaints of municipal officials relating to for-hire service within such municipalities and expedite the solution of same.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Perform any other functions assigned by the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Coordinate cooperative enforcement activities with municipalities, including implementing procedures for the disposition of fine revenues collected.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Prepare and implement, in coordination and after consultation with the industry, changes, amendments or modifications to administrative orders establishing fees pursuant to this article and provide the industry with at least ten (10) days notice prior to consideration of such changes, amendments or modifications by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Upon court order have closed and sealed unlicensed service provider establishments in accordance with this article.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Develop and implement a Taxicab Driver Incentive Program. The Driver Incentive Program shall be subject to approval of the Board of County Commissioners by resolution. The incentive program shall be developed to reward, among other things:<section prefix='(a)'>Driver courtesy and professionalism;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Customer service;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Knowledge of the community and historic landmarks;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Cleanliness of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>Professional attire.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director may propose and the County Manager may promulgate further rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this article, which rules and regulations, when approved by the Board of County Commissioners, shall have the force and effect of the law.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Except for the fees established by the County Manager and approved by the Commission for for-hire vehicles providing transportation of persons and their baggage from Miami International Airport and from the Port of Miami, whenever in this article a fee is charged or is required to be paid, the amount of such fee shall be established by administrative order of the county manager and approved by the commission. Such fees shall be deposited in a separate Miami-Dade County fund and shall be used exclusively to accomplish the regulatory purposes of this article. The amount of each fee established hereunder shall be reasonably related to the cost of the services and regulation provided therefor.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 82-114, § 1, 12-21-82; Ord. No. 87-12, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 88-118, § 2, 12-6-88; Ord. No. 88-126, § 1, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 98-105, § 1, 7-9-98)</history></law>