<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-87</section_number>
<catch_line>Rate regulation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003714</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-87. Rate regulation.<section prefix='(A)'>The provisions of this section shall be the exclusive method for the establishment of for-hire motor vehicle rates throughout Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding the provisions of any municipal ordinance, resolution or agreement to the contrary, from and after the effective date of this article, no municipality shall authorize, establish, change, alter, amend, or otherwise regulate rates charged by the industry. All municipal ordinances or resolutions to the contrary are hereby superseded.</section><section prefix='(B)'>It shall be unlawful for an operator or chauffeur to charge, demand, request or accept any fare other than the rates established pursuant to this article. Rates established by this article shall be applicable through Miami-Dade County, both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas, without regard to any municipal boundaries.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Except as otherwise provided herein, the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall establish all rates for taxicabs and for-hire vehicles operating in Miami-Dade County. From and after the effective date of this article, rates shall be established, altered, amended, revised, increased or decreased in accordance with the following procedures:<section prefix='(1)'>The CSD, upon request of the Commission or the County Manager, shall investigate and prepare a report concerning the existing rates. In the case of taxicab rates, said investigation shall specify the relative changes in the consumer price index over the preceding two-year period and shall quantify what rates would be if the currently approved uniform taxicab meter rates were adjusted for such change. Such investigation shall also consider any additional matters, or review of special service rates when requested by the Commission or Manager. For ratemaking purposes, the CSD will not consider any costs incurred in the acquisition of a license and political contributions. Costs which will be considered in rate studies will include vehicle operating, maintenance and repair expenses, salaries of drivers, dispatchers and supervisors, insurance costs, taxes and license fees, and administrative and general expenses as prescribed on CSD financial and operating report forms.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The CSD's report shall be forwarded to the County Manager who shall prepare a recommendation to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A public hearing concerning rates shall be scheduled. At such hearing, all interested parties shall have an opportunity to be heard. The Board of County Commissioners shall consider the CSD's report, the County Manager's recommendation, and all evidence produced at the hearing and, by resolution, shall determine and set the appropriate rates as may be in the public interest. Appeals of the Board of County Commissioners' decision shall be in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action.</section><section prefix='(4)'>As part of the rate-making procedure, the Board of County Commissioners may authorize special service rates such as shared rides, group rides, contract services, prearranged service, services to an identified segment of the population, flat rates for all licensed vehicles from one (1) point or area to another, or package delivery.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Operators who desire to provide service at a rate other than that established under the preceding provisions of this section may request approval of such special rates by filing an application with the CSD. Within forty-five (45) days after receipt of the request, the CSD shall conduct an administrative hearing on the proposed rate, after written notice to the public and all operators, investigate the proposed rate and forward its analysis and recommendations to the County Manager. The CSD shall, among other things, consider:<section prefix='(a)'>The effect of the proposed rate on increased public use of for-hire motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The ability of the operator to provide the proposed service.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The operator's ability to manage the proposed rates.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All information contained in the rate request application.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Improved transportation in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The economic impact on the industry and the general public.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>The Director shall be authorized to approve a per trip taxicab rate surcharge in addition to the existing rates then in effect. Such surcharge, which is to be a fixed amount, may be imposed upon the occurrence of an unforeseen change in petroleum market conditions which causes the price of regular unleaded gasoline to increase by 50 cents from the base price. The base price shall be the average price of regular unleaded gasoline in effect as of the most recent taximeter rate adjustment. Upon reaching the first benchmark dollar value a one dollar ($1.00) surcharge may be implemented. Following the initial surcharge, each additional increase of 50 cents of regular unleaded gasoline may trigger an increase in the dollar value of the surcharge by 50 cents. The average weekly price of regular unleaded gasoline must remain at or above a level, as described above, for three (3) consecutive weeks before a surcharge, or an increase in the surcharge, may be authorized by the Director. The fuel surcharge shall expire upon the effective date of any taximeter rate adjustments. The fuel surcharge may be decreased or removed, by the Director, should the average weekly price of regular unleaded gasoline remain at or below a level, as stated above, for three (3) consecutive weeks. The average price of regular unleaded gasoline shall be based on the retail prices listed for regular unleaded gasoline by the United States Department of Energy, Energy Information Administration. The surcharge may be added to the taximeter rate or flat fare rate and, if added, shall be reflected on the taximeter as an extra charge on vehicles so equipped. Notice of a surcharge approved pursuant to this section must be prominently displayed within the taxicab, as required by regulations promulgated by CSD.</section></section><section>The County Manager is authorized to approve proposed rates that result in lower fares being charged by operators. All other proposed rates must be reviewed and approved by the Commission.</section><section>Any approved special rates must be filed with the CSD and be posted in each for-hire motor vehicle of the operator for which said rate applies, and copies provided to anyone requesting same. All approved special rates may not be modified or altered without prior written approval of the County Manager, in the case of reductions, or the Commission, in the case of increases. An operator may eliminate special rate(s) by thirty (30) days' advance notice to the CSD and posting thirty (30) days' written notice of the changes in all vehicles.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 87-12, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 89-83, § 1, 9-12-89; Ord. No. 90-141, § 1, 12-6-90; Ord. No. 00-88, § 1, 7-6-00; Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 08-71, § 1, 6-3-08)</history></law>