<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-86</section_number>
<catch_line>Taximeters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003713</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-86. Taximeters.<section prefix='(a)'>Each taxicab shall be equipped with a taximeter meeting the requirements described in this article. All customer receipts, whether handwritten or generated by a taximeter, shall contain the fare charged, the name and telephone number of the passenger service company, the operating permit number and the telephone number for filing complaints with the CSD. It shall be a violation of this article for any operator or chauffeur to operate any taxicab unless and until its taximeter has been inspected and certified as operable and accurate by CSD and has affixed thereto a current valid taximeter certification label, sticker or decal.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each taxicab shall have its taximeter inspected before being placed in service and at least once every twelve (12) months thereafter. The CSD may require additional testing and inspection at any time. All taximeters passing inspection shall be sealed and a sticker placed thereon. The result of each taximeter test or inspection shall be recorded on forms provided by the CSD. A copy of the report will be provided to the operator. Taximeters with expired stickers or missing or broken seals shall be considered as failing inspection. The for-hire license of any taxicab whose taximeter fails inspection shall be automatically suspended without hearing until the taximeter has been repaired or replaced, and passed inspection.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The face of every taximeter shall at all times be visible from the taxicab's passenger compartment and shall be illuminated so passengers may ascertain the amount of fare registered by said taximeter.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No taxicab shall be operated unless the case of the taximeter installed therein has been sealed.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The signal affixed to any taximeter shall under no circumstances indicate that the taxicab is vacant when in fact such taxicab is engaged by a passenger.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The amount of fare collected from any passenger shall be that amount shown by the taximeter, unless the passenger is being transported at one (1) of the approved special service rates.</section><section prefix='(g)'>It shall be a violation of this article for any person to tamper with, mutilate or break any taximeter or the seal thereon. Taximeters may be transferred from one (1) taxicab to another; provided, however, that a taxicab with a transferred taximeter shall not be used to transport passengers unless and until said taximeter has been inspected, tested and sealed by the CSD.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, ยง 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 87-12, ยง 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 98-105, ยง 1, 7-9-98)</history></law>