<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-93</section_number>
<catch_line>Special provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003720</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 31-93. Special provisions.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive regulations applicable to the provision of and operation of for-hire motor vehicle transportation services in Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding the provisions of any municipal ordinance, resolution or agreement to the contrary, from and after the effective date of this article no municipality shall authorize, establish, change, alter, amend, or otherwise regulate for-hire transportation in Miami-Dade County. Regulations established by this article shall be uniform throughout Miami-Dade County both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries. All municipal ordinances or resolutions to the contrary are hereby superseded and rescinded.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any taxicab licensed pursuant to Section 31-82 of this article and meeting all standards set forth in Section 31-89 of this article shall be authorized to provide transportation of persons and their baggage from Miami International Airport and from the Port of Miami upon compliance with reasonable and nondiscriminatory terms, conditions and fees, as established by the County Manager. The transportation of persons and baggage from Miami International Airport or from the Port of Miami shall constitute an agreement by the operator that he will conform and cause the chauffeur driving such taxicab to conform to such terms, conditions, and fees.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Underserved taxicab service area.<section prefix='(1)'>An underserved taxicab service area is hereby established. For purposes of this subsection, an "underserved taxicab service area" means the economically disadvantaged area in Miami-Dade County that is bounded as follows:<section prefix='1.'>on the north by a line commencing at N.W. 47th Avenue and N.W. 215th Street running east to N.E. 2nd Avenue;</section><section prefix='2.'>on the east by a line commencing at N.W. 215th Street and running north to south along N.E. 2nd Avenue to N.W. 7th Street;</section><section prefix='3.'>on the south by a line commencing at N.E. 2nd Avenue and running west along 7th Street to N.W. 42nd Avenue; and</section><section prefix='4.'>on the west by a line commencing at N.W. 7th Street and N.W. 42nd Avenue north to N.W. 119th Street, west along N.W. 119th Street to N.W. 47th Avenue, north along 47th Avenue to N.W. 135th Street, west along 135th Street to N.W. 57th Avenue, north along 57th Avenue to N.W. 167th Street, east along N.W. 167th Street to N.W. 47th Avenue, north along 47th Avenue to N.W. 215th Street.</section><section>For purposes of this subsection, an "underserved area taxicab" means a taxicab where: (a) the for-hire license holder has entered into a passenger service company agreement with a passenger service company that has its principal place of business within the underserved taxicab service area; (b) an average minimum of seventy-five (75) percent of all pickups by the taxicab during each twenty-four hour period originate in the underserved taxicab service area; and (c) the for-hire license holder has applied for and been designated by the Director of CSD as an underserved area taxicab. Any for-hire license holder who seeks to be designated as an underserved area taxicab shall complete and submit a form provided by CSD documenting compliance with the provisions of this subsection for the three-month period preceding submission of the application. Each for-hire license holder authorized to operate as an underserved area taxicab shall on a semiannual basis submit on a form provided by CSD documentation demonstrating continuing compliance with the requirements of this subsection. Failure of the underserved area taxicab for-hire license holder to comply with any of the provisions of this subsection shall result in the suspension or revocation of authorization to operate as an underserved area taxicab. All taxicabs operated pursuant to this subsection that were, as of March 14, 2007, equipped with a properly installed and operating two-way dispatch system shall continue to utilize and maintain the two-way dispatch system which shall be operated twenty-four hours a day.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Underserved area for-hire taxicab licenses shall be issued through a separate lottery pursuant to Section 31-82(o)(3) to qualified chauffeurs who satisfy the criteria of Section 31-82 (q) and enter into a binding agreement with the County that contains, among others, the following provisions: (i) the chauffeur is restricted to picking up passengers in an underserved taxicab service area only; and (ii) the chauffeur shall enter into a passenger service company agreement with a passenger service company which has its principal place of business in an underserved taxicab service area. Any chauffeur issued a for-hire taxicab license pursuant to this subsection shall not transfer the taxicab license during the time periods specified in Section 31-82(q) of the Code. Any transfer of an underserved taxicab license shall only be made to a qualified chauffeur who meets the requirements of this subsection. The price for an underserved taxicab area for-hire license issued pursuant to a lottery shall be fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000.00).</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, a taxicab that satisfies the requirements of either subsection (c)(1) or (c)(2) shall meet the following vehicle age requirements: any vehicle initially placed into service shall not have been previously used as a taxicab and shall be no greater than eight (8) model years of age. Any vehicle over ten (10) years of age shall not be operated as a taxicab.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, a taxicab that satisfies the requirements of either subsection (c)(1) or (c)(2) may utilize a color scheme approved by the Director of CSD which does not satisfy the requirements of Section 31-85(a) pertaining to uniform color scheme.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>South Miami-Dade taxicab service area. A South Miami-Dade taxicab service area is hereby established. For purposes of this subsection, the South Miami-Dade taxicab service area means the area located south of S.W. 88 Street. South Miami-Dade taxicab service area for-hire taxicab licenses shall be issued through a separate lottery, pursuant to Section 31-82(o)(2), to qualified chauffeurs who satisfy the criteria of Section 31-82(q) and enter into a binding agreement with the County that the chauffeur is restricted to picking up passengers in the South Miami-Dade taxicab service area only. Any chauffeur issued a for-hire taxicab license pursuant to this subsection shall not transfer the taxicab license during the time periods specified in section 31-82(q) of this Code. Any transfer of a South Miami-Dade taxicab service area license shall only be made to a qualified chauffeur who meets the requirements of this subsection. The price for a South Miami-Dade taxicab service area for-hire license issued pursuant to a lottery shall be fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000.00). All taxicabs operated pursuant to this subsection that were, as of March 14, 2007, equipped with a properly installed and operating two-way dispatch system shall continue to utilize and maintain the two-way dispatch system which shall be operated twenty-four (24) hours a day.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding the vehicle age limits required by Sections 31-82(l)(4), 31-89(f) and 31-93(c)(3) of the Code, any properly permitted and inspected taxicab scheduled for retirement on December 31, 2012, shall be allowed to be operated for an additional one-year period.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, each for-hire license holder who has been issued a for-hire taxicab license prior to September 3, 2012, which is required to be operated using a taxicab in the underserved taxicab service area pursuant to Section 31-93(c) or the South Miami taxicab service area pursuant to Section 31-93(d) may convert that for-hire license into a license which may be operated in both the designated underserved area and countywide (hereinafter "hybrid underserved taxicab license" or "hybrid underserved taxicab") as provided herein. An underserved taxicab license may be converted into a hybrid underserved taxicab license upon payment of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00). A hybrid underserved taxicab license may be operated countywide on alternating days as follows. All hybrid underserved taxicabs whose license number ends in an odd number (i.e., 1, 3, 5, 7, 9) are required to pick up passengers exclusively in the designated underserved taxicab service area or South Miami taxicab service area, whichever is applicable, on odd-numbered days of the month. All hybrid underserved taxicabs whose license number ends in an even number (i.e., 0, 2, 4, 6, 8) are required to pick up passengers exclusively in the designated underserved taxicab service area or South Miami taxicab service area, whichever is applicable, on even-numbered days of the month. To "pick up passengers exclusively in the designated underserved taxicab service area or South Miami taxicab service area" means that such taxicabs may discharge passengers at any location, but may only accept passengers in the designated underserved taxicab service area. No hybrid underserved taxicab operating pursuant to this section may provide transportation of persons and their baggage from Miami International Airport.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 81-116, § 1, 10-26-81; Ord. No. 83-2, § 1, 1-18-83; Ord. No. 84-17, § 1, 2-2-84; Ord. No. 85-40, § 2, 6-6-85; Ord. No. 88-70, § 1, 7-19-88; Ord. No. 88-118, § 2, 12-6-88; Ord. No. 90-7, § 1, 2-6-90; Ord. No. 98-105, § 1, 7-9-98; Ord. No. 99-71, § 1, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 01-177, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 04-103, § 1, 5-11-04; Ord. No. 07-60, § 1, 4-24-07; Ord. No. 11-11, § 1, 3-1-11; Ord. No. 11-102, § 1, 12-19-11; Ord. No. 12-65, § 1, 9-6-12; Ord. No. 12-68, § 1, 9-6-12)</history></law>