<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. CROSS CONNECTION CONTROL PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-157</section_number>
<catch_line>Installation of backflow preventer.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003848</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-157. Installation of backflow preventer.<section prefix='(a)'>Water customers, at their own expense, shall prepare plans and shall obtain a permit for the required backflow preventer. For properties located in unincorporated Miami-Dade County, the Miami-Dade County Building Official shall review said plans and charge a fee in accordance with Administrative Order No. 4-63A, as may be modified from time to time, for the review of each backflow preventer and the issuance of a permit. In the case of fire suppression systems, the Miami-Dade Fire Rescue Department shall charge a fee in accordance with Administrative Order No. 4-45 to review and inspect each installation. The applicable municipal Building Official and municipal Fire Department may impose a similar fee for similar services. Permitting procedures and standard details shall be established and modified from time to time by means of agreements between and among applicable County, municipal and State agencies.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The backflow preventer installer must be a validly licensed contractor possessing a certificate of competency appropriate for the preventer type and location involved.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The backflow preventer shall be installed at the customer's expense on the customer's property immediately adjacent to the water meter serving that property. The customer shall provide adequate space for a backflow preventer on the customer's property. The backflow preventer shall be readily accessible for maintenance and testing. No part of it may be beneath the ground surface or submerged under water, and it must not be subject to flooding by a ten-year storm.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The installation shall be located at the front property line at one (1) side of the property in accordance with the Department's standard details. All backflow preventers that are installed where visible from an area accessible to the public shall be shielded from public view by a visual barrier as listed below:<section prefix='1)'>A barrier wall not more than six (6) inches above the highest point of the body of the assembly whereas the stems of the shutoff valves are visible from outside of the wall structure; or</section><section prefix='2)'>A recessed covered space which is part of the building envelope; or</section><section prefix='3)'>A manufactured cover for small diameter assemblies up to two (2) inches</section></section><section>Such barriers shall be at least two (2) feet apart from the backflow preventer and must not obstruct access for maintenance and testing. Existing backflow preventer installations, shall be exempt from the installation of a visual barrier. Additionally, any such barrier shall be a minimum of seven and one-half (7-½) feet apart from any fire department connection including, but not limited to siamese connections and post indicator valves. Said fire department appliances are to be installed in accordance with the Florida Fire Prevention Code, and NFPA standards 13 and 24.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Upon completion of the installation, satisfactory testing shall be performed as provided in Section 32-163(b). Testing requires a water shutdown usually lasting five (5) to thirty (30) minutes. For facilities that require an uninterrupted supply of water, and when it is not possible to provide water service from two (2) separate meters, provisions shall be made for a parallel installation of backflow preventers. The existence of any unprotected bypass around a backflow preventer when the apparatus is in need of testing, repair or replacement is unlawful.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The customer shall install plumbing lines of sufficient size to compensate for pressure losses which may result from operation of a backflow preventer. Provision must be made for thermal expansion.</section><section prefix='(g)'>It shall be unlawful for any water connections to exist between the water meter and the backflow preventer.</section><section prefix='(h)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to remove a backflow preventer from service without the express written consent of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, except for the purposes of replacement, as described in Section 32-164 (c). Unauthorized removal will be considered tampering, as described in Section 32-162 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-165, § 1, 12-7-99; Ord. No. 01-169, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 06-158, § 1, 10-24-06)</history></law>