<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. CROSS CONNECTION CONTROL PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-163</section_number>
<catch_line>Testing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003854</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-163. Testing.<section prefix='(a)'>Testing standards. All required tests of backflow preventers shall be accomplished in accordance with the procedures in the latest editions of Chapter 8 of AWWA Manual M14 and Section 9 of the University of Southern California's Manual of Cross-Connection Control.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Initial. All backflow preventers shall be installed under a plumbing, mechanical or fire permit obtained from the Building Official. The backflow preventer shall be tested by a certified backflow preventer tester as defined herein and certified as testing satisfactory prior to final plumbing approval being granted and prior to the installation of the permanent water meter. Where a permanent water meter is not yet installed, the certified tester shall obtain water for testing the backflow preventer cia a method approved by the Department.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Annual.<section prefix='(1)'>All backflow preventers must be tested annually to assure that they are performing satisfactorily by a certified backflow preventer tester.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The first annual testing of each backflow preventer installed subsequent to enactment of this article shall occur within twelve (12) months of installation.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Change of Occupancy or Ownership. Inspection of premises and satisfactory testing of an existing backflow preventer may be required before initiation of water service to a new customer or issuance of a new certificate of occupancy.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Deficiencies. If deficiencies are identified during any testing, the tester shall provide the water customer and the Department with a listing of the defects, on a form acceptable to the Department, within five (5) days of the test, which warns the customer that defects must be repaired within thirty-five (35) days of the Department's receipt of the report. Retesting shall be performed at or before the end of that period.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-165, ยง 1, 12-7-99; Ord. No. 06-158, ยง 1, 10-24-06)</history></law>