<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. CROSS CONNECTION CONTROL PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-156</section_number>
<catch_line>Technical requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003847</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-156. Technical requirements.<section>All approved backflow preventers shall conform to specifications set forth in the applicable building code and to rules and regulations promulgated by State agencies. The following specifications are adopted until and unless superseded:<section prefix='(a)'>Air Gap (AG) shall conform to ANSI/ASME standard A 112.1.2-1991.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All other preventers shall have satisfactorily passed a laboratory and field evaluation in accordance with the latest editions of either Section 10 of the ninth edition of the University of Southern California's Manual of Cross-Connection Control and been approved by the University of Southern California Foundation for Cross Connection Control and Hydraulic Research (USC-FCC & HR); or with ANSI/AWWA Standard C510-97 or C511-97. They are required to be testable in line.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Reduced Pressure Principal Backflow Prevention Assembly (RP) shall conform to ASSE Standard 1013 or ANSI/AWWA Standard C511-97.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Double Check Valve Assembly (DC) shall conform to ASSE Standard 1024 or ANSI/AWWA Standard C510-97.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Pressure Vacuum Breaker Assembly (PVB) shall conform to ANSI/ASSE Standard 1020-1990.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Double Check Detector Assembly (DCDA) shall conform to ANSI/ASSE Standard 1048-1995.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Reduced Pressure Detector Backflow Assembly (RPD) shall conform to ANSI/ASSE Standard 1047-1995.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Further specifications for backflow preventers and their installation, and additional and modified ones for specific purposes, may be provided in standard details and/or written specifications issued by the Department, in accord with standards adopted by the Florida Building Code and any regulations promulgated by State agencies.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-165, ยง 1, 12-7-99; Ord. No. 06-158, ยง 1, 10-24-06)</history></law>