<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAMPERING WITH UTILITY FIXTURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-128</section_number>
<catch_line>Consent agreements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003839</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-128. Consent agreements.<section>The Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, in the Director's or his designee's discretion, may terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this chapter upon execution of a written consent agreement between the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, and the persons who are the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance by said persons with the applicable provisions of this chapter. The consent agreement may, in the discretion of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, provide the following: Posting of a surety, bond, or other security to assure compliance; costs and expenses of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department for investigation, enforcement, testing, monitoring, and litigation, including attorneys' fees; civil penalties; remedial or corrective action. An executed written consent agreement shall not be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter. Such consent agreement shall not be deemed to impose a limitation upon any investigation or action of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, in the enforcement of this chapter. The consent agreement shall not constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State, or local laws and ordinances. Executed written consent agreements are hereby deemed to be lawful orders of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate offense under this chapter, by the persons who executed the consent agreement, their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees, and attorneys; and by those persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who receive actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-148, ยง 1, 10-19-99)</history></law>