<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAMPERING WITH UTILITY FIXTURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-121</section_number>
<catch_line>Tampering with utility fixtures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003832</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-121. Tampering with utility fixtures.<section prefix='(1)'>As used in this Section, "utility" means the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department.</section><section prefix='(2)'>It shall be unlawful for any person, without the written consent of the utility:<section prefix='(a)'>To alter, tamper or meddle with, injure, remove, bypass or otherwise hinder or disturb, or to cause, permit, suffer, let or allow to be altered, tampered or meddled with, injured, removed, bypassed or otherwise hindered or disturbed, any meters, meter seals, pipes, wire locks, lines, valves, mains, laterals, collectors, connections, interceptors, manholes, appliances, appurtenances or other apparatus or device used for or in connection with any water or sewer system belonging to the utility, in such a manner as to cause loss or damage or to prevent any meter installed for registering water from registering the quantity which otherwise would pass through the same; or to alter or break the wire lock or seal of any such meter; or in any way to hinder or interfere with the proper action or just registration of any such meter or device; or to use, waste, or suffer the waste, by any means, of water passing through any such meter, pipe, or fitting, or other appliance or appurtenance connected with or belonging to the utility, after such meter, pipe or fitting, or other appliance or appurtenance has been tampered with, injured, or altered; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>To make or cause, permit, suffer, let or allow to be made any connection with mains, service pipes or other pipes, appliances, or appurtenances in such manner as to use, without the written consent of the utility, any water, or to cause to be supplied any service, water or sewer, from the utility to any person, firm or corporation through any orifice, faucet or other outlet whatsoever, without such service being reported for payment or such water passing through a meter provided by the utility and used for measuring and registering the quantity of water passing through the same; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>To use or receive the direct benefit from the use of the utility knowing, or under such circumstances as would induce a reasonable person to believe, that such direct benefits have resulted from any tampering with, altering of, or injury to any connection, meter, pipe, conduit, line, meter seal, valve, main, wire lock, lateral, collector, interceptor, manhole or other apparatus or device owned, operated, or controlled by the utility, for the purpose of avoiding payment.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-148, ยง 1, 10-19-99)</history></law>