<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. CROSS CONNECTION CONTROL PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-158</section_number>
<catch_line>Exemptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003849</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-158. Exemptions.<section prefix='(a)'>Buildings of three (3) stories or less without booster pumps which contain only dwelling units (including single family residences, town homes, small apartment buildings), and all other structures or facilities not listed in Section 32-154, shall be exempt from the requirement of installation of a backflow preventer, provided that:<section prefix='(1)'>No cross-connections exist or are subsequently installed on the property;</section><section prefix='(2)'>No uses or facilities listed in Section 32-154 receive water through the same service connection; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any auxiliary water supply is not cross-connected.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Buildings of four (4) stories or more which contain only dwelling units (including condominium residences and apartment buildings) shall be exempt from the requirement of installation of a backflow preventer, provided that:<section prefix='(1)'>A certified plumber trained in cross-connection control conducts an annual inspection of the building's plumbing system to determine whether a cross-connection exists;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each inspection shall be reported to the Department within five (5) days of such inspection; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>If an inspection of the building indicates a cross-connection, such cross-connection shall be eliminated pursuant to the provisions of this section.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Exemptions from or exceptions to the Department's standard details may be granted by the applicable Building Official or his designee for installation of backflow preventers where physical limitations are present, provided that the preventer as installed is tested satisfactorily and certified.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-165, ยง 1, 12-7-99; Ord. No. 01-169, ยง 1, 10-23-01)</history></law>