<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. CROSS CONNECTION CONTROL PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-154</section_number>
<catch_line>Backflow preventers required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003844</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-154. Backflow preventers required.<section>Certain water customers of the Department shall install a backflow preventer as provided herein. Backflow preventers installed in the facilities listed in (c) and (d) below shall be tested by a certified backflow preventer tester.<section prefix='(a)'>Water customers who own or operate or use or engage in the types of businesses, facilities, substances, and activities listed in (c) or (d) below shall install an approved backflow preventer of the type indicated below at the service connection entering their property, within the deadlines listed herein. The same deadlines apply to installation of backflow preventers on Classes 3, 4 and 5 fire suppression systems, as defined in Section 32-155 serving the premises. New water customers who own or operate or use or engage in the types of businesses, facilities, substances, and activities listed in (c) or (d) below shall have an approved backflow preventer as a condition of issuance of building permits or of a certificate of occupancy, and the permanent installation of a water meter. This requirement is not limited to those facilities, premises, uses or situations listed herein but also applies to any others distinctly determined by the Department to require such protection. Failure to install a required backflow preventer as required herein, will result in civil penalties to be levied against the responsible party, pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County. In the event that the customer provides proof that a plumbing permit has been obtained from the applicable building department, and installs the required backflow preventer, within 90 days of notice of the violation, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department may choose to waive the applicable penalties.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event that the use of a property is changed to one listed in (c) or (d) below, and such property does not have a backflow preventer, the property owner must notify the Department of the new use and comply with this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Backflow preventers shall be installed by existing water customers in the following facilities by June 1, 2007.</section></section><section>* Abbreviations refer to types of preventers described in(j).</section><section>AG = Air gap</section><section>DC = Double check value</section><section>PVB = Pressure vacuum breaker</section><section>RP = Reduced pressure principle backflow preventer<section prefix='(d)'>Backflow preventers shall be installed by existing water customers in the following facilities by January 1, 2014:</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>When an addition is made to an existing building and the addition is twenty-five (25) percent or more of the area of the existing building, a water customer who owns, operates, uses or engages in a business, facility, substance or activity of a type listed in (c) or (d) above shall install an approved backflow preventer of the appropriate type. When repairs and alterations amounting to more than fifty (50) percent of the value of the existing building are made during any twelve (12) month period, a water customer who owns, operates, uses or engages in a business, facility, substance or activity of a type listed in (c) or (d) above shall install an approved backflow preventer of the appropriate type. The value of a building or structure shall be the estimated cost of constructing a new building of like size, design and materials at the site of the original structure, assuming such site to be clear. Cost of additions, alterations and repairs shall be construed as the total cost of labor, materials and services based on current prices for new materials.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All consecutive water systems (wholesale or volume customers) distributing the Department's potable water to their customers must have cross-connection control programs duly approved by their governing authorities, which are operated and maintained in accordance with Chapter 62-555.360, Florida Administrative Code. Any non-complying consecutive water systems may be required to install an approved backflow preventer assembly at the interconnection between the Department and the consecutive system. All consecutive water systems shall use reasonable good faith efforts to comply with the compliance dates specified in section 32-154</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-165, ยง 1, 12-7-99; Ord. No. 01-169, ยง 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 06-158, ยง 1, 10-24-06; Ord. No. 11-35, ยง 2, 6-7-11)</history></law>