<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAMPERING WITH UTILITY FIXTURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-124</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement; procedure; remedies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003835</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-124. Enforcement; procedure; remedies.<section prefix='(A)'>It is unlawful for any person to violate or to cause, permit, allow, let, or suffer any violation of: any of the provisions of this chapter; any lawful orders of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee; and consent agreements. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by this chapter, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, shall have the following judicial remedies:<section prefix='(1)'>To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of: Any of the provisions of this chapter; any lawful order of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department; or any consent agreement.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to impose and recover a civil penalty in an amount of not more than Twenty -Five Thousand Dollars ($25,000.00) for each violation of: Any of the provisions of this chapter; any lawful order of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee; or any consent agreement.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek restitution and other equitable relief to recover any sums expended and cost incurred for tracing, investigating, preventing, controlling, abating, or remedying violations of: This chapter, or any lawful order of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee; or any consent agreement.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to recover a monetary amount equal to three (3) times the amount of services unlawfully obtained or $1,000.00, whichever is greater. The Department may add damages and costs to enforce this Article which remain unpaid after sixty (60) days to the customer's bill and enforce a lien when and as authorized by Article VI of Chapter 32 of the County Code.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs or continues to occur constitutes a separate violation. The right of trial by jury shall be available in any court to determine both liability for and the amount of the civil penalty to be imposed and recovered hereunder.</section><section prefix='(C)'>In addition to a civil penalty or court award of damages, any violator shall be liable for the reasonable costs and expenses incurred by the County in enforcing the provisions of this Article, including but not limited to the labor and materials costs (including overhead and fringe benefits) of enforcement actions, inspections, preparation of enforcement reports, photographs, title searches, postage, court or hearing attendance time, and other demonstrable administrative costs for enforcement and collection. All such sums shall become delinquent if not paid within thirty days after receipt by the violator of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department's bill itemizing the costs incurred in enforcing the provisions of this Article, or after a hearing officer or court order become final (the "due date"). All such delinquent sums shall bear interest at the rate of twelve (12%) percent per annum after the due date. Any sums remaining unpaid after sixty (60) days shall be added to the customer's bill for services and the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department shall record and enforce liens as authorized by Article VI of Chapter 32 of the County Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-148, ยง 1, 10-19-99)</history></law>