<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAMPERING WITH UTILITY FIXTURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-127</section_number>
<catch_line>Attorneys' fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003838</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-127. Attorneys' fees.<section>Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this State against any person in favor of the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, to enforce any of the provisions of this chapter, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, prevails, the appellate court shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney who prosecuted the suit in which the recovery was had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all pending or prospective civil actions, legal or equitable, filed by the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, to enforce the provisions of this chapter. Cessation, correction or remediation of any violation of the provisions of this chapter, prior to rendition of a judgment or of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, to enforce the provisions of this chapter, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgement or verdict in favor of the Director of Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, for which attorneys' fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth herein above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-148, ยง 1, 10-19-99)</history></law>