<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAMPERING WITH UTILITY FIXTURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-122</section_number>
<catch_line>Strict liability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003833</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-122. Strict liability.<section prefix='(1)'>Whenever a violation of this chapter occurs or exists, any person, individually or otherwise who has a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the device or instrumentality causing or contributing to the violation or who has a legal, beneficial, or equitable interest in the real property which is receiving the benefit of the utility service shall be jointly and severally liable for said violation regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation. This provision shall be construed to impose joint and several liability regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation, upon all persons, individually or otherwise, who, although no longer having any such legal, beneficial or equitable interest in said device or instrumentality or real property, did have such an interest at any time during which such violation existed or occurred or continued to exist or to occur. This provision shall be liberally construed and shall be retroactively applied to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and to accomplish the purposes of this Article. provided, however, that no owner of rental property shall be held liable under this section unless the County notifies, in accordance with Section 32-122(2) of the Miami-Dade County Code, said owner of the County's intent to impose liability.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notice to Owners of Tampering at Rental Property<section prefix='(a)'>No citation, order, or action issued or filed pursuant to this Section arising out of tampering at any rental property shall be effective against the owner of said rental property unless that owner is first given notice of the County's intent to issue such citation, order, or action. Said notice shall be by certified mail, with return receipt requested, to the owner of the rental property as shown on the tax records of Miami-Dade County and shall be issued no less than thirty (30) days prior to the issuance or filing of any citation, order, or action pursuant to this Section against such owner. Said notice shall be deemed given upon mailing of said notice by the County, whether or not said notice is received.<section>Notwithstanding the foregoing, water and sewer service shall not be provided to the rental property until the citation, action, or order is resolved.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event that a citation, action, or order is or has been filed or issued pursuant to any provision hereof against a tenant or other person using or occupying a rental property other than the owner of such property as listed on the tax records of Miami-Dade County, the County shall provide a reference to this earlier citation, action, or order in the notice to owners specified in this section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When used herein, the term "rental property" shall include any property, including a single family home, which is used or occupied, in whole or in part, by any person other than the owner of said property as shown on the tax records of Miami-Dade County, pursuant to a rental agreement, either written or oral, between the owner and a tenant</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-148, ยง 1, 10-19-99; Ord. No. 04-93, ยง 1, 5-11-04)</history></law>