<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. SECURITY AT MIAMI-DADE WATER AND SEWER DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-173</section_number>
<catch_line>Administrative Review procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003864</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-173. Administrative Review procedure.<section prefix='32-173.1'>Administrative review. Any person, including the County, aggrieved with any action or inaction by the Director and/or the Department, may file a written request with the County Manager within ten (10) days of the action or inaction. Such person shall be entitled to an appeal before a hearing examiner assigned by the County Manager or his designee from a list supplied by the American Arbitration Association. Such hearing examiners may be paid a fee for their services but shall not be deemed County officers or employees within the purview of Sections 2-10.2, 2-11.1 or otherwise. The hearing examiner shall conduct a hearing after notice and shall transmit his findings of facts, conclusions, and any recommendations together with a transcript of all evidence taken before him and all exhibits received by him, to the Manager who may sustain, reverse or modify the action at issue. Such hearings shall be conducted insofar as is practicable in accordance with the rules of civil procedure governing the procedure in the Circuit Court, except as may be provided in this Code or by rules adopted by the Board of County Commissioners. Any interested party may procure the attendance of witnesses and the production of records at such hearings in the manner provided by Section 2-50. Any person appearing before a hearing examiner under the provisions of this section has the right, at his own expense, to be accompanied, represented and advised by counsel or other qualified representative. (Counsel shall mean a member of the Florida Bar).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-68, ยง 1, 4-23-02)</history></law>