<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TAMPERING WITH UTILITY FIXTURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-125</section_number>
<catch_line>Authority to issue lawful orders.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003836</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-125. Authority to issue lawful orders.<section prefix='(A)'>Whenever evidence has been obtained or received establishing that a violation of this chapter has been committed, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department or the Director's designee, shall issue a notice to correct the violation or a citation to cease the violation and cause the same to be served upon the violator and/or the property owner of the place where the violation occurred by personal service or certified mail or by posting in a conspicuous place on the premises where the violation occurred. Such notice or citation shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation and specify a reasonable time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped, commensurate with the circumstances. Reasonable time herein means the shortest practicable time to rectify or stop the violation. If notice to correct the violation or citation to cease the violation is not obeyed within the time set forth therein, the Director or the Director's designee, shall have the power and authority to issue any lawful orders to enforce the provisions of this chapter. Any orders issued by the Director or the Director's designee may be enforced by suit brought by him in the appropriate court of competent jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Whenever a violation of this chapter has been committed, the Director or the Director's designee may initiate proceedings against the violator in the appropriate court for such violation, whether or not a notice to correct the violation or citation to cease the violation has been issued.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-148, ยง 1, 10-19-99)</history></law>