<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. CROSS CONNECTION CONTROL PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-152</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003842</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-152. Definitions.<section>The following definitions shall apply in this Article:<section prefix='(a)'>Approved backflow preventer shall mean a backflow preventer as defined herein that is approved by the Department in accordance with applicable State and local regulations including the Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(b)'>ANSI shall mean American National Standards Institute, Inc., 1430 Broadway, New York, N.Y. 10018.</section><section prefix='(c)'>ASME shall mean American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 345 E. 47 St., New York, N.Y. 10017.</section><section prefix='(d)'>ASSE shall mean American Society of Sanitary Engineering, 28901 Clemens Rd., Westlake, Ohio 41445.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Auxiliary water supply shall mean any water supply on or available to the premises other than the public potable water supply. Auxiliary water supplies include, but are not limited to, another provider's potable water supply; a private water supply such as a well for domestic, irrigation or fire flow purposes; natural source(s) such as a spring, lake, river, stream, canal or ocean; used water; reclaimed water; and industrial fluids.</section><section prefix='(f)'>AWWA Manual M14 3rd Ed. shall mean American Water Works Association Manual of Water Supply Practices "Recommended Procedure for Backflow Prevention and Cross-Connection Control", as amended.</section><section prefix='(g)'>AWWA shall mean the American Water Works Association, 6666 W. Quincy Ave., Denver, Colorado 80235.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Backflow shall mean the reversal of flow of water or inflow of other substances into a potable water distribution system through a cross-connection. Backflow may degrade the quality of the potable water below required standards.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Backpressure shall mean any elevation of pressure in the downstream piping system above the supply pressure at the point of consideration, which could cause a reversal of the normal direction of flow.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Backflow preventer shall mean a mechanical assembly or device or means that prohibits backflow into a potable water system. Only the following types may be approved:<section prefix='(1)'>Air gap separation (AG) shall mean unobstructed vertical physical separation between the free-flowing discharge end of a potable water supply pipeline and the flood level rim of an open or non-pressure receiving vessel. An approved air gap separation shall be at least double the diameter of the supply pipe measured vertically above the top of the rim of the vessel. In no case shall an air gap separation be less than one (1) inch.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Double check detector assembly (DCDA) shall mean a specially designed assembly composed of a line-size approved double check valve assembly with a bypass containing a specific water meter and an approved double check valve assembly. The meter shall register accurately for only very low rates of flow up to three (3) gallons per minute (gpm) and shall show a registration for all rates of flow. The DCDA is used only on fire systems.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Double check valve assembly (DC) shall mean an assembly composed of two (2) single, independently acting approved check valves, including tightly closing resilient seated shutoff valves located at each end of the assembly, and fitting with properly located resilient seated test cocks suitable for testing the water tightness of each check valve. A check valve is a valve that is drip-tight in the normal direction of flow when the inlet pressure is one (1) psi and the outlet pressure is zero. The check valve shall permit no leakage in a direction reverse to the normal flow. The closure element (e.g., clapper) shall be internally weighted or otherwise internally loaded to promote rapid and positive closure. This assembly shall be used only to protect against a nonhealth hazard.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Pressure vacuum breaker (PVB) shall mean an assembly consisting of an independently operating internally loaded check valve and an independently operating loaded air inlet valve located on the discharge side of the check valve, with properly located resilient-seated test cocks and tightly closing resilient-seated shutoff valves attached at each end. The PVB prevents backsiphonage, but it is not effective, and should not be used, in backpressure conditions.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Reduced pressure detector assembly (RPDA) shall mean a specially designed assembly composed of a line-size approved reduced pressure principle backflow prevention assembly with a bypass containing a specific water meter and an approved reduced pressure principle backflow preventer. The meter shall register accurately for only very low rates of flow up to three (3) gpm and shall show a registration for all rates of flow. The RPDA is used only on fire systems.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Reduced pressure principle backflow preventer (RP) shall mean an assembly containing within its structure a minimum of two (2) independently acting approved check valves, together with an automatically operating pressure differential relief valve located between the two (2) check valves. The first check valve reduces the supply pressure by a predetermined amount so that during normal flow and at cessation of normal flow the pressure between the checks shall be less than the supply pressure. In case of leakage of either check valve, the differential relief valve, by discharging to the atmosphere, shall operate to maintain the pressure between the checks less than the supply pressure. These units are equipped with tightly closing resilient seated shut-off valves located at each end of the assembly, and with properly located resilient seated test cocks.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>Backsiphonage shall mean a form of backflow due to a reduction in system pressure which causes a subatmospheric pressure to exist at a site in the water system.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Building Official shall mean that official designated by the appointing authority, as defined in the Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Certified backflow preventer tester shall mean a person who has satisfactorily completed a nationally recognized backflow preventer testing training program that meets or exceeds any existing Florida Department of Environmental Protection (FDEP) standards or that is determined by Miami-Dade County to meet the requirements of the latest edition of AWWA M14 Manual. After satisfactorily completing a backflow preventer testing training program, as described above, the person shall be required to pass a written examination administered under the direction of Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board (CTQB). All testers are required to be re-certified by Miami-Dade County CTQB every two years. Backflow preventer testers who are currently certified as of the date of the ordinance from which this subsection derives will be permitted to test backflow preventers in Miami-Dade County until such time as the Miami-Dade County exam is first administered or until the existing certification expires whichever occurs later, but not to exceed two (2) years. In no event shall the training institute also serve as an examiner for the Miami-Dade County test. Code inspector shall have the meaning and powers defined in Section 8CC-3 of the County Code.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Cross connection shall mean any temporary or permanent physical connection or arrangement between a public water system and any other system or source through which it is possible, given pressure differentials, for any substance other than potable water to flow into the public water system.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Department shall mean the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, including its director, employees, agents, designees, and successors.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Existing water customer shall mean a water customer as defined herein for which a water meter is installed and operating on or before January 1, 2002.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Florida Fire Prevention Code shall mean rule 69A-60 Florida Administrative Code.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Industrial fluid shall mean any fluid or solution which is intended to be or has been used in or results from activities of manufacture, production, fabrication, repair, packaging, processing or sale of goods or services or growing of agricultural crops or for fire suppression purposes. This may include, but is not limited to: polluted used waters; polluted auxiliary water; all types of process waters; chemicals in fluid form, including pesticides and fertilizers; fuels and oils; acids and alkalies; circulated cooling waters connected to an open cooling tower and/or cooling waters that are chemically or biologically treated or stabilized with toxic substances.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Internal isolation shall mean fixture isolation and/or isolation of an area or zone within a customer's premises, downstream of the service connection. Fixture isolation means installing an approved backflow preventer at the source of the potential contamination. Area or zone isolation is confining the potential source of contamination within a specific area.</section><section prefix='(t)'>NFPA shall mean National Fire Protection Association, Quincy, Massachusetts.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Nonhealth hazard shall mean substances which, although not dangerous to health, may impart offensive solids, color, odor or taste to the public water supply.</section><section prefix='(v)'>New water customer shall mean a water customer, as defined herein, who applies for the provision of water service after January 1, 2002.</section><section prefix='(w)'>Reclaimed water shall mean waste water which has received at least secondary treatment and basic disinfection and is approved for reuse in compliance with regulations of State agencies.</section><section prefix='(x)'>Service connection shall mean the terminal end of water delivery from the public water system, that is, where the utility loses jurisdiction and sanitary control over the water at its juncture with the customer's water system. If a meter is installed at the end of the service connection, then the service connection shall mean the downstream end of the meter. Service connection shall also include water service connection from a fire hydrant and all other temporary or emergency water service connections from the potable water system.</section><section prefix='(y)'>State agencies shall mean the Department of Environmental Protection, the Department of Health, the State Fire Marshal, their successors, and any other instrumentality of the State of Florida charged under provisions of Part VI of Chapter 403, Florida Statutes or other statute or regulation with testing, inspecting, certifying, enforcing, or otherwise assuring compliance with environmental, health and safety standards, especially those for safe drinking water.</section><section prefix='(z)'>Tampering shall mean dismantling, removal, or rendering ineffective after installation, testing and certification, except in order to effect an approved replacement.</section><section prefix='(aa)'>Used water shall mean any water supplied to a customer's water system after it has passed through the service connection.</section><section prefix='(ab)'>Water customer shall mean any individual, municipality, corporation, partnership, firm, association or other entity receiving water service from the Department for consumption or usage within its premises or for resale to ultimate consumers.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-165, ยง 1, 12-7-99; Ord. No. 01-169, ยง 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 06-158, ยง 1, 10-24-06)</history></law>