<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. CROSS CONNECTION CONTROL PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-160</section_number>
<catch_line>Access required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003851</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-160. Access required.<section prefix='(a)'>Any code inspector, certified backflow preventer tester, or authorized representative of the Department, at any reasonable time upon reasonable notice and presentation of proper credentials, and upon consent by the property owner or person in charge of the property, building or place, may enter, monitor, sample, test, and inspect, as often as may be necessary, any structure, property, premises, building or place, public or private, residential or nonresidential within the water distribution system of the Department, for the purpose of assuring that no cross connections exist and that approved backflow preventers are in place where required. This right of access includes the right to effect any emergency actions necessary, including but not limited to disconnecting water service. Inspections of the facilities listed in Section 32-154, which pose the greatest potential hazard to the public water supply, are deemed to be a public necessity.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall refuse reasonable entry or access to the duly authorized representative who requests entry for any of the purposes set forth in (a) above and who presents appropriate credentials identifying himself.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall obstruct, hamper, or interfere with any such inspection, entry, monitoring, testing, or sampling.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An inspection, entry, monitoring, testing and sampling, pursuant to this section may be conducted only after:<section prefix='(1)'>Consent for the entry, inspection, testing, monitoring and sampling is received from the owner or person in charge of the property, building, premises or place; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>An inspection warrant as provided in this section or by law is obtained.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>An inspection warrant is authorized by this article and may be issued by a judge of any County Court or Circuit Court of this State which has jurisdiction of the place or thing to be searched.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Department Director or his designee is hereby authorized and empowered to obtain all search or inspection warrants reasonable and necessary to carry out the responsibilities, powers and duties set forth in this article, in accordance with the requirements of the Constitutions of the United States of America and the State of Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-165, ยง 1, 12-7-99)</history></law>