<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CERTIFICATES OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-35</section_number>
<catch_line>Contents of certificates; expiration date; construction.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003795</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-35. Contents of certificates; expiration date; construction.<section prefix='(a)'>Each certificate of public convenience and necessity issued hereunder for new or existing systems shall contain the name of the public utility to which it is issued, its principal place of business, the nature of the service authorized, and the specific territory or service area in which the public utility is authorized to operate, construct, maintain, repair, remove, or extend lines, facilities or equipment for the supply or distribution of water and the collection and disposal of sewage under, on, over or across, and along any public roads, streets or highways, for the purpose of constructing or operating a water or sewer system. Each certificate shall contain adequate, uniform provisions:<section prefix='(1)'>To prevent the creation of any obstruction or conditions which are or may become dangerous to the traveling public.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To require the licensee under said certificate to repair any damage or injury to the road or highway or street by reason of the exercise of the privileges granted in said certificate and to repair said road or highway or street promptly, restoring the same to a condition at least equal to that which existed immediately prior to the infliction of such damage or injury.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Whereby the licensee under said certificate shall hold the Board and its members, and the County harmless from the payment of any compensation or damages resulting from the exercise of the privileges granted in said certificate.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To require that, in the event of widening or repair or reconstruction of any such road or highway or street, the public utility under such certificate shall move or remove such water or sewerage lines at no cost to the County.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To require such additional uniform undertakings as may be reasonably necessary for the protection of the County and the public.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Each certificate issued in accordance with the provisions of this chapter shall remain in force and effect until terminated, revoked, or cancelled, upon due notice and hearing, in accordance with the provisions herein contained.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Subject to the limitations contained in this chapter, the certificate shall be construed as vesting in the lawful holder thereof the exclusive right or privilege to operate and serve such certificate. However, no certificate shall be construed as a franchise or to confer any vested property right upon the holder thereof, nor to deny the right of the Board to cancel, terminate or revoke a certificate and grant another certificate to another public utility to render the same type or class of service within the same territory, if the public convenience and necessity and the public interest require it, after due notice and public hearing. The Board may adopt and prescribe rules and regulations governing maps or sketches and the legal descriptions delineating service areas which each holder of a certificate is authorized to serve, to the end that such maps, sketches and descriptions shall be uniform and standardized.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, ยง 9, 7-5-60)</history></law>