<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CERTIFICATES OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-42</section_number>
<catch_line>Transfer of certificate.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003802</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-42. Transfer of certificate.<section prefix='(a)'>Approval of Board required. No certificate issued pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be sold, in whole or in part, assigned, or transferred by the holder to another, until the same has been approved and authorized by the Board as herein provided. The provisions of this section shall be applicable to municipally owned or operated water and sewer systems.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Application for approval of transfer. When any such certificate is proposed to be sold, assigned, or transferred, all of the parties, nominal and actual, to such transaction shall jointly file an application with the Board, in such form as may be prescribed by said Board, and shall set forth, among other things, the details of the transaction, specifying the consideration and the method of payment, the date such transaction is desired to be consummated, a financial statement of the transferee, the certificate authority, if any, held by said transferee under this chapter, the franchise authority, if any, held by the transferee, and any other pertinent facts. Such application shall be accompanied by a fee of one hundred dollars ($100.00). In such application the proposed transferee shall agree to pay all taxes, assessments, and obligations which may be due or owing to the State, County, and any other political subdivision of the State or County, by the transferor to the date of the entry of the order by the Board approving the transfer, as a condition precedent to such approval.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notice of filing applications. Upon the filing of an application for approval of the transfer of a certificate the Board shall issue and serve by mail, upon all parties entitled to notice of hearing on application for certificate to commence construction or operation of a new system, a written notice which shall contain the general pertinent facts of such application. Said notice shall require any objections or protests to such transfer to be filed in writing with the Board, by a date to be fixed in such notice. Any objection or protest filed shall state fully the basis therefor. In the event no such written protest is filed with the Board within the time fixed in such notice, then and in that event, the Board may consider said application and act upon the same as an ex parte matter without the necessity of public hearing, and for the purpose of such consideration, the Board may require either, or both, of the parties to such proposed transfer to appear before it for the purpose of giving testimony, or to produce any such records or information as the Board may direct and find necessary to consider in passing upon said application.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Public hearing on transfer. In the event one (1) or more written protests stating material and legal grounds therefor are filed with the Board objecting to the proposed transfer of any such certificate within the time allowed, then the Board shall cause a public hearing to be held, and shall issue and serve, by mail, upon the applicants and all parties who have filed such protests a written notice that a public hearing will be held by the Board at a stated time on the application for, and the protests objecting to, approval of the proposed transfer. At such hearing the applicants shall present testimony and evidence in support of the proposed transfer, and those who have filed written protests shall be entitled to present testimony and evidence in opposition thereto.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Disposition of application for transfer. Following a public hearing on an application for approval of transfer of a certificate under this chapter, and written protests thereto, if the Board finds and determines that the proposed transfer is not contrary to the public interest, health, and welfare, it shall enter an appropriate order in the premises. If the Board finds otherwise the application shall be denied. In making its determination of whether or not the transfer is in the public interest, health, and welfare, the Board shall consider, but shall not be limited to, the following factors: The effect of said proposed transfer upon the policy of Miami-Dade County as expressed and codified in Chapter 32A of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County; the effect of said transfer on the consumers of the area of the transferee as to rates, service, and the quality of water and sewer service; the effect of the proposed transfer on the transferor as to its ability to maintain quality of water and sewer service to its existing consumers and to the proposed consumers located within the service area of the transferee; the effect of the proposed transfer based upon the considerations expressed within the comprehensive development master plan, as amended, for Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. The consideration of such factors shall not exclude consideration of factors other than those specifically mentioned above.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Judicial assignee of permit. Notwithstanding any of the provisions herein, any executor, administrator, receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or in reorganization, or other court officer, shall be entitled, as judicial assignee, to operate the business of the certificate holder, without the approval of the Board, upon filing with the Board a certified copy of his order of appointment, but any sale, transfer, or assignment by any such judicial officer shall be subject to the terms and conditions hereof. Any sale or transfer accomplished by means of judicial decree or order shall not be subject to the provisions of this section. However, the purchaser at judicial sale or under judicial decree shall register and comply with all other provisions of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, ยง 16, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 77-27, ยง 1, 5-3-77)</history></law>