<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CERTIFICATES OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-43</section_number>
<catch_line>Cancellation of permit for failure to serve.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003803</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-43. Cancellation of permit for failure to serve.<section>When any public utility fails or refuses, or is unable to provide any reasonable service, or make any reasonable extension of its existing facilities, within the territory authorized to be served by said public utility, as may be directed and required by the Board, the certificate held by said public utility under the provisions of this chapter may be revoked and canceled in whole or in part by the Board after notice and public hearings; and any public utility holding a certificate from the Board authorizing a similar service in contiguous territory may be authorized, after notice and public hearing, to make such reasonable extensions of its facilities into, and render such reasonable service in, the territory covered by any such canceled certificate or portion thereof, as may be justified by the public interest, health, and welfare, and as may be required by public convenience and necessity, provided, however, that no public utility shall be required to extend its facilities into such new territory, except in accordance with rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The power to cancel a certificate as provided herein for failure to render service shall be in addition to the power of the Board to cancel a certificate when the existing facilities are inadequate to provide for the reasonable needs of the consumers involved, and in addition to the power to levy and impose fines for violations of this chapter, provided, however, that all such public hearings relating to water quality required by this section shall be heard by the Environmental Quality Control Board as hearing examiner for the Water and Sewer Board. The Environmental Quality Control Board shall thereafter make findings of facts and recommendations to the Water and Sewer Board. The findings of fact relating to water quality shall be binding upon the Water and Sewer Board.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, ยง 18, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 62-28, ยง 5, 7-3-62; Ord. No. 75-28, ยง 10, 5-7-75)</history></law>