<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CERTIFICATES OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-45</section_number>
<catch_line>Acquisition of public utility by Miami-Dade County or Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003805</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-45. Acquisition of public utility by Miami-Dade County or Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority.<section>Notwithstanding any other section of this chapter, upon acquisition by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority of any public utility, as defined in this chapter, either through merger, transfer, negotiated sale, eminent domain, or otherwise:<section prefix='(a)'>Any and all certificates or temporary certificates of public convenience and necessity and designated service areas possessed by the acquired public utility shall be cancelled and terminated and of no further force and effect as to said public utility as of the date upon which Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority assumes the duties and responsibilities of providing water and sewer service to the consumers within the service areas formerly served by the public utility. On that date, Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall assume said duties and responsibilities of providing water and/or sewer service without any further action of the Board.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any and all franchise agreements between the acquired public utility and any municipality shall terminate and cease to exist as of the date upon which change of title from that utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water Sewer Authority occurs and any municipal charter, ordinance or resolution approving same are specifically repealed.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any and all outstanding orders of the Board and/or provisions of Chapter 32 of the Code that affect the public utility to be acquired shall have no further effect, and shall not be enforced or enforceable against Miami-Dade County, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority or the acquired public utility as of the date upon which change of title from the utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority takes place. However, said public utility shall be responsible and liable for compliance with said orders and/or provisions of the Board, Director of Environmental Resources Management or Environmental Quality Control Board or other affected County regulatory agency, at all times up to the date upon which change of title occurs or thereafter for orders and/or provisions where compliance was required prior to the date of County or Authority ownership of the acquired public utility. This continuing responsibility and liability of the acquired utility is subject to qualification, however, by the other provisions of this section and said responsibility and liability shall be for specific acts that were required to be performed prior to the date of County or Authority ownership of the acquired utility where said orders or provisions had become or became final by virtue of the expiration of all times for rehearings and appeals, if any, in connection with said specific acts.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any and all escrowed funds possessed by the acquired public utility or being held on its behalf, escrowed pursuant to Board order or the Code, shall be released to the use of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority for the purpose of providing water and/or sewer service to consumers within the service area of the acquired public utility. If such funds have been escrowed by the acquired public utility for certain capital projects or other particular purposes, Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall assume the responsibility for fulfillment of those specific projects or purposes without the need for such escrow accounts and shall rebate to consumers of the acquired public utility or to those consumers directly responsible for establishing said fund or funds, any of such funds not so utilized for those specific projects or purposes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Upon acquisition of a public utility, Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall be liable to make construction cost refunds to developers for which the acquired utility was liable, except to the extent that such liability is extinguished or assumed by the acquired utility by the terms of the agreement reflecting a sale, merger or transfer or by eminent domain proceedings.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Notwithstanding any provision hereof, as of the date upon which change of title from the acquired public utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority occurs, any and all contracts, agreements, memoranda, understandings or other obligations, whether written or verbal, for service, construction, cost allocations, charges, costs, refunds, reimbursements or other payments, notwithstanding any terms or provisions thereof, shall be modified, amended, revised, construed and entered for all purposes, including, without limitation, the determination of all obligations of Miami-Dade County, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority and the acquired public utility, as if the charges, rules, regulations, standards, specifications and practices of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority are in effect on the date that any service, construction, cost allocations, charges, costs, refunds, reimbursements or other payments are to be performed or made had been incorporated originally in such contracts, agreements, memoranda, understandings or other obligations and any provisions of said contracts, agreements, memoranda, understandings or other obligations which are contrary to said charges, rules, regulations, standards, specifications and practices shall be deemed null, void, invalid and unenforceable. The Authority or County Commission shall waive or modify the provisions of this subsection for acquisitions prior to the date hereof in those exceptional circumstances where a developer has substantially altered its position and expended substantial sums of money in reliance on said differing standards and said alteration of position has been authorized or cause by action of the County or Authority.</section><section prefix='(g)'>In the interim period between the date upon which Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority signs a letter of intent with said utility or such other date as may be agreed to between Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority and the acquired utility to purchase that utility, and the date upon which the change of title of that public utility to Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority occurs, the rates, charges, fees, construction standards and specifications imposed by the utility upon consumers within its franchised service area shall remain subject as before to control of the Board. However, any developer, as described in Section 32-55, who desires to enter into a service agreement with that utility during the interim period described above, shall be required to install improvements and to submit design data that meet the standards set forth in the rules and regulations of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority. Said developer shall have the right to appear before the Board during the interim period to obtain a waiver or modification of said standards during the interim period where the developer can show mitigating circumstances, that preexisted the date upon which binding contract, agreement or settlement agreement was signed that justify such a waiver or modification.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code, personnel rules or any other rules, regulations or administrative orders, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority (when the system is acquired by the Authority) or the County Manager (when the system is acquired by the County) may determine that all or certain of the employees of the acquired utility (except for acquired utilities of municipalities) should be retained as employees in those or similar capacities, in the County's service, in order to maintain service continuity and prevent a detrimental interruption of these essential services. In so doing, the determination of the Director or the Manager shall result in the waiver of any requirements for competitive or promotional examinations and the Director or County Manager may place said employees in a job status or classification reasonably comparable to that held by the employee prior to the acquisition, if available. Any employee so hired shall be considered and treated as a new County employee and shall serve a probationary period as determined by the County Manager or Director.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The terms of this section shall be applicable to all public utilities heretofore or hereafter acquired by either Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-9, ยง 2, 2-13-79)</history></law>