<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CERTIFICATES OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-41</section_number>
<catch_line>Certificate required for extensions of systems; approval by Board for new water source.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003801</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-41. Certificate required for extensions of systems; approval by Board for new water source.<section>No public utility shall extend the facilities of its water and sewer systems without first obtaining for such extension a certificate of public convenience and necessity in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, unless such extension is made in accordance with rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Any such applications for extensions of water and/or sewer service areas into previously unassigned areas must be accompanied by a release by the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority issued pursuant to Section 32A-16(a) of the Code. Any action of the Board granting an extension of water and/or sewer systems issued under this section shall incorporate, as a minimum, the applicable conditions of release set out in Section 32A-16(a) of the Code. No public utility shall effectuate a change of more than ten (10) percent in the source of their water supply without the approval of the Board after a public hearing has been conducted. Utilities owned or operated by municipalities shall have the right to extend facilities within their municipal boundaries as a matter of right.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, § 15, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 62-28, § 4, 7-3-62; Ord. No. 64-23, § 3, 7-7-64; Ord. No. 74-95, § 1, 11-19-74; Ord. No. 76-67, § 1, 7-20-76)</history></law>