<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CERTIFICATES OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-40</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure for certificates for new systems.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003800</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-40. Procedure for certificates for new systems.<section prefix='(a)'>All applications for certificates required under Section 32-39 hereof shall be filed with the Board in compliance with rules and regulations promulgated by the Board and in such form as the Board may from time to time adopt or prescribe. Each such application shall be accompanied by a filing fee of two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00). Upon the filing of an application complying with the rules and regulations of the Board and payment of the filing fee, the Board shall cause the application to be set for public hearing. At least ten (10) days' written notice of such public hearing shall be given by mail to each of the public utilities that have registered with the Board in accordance with the provisions of Section 32-53 hereof, and notice shall be given by the Board to the Public Health Department, and notice of such public hearing shall be published once in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least ten (10) days prior to the date of such public hearing. Pursuant to such notice the Board shall conduct a public hearing to determine whether public convenience and necessity require or permit such construction or operation of said new water or sewer system; and the Board shall take into consideration whether or not in the issuance of the certificate applied for it would be in the public interest, health and welfare and whether the applicant can reasonably be expected to provide adequate service at reasonable rates. After such public hearing the Board shall make its determination of public convenience and necessity and shall state the reasons therefor and make findings of fact upon which the determination is predicated.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Board may prescribe in the certificate a reasonable time within which the applicant shall provide the services specified in the certificate within the service area described therein. If the services authorized by the certificate are not provided within the time so prescribed, the certificate shall be canceled and rendered null and void; provided, that prior to the expiration of the time prescribed in the certificate the Board shall have the power, for good cause shown, to extend such time and to impose such conditions as will assure the providing of adequate service at reasonable rates and any other reasonable conditions commensurate with the public interest, health and welfare.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Board shall not grant a certificate for the construction, operation, extension or expansion of a water or sewer system into any territory described in a prior certificate issued to another public utility except in accordance with rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners, or unless the Board shall first determine, after public notice and hearing, that the existing facilities are inadequate to meet the reasonable needs of the public involved, or that the standards of service are inadequate to provide for the reasonable needs of the consumers involved. In the event of any such determination, the Board may revoke, amend, limit or restrict any certificate previously issued. In making any such determination the Board shall be governed by consideration of the public interest, health and welfare, and shall endeavor to provide for the benefit of the consumers affected adequate standards of service at the lowest feasible rates. Any such determination shall embody a statement of the reasons therefor and findings of the facts upon which the determination is predicated.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, ยง 14, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 62-28, ยง 3, 7-3-62)</history></law>