<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. CERTIFICATES OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-44</section_number>
<catch_line>Review and assessment of existing service area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003804</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-44. Review and assessment of existing service area.<section>Board review and assessment of existing service areas assigned pursuant to the terms of this chapter may be initiated at any time by the Board of County Commissioners; Director, Environmental Resources Management of Miami-Dade County; the Director of the Miami-Dade County Health Department; the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning; the Consumer Advocate of Miami-Dade County; or the staff of the Water and Sewer Board, or any other department or agency or instrumentality of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. The application for a service area review and assessment shall designate the area or areas sought to be reviewed and the reasons of the applicant therefor. Upon receipt of such an application, the Secretary of the Board shall notify the affected utility of its filing and all other utilities adjacent to the service area concerned. In addition, the Secretary shall notify all affected County agencies, instrumentalities or departments of the application. Said notices shall include a copy of the application and shall request information dealing with the quality and capacity of service now being provided or available within the area concerned by the utility, the extent of service that is actually available without water or sewer main extension by the utility; and, the extent to which further development in the area is in accordance with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan. The Secretary to the Board shall thereupon schedule the matter for a public hearing in not less than forty-five (45) days from receipt of the application and shall notify all parties of the date thereof and shall publish notice of the time and place of said hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the existing service area. In the event the Board determines, after due notice and public hearing, that it is required for the public convenience and necessity that a currently unserved portion of an assigned service area should be reassigned, either to another utility or should not be assigned to any utility, the Board shall enter its order accordingly and shall state its reasons therefor and make findings of fact upon which the determination is predicated.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-68, ยง 1, 7-20-76; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 20, 9-3-98)</history></law>