<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. WATER AND SANITARY SEWER CONNECTION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-78</section_number>
<catch_line>Connection to public water supply and public sewer disposal in abutting streets and easements required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003809</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-78. Connection to public water supply and public sewer disposal in abutting streets and easements required.<section prefix='(a)'>All premises used or intended for human habitation or occupancy including, but not limited to, establishments to be used for household, domestic, food processing, food handling, restaurant, dairy or bottling processors, public buildings and places of assembly or other establishments where a water supply is or may be used for human consumption or where human wastes may be disposed of, and which abuts a water main owned by a water utility, or a sewage main owned by a sewage utility, shall be connected to the said water and/or sewer main in such manner as to meet the requirements of the South Florida Building Code and the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual. A water or sewer main shall be deemed to abut a building or premises if it is located in a street or easement adjoining the land on which the building is located and if it traverses one (1) full dimension of the building.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Where a premises is abutted by two water mains, either one of which the premises can validly be connected to in compliance with the South Florida Building Code and the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, and the premises is currently connected to the water main located in the rear of the premises, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department may require such premises to connect to a water main owned by the Department which abuts the front of the property and to which such premises may validly be connected, at no cost to the property owner. The Department shall be responsible for all costs of disconnection of the water main abutting the rear of the premises and connection to the water main abutting the front of the premises. An owner of a premises who has previously paid a water connection fee to the Department shall not be required to pay an additional water connection fee if the premises was connected to a different water main pursuant to this Section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Should the owner of a premises currently connected to a water main refuse to allow the Department to disconnect the premises from the water main abutting the rear of the premises and to connect the premises to the water main abutting the front of the premises in accordance with Section 32-78(b), the Department shall have the right to terminate water service to such premises, and shall incur no liability therefore.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The department shall use certified plumbing contractors to disconnect the premises from the rear water main and to connect the premises to the front water main as provided in Section 32-78(b).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-47, ยง 1, 6-1-71; Ord. No. 08-140, ยง 1, 12-2-08)</history></law>