<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. WATER AND SANITARY SEWER CONNECTION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-79</section_number>
<catch_line>Notice to connect; procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003810</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-79. Notice to connect; procedure.<section>If the County Manager finds and determines that buildings subject to the terms of this article have not been connected to water mains of water utilities, or sewer mains of sewer utilities, he shall so notify the record owner of the said buildings in writing and demand that such owner cause the connections to be made by duly licensed contractors or the property owner in accordance with the South Florida Building Code within ninety (90) days of the date of service of the notice as hereinafter provided. The notice shall be served by registered mail, addressed to the owner or owners of the property described as they are known to the Manager or as their names and addresses are shown upon the records of the County Tax Assessor, or other Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and shall be deemed complete and sufficient when so addressed and deposited in the United States mail with proper postage prepaid. In the event that such notice is returned by postal authorities the Manager shall cause a copy of the notice to be served by a law enforcement officer upon the occupant of the land or upon any agent of the owner thereof. In the event that personal service upon the occupant of the land or upon any agent of the owner thereof cannot be performed after reasonable search by a law enforcement officer the notice shall be served by physical posting on the said property, and by publication in a newspaper of general circulation at least twice, seven (7) days between publications, and ninety (90) days before the date of connection is required. The notice shall be in substantially the following form:</section><section>"NOTICE REQUIRING CONNECTION TO WATER AND/OR SEWER MAIN</section><section>Name of owner   </section><section>Address of owner   </section><section>Our records indicate that you are the owner(s) of the following land in Miami-Dade County, Florida: (describe property)</section><section>An inspection of this land discloses, and I have found and determined, that a building is located thereon which is not connected to a water main of the (name of utility) and/or to a sewer main of the (name of utility) located in (name of street or description of easement) abutting the said property.</section><section>You are hereby notified that unless the said building is connected to the said main(s) within ninety (90) days of personal service upon you, or of the second publication hereof, Miami-Dade County will proceed to effect said connection and the cost of the work, including advertising costs, connection charges and other expenses necessary to make complete connection to building, will be imposed as a lien on the land if not otherwise paid within ninety (90) days after said connection has been made and the cost thereof ascertained by Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-47, § 1, 6-1-71)</history></law>