<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. WATER AND SANITARY SEWER CONNECTION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-80</section_number>
<catch_line>Connection effected by County; lien; recording; redemption.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003811</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-80. Connection effected by County; lien; recording; redemption.<section>If within ninety (90) days after service of the said notice or by physical posting of the notice on the property, or by publication in a newspaper, all as set forth in the preceding section, the connection required thereby has not been effected, the County Manager shall cause the connection to be effected by Miami-Dade County at the expense of the property owner. The cost of the said connection shall constitute a lien upon the real estate served thereby as is hereinafter set out. Upon ordering a connection to be made by the County, the County Manager shall cause to be recorded in the public records a Notice of Water and/or Sewer Connection Lien Pending, which shall include a description of the property and a statement that a connection has been ordered, the cost of which shall under this article constitute a lien. The said notice of water or sewer connection lien shall, eight (8) months after the date thereof, be null and void and constitute no record notice of a pending lien. After causing the connection to be effected the County Manager shall certify to the Director of Finance the expenses, including such connection charges as may have been approved by the appropriate Miami-Dade County agency, incurred in effecting the connection and shall include a copy of the notice above described, whereupon such expense shall become payable within ninety (90) days, after which a special assessment lien and charge will be made upon the property, which shall be payable in ten (10) equal annual installments together with costs of recordation of all documents required to be recorded hereby and with interest at the rate of six (6) percent per annum on the unpaid balance from the date of such certification until paid; provided, however, that the said lien may be satisfied at any time by the payment of the entire sum due plus accrued interest, recordation costs, and such expenses and penalties as may result from the advertisement and sale of certificates for delinquent liens as hereinafter set out. The Director of Finance shall file for record a notice of such lien in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court, and shall keep complete records relating to the amount payable thereon. One-tenth of the amount of liens accruing during any year ending on June first, shall be billed and mailed in the fall of the same year to the owners of land subject to such liens at the same time as tax statements for ad valorem taxes are mailed, and if the said amount shall not be paid on or before April first of the following year, the entire lien and all annual installments thereof shall be delinquent, overdue, and in default, and the entire amount of the lien shall be collected in the same manner as delinquent taxes by advertisement and sale of certificates. Upon full payments of liens provided hereby or tax sale certificates resulting therefrom, the Director of Finance shall, by appropriate means, evidence the satisfaction and cancellation of such lien upon the public records. The cost of recordation of the notice of water and sewer connection lien pending, the notice of lien, and the satisfaction of lien shall be secured by the lien hereby provided.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-47, ยง 1, 6-1-71)</history></law>