<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. WATER AND SANITARY SEWER CONNECTION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-83</section_number>
<catch_line>Peak Flows.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003814</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-83. Peak Flows.<section prefix='(A)'>Submission of peak flow data. Every publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system shall submit its peak flow data to the County for use in the County-wide rainfall dependent peak flow management study no later than February 8, 2007. Peak flow data is defined as the hourly flow rates that the system is expected to discharge into the County system during and resulting from a two year storm event. In the event a publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system fails to provide its peak flow data by said date, the County shall determine and establish the peak flow limit for such publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system and such system shall be bound by such determination and the publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer system shall be subject to the provisions in subsection (B).</section><section prefix='(B)'>Enforcement; procedure; remedies. If actual peak flows exceed the data provided by a publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system or the Peak Flow limit as set by the County pursuant to subsection (A), the owner or operator of such system shall be required to pay additional fees in accordance with the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department's schedule of rates, fees and charges, as amended, and may be subject to a building moratorium in accordance with section 24-13.2 of this code. In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by this chapter, the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department, or his designee, is authorized to institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek temporary or permanent, prohibitory or mandatory injunctive relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of; any provisions of this chapter; any lawful order of the Director of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department; or any consent agreement.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-104, ยง 1, 6-5-01; Ord. No. 02-107, ยง 1, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 06-87, ยง 1, 6-6-06)</history></law>