<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. WATER AND SANITARY SEWER CONNECTION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-83.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Water Conservation Plans.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003815</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-83.1. Water Conservation Plans.<section prefix='(A)'>Submission of Water Conservation Plan. Every publicly owned or operated water distribution system supplied potable water, in whole or in part, by Miami-Dade County, shall submit a water conservation plan to the County. All water conservation plans submitted must comply with the South Florida Water Management District Basis of Review for Consumptive Use Permit Application and the Florida Department of Environmental Protection Conserve Florida Guide, as well as the Environmental Protection Agency WaterSense Program. Said Plan shall be updated for the County's approval every five years following submittal and Conserve Florida Guide generated reports shall be filed annually at the close of the fiscal year. All water conservation plans submitted shall consider a twenty year horizon. In the event a publicly owned or operated water distribution system fails to provide its water conservation plan by the close of the fiscal year, the County shall determine and establish the conservation measures to be implemented by said system and the amount of water supplied to such system by the County which could be conserved via implementation of such measures, and such system shall be bound by such determination and the publicly owned or operated water distribution system shall be subject to the provisions in subsection (B).</section><section prefix='(B)'>Enforcement; procedure; remedies. Where the County has, pursuant to subsection (A), established the conservation measures and the amount of water supplied to a water distribution system which could be conserved through the implementation of such measures, the owner or operator of such system shall be required to pay additional fees, in accordance with the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department's schedule of rates, fees and charges, as amended, for continued use of the water which could be conserved through implementation of the specified conservation measures. The Miami Dade Water and Sewer Department shall develop a water conservation plan for the water distribution system documenting the proposed measures, best management practices and projected water savings.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-177, ยง 1, 12-5-06)</history></law>