<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. MIAMI-DADE WATER AND SEWER AUTHORITY DEPARTMENT BILLING PROCEDURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-94</section_number>
<catch_line>Recording of liens.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003823</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-94. Recording of liens.<section prefix='(a)'>For water and sewer service charges for service rendered during the period of February 13, 1981, through December 31, 1984, which become more than sixty (60) days past due and unpaid, the Department shall cause to be filed in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida, on or before June 30, 1985, a notice of lien or statement showing a legal description of the property against which the lien is claimed, its location by street and number, the name of the owner, an accurate statement of the water and sewer service charges then unpaid, and a copy of such notice of lien shall be mailed within a reasonable time to the owner of the property involved as shown by the records of the Tax Collector of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. If the Department fails to file a notice of lien on or before June 30, 1985, for water and sewer service charges becoming more than sixty (60) days past due during said period of February 13, 1981, through December 31, 1984, the lien shall not be enforceable by the County. Thereafter, no lien shall be enforceable by the County unless a notice of lien is filed by the County. Liens imposed prior to February 17, 1984, shall not be enforced.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Liens may be discharged and satisfied by payment to the Department of the aggregate amounts specified in the notice of lien, together with interest accrued thereon, and all filing and recording fees. When any such lien has been fully paid and/or discharged, the Department shall cause evidence of the satisfaction and discharge of such lien to be filed with the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Any person, firm, or corporation or legal entity, other than the present owner of the property involved, who fully pays any such lien shall be entitled to receive an assignment of the lien and shall be subrogated to the rights of the County in respect of the enforcement of such lien.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-10, ยง 1, 2-7-84; Ord. No. 84-68, ยง 1, 7-17-84; Ord. No. 08-22, ยง 1, 2-7-08)</history></law>