<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XA. EDUCATIONAL AND CHILD CARE FACILITIES, NONPUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-151.15</section_number>
<catch_line>Required information.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004028</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-151.15. Required information.<section>All nonpublic educational facilities, as defined in this article, shall submit the following applicable information to the Department for review by the Department.<section prefix='(A)'>Written information.<section prefix='(1)'>Total size of the site;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Maximum number of students to be served;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Number of teachers and administrative and clerical personnel;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Number of classrooms and total square footage of classroom space;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Total square footage of nonclassroom space;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Amount of exterior recreational/play area in square footage;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Number and type of vehicles that will be used in conjunction with the operation of the facility;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Number of parking spaces provided for staff, visitors, and transportation vehicles, and justification that those spaces are sufficient for this facility;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Grades or age groups that will be served;</section><section prefix='(10)'>Days and hours of operations;</section><section prefix='(11)'>Means of compliance with requirements by the Miami-Dade County Fire Department, Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health, the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, and any federal guidelines applicable to the specific application.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Graphic information, less than fifty (50) students.<section prefix='(1)'>A detailed plot use plan shall be submitted to the Department of Planning and Zoning, and the same shall be drawn to scale and include dimensions to indicate lot size, street rights-of-way and pavement measured from center line, size of building or buildings, interior floor layout and interior uses, location and size of recreation and/or play areas, location of fences and/or walls that shall enclose recreation and/or play areas; said plans shall include, but not be limited to, off-street parking areas and driveways, walls, fences, signs and landscaping. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code. The plot use plan shall include a title block giving the name of the project, the title of the person preparing the plan, the date of preparation of the plan and scale of drawings.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Other data shall be furnished as requested by the Director where such data may be needed in order to determine that standards as specified in this article have been met.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Graphic information, fifty (50) or more students. The following graphic information shall be prepared by design professionals, such as registered Florida architects and landscape architects, for proposed facilities with fifty (50) or more students.<section prefix='(1)'>A plan indicating existing zoning on the site and adjacent areas.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A site plan indicating the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Location of all structures;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Parking layout and drives;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Walkways;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Location of recreation areas and play equipment which shall include surrounding fences and/or walls;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any other features which can appropriately be shown in plan form.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Floor plans and elevations of all proposed structures.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Landscape development plan listing quantities, size, and names of all plants in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-59, § 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 86-27, § 1, 4-1-86; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98)</history></law>