<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.13</section_number>
<catch_line>Required declaration of restrictive covenants</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004106</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.13. Required declaration of restrictive covenants<section>Prior to final approval of any application seeking to utilize the density or intensity bonus available pursuant to this article, the applicant shall submit a separate declaration of restrictive covenants, encumbering the entire project, approved in form by the Director and sufficient for recording in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, including provisions requiring development of a specified number, type, and location of all dwelling units, a general plan for staging construction of all units, and such other provisions as the Department may require to demonstrate the applicant's compliance with this article. The development and the WHU staging plan must be consistent with the CDMP and any applicable land use, subdivision regulations, zoning and site plan approval for the property. The declaration of restrictive covenants shall require the property to be developed in accordance with the following specifications:<section prefix='(A)'>A general description of the covered development, including whether the covered development will contain rental dwelling units or owner-occupied dwelling units, or both;</section><section prefix='(B)'>The total number of market rate dwelling units and WHUs in the development and the timetable for construction; and</section><section prefix='(C)'>The location of the WHUs in the development and phasing, if any, and construction schedule for the development sequence demonstrating that:<section prefix='(1)'>WHUs will be built and made available for occupancy simultaneously with or before market-rate dwelling units, except that building permits for the last 10% of the market-rate units shall be withheld until building permits have been issued for all of the WHUs; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The last building shall not contain only WHUs.</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>If the requirements of this article are to be satisfied through the use of an alternative to on-site construction as provided in section 33-193.8, of this code, the declaration of restrictive covenants shall identify and commit to the development of WHUs on an approved alternative site. A separate declaration of restrictive covenants encumbering the alternative site shall identify and commit to the development of the approved off-site WHUs, and shall further provide appropriate assurances that the WHUs that will be required for the alternative site itself will be provided.</section><section prefix='(E)'>The declaration of restrictive covenants may be modified by mutual consent of the applicant and the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Miami-Dade Housing Agency, as long as the modified agreement remains in conformity with this article and substantially conforms to the recorded declaration's provisions relating to number, location, distribution and timing or construction of WHUs.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>