<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XA. EDUCATIONAL AND CHILD CARE FACILITIES, NONPUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-151.17</section_number>
<catch_line>Combination of residential and nonpublic educational facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004030</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-151.17. Combination of residential and nonpublic educational facilities.<section>No combination of residential use and nonpublic educational facility will be permitted on the same property except as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>A single-family residential use will be permitted in the same building with a nursery or kindergarten use, where the same is used only by the nursery-kindergarten operator.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In connection with day nursery and kindergarten facilities, a residential unit for a caretaker may be permitted only when the facility operator does not reside on said premises.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A residential unit will be permitted for a caretaker on the site of an elementary, junior and/or senior high school.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An existing multifamily apartment building or complex may incorporate a day nursery and/or kindergarten for the accommodation of residents only; provided, that such facility will not be contrary to any site plans previously approved at a public hearing.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Nonpublic educational facilities may be incorporated into a proposed apartment building or complex, provided said schools are included in the plans submitted for approval at public hearing (in case of apartment complex) and/or for permit (in case of apartment building).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-57, ยง 1, 9-6-77)</history></law>