<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. MOBILE HOMES AND MOBILE HOME PARKS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-169</section_number>
<catch_line>Mobile home park, public hearing approval and permit required to establish; requirement to obtain an annual certificate of use.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004067</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-169. Mobile home park, public hearing approval and permit required to establish; requirement to obtain an annual certificate of use.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to own, operate, maintain or permit to be operated or maintained, or to construct, increase by number of spaces or otherwise extend any mobile home park unless such person shall first obtain a permit as a result of approval of the use and of the site plan of such park after public hearing. Such park shall comply with the approved plan and the provisions of this chapter and all other applicable State and County regulations and laws in its development and maintenance. The provisions of this article shall not apply to legal, existing mobile home parks nor to parks approved prior to the effective date of this article, but on which development has not commenced except as provided in Section 33-170(B).</section><section>Anything to the contrary notwithstanding, mobile homes or manufactured homes, their porches, and other additions to mobile homes or manufactured homes in mobile home parks in existence prior to June 25, 1971 or which have been established subsequent to said date pursuant to(B), are permitted providing they conform to the requirements of(b).</section><section prefix='(2)'>All legally established mobile home parks shall apply for and obtain an annual certificate of use.<section prefix='(a)'>The scope of the certificate of use Inspection shall be limited to zoning compliance issues, including the following:<section prefix='1.'>A tenant occupancy report indicating the number of occupied lots and unoccupied lots; if the park is a combination of mobile homes and manufactured homes, the report shall list the information separately.</section><section prefix='2.'>The current occupancy rate of the mobile home park based on the number of occupied lots and the number of legally permitted lots.</section><section prefix='3.'>Inspection for compliance with the property maintenance standards of Chapter 19 of the Code.</section><section prefix='4.'>Inspection for compliance with commercial vehicle storage regulations.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>A copy of the certificate of use inspection report shall be sent to the owner of the mobile home park and referrals of violations of items listed in this section shall be made to the County department responsible for such code enforcement.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Reports of violations and the park occupancy information shall be sent to the appropriate state agency for enforcement action.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All legally existing mobile home parks must apply for a certificate of use within 90 days after the effective date of this ordinance. Renewals of the certificate of use shall be made each year in the month of June.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-54, ยง 1, 6-15-71; Ord. No. 73-38, ยง 1, 4-3-73; Ord. No. 10-58, ยง 3, 9-21-10)</history></law>