<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XA. EDUCATIONAL AND CHILD CARE FACILITIES, NONPUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-151.18</section_number>
<catch_line>Physical standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004031</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-151.18. Physical standards.<section prefix='(a)'>Outdoor areas. Outdoor recreation/play areas shall be in accordance with the following minimum standards, calculated in terms of the proposed maximum number of children for attendance at the school at any one (1) time unless otherwise indicated.</section><section>Minimum Standards for Outdoor Recreation Playground/Play Areas</section><section>Where there are category combinations, each classification shall be calculated individually.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Signs. Signs shall comply with district regulations as contained in Chapter 33 of the Miami-Dade County Code; provided, however, that the total square footage of all freestanding signs in any residential district shall not exceed six (6) square feet in size.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Auto stacking. Stacking space, defined as that space in which pickup and delivery of children can take place, shall be provided for a minimum of two (2) automobiles for schools with twenty (20) to forty (40) children; schools with forty (40) to sixty (60) [children] shall provide four (4) spaces; thereafter there shall be provided a space sufficient to stack five (5) automobiles.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Parking requirements. Parking requirements shall be as provided in the Miami-Dade County Zoning Code, Section 33-124(1).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Classroom size. All spaces shall be calculated on the effective net area usable for instruction or general care of the group to be housed. This space shall not include kitchen areas, bathrooms, hallways, teachers' conference rooms, storage areas, or any other interior space that is not used for instruction, play or other similar activities. The minimum classroom space shall be determined by multiplying the maximum proposed number of pupils for attendance at any one (1) time by the minimum square footages, (1) through (4) below. Where a private educational facility is nongraded, calculations shall be based on the age level that corresponds to the grade level in the public school system. Where a school includes more than one (1) of the following categories, each category shall be individually computed:<section prefix='(1)'>Day nursery and kindergarten, preschool and afterschool care, 35 square feet per pupil.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Elementary (grades 1—6), 30 square feet per pupil.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Junior high and senior high (grades 7—12), 25 square feet per pupil.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Baby-sitting service, 22 square feet of room area per child.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Height. The structure height shall not exceed the height permitted for that site by the existing zoning.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Trees. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(h)'>[Exemptions.] Baby-sitting services are exempted from the requirements of Subsections (a), (c), (d) and (g), "Outdoor Areas," "Auto Stacking," "Parking" and "Trees," Section 33-151.18. Schools permitted within existing multifamily structures (Subsection (d), Section 33-151.17) are exempted from Subsections (c) and (d), Section 33-151.18, provided such schools are limited to the occupants of the subject multifamily structures.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Child care facilities as described in Section 33-151.11(a), (b) and (f), shall be prohibited from operating on property abutting or containing a water body such as a pond, lake, canal, irrigation well, river, bay, or the ocean unless a safety barrier is provided which totally encloses or affords complete separation from such water hazards. Swimming pools and permanent wading pools in excess of eighteen (18) inches in depth shall be totally enclosed and separated from the balance of the property so as to prevent unrestricted admittance. All such barriers shall be a minimum of forty-eight (48) inches in height and shall comply with the following standards:<section prefix='(1)'>Gates shall be of the spring back type so that they shall automatically be in a closed and fastened position at all times. Gates shall also be equipped with a safe lock and shall be locked when the area is without adult supervision.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All safety barriers shall be constructed in accordance with the standards established in Section 33-12, except that screen enclosures shall not constitute a safety barrier for these purposes.</section></section><section prefix='(j)'>Location requirement for outdoor recreation playground/play areas for Child Care facilities. Where the front or side street property line of a child care facility as described in Section 33-151.11(a), (b) and (f), abuts a section line or half section line right-of-way no outdoor recreation playground/play area shall be located between the right-of-way and the building line parallel to the right-of-way. Within two years after the Director mails notice of the requirement of this ordinance all existing child care facilities shall either comply with the foregoing requirement or install a safety barrier from vehicular traffic designed by a professional engineer and approved by the Public Works Department. For any existing child care facility which is required to either relocate its outdoor recreation playground/play area or provide a safety barrier, any resulting reduction in outdoor recreation playground/play area shall be deemed in compliance with the minimum playground/play area requirements of Section 33-151.18(a). Any such reduction shall also be deemed to be in substantial compliance with any site plan previously approved at public hearing. In event that such a child care facility whose site plan was approved at public hearing seeks to relocate its playground/play area, such relocation shall be subject to approval after public hearing upon appropriate application. No fee shall be charged for such application. This subsection shall not be deemed to allow the future expansion of any child care facility to occur without complying with the requirements of Section 33-151.18(a). Notwithstanding any thing in the Code to the contrary the provision of this subsection shall apply to Miami-Dade County child care facilities.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-59, § 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 86-27, §§ 1, 2, 4-1-86; Ord. No. 90-115, § 1, 10-16-90; Ord. No. 93-126, § 3, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 01-24, § 1, 2-13-01; Ord. No. 05-16, § 1, 1-27-05)</history></law>