<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. OFF-STREET PARKING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-122.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003989</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-122.2. Parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers.<section>Parking spaces specifically designed for persons transporting young children under the age of three (3) and strollers, shall be required for all uses other than single-family, duplex, townhouse or multifamily; provided, however, industrial zoned properties shall not be required to comply with this section. Such baby stroller parking spaces shall be provided as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Quality of specially designated parking spaces:</section><section prefix='(b)'>Location of parking spaces. Such spaces shall be located as closely as possible to parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons; provided however, parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons shall take precedence. Where no parking spaces designated for the physically handicapped and/or disabled persons have been provided, parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers shall be located on the shortest accessible route of travel from adjacent parking to an accessible entrance.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Signage and markings. All parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers shall be prominently outlined with green paint and posted with an approved permanent above-ground sign which shall conform to the figure entitled "Baby Stroller Parking Sign" hereby incorporated in this section. The bottom of the sign must be at least five (5) feet above grade when attached to a building, or seven (7) feet above grade for a detached sign.</section></section><section></section><section>All property owners who are required by this section to provide parking spaces for persons transporting young children and strollers shall provide such parking spaces within two (2) years from the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives (Ordinance No. 94-104). In no event shall the number of parking spaces for the physically handicapped and/or disabled be reduced below the quantity required by the South Florida Building Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-104, ยง 1, 6-7-94; Ord. No. 96-161, ยง 2, 11-12-96; Ord. No. 98-108, ยง 3, 7-21-98)</history></law>