<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. VILLA DEVELOPMENT DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-163.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Perimeter greenbelt and maintenance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004054</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-163.7. Perimeter greenbelt and maintenance.<section>A minimum 10-foot wide landscaped buffer area shall be provided and maintained along and extending inward from the property lines of the villa development that are adjacent to other private property, and shall be expanded to 20 feet along property lines adjacent to rights-of-way. The buffer area shall be landscaped with a balanced arrangement of ground cover, shrubs, vines, hedges and trees and other landscape features such as walls, fences and berms, or a combination of any of the above items.</section><section>Those buffer areas adjacent to other private properties shall be designed to provide at least a 75 percent visual barrier, after 2 years' growth, along the entire property line. Buffer areas adjacent to public rights-of-way shall be designed to provide at least 50 percent visual barrier, after 2 years' growth, along the entire such property line. Plant material and other such landscape features shall be arranged in such a way so as to prevent vehicular access through, or parking in such buffer areas.</section><section>Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with of this Code. Plant materials used shall conform in definition, quality, and size when planted to the provisions of of this Code for each type of plant except that trees shall be a minimum of 7 feet tall by three and one-half foot spread when planted. This minimum size tree shall be required for those trees placed 75 feet on center, but additional smaller trees may be planted as part of the required landscaping.</section><section>Planting at street intersections of any vehicular or pedestrian exits shall be in accordance with the safety standards of this Code to prevent visual obstructions along street rights-of-way.</section><section>All plant material shall be installed in such a manner as to ensure the survival and healthy growth of the plants. The buffer area shall be maintained in accordance with good landscape maintenance practices, including installation and use of sprinklers or other acceptable water delivery system, to ensure the good health and appearance of all planted material.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-22, ยง 2, 3-2-10)</history></law>