<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.10</section_number>
<catch_line>Density bonuses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004103</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.10. Density bonuses.<section prefix='(A)'>Any application providing a minimum of 12.5 percent WHUs on-site, or otherwise complying with Section 33-193.8 of this article, shall be entitled to a residential density bonus of 25 percent above the applicable CDMP Land Use map maximum density (provided the application satisfies all of the requirements of this article) as well as the benefit of the intensity standards provided in section 33-193.11</section><section>The density bonus for the primary site shall not be transferable to the off-site property, where an alternative site is approved after public hearing for the development of off-site WHUs.</section><section prefix='(B)'>WHU applicants providing 5% workforce housing units or an approved contribution in lieu thereof shall be entitled to a density bonus above the CDMP maximum density to such increased density as is required to provide the 5% WHUs, as well as the benefit of the intensity standards provided in section 33-193.11</section><section prefix='(C)'>The total number of dwelling units permitted, including bonus units, market rate units, and WHUs may exceed the permitted maximum density allowed in the zoning district in accordance with the foregoing provisions, provided that in no event shall the density exceed the maximum densities, including applicable bonuses, set forth in the CDMP, as amended.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Severable use rights, as provided in Chapter 33B of this code, shall not be utilized in conjunction with the density bonuses contained in this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>