<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. MOBILE HOMES AND MOBILE HOME PARKS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-170</section_number>
<catch_line>Site plan details, time limit for commencement, platting.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004069</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-170. Site plan details, time limit for commencement, platting.<section prefix='(A)'>The site to be submitted for approval at public hearing shall be complete and properly identified and drawn to scale clearly showing compliance with the standards hereinafter mentioned, including, but not limited to, the area and boundary dimensions of the mobile home park, layout and sizes of mobile home spaces (typical arrangement on larger scale of mobile home, its appurtenances, attachments and space), location of commercial and service buildings and uses, location of signs, parking spaces, streets, both private and public, walkways, open space areas of all kinds, walls, fences, garbage collection points, if any, and community storage buildings, if any, and all other buildings and structures, areas to be reserved for travel trailers, if any, entrance features and signs thereon, and including general landscaping plan showing grassed areas, and location, size and type of hedges, shrubs, trees, and other landscaping. The plan shall also include a legend listing the overall acreage, gross and net density, percentage and area of open spaces by types, number of spaces, coverage by permanent park buildings, parking spaces required and provided, and estimated total population. Mobile home parks, as evidenced by the site plan submitted, shall be arranged in an aesthetic residential manner, to be achieved by variation in street patterns, with the clustering of spaces, cul-de-sacs and curvilinear streets as suggested features, and including variation in block shapes and in the arrangement of the mobile home spaces and mobile homes thereon.</section><section prefix='(B)'>The approval of the mobile home park use and the site plan, as detailed above, shall expire within eighteen (18) months from the date of final resolution of approval unless development is commenced within that period; provided, if the commencement of development is not feasible in view of litigation involving the validity of the resolution of approval, the said eighteen (18) month period shall not begin to run until final decision of the court. This time limitation for commencement of development shall also apply to those previously approved mobile home parks, and such time limitation for those previously approved shall commence running from the effective date of this article. For the purpose of this subsection commencement of development shall mean site improvement, if such improvement and installation of facilities is progressively continued and completed within a reasonable time under the circumstances. If development is terminated for a period of six (6) months the special exception and any permits issued for improvements shall be abandoned and become null and void.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The site involved with the development of the mobile home park shall be platted, such plat to include only exterior boundaries of park and all public dedications and easements.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-54, ยง 1, 6-15-71)</history></law>