<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. OFF-STREET PARKING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-122.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Requirement of bicycle racks or other means of storage.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003990</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-122.3. Requirement of bicycle racks or other means of storage.<section>Racks or other means of storage that can secure at least four (4) bicycles shall be required for all park, shopping center, office and restaurant uses with parking lots, as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Quantity of bicycle parking spaces required:</section><section prefix='(b)'>Other uses. All other uses, other than airport or seaport terminals, single-family, duplex or townhouse which are exempt, shall provide racks or other means of storage as provided herein only where their total parking lot has one hundred one (101) or more spaces.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Location and design of bicycle parking spaces; requirements.</section><section prefix='(1)'>The bicycle parking spaces shall be located near the entrances to the building.</section><section prefix='(2)'>At buildings and shopping centers that have multiple parking lots, the bicycle parking spaces should be installed near the entrances to the buildings served by the lots.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The bicycle parking spaces should be in a highly visible, well lighted location that provides enough clear space to facilitate easy use and does not impede pedestrian traffic or handicap accessibility.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The parking spaces may not be placed in the County maintained right-of-way.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The design of the bicycle rack should permit the locking of the frame and at least one (1) wheel with a standard size "U" lock and accommodate the typical range of bicycle sizes.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The bicycle rack must resist removal, resist rust, corrosion and vandalism, and must be properly maintained.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Other forms of storage. At the owner's option, bicycle parking may also be installed in the form of storage rooms, lockers or cages.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Signage and markings. All bicycle parking spaces shall be posted with a permanent and properly maintained above-ground sign which shall conform to the figure entitled "Secured Bicycle Parking" hereby incorporated in this section. The bottom of the sign must be at least five (5) feet above grade when attached to a building, which may not be installed in the County maintained right-of-way. No permit shall be required for such signs.</section></section><section><section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Application to existing uses. All property owners of existing establishments that are required by this section to provide bicycle parking spaces shall comply within one (1) year from the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives and shall be responsible to maintain such facilities. Existing multifamily uses are exempt from this subsection.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-81, ยง 1, 7-13-99; Ord. No. 00-107, ยง 1, 9-7-00)</history></law>