<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. MOBILE HOMES AND MOBILE HOME PARKS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-168</section_number>
<catch_line>Use of mobile homes outside of mobile home parks.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004066</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-168. Use of mobile homes outside of mobile home parks.<section>It shall be unlawful to place, store, or use mobile homes in the unincorporated area of the County, outside of approved mobile home parks, except as follows:<section prefix='(A)'>Temporary occupancy during construction of a residence. A mobile home may be occupied as a residence for one (1) family only on a residential building site while a permanent residence is being constructed thereon under the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>That a building permit has been obtained for a permanent residential building on the site on which the mobile home is to be placed.</section><section prefix='(2)'>That the mobile home shall not be placed on such site until authorized sanitary waste facilities have been installed thereon.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A letter shall be submitted by the holder of the building permit explaining in detail the means of financing the construction, which will assure expeditious completion, such letter to also give assurance that the trailer will be maintained and occupied on the subject premises only so long as the original building permit is in full force and effect, which shall be an additional condition of the bond hereafter mentioned.</section><section prefix='(4)'>That the applicant give the County a cash or surety bond in the amount of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) guaranteeing:<section prefix='(a)'>That the mobile home shall remain on the building site only so long as the building permit is in full force and effect, and subject to the condition that no extension of time on the building permit and no completion permit for the resident shall extend the time for maintenance of the mobile home on the property unless substantial progress has been made on the construction of a permanent residential building as evidenced by progressive required inspections having been completed within the time limit permitted.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the mobile home will be removed from the premises upon the completion of the residential structure or when any provisions hereof have been violated.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The wheels shall not be removed from the mobile home.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The mobile home shall comply with Chapter 19A of this Code.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>The bond will be released by the Director when the mobile home is timely removed from the premises.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Watchman's quarters. A mobile home may be used as a watchman's quarters if approved after public hearing.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-54, ยง 1, 6-15-71)</history></law>