<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Fences and safety barriers for swimming pools.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003895</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-12. Fences and safety barriers for swimming pools.<section prefix='(a)'>Required for final inspection of pool. No final inspection and approval for a swimming pool shall be given by the Department, unless there has been erected a safety barrier as hereinafter provided. No pool shall be filled with water unless a final inspection has been made and approved, except for testing purposes as may be approved by the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Types permitted. The safety barrier shall take the form of a screened-in patio, a wooden fence, a wire fence, a rock wall, a concrete block wall or other materials, so as to enable the owner to blend the same with the style of architecture planned or in existence on the property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Height. The minimum height of the safety barrier shall be not less than four (4) feet.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Location of barrier. The safety barrier shall be erected either around the swimming pool or around the premises or a portion thereof on which the swimming pool is erected. In either event, it shall enclose the area entirely, prohibiting unrestrained admittance to the enclosed area. Pools located in enclosed structures or on the roofs of buildings shall not require the installation of barriers as required herein.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Gates. Gates shall be of the spring lock type, so that they shall automatically be in a closed and fastened position at all times. Gates shall also be equipped with a safe lock and shall be locked when the swimming pool is not in use.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Permits. Before any work is commenced, permits shall be secured for all swimming pools and for the safety barriers. Plans shall contain all details necessary to show compliance with the terms and conditions of this chapter. No swimming pool permit shall be issued unless simultaneously therewith a permit is secured for the erection of the required safety barrier, provided however, that in lieu of the permit for a safety barrier, a written statement from the owner certifying that he understands and agrees that the pool cannot be used or filled with water until a permit has been obtained for an approved safety barrier and such barrier erected, inspected and approved will be acceptable. This certification, however, will not eliminate the need for obtaining a permit and erecting an approved barrier prior to final inspection and use of the pool. If the premises are already enclosed, as hereinbefore provided, permit for the safety barrier shall not be required, if, upon inspection of the premises, the existing barrier and gates are proven to be satisfactory.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Wooden fences. In the wooden type fence, the boards, pickets, louvers, or other such members, shall be spaced, constructed, and erected, so as to make the fence nonclimbable and impenetrable.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Walls. Walls, whether of the rock or block type, shall be so erected to make them nonclimbable.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Wire fences. Wire fences shall be the two (2) inch chain link or diamond weave nonclimbable type, or of an approved equal, with top rail, they shall be of a heavy, galvanized material.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Refusal of permit. It shall be within the discretion of the Director to refuse approval of an barrier which, in his opinion, does not furnish the safety requirements of this section, i.e., that is high enough and so constructed to keep the children of preschool age from getting over or through it.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Maintenance. It shall be the responsibility of the owner and/or occupant of the premises upon which the swimming pool is hereafter erected to maintain and keep in proper and safe condition the safety barrier required and erected in accordance with this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 5, (CC), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 64-53, § 1, 10-23-64; Ord. No. 74-33, §§ 1, 2, 5-7-74; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98)</history></law>