<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XA. EDUCATIONAL AND CHILD CARE FACILITIES, NONPUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-151.13</section_number>
<catch_line>Zoning district requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004026</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-151.13. Zoning district requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>All day nurseries, after-school centers, kindergartens and private schools shall meet the requirements included herein and the requirements of the particular zoning district in which they are located if that district is one (1) in which the facility is a permitted use; facilities in other districts shall meet RU-3 requirements.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, office developments in the RU-5, and RU-5A Districts (i) that contain a platted lot of not less than five (5) acres net approved under one (1) site plan, and under one (1) ownership with a recorded unity of title agreement, and (ii) that include day nursery, kindergarten or after school care space, shall be eligible for a floor area bonus of three (3) square feet for each square foot of floor area dedicated to child care use, subject to the following requirements and entitlements:<section prefix='(1)'>Physical standards for the licensed child care facility shall be as provided in Section 33-151.18 and elsewhere in this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The outdoor area provided in connection with any licensed child care facility qualifying under this Subsection (b) shall be included in the calculation of open space required to be provided in the zoning district in which the facility is located. As a condition of qualifying for inclusion in the calculation of total required open space, the outdoor area shall be shown in the plot use or site plan required by Section 33-151.15. The required plot use or site plan shall establish (A) direct proximity or protected access between the child care facility and the open area; (B) adequate provisions for safety in the outdoor area; and (C) reasonable provisions for integrating use and enjoyment of the outdoor area both for child care and for other uses at the site.</section><section prefix='(3)'>For each square foot of floor area dedicated to child care use under this Subsection (b), an additional three (3) square feet of floor area for uses other than the child care use at the site shall be allowed in calculating the maximum floor area ratio permitted in the zoning district in which the child care facility is provided. As a condition of approving the plot use or site plan required by Section 33-151.15, the Director shall require a recorded covenant establishing (A) the calculations and conditions upon which the additional square footage has been permitted; and (B) restricting the area designated for child care to child care use only.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding any other provisions of Chapter 33 to the contrary, horses used to provide therapy as a part of the curriculum of private schools primarily dedicated to the education of developmentally disabled children as specified in Section 393.063, Florida Statutes, shall be permitted in conjunction with school use that has been approved in the EU-1, EU-2, GU and AU zoning districts. The number of horses and the location of the accessory structure(s) to house them shall comply with the underlying zoning district regulations.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-59, ยง 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 90-145, ยง 1, 12-18-90; Ord. No. 09-105, ยง 1, 11-17-09)</history></law>