<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. MOBILE HOMES AND MOBILE HOME PARKS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-169.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Applications for zoning action or development permits on property utilized as a mobile home park.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004068</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-169.1. Applications for zoning action or development permits on property utilized as a mobile home park.<section prefix='(a)'>Applications for a zoning action or development permit on properties utilized as an existing mobile home park at the time the application is filed shall be approved only upon a determination that (1) approval of the application would not result in the removal or relocation of mobile home owners residing in the mobile home park or (2) adequate mobile home parks or other suitable alternative affordable housing exists for the relocation of the mobile home owners.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Applications for zoning action or development permit on properties utilized as mobile home parks at the time of filing shall include the following information, which shall be presented in a sworn statement by the applicant and the owner of the property:<section prefix='(1)'>The total number of mobile homes in the park that are owned and occupied by mobile home or manufactured home owners; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The range of rents and number of mobile home and manufactured home spaces occupied and of tenants renting mobile home park owned units; and a summary of the number of mobile home owner and manufactured home owner leases or mobile home tenant rental agreements currently in place; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>A report indicating the number of lots occupied by mobile home owners or manufactured home owners; in addition the report shall list the number of units owned by the mobile home park owner and shall include the number of tenants residing in those mobile home units. In addition, the list shall identify how many owner occupied mobile homes or manufactured homes are suitable for relocation. The relocation and alternative housing plan shall include potential mobile home parks with lots suitable for the units that can be relocated; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>An estimate of the household profile for each household within the park, including an estimate of the number of adults, and number of children under eighteen years of age, and whether pets have been allowed in the park. Replacement units identified should be suitable for similar household profiles; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>A list of other mobile home parks or other suitable relocation facilities within a 10-mile radius of the subject mobile home park and located near public transit facilities, describing the number and size of available vacant units or vacant replacement lots at the time of the application is filed, that are of a similar cost profile as that of the mobile home or manufactured home owners residing in the application property. This list will include, at a minimum, the name and address of the park, park contact name and phone number, the number of vacant spaces available, the lot sizes, park guidelines on age and description of available or acceptable units for relocation of mobile homes or manufactured homes. The report shall include the number of rental units or vacant replacement lots available and the rental costs of such units or replacement lots. All parks or other suitable affordable housing alternative facilities must be located within a ten-mile radius of the subject property and located near a public transit facility and serve the same general age, household, and occupancy profiles as the subject property. In the event that the existing park is not within 10 miles of a public transit facility, the comparison search area radius may be extended to 15 miles; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Submittal of a relocation and alternative housing protection plan detailing the anticipated timing for park closure, a tenant communication plan and actions the mobile home park owner will take to refer mobile home park residents to alternative public and private housing resources and other forms of assistance that may be voluntarily offered by the mobile home park owner and assistance to mobile home park residents to obtain applicable benefits through the state of Florida Mobile Home Relocation Corporation; and</section><section prefix='(7)'>A sworn affidavit by the mobile home park owner and operator that they will, in good faith, comply with state laws concerning the sale of the park and notification to park residents.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to the application information to be provided in Section 33-169.1(b) the Director shall review the history of code enforcement actions on the subject property and status information of all code enforcement cases initiated by Miami-Dade County departments.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-58, ยง 4, 9-21-10)</history></law>