<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004098</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.6. Definitions.<section>The following words and phrases, as used in this article, have the following meanings:<section prefix='(1)'>Application means any request for zoning action, building permit, administrative site plan review, or administrative modification under Chapter 33, or any request for approval or extension of approval of any type of application for subdivision of land pursuant to Chapter 28, where such request seeks approval to develop residential or mixed uses subject to the requirements of this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>At one location means all land owned by the applicant, including:<section prefix='(a)'>All adjacent parcels, the property lines of which are contiguous at any point; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>All adjacent parcels, the property lines of which are separated only by a public or private street, road, highway or utility right-of-way, or other public or private right-of-way at any point; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>All adjacent parcels, under common ownership or control of the applicant, including land owned or controlled by any business entities in which the applicant or immediate family members of the applicant possesses any form of management control.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Transit corridor area is the area which lies within a one-half mile radius of the Metrorail stations.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Urban Infill Area (UIA) is the area as defined in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP).</section><section prefix='(5)'>Work-force housing unit or WHU shall mean a dwelling unit, the sale, rental or pricing of which in accordance with this article is restricted to households whose income is within the workforce housing target income range.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Workforce housing target income range means households whose income range is established at 65% up to 140% of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. HUD as maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>