<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. OFF-STREET PARKING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-127</section_number>
<catch_line>Districts where parking area permitted between setback line and right-of-way.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003997</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-127. Districts where parking area permitted between setback line and right-of-way.<section>No parking areas including driveways except for minimum ingress and egress drives in the RU, EU, AU, GU and RU-5 (with the exception of RU-5A), Districts shall be located closer than twenty-five (25) feet to an official right-of-way except parking areas for single-family, two-family, three- and four-unit apartment uses.</section><section>In the RU-1 and RU-2 Districts and single-family, two-family, three-unit apartment and four-unit apartment users in the RU-3 District, front, side, and side street setback areas may be used for off-street parking if said area is of sufficient depth to permit the parking of vehicles. Parking in the BU Districts shall be permitted between the required setback line and the official right-of-way line, providing a continuous, extensively planted greenbelt of not less than five (5) feet shall be placed along all property lines abutting said official right-of-way line. Parking in the IU-1, IU-2, IU-3 Districts shall be permitted between the required setback line and the official right-of-way line providing that greenbelt requirements as provided elsewhere in this chapter are satisfied. In no event may parking areas located in the setback areas be sheltered or enclosed in any manner.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 5(BB)(5), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 64-19, ยง 3, 5-5-64; Ord. No. 68-29, ยง 1, 5-21-68; Ord. No. 91-36, ยง 1, 3-19-91)</history></law>