<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. OFF-STREET PARKING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-128</section_number>
<catch_line>Location on same lot as use; exceptions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003998</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-128. Location on same lot as use; exceptions.<section prefix='(a)'>Off-street parking areas shall be located on the same lot, parcel or premises as the use to be served; provided, if the use to be served is a business or commercial use, the parking area therefor may be on a lot or parcel of land that is in an IU or BU District and is within three hundred feet (300′) from the site of such business or commercial use to be served; provided such business or commercial use shall immediately terminate in the event such parking area therefor is not available and all those having any right, title or interest in and to such business or commercial use property site shall execute and place on the public records of this County a covenant approved by the Director that such business or commercial use shall cease and terminate upon the elimination of such parking area, and that no business or commercial use shall be made of such property until the required parking area is available and provided.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Off-street parking areas shall be located on the same lot, parcel or premises as the use to be served; provided, if the use to be served is an apartment building, the parking area therefor may be located on a lot or parcel of land that is in the same apartment district which permits the use, or more liberal apartment or business district and within three hundred feet (300′) from the site of such apartment structure to be served, said distance to be measured by the normal and legal way a pedestrian would travel; provided such apartment use shall immediately terminate in the event such parking area therefor is not available and all parties having any right, title or interest in and to such apartment shall execute and place on the public records of this County a covenant approved by the Director that such apartment use shall cease and terminate upon the elimination of such parking area, and that no apartment or other use shall be made of such property until the required parking area is available and provided.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 5(BB)(6), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 62-23, § 2, 6-5-62; Ord. No. 70-18, § 1, 3-11-70)</history></law>