<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='3'>ARTICLE XIV. RU-1, SINGLE-FAMILY RESIDENTIAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-199</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses—Permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004116</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-199. Uses—Permitted.<section>No land, body of water and/or structure shall be used or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed, structurally altered or maintained for any purpose in a RU-1 District which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose other than the following, unless otherwise specifically provided herein:<section prefix='(1)'>Every use as a one-family residence, including every customary use not inconsistent therewith, including a private garage.</section><section prefix='(1.1)'>Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of Article XIIA of this code.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Municipal recreation building, playgrounds, parks or reservations owned and operated by a municipality, County, State or the United States Government.</section><section prefix='(2.1)'>Private recreation area, private recreation building or playground owned and maintained by a homeowner's or tenant association, provided same is approved in conjunction with approval of the subdivision at time of site plan approval or plat.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Golf courses.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Business telephone will be permitted in a residence provided no truck, heavy equipment, or similar vehicle is kept on the property and no storage or any other business activity is carried on.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Noncommercial boat piers or slips for docking of private watercraft incidental to an existing residential use, except houseboats without power.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Servants' quarters, only upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Noncommercial pigeon lofts, provided the pigeons shall be housed in a structure meeting the requirements of the building code and the requirements of these regulations for accessory buildings; the activity shall be conducted in a manner meeting the requirements of the Health Department, provided birds shall not be exercised later than two (2) hours after sunrise and more than two (2) hours before sunset.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Code, family day care and after-school care for children is permitted upon compliance with the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That the total number of children on the premises does not exceed five (5) in number, including in the count only preschool children of the resident family. Preschool children shall consist of children five (5) years of age or younger.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the age of the children, excluding those of the resident family, shall not exceed eleven (11) years of age.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That the applicant secure a license from the Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Service to operate a family day care home at the subject property.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Where applicable, compliance with the requirements of this Code pertaining to educational and child care facilities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Upon compliance with all conditions enumerated, a certificate of use and occupancy is secured from the Department.</section><section prefix='(f)'>That the facility shall comply with the safety barrier requirements and restrictions enumerated in Section 33-151.18(j).</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>A group home shall be permitted in a dwelling unit provided:<section prefix='(a)'>That the total number of resident clients on the premises not exceed six (6) in number.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the operation of the facility be licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services and that said Department or sponsoring agency promptly notify the Director of the Building and Zoning Department of said licensure no later than the time of home occupancy.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That the structure used for a group home shall be located at least one thousand (1,000) feet from another existing, unabandoned legally established group home. The 1,000-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use.</section></section><section prefix='(11)'>Reserved.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 8(A), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 58-41, § 2, 10-21-58; Ord. No. 63-16, § 3, 5-7-63; Ord. No. 68-1, § 3, 1-9-68; Ord. No. 79-78, § 1, 10-2-79; Ord. No. 80-28, § 1, 4-15-80; Ord. No. 81-25, § 1, 3-17-81; Ord. No. 81-26, § 3, 3-17-81; Ord. No. 81-60, § 1, 6-2-81; Ord. No. 90-115, § 2, 10-16-90; Ord. No. 90-117, § 1, 10-16-90; Ord. No. 91-51, §§ 2, 3, 5-7-91; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 99-122, § 2, 9-21-99; Ord. No. 07-05, § 2, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>