<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. MOBILE HOMES AND MOBILE HOME PARKS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-176</section_number>
<catch_line>Utilities and services.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004076</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-176. Utilities and services.<section>All mobile homes shall be connected to public water and sewer lines (unless temporary package sewage disposal plants and water treatment plants are approved by the Pollution Control Officer and Public Health Department). All telephone and TV cables, if any, and all electrical cables and lines shall be installed underground.</section><section>Necessary access and turnarounds with a minimum turning radius of sixty-six (66) feet for fire-fighting, garbage and waste collection and other service vehicular equipment shall be provided. Any private dead-end access way of more than two hundred (200) feet in length shall have a cul-de-sac at the dead end with a minimum turn radius of sixty-six (66) feet.</section><section>Garbage and waste collection areas shall be screened by hedges or decorative walls and shall be placed in locations as approved by the Department of Solid Waste Management for the convenience of collection and for sanitation purposes. Such requirements shall not apply to garbage receptacles at individual mobile home spaces.</section><section>Area lighting shall be designed to produce a minimum of 0.1 foot candle throughout the street system and public use areas. Potentially hazardous locations such as, but not limited to, major street intersections and steps or pedestrian ramps shall be individually illuminated with a minimum of 0.3 foot candle with no greater foot candle differential than 5 to 1 between adjacent areas.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-54, ยง 1, 6-15-71)</history></law>