<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative intent, findings, and purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004096</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.4. Legislative intent, findings, and purpose.<section prefix='A.'>Need for workforce housing in Miami-Dade County. The health, safety, and welfare of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County depend on the availability of a range of housing choices affordable to persons and families of all income levels in all areas of Miami-Dade County. Current patterns of development have resulted in a persistent shortage of housing for certain sectors of the community. Studies of market demand show that for the foreseeable future more than 50% of the new labor force in Miami-Dade County will require moderately priced housing units. Currently, there exists in Miami-Dade County a shortage of housing affordable to individuals and families of moderate incomes, particularly those whose earnings range from 65% to 140% of the County's median income, the "workforce target income group." The workforce target income group includes many public employees and others employed in key occupations that support the local community. Increasingly, the high cost and short supply of housing affordable to persons and families of moderate income mean that many employees in the workforce target income group cannot afford to live in Miami-Dade County, while others can only afford to live in areas concentrated according to price and income level.</section><section>The uneven distribution of moderately-priced housing results in additional stratification of housing according to price and income level. It is in the best interests of the public health, safety, and welfare of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County to reduce or eliminate such economic stratification by adopting land use regulations that encourage development of land available for residential use in Miami-Dade County in a manner that emphasizes integration of new housing for individuals and families in the workforce target income group into new, expanding, or redeveloping neighborhoods.</section><section>The uneven geographic distribution of housing affordable to the workforce target income group, as well as the distance between jobs and available housing, also increase traffic congestion and decrease economic productivity. Traffic and roadway congestion in turn adversely affect the environment and diminish air quality, increasing the burden on the public health care system and resulting in rising health care costs. The public health, safety, and welfare of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County can best be protected by adopting land use policies to ensure that housing affordable to the workforce target income group is distributed throughout the county near workplaces, rather than being concentrated in enclaves separate from jobs and higher-priced housing.</section><section>The Florida Growth Management Act requires Miami-Dade County to adopt a comprehensive plan to guide future development and growth, including a housing element consisting of standards, plans, and principles to be followed in the provision of housing for all current and anticipated future residents. Exercising the authority conferred by the Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter, and in furtherance of the Growth Management Act, the Board of County Commissioners has adopted the Comprehensive Development Master Plan ("CDMP"), including a housing element which establishes goals, objectives, and policies to ensure the provision of all variations of affordable housing products to meet the spatial and economic necessities of all current and future residents regardless of household type or income.</section><section prefix='B.'>Causes and consequences of lack of sufficient workforce housing supply. In order to assess the extent of the housing shortage, identify the most severely affected sectors of the community, and ascertain the need for a workforce housing development program, the Board of County Commissioners established a task force consisting of county housing, zoning, and planning professionals, and representatives of the private, for-profit, development community. The mission of the task force was to analyze the current and anticipated future make-up of Miami-Dade County's workforce and population, the geographic distribution of moderately-priced housing, historical and current patterns of development applications and approvals, the distance between jobs and housing for the workforce target income group, the overall impact of the housing shortage on the economy of Miami-Dade County, and the adverse consequences failure to act would have on the health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County. The need for the workforce housing development program as identified by the task force is the result of a variety of factors, including, but not limited to, those noted below.<section prefix='(1)'>Increasing population pressure. Miami-Dade County, in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas, is experiencing a rapid increase in the numbers of residents in the workforce target income group, including persons with fixed or reduced incomes, young adults forming new households, minority households, single adults, and many public employees and others in key occupations serving the entire community including teachers, police and public safety personnel, health care workers and mid-level management workers. Studies show that, as a result of this population increase, for the foreseeable future more than one-half of the new labor force in Miami-Dade County will require workforce housing.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Cost burdens. Households in Miami-Dade County suffer from a high and increasing housing cost burden. Households have traditionally been regarded as "cost burdened" if they spend more than 30% of their gross income on housing costs. In Miami-Dade County, nearly 51% of all renter households pay more than 30% of their income in gross rent. In owner-occupied units, more than 36% of all households pay more than 30% of their income on housing.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Inadequate housing supply for the workforce target income group. Current patterns of development, the costs of acquiring land suitable for residential development, and the disposition of remaining developable land have resulted in an abundance of higher-priced housing and a shortage of housing economically attainable by the workforce target income group. With the exception of housing developed with government subsidies, privately developed new residential housing being built in Miami-Dade County generally is not affordable to the workforce target income group. Experience indicates that state and federal funds for the construction of affordable housing will not address the housing needs of the workforce target income group.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Overcrowding. Overcrowding is a major problem in Miami-Dade County. The problem is acute in low to moderate income households and households in the workforce target income group. Analyses indicate nearly 20% of all housing units in Miami-Dade County are overcrowded.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Concentration of housing based on economic status. Demographic analyses indicate that development applications and approvals that reduce the supply of land developable for residential use, and which result in a disproportionate amount of higher-priced housing, result in a reduced supply of housing for individuals and families in the workforce target income group, including young families, retired and elderly persons, single adults, female heads of houses, and minority households. Such development activity produces the undesirable and unacceptable effect of concentrating housing according to price, thus frustrating the policies and goals of the housing element of the CDMP, and increasing the threat to the public health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Need for involvement of private development community. Existing efforts to encourage private, for-profit, developers to construct housing within the economic reach of the workforce target income group have met with very limited success. It is apparent that the need for housing for the workforce target income group can only be addressed if the responsibility for ensuring a diverse and adequate supply of housing is shared by Miami-Dade County, and the private, for-profit, development community.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Authority to establish and administer a workforce housing development program. The Miami-Dade County Home Rule Charter specifically authorizes the Board of County Commissioners to prepare and enforce comprehensive plans for the development of Miami-Dade County in the incorporated and unincorporated areas, to establish, coordinate, and enforce such zoning regulations as are necessary for the protection of the public, to exercise all powers and privileges granted to municipalities, counties and county officers by the Constitution and laws of the State, to exercise all powers not prohibited by the Constitution or by the Charter, and to perform any other acts consistent with law which are required by the Charter or which are in the common interest of the people of the County. The workforce housing development program of Miami-Dade County is declared to be a proper and necessary exercise of the powers conferred upon the Board of County Commissioners for the protection of the health, safety, welfare, comfort, and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>Consistent with the goals, objectives, and policies of the land use and housing elements of the CDMP, the objective of the workforce housing development program is to increase the supply of housing affordable to the workforce target income group, and to address many of the problems associated with the short supply of housing affordable to the workforce target income group and with the uneven, poor geographic distribution of such housing throughout Miami-Dade County. Through utilization of a combination of density bonuses, relaxation of intensity standards, flexible design criteria, and other incentives, the workforce housing program established herein will help alleviate the existing housing shortage by making it more feasible for the private, for-profit, development community to create and deliver a greater number of housing units affordable to the workforce target income group. Dispersal of workforce housing units throughout this community will avoid overconcentration of such housing.</section><section prefix='D.'>Joint effort of private development community, public sector, and not-for-profit sector. It is the further intent of the Board of County Commissioners that the workforce housing development program established herein will foster and encourage the private, for-profit, development community to join with the public sector and the nonprofit sector to further the goal of meeting the housing needs of the workforce target income group.</section><section prefix='E.'>Adoption of legislative intent, findings and purpose. The foregoing statements are declared to be the legislative intent, findings and purpose of the Board of County Commissioners and are hereby adopted and made a part hereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>