<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. PUBLIC CHARTER SCHOOL FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-155</section_number>
<catch_line>Required information.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004039</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-155. Required information.<section>All public charter school facilities, as defined in this article, shall submit the following applicable information to the Department in accordance with the filing provisions of Article XXXVI of this code for review by the Department and for consideration at public hearing:<section prefix='(A)'>Written information<section prefix='(1)'>Total size of the site</section><section prefix='(2)'>Maximum number of students to be served</section><section prefix='(3)'>Maximum number of teachers and administrative and clerical personnel</section><section prefix='(4)'>Maximum number of classrooms and total square footage of classroom space</section><section prefix='(5)'>Total square footage of non-classroom space</section><section prefix='(6)'>Amount and location of exterior recreational/play area in square footage</section><section prefix='(7)'>Maximum number and type of vehicles that will be used in conjunction with the operation of the facility</section><section prefix='(8)'>Number of parking spaces provided for staff, visitors, and transportation and operation vehicles, and justification that those spaces are sufficient for this facility</section><section prefix='(9)'>Grades or age groups that will be served</section><section prefix='(10)'>Days and hours of operation, weekly and annually</section><section prefix='(11)'>An explanation of any such activities anticipated to be conducted in association with the charter school but typically conducted outside of the hours of operation of the charter school</section><section prefix='(12)'>Means of compliance with requirements by the Miami-Dade County Fire Department, Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health, the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, and any Federal or State regulations applicable to the specific application</section><section prefix='(13)'>A copy of the charter approved by the Miami-Dade County Public School Board.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Graphic information. The following graphic information shall be prepared by design professionals, such as registered Florida architects and landscape architects:<section prefix='(1)'>A plan indicating existing zoning on the site and adjacent areas</section><section prefix='(2)'>A site plan indicating the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Location of all structures</section><section prefix='(b)'>Parking layout, automobile stacking area and drives</section><section prefix='(c)'>Walkways</section><section prefix='(d)'>Location of recreation areas and play equipment which shall include surrounding fences and/or walls</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any other features which can appropriately be shown in plan form.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Floor plans and elevations of all proposed structures.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Landscape development plan listing quantities, size, and names of all plants in accordance with Chapter 18A of this code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-108, ยง 1, 6-8-04)</history></law>