<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. PUBLIC CHARTER SCHOOL FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-154</section_number>
<catch_line>Limitations on the siting of public charter school facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004038</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-154. Limitations on the siting of public charter school facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>New kindergarten, elementary, middle and senior high charter school facilities as well as the expansion of existing charter school facilities shall be prohibited on sites located outside the Urban Development Boundary (UDB), as established in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Except as provided in subsection (c) below, the following new charter school facilities and the expansion of such facilities shall be located inside the UDB and spaced from the UDB as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Kindergarten, Elementary school: at least ¼ mile inside the UDB</section><section prefix='(2)'>Middle school: at least ½ mile inside the UDB</section><section prefix='(3)'>Senior high school: at least one mile inside the UDB.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>A proposed new kindergarten, elementary, middle, or senior high charter school facility, or the expansion of an existing charter school site, inside but closer to the UDB than indicated in (b) above, may be approved at public hearing, when it is demonstrated that within a one-half mile radius of the outer boundaries of the proposed new charter school or charter school expansion site:<section prefix='(1)'>that the majority of the lots, parcels or tracts lying within the radius are developed or approved for development; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>there are no other lots, parcels or tracts within the radius that are available for development that meet the requirements of subsection (b) above and that meet all the requirements of this article.</section></section><section>Approval of such a site shall require that the majority of the subject site and the proposed buildings' ground floor square footage be located in accordance with (b) above, and that the principal buildings and entrances be placed as far from the UDB as possible.</section><section prefix='(d)'>For purposes of establishing the distances provided by this section, the applicant shall furnish a certified survey from a registered surveyor, as well as a proposed site plan, which shall indicate that the distance requirements of this section have been met.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-108, § 1, 6-8-04)</history></law>