<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XA. EDUCATIONAL AND CHILD CARE FACILITIES, NONPUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-151.14</section_number>
<catch_line>Private colleges and universities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004027</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-151.14. Private colleges and universities.<section prefix='(A)'>Main campus requirements. Private colleges and universities with sites of thirty (30) acres or less shall meet the minimum standards established herein for high school facilities. Above thirty (30) acres, in addition to said minimum standards, said facilities shall be subject to intensive review by the Department and the County Commission utilizing the study entitled "Physical Standards for Proposed Private Educational Facilities in Unincorporated Miami-Dade County," adopted pursuant to Resolution No. R-633-77.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Exception for Satellite Classroom Facilities. The requirements set forth in subsection (a) above or any other section of this Article shall not apply to satellite facilities either owned or leased by private colleges or universities located in either a shopping center in a BU-2 or more liberal BU district or in an industrial park in an IU-1 or more liberal IU District, where the shopping center or industrial park is not less than twenty-five (25) acres under one (1) ownership of title, unity of title, or a declaration in lieu of unity of title, with an approved plan showing at least 200,000 square feet of building area with facilities for parking for not less than three hundred (300) vehicles. A satellite classroom facility is a permitted use within such a shopping center or industrial park, provided that it satisfies the following requirements: (a) the total cumulative square footage of all satellite classroom facilities located in a shopping center or industrial park shall be less than fifty (50) percent of the square footage of the shopping center or industrial park; (b) the satellite classroom facility shall be located at least five (5) miles away from the main campus of the private college or university; and (c) the total cumulative square footage of the satellite classroom facilities located in a shopping center shall not exceed ten (10) percent of the total cumulative classroom square footage located at the main campus of the private college or university. For the purposes of this subsection (B), distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the front door of the proposed satellite classroom facility to the nearest point of the main campus grounds. All satellite classroom facilities must comply with the parking requirements set forth in Section 33-124(1)(3). Applicants for satellite classroom facilities shall submit to the Department an affidavit setting forth the total cumulative classroom square footage located at the main campus of the private college or university. A school bookstore selling both new and used books shall be permitted to operate as an ancillary use in connection with satellite classroom facilities provided that the square footage of such bookstore does not exceed ten (10) percent of the total cumulative classroom square footage located at the shopping center or industrial park. The square footage of such a bookstore shall be included in the total cumulative classroom square footage at the shopping center for the purposes of this subsection (B).</section><section prefix='(C)'>Exception for Commuter Colleges/Universities. The requirements set forth in subsection (A) above or any other section of this article shall not apply to commuter colleges/universities.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Exception for Allied Health Care Clinical Colleges/Universities. The requirements set forth in subsection (a) above or any other section of this article shall not apply to allied health care clinical colleges/universities. An allied health care clinical college/university shall be located on a site containing a minimum lot area of not less than 1 gross acre and a maximum of five (5) gross acres and shall front on a major roadway (three (3) lanes or more). No allied health care clinical college/university shall exceed 30,000 gross square feet in size, of which the clinic shall not exceed 20 percent of the total gross area or a maximum of 3,000 square feet, whichever is less. Prior to building permit issuance, each allied health care clinical college/university shall be subject to an administrative site plan review (ASPR) in accordance with the applicable standards of the district where located, as provided in Sections 33-245.2, 33-251.5, 33-253.9 and 33-256.8 of this code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-59, § 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 00-55, § 1, 5-9-00; Ord. No. 07-75, § 1, 6-5-07; Ord. No. 09-102, § 2, 11-17-09; Ord. No. 10-08, § 2, 2-2-10)</history></law>