<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. MOBILE HOMES AND MOBILE HOME PARKS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-174</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum yard areas (setbacks) for mobile homes on mobile home space.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004074</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-174. Minimum yard areas (setbacks) for mobile homes on mobile home space.<section prefix='(a)'>A setback for mobile homes of at least five (5) feet from both sides of the mobile home space, at least seven and one-half (7½) feet from the rear line of the space, and at least twelve and one-half (12½) feet (excluding hitch) from the front line of the space (adjacent to the access road) shall be provided; provided that any porch or other addition to the mobile home will be regarded as a part of the mobile home for the purpose of setbacks and spacing, and further provided that no mobile home or additions thereto shall be located closer than fifteen (15) feet to any other mobile home or any of its habitable additions, and ten (10) feet from any other structure or addition.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Mobile homes, their porches and other additions to mobile homes existing prior to June 25, 1971 or which have been established subsequent to said date pursuant to Section 33-170(B) shall comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>No porch, other addition, or awning shall be constructed within ten (10) feet of another mobile home, addition, porch, awning, or other structure or building.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No part of a mobile home, including, but not limited to, its porch, wall, or awning column shall be closer than five (5) feet to the limits of a mobile home site.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In no event shall the wall or supporting columns of any additions extend more than ten (10) feet from the limits of the mobile home to which it pertains.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No eave, or overhang, or roof of a mobile home addition shall extend beyond the wall or column more than one (1) foot.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No porch shall exceed eight (8) feet in height at the eave except that this height limitation shall not prevent the use of a portable canvas shelter over the roof of the mobile home.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Only one (1) porch shall be permitted to a mobile home.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A building permit shall be obtained from the Department before any construction is begun on a porch addition. Accompanying the application for a building permit shall be an accurate plot plan showing size of porch and distances to mobile home site boundaries and to adjacent mobile homes, mobile home porch additions, and other structures or buildings.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>A variation to these setback provisions may be permitted if approved after a special exception hearing based on site plan submitted, these variations to permit flexibility of design and layout that will still conform to the purpose and intent of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-54, § 1, 6-15-71; Ord. No. 73-38, § 2, 4-3-73; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>