<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XA. EDUCATIONAL AND CHILD CARE FACILITIES, NONPUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-151.19</section_number>
<catch_line>Review standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004032</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-151.19. Review standards.<section>The following review standards shall be utilized by the Department, and, where a hearing is required, by the public hearing body.<section prefix='(a)'>Study guide. The study entitled "Physical Standards for Proposed Private Educational Facilities in Unincorporated Miami-Dade County," date 1977, shall be used as a general guide in the review of proposed nonpublic educational facilities; provided, however, that in no case shall the educational philosophy of a school be considered in the evaluation of the application.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Planning and neighborhood studies. Planning and neighborhood studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include recommendations relevant to the facility site shall be used in the review process.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Scale. Scale of proposed nonpublic educational facilities shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses and shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Compatibility. The design of the nonpublic educational facilities shall be compatible with the design, kind and intensity of uses and scale of the surrounding area.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Buffers. Buffering elements shall be utilized for visual screening and substantial reduction of noise levels at all property lines where necessary.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Landscape. Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing the removal of trees or the alteration of favorable characteristics of the site. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Circulation. Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the facility and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the facility.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Noise. Where noise from such sources as automobile traffic is a problem, effective measures shall be provided to reduce such noise to acceptable levels.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Service areas. Wherever service areas are provided they shall be screened and so located as not to interfere with the livability of the adjacent residential properties.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Parking areas. Parking areas shall be screened and so located as not to interfere with the livability of the adjacent residential properties.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Operating time. The operational hours of a nonpublic educational facility shall be such that the impact upon the immediate residential neighborhood is minimized.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Industrial and commercial. Where schools are permitted in industrial or commercial areas it shall be clearly demonstrated in graphic form how the impact of the commercial or industrial area has been minimized through design techniques.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Fences and walls. Recreation and/or play areas shall be enclosed with fences and/or walls.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-59, ยง 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 86-27, ยง 2, 4-1-86; Ord. No. 95-223, ยง 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>