<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. OFF-STREET PARKING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-124</section_number>
<catch_line>Standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003993</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-124. Standards.<section>Off-street parking shall be provided in accordance with the following minimum standards:<section prefix='(a)'>Dwellings:<section prefix='(1)'>Single-family dwellings not specifically referenced elsewhere in this section shall be provided two (2) parking spaces. Paving of said spaces shall not be required.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Two-, three- and four-unit dwellings shall be provided two (2) parking spaces per unit.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Townhouses shall be provided a minimum of two (2) off-street parking spaces per townhouse unit. Such parking spaces may be provided on the lot of the townhouses or in a commonly owned and maintained off-street parking bay or facility; provided, that no parking space shall be more than one hundred fifty (150) feet, by the most direct pedestrian route, from the door of the townhouse to the parking space it is intended to serve.<section>Each townhouse site shall have its own off-street parking area and driveway thereto where on-site off-street parking is to be provided. In addition to the above required residents off-street parking spaces, a minimum of twenty-five hundredths (0.25) visitors parking spaces per townhouse shall be provided in a convenient commonly owned and maintained off-street parking bay or facility. Individual garages shall not be credited towards the parking requirement.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Cluster communities shall have two and one-quarter (2.25) parking spaces provided for each dwelling unit either on the individually owned lot(s) or on common property. Tandem parking is permitted only on individual lots and in the driveways connecting such lots with the adjacent roads provided said driveways are for the exclusive use of each individual lot; however, tandem parking shall be limited to no more than one (1) such tandem parking space for each individual lot. Individual garages shall not be credited towards the parking requirement.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Zero lot line communities shall have a minimum of two (2) off-street parking spaces provided on each platted lot.<section>In addition, zero lot line communities shall provide one (1) guest parking space for every four (4) dwelling units for all projects, except for those developed on public streets.</section><section>Tandem parking is permitted only on individual lots and in the driveways connecting such lots with the adjacent roads; provided, said driveways are for the exclusive use of each individual lot; however, tandem parking shall be limited to no more than one (1) such tandem parking space for each individual lot. Individual garages shall not be credited towards the parking requirement.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Five (5) or more unit apartment buildings or apartment hotels:<section>One and one-half (1.50) parking spaces for each guest room, efficiency, or one (1) bedroom unit.</section><section>One and three-quarters (1.75) parking spaces for each two-bedroom unit.</section><section>Two (2.0) parking spaces for each three- or more bedroom unit.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>A minimum of two (2) off-street parking spaces shall be provided for each mobile home space, both such parking spaces may be on the mobile home space, and each of the same shall be hard surfaced, or one (1) or both parking spaces may be in a common parking court, such courts, where provided, to be installed throughout the park to conveniently serve the inhabitants in different areas of the park, and such courts shall be hard surfaced.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Hotels, rooming houses. At least one (1) parking space for each of the first forty (40) individual guest rooms or suites; one (1) additional parking space for every two (2) guest rooms or suites thereafter. Public meeting rooms in hotels shall be further controlled as to parking by Subsection (e) of this section and by Subsection (k) where the meeting room does not contain permanent seats; and restaurants by Subsections (i) and (j). In addition, one (1) parking space shall be provided for each four (4) employees.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Motels, tourist courts, bed and breakfast establishments, and transient accommodations. One (1) parking space for each individual sleeping room or bedroom.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Churches. At least one (1) parking space for each one hundred (100) square feet or fractional part thereof of the seating area in the main auditorium (sanctuary), including adjacent areas which may be used as part of the auditorium.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Hospitals. At least one (1) parking space for each of the first three hundred (300) beds and one (1) additional parking space for every two (2) additional beds thereafter for patients contained in such building, plus one (1) parking space for each three (3) employees and resident staff members.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Sanitariums, convalescent homes, homes for the aged and similar institutions. At least one (1) parking space for each two (2) beds for patients contained in such buildings, plus one (1) parking space for each two (2) employees.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Commercial:<section prefix='(1)'>Retail—Food or grocery stores, drug and sundry stores, department stores, membership warehouses, retail stores, retail stores similar to the foregoing, banks, post offices, mortuaries, funeral homes, waiting rooms stations for common carriers and shopping centers shall be provided parking at a rate of one (1) parking space for each and every two hundred fifty (250) square feet of the gross floor area or fractional part thereof. All retail uses within enclosed malls in excess of three hundred thousand (300,000) square feet shall provide parking at the rate of one (1) parking space for each and every three hundred and fifty (350) square feet of the gross floor area or fractional part thereof, excluding theaters, restaurants and food courts which shall provide parking as delineated in this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Auto dealership showrooms, garage and gas station bay areas, and similar uses shall be provided three (3) parking spaces for the first twenty-five hundred (2,500) square feet of floor area, or fractional part thereof, and one (1) parking space for each additional five hundred (500) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof, plus three (3) parking spaces for each five thousand (5,000) square feet, or fractional part thereof, of open lot area. Office and retail parts areas shall be provided parking spaces as otherwise contained in this article. Customer and employee parking shall be labeled as such.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Furniture showrooms shall be provided three (3) parking spaces for the first twenty-five hundred (2,500) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof, and one (1) parking space for each additional five hundred (500) square feet of gross floor area or fractional part thereof. When such a use is located within any BU District, the site plan submitted to the Department shall illustrate future parking spaces based on a calculation of one (1) parking space for each two hundred fifty (250) square feet of gross floor area or fractional part thereof, which shall be provided in the event the furniture use is discontinued. The lot area reserved for future parking spaces shall remain unencumbered with any structures and shall be landscaped. However, this landscaped area shall not be credited toward the minimum required open space. Prior to the issuance of a Certificate of Use and Occupancy for any use other than a furniture store, the property owner must provide the required number of parking spaces for the intended use as provided elsewhere in the article.</section><section prefix='(3.1)'>Home improvement centers, including all storage/sales areas, shall have parking provided at a rate of one parking space for each two hundred fifty (250) square feet of gross floor area or fractional part thereof.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Plant nurseries shall have parking provided at a rate of eight (8) spaces for the first acre, or fractional part thereof, and one (1) parking space for each two (2) acres thereafter up to ten (10) acres. One (1) additional parking space shall be provided for each five (5) acres or portion thereof thereafter.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Packing plants shall have parking provided at a rate of one (1) parking space for each one thousand (1,000) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Open lot commercial uses such as, but not limited to, used care lots, storage yards and recreational vehicle sales lots shall be provided five (5) off-street parking spaces for the first five thousand (5,000) square feet of net lot area, or fractional part thereof and one (1) parking space for each additional five hundred (500) square feet of net lot area so used. These spaces shall be reserved for customer and employee parking only, and shall be labeled as such.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Automobile gas stations/mini marts shall be provided one (1) parking space for each two hundred fifty square feet (250) of gross floor area or fractional part thereof, with a minimum of three (3) spaces which shall be designed so as not to interfere with the dispensing operation.<section prefix='(8)'>Wholesale showrooms in the industrial districts shall be provided one (1) parking space for each six hundred (600) square feet of showroom area, or fractional part thereof.</section><section prefix='(9)'>All commercial uses not identified in Subsections (1) through (7) above shall be provided three (3) parking spaces for the first twenty-five hundred (2,500) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof, and one (1) parking space for each and every additional five hundred (500) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Restaurants, lounges, nightclubs, or similar places dispensing food, drink or refreshments.<section prefix='(1)'>Table service establishments shall be provided one (1) parking space for each fifty (50) square feet of floor area, or fractional part thereof devoted to patron use.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Take-out establishments shall be provided one (1) parking space for each two hundred fifty (250) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof.</section></section><section prefix='(j)'>Adult Day Care Center, shall be provided with one (1) parking space for each five hundred (500) square feet of gross floor area, or equal to the combined total of personnel and transportation vehicles whichever is greater.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Recreational and entertainment use:<section prefix='(1)'>Art galleries, amusement centers, cultural centers, libraries and museums shall be provided one (1) parking space for each two hundred fifty (250) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Banquet halls, bingo halls, convention halls and private clubs shall be provided one (1) parking space for each one hundred (100) square feet of patron area, or fractional part thereof.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Bowling alleys, skating rinks, and indoor gun ranges shall be provided one (1) parking space per two hundred fifty (250) square feet of gross floor area, or fractional part thereof. Office, retail, restaurant and other areas in conjunction therewith shall have parking spaces provided as otherwise contained in this article.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Dance, karate, and aerobics schools, and health/exercise studios shall be provided one (1) parking space for each one hundred (100) square feet of classroom area, or fractional part thereof. Office, retail, and restaurant areas in conjunction therewith shall have parking spaces provided as otherwise contained in this article.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Golf courses shall be provided three (3) parking spaces per hole plus three (3) additional spaces. Office, retail, restaurant and other areas in conjunction therewith shall have parking provided as otherwise contained in this article.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Live-aboard marinas shall be provided one (1) parking space per boat slip.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Non-live-aboard marinas shall be provided one (1) parking space for each two (2) boat slips.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Boats stored in racks shall be provided one (1) parking space for each three (3) boat racks.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Stadiums and basketball gymnasiums shall be provided at least one (1) parking space for each four (4) seats.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Commercial tennis and racquetball clubs shall be provided four (4) parking spaces per court. Office, retail, and restaurant areas in conjunction therewith shall have parking provided as otherwise contained in this article.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Theaters, including move theaters, and general auditoriums shall be provided one (1) parking space for each one hundred (100) square feet of auditorium seating area or fractional part thereof.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Open lot recreational use parking requirements shall be determined by the Director and such requirements shall be based on the number of people that can reasonably be expected to be on such premises at one (1) time. Said determination shall be calculated on a basis of one (1) parking space for each four (4) persons.</section></section><section prefix='(l)'>Schools.<section prefix='(1)'>Day nurseries, kindergarten and elementary schools: Total parking spaces shall equal the combined total of personnel and transportation vehicles.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Junior high [schools]: Total parking spaces shall equal one and one-quarter (1¼) times the combined total of personnel and transportation vehicles.</section><section prefix='(3)'>High schools, trade schools and colleges: One (1) parking space per two hundred (200) square feet of classroom area, including laboratories, libraries and administrative areas. Housing facilities on college campuses must provide off-street parking of two (2) spaces for each three (3) sleeping rooms. Other such uses, such as restaurants, auditoriums, theaters, etc., shall provide parking as required in this section for such uses. In addition, in connection with the foregoing schools, one (1) parking space shall be required for each four (4) employees, excluding teachers.<section> In connection with the foregoing school use, parking required for church use may be credited toward parking requirements for school use, where the same are operated by the same ownership and on the same property.</section><section> The applicant shall submit information substantiating the personnel and vehicle figures used for computing the above parking requirements.</section></section></section><section prefix='(m)'>Office, professional building or similar uses. One (1) parking space for each three hundred (300) square feet of gross floor area of such building or fractional part thereof.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Industrial.<section prefix='(1)'>For a warehouse building, one (1) parking space shall be provided for each one thousand (1,000) square feet of gross floor area in the building up to ten thousand (10,000) square feet and then one (1) space for each two thousand (2,000) square feet of gross warehouse floor area thereafter. Office, retail and wholesale showroom areas provided in conjunction with the industrial use shall have parking spaces provided for such areas as otherwise contained in this article. Regardless of the intended mix of use, a minimum of two (2) parking spaces shall be provided for each bay in the building. In determining the number of bays, the Director shall take into account the possibility of partitioning the building into multiple units, the number and location of bathrooms, the number and location of overhead or other door openings, the layout of electrical circuits and air conditioning units, etc. In determining the number of spaces to be provided, the formula requiring the greatest number of parking spaces shall be applied.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where open lot or walled-in uses only are involved, such as salvage yards, batching plants, precast or prestressed concrete products, or the like, two (2) parking spaces for each five thousand (5,000) square feet of lot area shall be provided, or one (1) space for each two (2) employees shall be provided, whichever requires the greater number of parking spaces. Such parking spaces shall be located no farther than one thousand five hundred (1,500) feet from the industrial use in question. Such noncontiguous property to be used for parking must be located in BU-1A, BU-2, BU-3 or an industrial district.</section><section prefix='(3)'>For a telecommunications hub, one (1) parking space for each two thousand (2,000) square feet of gross floor area shall be provided. Office areas provided in conjunction with the industrial use shall have parking spaces provided for such areas as otherwise contained in this article. In the event of a subsequent change in use from a telecommunications hub to a permitted, alternative use, the alternative use shall conform to the parking standards otherwise contained in this article. A variance to reduce the number of required parking spaces shall not be granted solely on the basis of a proposed change in use from an existing telecommunications hub to an alternative use.</section></section><section>The ownership of the parking area shall be the same as that of the individual site which it is to serve. Before any permit for industrial use may be obtained, which under this chapter requires additional and separate parking areas, the owner of the industrial site shall cause to be recorded an agreement to the effect that the ownership of the industrial site and of the separate parking area shall remain the same until the regulations are amended eliminating the need for such separate parking area.</section><section>Prior to the issuance of a building permit for the erection of a new structure or building, or for an addition thereto, either of which is to be used for industrial purposes, or prior to the issuance of a certificate of use and occupancy for a different use of an existing industrial structure or building, the applicant shall complete and execute a form prescribed by the Director which shall, among other things, provide the necessary information upon which the required off-street parking may be determined; and the applicant shall therein acknowledge that such information is submitted for such determination; and in the event of a change in use or additional use is contemplated, such additional off-street parking as may be required by this chapter, if any, must be furnished prior to such use change or additional use.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Housing for low and/or moderate income for older persons and/or persons with disabilities.<section prefix='(1)'>For any publicly owned or non-profit apartment building exceeding four (4) units providing housing for elderly persons or persons with disabilities that is developed and financially assisted under the United States Housing Act of 1937, fifty hundredths (0.50) parking space shall be provided for each dwelling unit in the apartment building.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For any other apartment building exceeding four (4) units providing low and/or moderate income housing for older persons as defined by the Fair Housing Act, 42 U.S.C. § 3607, one (1) parking space shall be provided for each dwelling unit in the apartment building.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Provisions of Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County concerned with the requirements for lot coverage and open space shall remain enforced under this section. The lot area not used as a result of the decrease in parking spaces as required under Section 33-124(a) shall remain as open space and shall be landscaped or used for recreational purposes. Said open space shall be in addition to the open space requirements of the Code. The site plan submitted to the Department shall illustrate future parking spaces if the present parking requirements are inadequate pursuant to subdivision (4) herein.</section><section prefix='(4)'>If it is determined by the Department at the time of annual renewal of certificate of occupancy that the parking reduction permitted pursuant to subsections (1) or (2) above does not allow adequate parking for the apartment building, the owner must increase the number of parking spaces to fulfill the needs as determined by the Director.</section></section><section prefix='(p)'>Self-service storage facilities.<section prefix='(1)'>Self-service storage facilities shall be defined as fully enclosed spaces used for warehousing which contain individual storage units with floor area no greater than four hundred (400) square feet and an interior height not to exceed twelve (12) feet. No wholesale or retail sales are permitted.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In self-service storage facilities, off-street parking shall be provided on the following basis: One (1) parking space per five thousand (5,000) square feet of building area for the first twenty thousand (20,000) square feet of building; one (1) parking space per ten thousand (10,000) square feet (or fraction thereof) of building area thereafter; and one (1) parking space for the manager's apartment, where provided. One (1) parking space per four hundred (400) square feet of gross office area (or fraction thereof) shall also be provided. In the application of these regulations, a minimum number of five (5) off-street parking spaces shall be provided for any self-service storage facility regardless of size.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 5(BB)(1)(3), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 61-27, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 62-23, § 1, 6-5-62; Ord. No. 64-13, § 1, 4-21-64; Ord. No. 64-31, § 1, 7-21-64; Ord. No. 69-71, § 2, 10-8-69; Ord. No. 77-10, § 1, 2-15-77; Ord. No. 77-61, § 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 83-14, § 1, 3-15-83; Ord. No. 83-57, § 1, 7-5-83; Ord. No. 83-116, § 1, 12-20-83; Ord. No. 91-36, § 1, 3-19-91; Ord. No. 94-165, § 1, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-218, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-5, § 1, 1-13-98; Ord. No. 01-99, § 2, 6-5-01; Ord. No. 03-80, § 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 03-117, § 1, 5-6-03; Ord. No. 08-78, § 1, 7-1-08; Ord. No. 10-20, § 2, 3-2-10; Ord. No. 11-04, § 2, 2-1-11; Ord. No. 13-76, § 2, 9-4-13)</history></law>