<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Religious facilities and schools in RU-5A, BU and IU districts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003907</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-18. Religious facilities and schools in RU-5A, BU and IU districts.<section prefix='(a)'>Buildings used for public assemblage as defined in Section 33-17, where located in RU-5A, BU or IU Districts may be permitted with the same yard requirements and setbacks as required of the office, business or industrial buildings legally allowed in these districts.</section><section prefix='(b)'>With the exception of religious facilities no building for public assemblage shall be permitted in IU-2 and IU-3 Districts unless directly connected with legally established industrial use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Churches in RU-1, RU-2, EU-M, EU-1, EU-1C, EU-2, AU and GU Districts will be permitted only upon approval after public hearing; schools in GU, EU-2, EU-1C, EU-1, EU-S, EU-M, RU-1, RU-2, RU-1(M)(a), RU-1(M)(b), RU-TH, RU-5, RU-5A, PAD, IU-2, IU-3 and IU-C will be permitted only upon approval after public hearing, and shall be subject to compliance with the requirements of sections 33-151.11 through 33-151.22 of this code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Duly constituted "missions" are permitted under the same conditions and in the same zoning districts that churches are permitted. For the purposes of this section, a "mission" shall mean any body, association, or organization for doing religious and charitable work, devoted entirely to the moral, religious and social improvement of those in need of such missionary work and assistance, which does not constitute a church but is sponsored by a duly constituted church.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 5(M)(2), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 59-18, § 1, 6-23-59; Ord. No. 61-33, § 1, 7-19-61; Ord. No. 77-60, § 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 95-123, § 1, 7-11-95; Ord. No. 02-46, § 2, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 02-103, § 1, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 02-255, § 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 04-118, § 3, 6-8-04; Ord. No. 07-178, § 1, 12-4-07)</history></law>