<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. RIGHT-OF-WAY PLAN AND MINIMUM WIDTH</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-133</section_number>
<catch_line>Right-of-way plan and minimum width of streets and ways.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004003</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-133. Right-of-way plan and minimum width of streets and ways.<section>The minimum right-of-way widths for streets, roads and public ways for the unincorporated area of the County shall be as follows:<section prefix='(A)'>NORTH AND SOUTH HIGHWAYS (Avenues).<section></section></section></section><section><section prefix='(1)'>North Miami Avenue from 79 St. North to Memorial Hwy. (Griffing Blvd.) (unincorporated areas)100</section><section>From State Road #9 to Miami-Dade County North Line</section><section prefix='(2)'>North Miami Avenue from Memorial Hwy. (Griffing Blvd.) to State Road. #9 (unincorporated areas)100</section><section prefix='(3)'>NE 2 Ave. from North limits of Miami Shores North to State Rd. #9 (unincorporated areas)70</section><section prefix='(4)'>W. Dixie Hwy. from NE 2 Ave. to 174 St. (unincorporated area), except—See No. 5 below70</section><section prefix='(5)'>W. Dixie Hwy. from NE 119 St. to NE 121 St.70</section><section prefix='(6)'>W. Dixie Hwy. from NE 174 St. North to County Line (unincorporated areas)66</section><section prefix='(7)'>NE 6 Ave. North limits of Miami Shores North to Griffing Blvd.70</section><section prefix='(8)'>NE 2 Ave. (Griffing Blvd.) (Memorial Hwy. NW 2 Ave.) from NE 6 Ave. North to Golden Glades Dr.70</section><section prefix='(9)'>(a)State Rd. #5 from NE 36 St. to South limits of North Miami Beach (unincorporated areas)100<section prefix='(b)'>State Rd. #5 from North limits of North Miami Beach to North County Line (unincorporated areas)116</section><section prefix='(c)'>State Rd. #5 from South limits of South Miami, South to Tennessee Rd. (unincorporated areas)116</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>State Rd. #5 from South limits of Florida City to South County Line (See State Dept. of Transportation r/w Map Project #5239-5240)100 to350</section><section prefix='(11)'>State Rd. #5 from Tennessee Rd. in Sec. 8-57-39 South to the North limits of Homestead116</section><section prefix='(12)'>Ingraham Hwy. (State Rd. #27) from Longview Rd. to Cape Sable125</section><section prefix='(13)'>Ingraham Hwy. (SW 217 Ave.) from Mowry Dr. South to State Rd. #27125</section><section prefix='(14)'>Longview Dr. from Mowry Dr. South to State Rd. #27125</section><section prefix='(15)'>Old Cutler Rd. through U.S. Dept. of Agriculture property in Sec. 24-55-40 to Chapman Field at Mitchell Dr. and Old Cutler Rd. (Ingraham Hwy.) from Coral Reef Dr. South to Silver Palm Dr.100</section><section prefix='(16)'>Card Sound Road from U.S. #1 (in Sec. 30, Twp. 57S, Rge. 39E going Se/ly to the Monroe County Line (being the East line of Sec. 13, Twp. 59S, Rge. 39E). Said right-of-way traversing the following Sections: 30 and 31, Twp. 575, Rge. 39E; 5, 6, 8, 16, 17, 21, 22, 27, 34 and 35, Twp. 58S, Rge. 39E; 2, 11, 12 and 13, Twp. 59S, Rge. 39E). Said right-of-way to be measured 55′ each side from the centerline of existing pavement110</section><section prefix='(17)'>State Rd. A1A Bakers Haulover North to County Line100</section><section prefix='(18)'>Rickenbacker Causeway Rd. from South end of Crandon Park South to Cape Florida Lighthouse120</section><section prefix='(19)'>Bayshore Dr. (Biscayne Key) from Cape Florida Lighthouse North to waterway and then East to North and South Highway100</section><section prefix='(20)'>Reserved</section><section prefix='(21)'>Seaboard Throughway from Galloway Road to Krome Avenue125<section> On portions of Sections 28, 32 and in Township 54 South, Range 40 East, Sections 5, 7, 8 and 18 in Township 55 South, Range 40 East, Sections 13, 23, 24, 26, 27, and 34 in Township 55 South, Range 39 East, and Sections 4, 5, 7, 8, and 18 in Township 56 South, Range 39 East, bounded on the northwesterly side of the Seaboard Airline Railway southeasterly right-of-way line and on the southeasterly side by a line parallel to the Seaboard Airline Railway southeasterly right-of-way line, and one hundred twenty-five (125) feet southeasterly therefrom as measured on a perpendicular from the southeasterly Seaboard Airline Railway right-of-way line.</section></section><section></section><section prefix='(22)'>State Rd. No. 7 Golden Glades Dr. north to County Line100</section><section prefix='(23)'>NW 7th Ave. (State Rd. No. 7) from NW 79th St. to south limits of North Miami and from north limits of North Miami to Golden Glades Dr. Cloverleaf100</section><section prefix='(24)'>NW 7th Ave. from Golden Glades Dr. extended north to County Line70</section><section prefix='(25)'>State Hwy. No. 9 from 27th Ave. north to north County Line (See State Dept. of Transportation r/w Project No. 8724-203)200 to 300</section><section prefix='(26)'>NW 12th Ave.—Extension from NW 71st St. north to south limits of North Miami and north limits of North Miami to Opa Locka Blvd.100</section><section prefix='(27)'>NW 17th Ave.—From NW 71st St., north to Opa Locka Blvd.100</section><section prefix='(28)'>NW 22nd Ave.—From NW 38th St., north to Miami-Dade County north line100</section><section prefix='(29)'>NW 27th Ave.—From NW 36th St. to Miami-Dade County north line100</section><section prefix='(30)'>West side of NW 27th Ave.—From 36th St., south to center line of 20th St.50</section><section prefix='(31)'>NW 37th Ave.—From NW 20th St. to County Line (unincorporated area)70</section><section prefix='(32)'>NW 47th Ave. (Bougainvillea Ave.)—From Gratigny Road to Opa Locka Blvd.70</section><section prefix='(33)'>LeJeune Road from the north Miami-Dade County Line to the north boundary of the City of Opa Locka (NW 151st Street)100<section>LeJeune Road from NW 36th Street to NW 20th Street</section><section>LeJeune Road from Tamiami Trail to 75 feet south of SW 16th Terrace (unincorporated)</section></section><section prefix='(34)'>Red Rd. (State Rd. No. 819) from SW 74th Street, north to NW 183rd Street (unincorporated areas)100<section> Said 100-foot right-of-way to be measured equidistant from the section lines except in that portion from NW 183rd Street to the North County Line where the right-of-way shall be established as follows:<section>East 100 feet of the west 130 feet of Section 6, Township 52 South, Range 41 East; east 100 feet of the west 130 feet of the south 1,256 feet of, Township 51 South, Range 41 East; the east 100 feet of west 145 feet of, Township 51 South, Range 41 East, less the south 1265 feet thereof.</section></section></section><section prefix='(34.1)'>Red Rd.(State Rd. No. 819) from Old Cutler Road north to SW 74th Street (unincorporated areas)70</section><section prefix='(34.'>2) SW 62nd Ave. from Coral Way (SW 24th St.) south to SW 30th St. (unincorporated areas)50</section><section prefix='(35)'>Ludlam Road from International Airport South to State Rd. No. 5 (unincorporated areas)70</section><section prefix='(36)'>Ludlam Road from Mitchell Road south to Coral Reef Dr.100</section><section prefix='(37)'>(a)Ludlam Road from Mitchell Road north to 160 feet south of North Kendall Drive70<section prefix='(b)'>Ludlam Road from 160 feet south of North Kendall Drive to 150 feet north of SW 85th Street80<section> The 80 feet to be measured 40 feet on each side of the following centerline:</section><section> Beginning at a point on the W line of northwest quarter of Section 1-55-40, said point being 200 feet S of the NW corner of said Section 1 and being the point of curvature of a circular curve; thence run northerly and northeasterly along the arc of a circular curve to the right, said curve being tangent to the West line of the northwest quarter of said Section 1 and having a radius of 818.51 feet through a central angle of 54 degrees 01 minutes 53 seconds for an arc distance of 771.88 feet to the point of tangency; thence run northeasterly along a line tangent to the last-described curve for a distance of 100 feet to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the left; thence run northeasterly and northerly along the arc of said circular curve to the left having a radius of 818.51 feet through a central angle of 53 degrees 48 minutes 33 seconds for an arc distance of 768.70 feet to the point of tangency with the E line of the southeast quarter of Section 35-54-40, said point of tangency being 1178.54 feet N of the SE corner of said Section 35 and being the end of the center line herein described</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Ludlum Road from 150 feet north of SW 85th Street to State Road No. 5 (US No. 1)70</section></section><section prefix='(38)'>Milam Road (NW 72nd Avenue) from Tamiami Canal (Miami city limits) to NW 74th Street (Town of Medley limits)100</section></section><section>(Ord. No. 63-37, § 1, 9-10-63)<section prefix='(39)'>Palmetto Rd. from NW 90th St. to Tamiami Trail300</section><section prefix='(40)'>Palmetto Rd. (From Tamiami Trail south to Coral Way (SW 25th St.) 125 feet all on west side of Canal)125</section><section prefix='(41)'>Palmetto Rd. (From Coral Way south to Bird Rd. 62½ feet on the west side of section line, 62½ feet on east side of section line)125</section><section prefix='(42)'>Palmetto Road from Bird Rd. south to Kendall Road—35 feet on the west side of the section line and 90 feet on the east side of the section line125<section> From Kendall Road to SW 98th Street, 40 feet on either side of the following described center line:</section><section> Beginning at the NW corner of the northwest quarter of Section 2-55-40; thence, run South along the West line of said northwest quarter of Section 2 for 2250 feet; thence deflecting 12 degrees 20 minutes to the left run southeasterly along a straight line for 1050 feet more or less to the point of intersection with the S line of the northwest quarter, northwest quarter, southwest quarter, of Section 2, said point being the end of the center line herein described</section></section><section prefix='(42a)'>NW 112 Avenue from NW 106th Street to NW 122 Street, Miami-Dade County, Florida, provided continuation of the existing use, or substantially similar future use, of the lands abutting the right-of-way on the effective date of this ordinance (June 28, 2002). Right-of-way plan and minimum width requirements for this half-section line roadway shall revert to 70 feet after a change in use or a determination by the Director that the current use has been abandoned0</section><section prefix='(43)'>(a)W. 117th Avenue from NW corner of Section 30-52-40 south to NW corner of Section 7-54-400<section prefix='(b)'>SW 117th Avenue from NW corner of Section 18-54-40 south to SW corner of Section 18-54-40; this portion of SW 117 Avenue extends from Coral Way (SW 24 St.) to Bird Drive (SW 40 St.) and more particularly described as the east 80 feet of the West 134 feet of Section 18-54-4080</section><section prefix='(c)'>SW 117th Avenue from SW corner of Section 18-54-40 south to State Road No. 5125</section></section><section prefix='(44)'>Burr Road (127 Ave.)—US No. 1 to Homestead Army Airbase100</section><section prefix='(45)'>South Allapattah Road (State Road #909) from North Canal Drive north to State Road #5100</section><section prefix='(46)'>(a)NW 137 Avenue from State Road #25 (Okeechobee Road) to Flagler Street110<section prefix='(b)'>SW 137 Avenue (Lindgren Road) from Flagler Street to State Road #5 (US #1)110</section></section><section prefix='(46.1)'>SW 157 Avenue from theoretical SW 112 Street to SW 120 Street80<section>Said 80-foot right-of-way shall be measured westward of the westerly line of the 140 foot wide Black Creek Canal (C-1W) right-of-way as constructed in the SE ¼ of Section 8, Township 55 South, Range 39 East and shall transition Northerly through said SE ¼ of said Section 8 to meet the existing alignment for SW 157 Avenue at theoretical SW 112 Street, on the north side of said Black Creek Canal (C-1W). Said transition shall meet with the approval of the Directors of the Departments of Planning and Zoning and Public Works.</section></section><section prefix='(46.2)'>SW 157 Avenue from SW 120 Street to SW 136 Street80<section>Said 80-foot right-of-way shall be measured westward of the westerly line of the 150 foot wide Black Creek Canal (C-1W) right-of-way as constructed across, Township 55 South, Range 39 East.</section></section><section prefix='(47)'>Krome Avenue from north limits of Homestead north to intersection of Krome Avenue and SAL right-of-way125</section><section prefix='(48)'>(a)Krome Avenue180<section> Krome Avenue (177 Avenue) [180-foot right-of-way]: The east 180 feet of Sections 12, 13, 24, 25 and 36 in Township 54 South, Range 38 East; the east 90 feet of the south ¼ of Section 1, Township 55 South, Range 38 East; the east 90 feet of Sections 12, 13, 24, 25 and 36 in Township 55 South, Range 38 East; the east 90 feet of Sections 1 and 12 in Township 56 South, Range 38 East; the east 90 feet of that portion of in Township 56 South, Range 38 East, lying north of Seaboard Coastline Railroad; the west 90 feet of the south ¼ of Section 6, Township 55 South, Range 39 East; the west 90 feet of Sections 7, 18, 19, 30 and 31, Township 55 South, Range 39 East; the west 90 feet of Sections 6 and 7, Township 56 South, Range 39 East; the west 90 feet of that portion of, Township 56 South, Range 39 East lying north of Seaboard Coastline Railroad; less that portion lying within the right-of-way as shown on the State of Florida right-of-way map for Krome Avenue as recorded in Plat Book 83 at page 22 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Krome Avenue300<section>Krome Avenue (177 Avenue) [300-foot right-of-way]: The 300-foot right-of-way as shown on the State of Florida right-of-way map for Krome Avenue as recorded in Plat Book 83 at page 22 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></section><section prefix='(49)'>SW 192 Avenue (Tower Road) from Coconut Palm Drive (SW 248 Street) to Palm Drive (SW 344 Street)86<section>The east 43 feet of the west ½ of each of the following sections: Sections 26 and 35 of Township 56 South, Range 38 East; Sections 2, 11, 14 and 23 of Township 57 South, Range 38 East; and the west 43 feet of the east ½ of each of the following sections; Sections 26 and 35 of Township 56 South, Range 38 East; Sections 2, 11, 14 and 23 of Township 57 South, Range 38 East.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>EAST AND WEST STREETS<section></section><section prefix='(1)'>West Flagler Street from Snapper Creek Canal Road to west limits of Miami100</section><section prefix='(2)'>NW 25 Street from NW 72 Avenue to NW 107 Avenue80<section>The centerline of this 80-foot official right-of-way shall be located along the south line of the north 40 feet of the northwest ¼ of Section 35, Township 53 South, Range 40 East for the portion between NW 72 Avenue and the Palmetto Bypass.</section><section> The centerline of this 80-foot official right-of-way shall be located along the south line of the north 100 feet of Sections 32, 33 and 34, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, for that portion between Palmetto Bypass and NW 107 Avenue.</section></section><section prefix='(2a)'>NW 25 Street from NW 107 Avenue to NW 117 Avenue70<section>The centerline of this 70 foot official right-of-way shall be located along the south line of the north 95 feet of, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, for the portion between NW 107 Avenue and NW 117 Avenue.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>NW 36 Street from 37 Avenue west to Milam Road100</section><section prefix='(4)'>NW 36 Street Extension and NW 41 Street, from NW 117 Avenue to NW 79 Avenue110<section>The centerline of this 110-foot official right-of-way shall be as follows: Begin at the northwest corner of, Township 53 South, Range 40 East; thence run north 89° 52′ 01″ east along the north line of the northwest ¼ of for 2631.75 feet to the northeast corner of the northwest ¼ of; thence run north 89° 52′ 11″ east along the north line of the northeast ¼ of for 2639.41 feet to the northeast corner of; thence run north 89° 58′ 49″ east along the north line of the northwest ¼ of, Township 53 South, Range 40 East for 2633.66 feet to the northeast corner of the NW ¼ of; thence run North 89° 59′ 39″ East along the North line of the NE ¼ of for 2640.70′ to the NE corner of; thence run North 89° 51′ 57″ East along the North line of the NW ¼ of, Twp. 53S, Rge. 40E for 2640.10′ to the NE corner of the NW ¼ of; then run North 89° 51′ 07″ East along the North line of the NE ¼ of for 966.04′ to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the right; thence run southeasterly along the arc of said circular curve to the right having a radius of 1909.86′ through a central angle of 30° 30′ 51″ for an arc distance of 1017.14′; then run South 59° 38′ 02″ East along a line which is tangent to the previously described curve for 264.83′ to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the left; thence run southeasterly along the arc of said circular curve to the left having a radius of 1909.86′ through a central angle of 30° 00′ 00″ for an arc distance of 1000′ to the point of tangency with the South line of Tract 31 in, Twp. 53S, Rge. 40E, Florida Fruit Land Company Subdivision #1 (Plat Book 2, Pge. 17); thence run South 89° 38′ 02″ East along the South line of Tracts 31 and 18 in of said plat, Florida Fruit Land Company Subdivision #1 for 2187.32′ to the point of intersection with the East line of the NW¼ of; thence run South 89° 38′ 43″ East along the South line of Tract 15 of, Florida Fruit Land Company Subdivision #1, for 378.35′ to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the right; thence run southeasterly along the arc of said circular curve to the right having a radius of 1145.92′ through a central angle of 15° 33′ 37″ for an arc distance of 311.21′; then run South 74° 05′ 06″ East along a line which is tangent to the previously described curve for 335.06′ to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the left; thence run southeasterly along the arc of said circular curve to the left having a radius of 1145.92′ through a central angle of 16° 14′ 59″ for an arc distance of 325′ to the point of intersection with the East line of the NW ¼, NE ¼ of and the end of the herein described center line, said point of intersection being 832.18′ Southerly of the NE corner of the NW ¼, NE ¼ of as measured along the East line of the NW ¼, NE¼ of; said center line being further described and shown on a right-of-way map recorded in Plat Book 81 at Page 24 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>NW 54 St. from West limits of Miami to Okeechobee Rd.100</section><section prefix='(6)'>NW 71 St.70</section><section prefix='(6.1)'>NW 74 Street from Palmetto Expressway (State Road No. 826) to NW 107th Avenue126</section><section prefix='(7)'>NW 79 St. (State Rd. #828) from West limits of Miami to East limits of Hialeah100</section><section prefix='(8)'>NW 91 St. from NW 7 Ave. to NW 12 Ave.70</section><section prefix='(9)'>NW 95 St. from West limits of Miami Shores to NW 37 Avenue (unincorporated areas)70</section><section prefix='(10)'>NW 103 St. from Federal Hwy. #1 to East limits of Hialeah, except as noted below.100<section>Note: NW 103 St. from NW 36 Ct. to NW 37 Ave.</section></section><section prefix='(10a)'>NW 114 Street from NW 107th Avenue to NW 117 Avenue (Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike), Miami-Dade County, Florida, provided continuation of the existing use, or substantially similar future use, of the lands abutting the right-of-way on the effective date of this ordinance (June 28, 2002). Right-of-way plan and minimum width requirements for this half-section line roadway shall revert to 70 feet after a change in use or a determination by the Director that the current use has been abandoned0</section><section prefix='(11)'>Gratigny Rd. (NW and NE 119 St.) from NW 27 Ave. East to West Dixie Highway100<section>Gratigny Rd. West of NW of NW 27 Ave.</section></section><section prefix='(12)'>NW 135 St. from West limits of Opa Locka West continuing into Atlantic Rd. as far as Okeechobee Rd.100</section><section prefix='(13)'>Opa Locka Blvd. from the East limits of Opa Locka East through Nichols Sub. swinging South to 135 St. at NW 2 Ave.80</section><section prefix='(14)'>NW 138 St. (All South of Section lines). (135 St. jogs to 139 Street West of Red Road)100</section><section prefix='(15)'>Golden Glades Dr. (Sunny Isles Rd.—State Rd. #826) from State Rd. A1A West to Okeechobee Rd. (unincorporated areas)100<section> Except from St. Rd. A1A to US #1, the same width as established on State Dept. of Transportation r/w Project #5155, State Rd. #826 as shown in Plat Book 38, Page 73, PB 44, Page 3, and as shown of Bella Vista Sub., 2nd Rev. Plat, Plat Book 50, Page 76.</section></section><section prefix='(16)'>(a)Miami Gardens Rd. US #1 to Red Rd. (NW 57 Ave.)100<section prefix='(b)'>Miami Gardens Rd. (NW 186 St.) from Red Rd. (NW 57 Ave.) to St. Rd. #25 (Okeechobee Rd.)100</section></section><section prefix='(17)'>Ives Dairy Rd. between St. Rd. #9 to NE 14 Ave.70</section><section prefix='(18)'>Miami-Dade County north line (215 St.)100</section></section><section><section prefix='(19)'>Tamiami Trail (SW 8 St.) from the center line from Ludlam Road (SW 67 Ave.) to the center line of SW 74 Ave.100<section> And from SW 74 Ave. to Palmetto Road (SW 77 Ave.) as previously dedicated and indicated on the amended plat of Miami Gateway Sub. (PB 28, Pg. 6), except as modified by acquisition of right-of-way for Palmetto Bypass, as shown on Florida D.O.T. right-of-way map recorded in PB 68, Pg. 7, and from Palmetto Road (SW 77 Ave.) to SW 82 Ave. as follows: All that part of the northwest quarter of the northeast quarter of Section 10, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, which lies north of a line that is 125 feet south of and parallel to the base line survey as shown on the Florida State Department of Transportation right-of-way map recorded in PB 72, Pg. 85 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and west of SW 82 Ave. to the County line as the same is shown on the Florida State Department of Transportation right-of-way map on file with the Miami-Dade County Public Works Department known as Section 8711, Project 669C and Section 8712, Project 669B.</section></section><section prefix='(20)'>(a)Coral Way (SW 24 St.) from Red Road (SW 57 Ave.) to Snapper Creek Canal100<section prefix='(b)'>Coral Way (SW 24 St.) from SW 117 Ave. to SW 157 Ave.100<section> Said right-of-way to be measured as follows: That portion of Sections 9 through 16 inclusive, Township 54 South, Range 39 East lying within a uniform strip of land 100 feet wide, 50 feet on each side of as measured at right angles and radially to the following described center line: Begin at the SW corner of Section 7-54-40; thence run westerly along a line parallel to the south line of Section 12-54-39 for a distance of 1144.53 feet to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the left; thence run southwesterly along the arc of said circular curve to the left having a radius of 1145.92 feet through a central angle of 40 degrees 43 minutes 44 seconds for an arc distance of 814.58 feet to a point of tangency; thence run south 49 degrees 16 minutes 16 seconds west along a line tangent to the last described curve for a distance 200 feet to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the right; thence run southwesterly along the arc of said circular curve to the right having a radius of 1145.92 feet through a central angle of 40 degrees 43 minutes 44 seconds for an arc distance of 814.58 feet to a point of tangency on the south line of Section 12-54-39, said point being 150 feet west of the SE corner of the southwest quarter of Section 12-54-39; thence run westerly along the south line of the southwest quarter of said to the SW corner of said; thence run westerly along the south line of said to the SW corner of said; thence run westerly along the south line of said Section 10 to the SW corner of said Section 10; thence run westerly along the south line of said Section 9 to the SW corner of said Section 9, said SW corner of said Section 9 being the end of the herein described center line.</section></section></section><section prefix='(21)'>(a)Bird Drive (SW 40 St.) from State Road No. 5 (unincorporated areas) to Snapper Creek Canal100<section prefix='(b)'>Bird Drive (SW 42 St.) from a point 125 feet West of the center line of SW 125 Avenue to SW 177 Ave.110<section> Said 110 feet to be measured as follows: The south 110 feet of the west 660.58 feet of and the south 110 feet of Sections 14 through 18 inclusive, all in Township 54 South, Range 39 East.</section></section></section><section prefix='(22)'>(a)Miller Drive (SW 56 St.) from State Road No. 5 to Snapper Creek Canal (unincorporated areas)100<section prefix='(b)'>Miller Drive (SW 56 St.) from SW 117 Avenue to SW 157 Avenue100<section> Said right-of-way to be measured as follows: A uniform strip of land 100 feet in width, lying 50 feet on each side of the following described center line: Begin at the NW corner of Section 30-54-40; thence run south 89 degrees 42 minutes 15 seconds west along the westerly extension of the north line of said for a distance of 150 feet to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the right; thence run westerly along the arc of said circular curve to the right having a radius of 954.93 feet through a central angle of 23 degrees 11 minutes 13 seconds for an arc distance of 386.45 feet to the point of tangency with a line; thence run north 67 degrees 06 minutes 32 seconds west along the line that is tangent to the last-described curve for a distance of 200 feet to the point of curvature of a circular curve to the left; thence run westerly along the arc of said circular curve to the left having a radius of 954.93 feet through a central angle of 22 degrees 53 minutes 14 seconds for an arc distance of 381.45 feet to the point of tangency with the north line of Section 25-54-39; thence run westerly along the north line of Sections 25, 26, 27 and 28 all in Township 54 South, Range 39 East to the NW corner of said and the end of the hereinafter described center line.</section></section></section><section prefix='(23)'>Sunset Drive (SW 72 St.) from Old Cutler Road (unincorporated areas) to Snapper Creek Canal Road100<section prefix='(b)'>Sunset Drive (SW 72 St.) from SW 118 Avenue to SW 157 Ave.100</section></section><section prefix='(24)'>SW 104 Street from the SAL Railroad to SW 117 Ave.110</section><section prefix='(25)'>North Kendall Dr. (SW 88 St.) from Palmetto Bypass (S.R. 826) to Krome Ave. (SW 117 Ave.)110</section><section prefix='(26)'>Chapman Field Dr.70</section><section prefix='(27)'>Mitchell Dr. from Chapman Field west to Ludlam Rd.100</section><section prefix='(28)'>Coral Reef Drive (SW 152 Street) from Ludlam Road to West Old Cutler Road110</section></section></section><section>(a.1)Hainlin Mill Drive (SW 216 Street) from Biscayne Bay bulkhead line to SW 177 Ave., except as noted below<section>Note: SW 216 Street from State Road No. 5 (US No. 1) to SW 127 Avenue</section></section><section>(b)Coral Reef Drive (SW 152 St.) from Krome (177) Ave. to US No. 1<section prefix='(29)'>Silver Palm Dr. from Old Cutler Rd. west to State Road No. 5100</section><section prefix='(30)'>Moody Drive from SW 107 Avenue to US No. 1100</section><section prefix='(31)'>Mowry Drive from east limits of Homestead to South Allapattah Drive100</section><section prefix='(32)'>Mowry Drive from west limits of Homestead to Longview Road125</section><section prefix='(33)'>Mowry Drive from Longview Road west to Ingraham Highway125</section><section prefix='(34)'>Biscayne Drive from U.S. No. 1 west to Krome Avenue100</section><section prefix='(C)'>Except as may provided in Sections 33-133(A) and (B) hereof, on all section lines, eighty (80) feet shall be the minimum right-of-way width, and on all other half-section (also known as quarter-section) lines, seventy (70) feet shall be the minimum official right-of-way width. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to those properties described in Section 33B-13(a) herein with the exceptions of S.W. 136 Street from S.W. 187 Avenue to S.W. 209 Avenue; S.W. 168 Street from Levee L-31N to S.W. 237 Avenue; S.W. 237 Avenue from S.W. 168 Street to S.W. 160 Street; Ingraham Highway (formerly S.R. 27); and that portion of N.W. 87 Avenue from N.W. 197 Terrace north to the north County line. Furthermore the provisions of this subsection shall not apply to that portion of S.W. 122 Avenue which lies within the S.E. ¼ of the S.W. ¼ of Section 36, Township 54, Range 39; nor shall the provisions of this subsection apply to that portion of the South 40 feet of N.W. 106 Street which lies between N.W. 112 Avenue and N.W. 117 Avenue or that portion of N.W. 122 Avenue south of N.W. 25 Street to theoretical N.W. 21 Terrace; nor shall the provisions of this subsection apply to that portion of S.W. 102 Avenue which lies between Black Creek Canal and SW 232 Street; nor to the portion of Red Road (57 Avenue), north of Old Cutler Road to S.W. 74 Street (unincorporated area) nor shall the provisions of this subsection apply to that portion of N.E. 191 Street which lies between N.E. 24 Avenue and N.E. 25 Avenue.</section><section prefix='(D)'>On all interior subdivision streets, forty-seven (47) feet shall be the official minimum right-of-way width, except as further modified by Chapter 28 of this Code. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to those properties described in Section 33B-13(a) herein with the exception of S.W. 136 Street from S.W. 187 Avenue to S.W. 209 Avenue; S.W. 168 Street from Levee L-31N to S.W. 237 Avenue; S.W. 237 Avenue from S.W. 168 Street to S.W. 160 Street; and Ingraham Highway (formerly S.R. 27). Furthermore, the provisions of this subsection shall not apply to that portion of S.W. 123 Avenue which lies within the South ¾ of the S.E. ¼ of the S.W. ¼ of Section 36-54-39, or to that portion of S.W. 124 Avenue which lies within the North 5.00 feet of the South ¾ of the S.E. ¼ of the S.W. ¼ of Section 36, Township 54, Range 39.</section><section prefix='(E)'>All five-acre fractional lines shall be deemed interior subdivision streets unless otherwise provided in this chapter, or unless waived by the Director and the Director of the Public Works Department. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to those properties described in Section 33B-13(a) herein with the exception of S.W. 136 Street from S.W. 187 Avenue to S.W. 209 Avenue; S.W. 168 Street from Levee L-31N to S.W. 237 Avenue; S.W. 237 Avenue from S.W. 168 Street to S.W. 160 Street; and Ingraham Highway (formerly S.R. 27).</section><section prefix='(F)'>On all alleys, twenty (20) feet shall be the official minimum width. The center line of all streets, roads and highways shall be approved and (or established by the Director of Public Works; in all cases where the right-of-way does not follow a fractional line, the location of the right-of-way shall be determined by the Director of Public Works.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 31(A), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 58-14, §§ 1, 2, 5-1-58; Ord. No. 60-13, § 1, 3-24-60; Ord. No. 61-46, § 1, 11-21-61; Ord. No. 62-13, § 1, 3-6-62; Ord. No. 63-5, § 1, 2-12-63; Ord. No. 63-10, § 1, 3-26-63; Ord. No. 63-37, § 2, 9-10-63; Ord. No. 63-54, § 1, 11-26-63; Ord. No. 64-62, § 1, 12-1-64; Ord. No. 65-22, § 1, 4-6-65; Ord. No. 65-42, § 1, 5-18-65; Ord. No. 65-49, § 1, 7-27-65; Ord. No. 65-67, § 1, 10-5-65; Ord. No. 65-69, §§ 1—3, 11-9-65; Ord. No. 68-9, § 1, 2-21-68; Ord. No. 68-10, § 1, 2-21-68; Ord. No. 68-46, §§ 1, 2, 8-20-68; Ord. No. 68-47, § 1, 8-20-68; Ord. No. 70-63, § 1, 9-1-70; Ord. No. 72-34, §§ 1, 2, 6-20-72; Ord. No. 77-73, § 1, 10-4-77; Ord. No. 82-60, § 2, 7-20-82; Ord. No. 86-12, § 1, 2-18-86; Ord. No. 91-144, § 1, 12-17-91; Ord. No. 92-151, § 1, 12-15-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-149, § 1, 10-8-96; Ord. No. 97-108, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 99-06, § 1, 1-21-99; Ord. No. 01-167, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-106, §§ 1, 2, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 02-249, § 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 03-77, § 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 03-136, § 1, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 03-212, § 1, 10-7-03; Ord. No. 04-209, § 1, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 05-144, § 8, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 05-186, § 1, 10-18-05; Ord. No. 06-96, § 4, 6-20-06; Ord. No. 07-95, § 1, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 08-99, § 1, 9-2-08)</history></law>