<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.9</section_number>
<catch_line>Required Workforce Housing Units.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004101</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.9. Required Workforce Housing Units.<section prefix='(A)'>All applications seeking to utilize the density or intensity bonus available pursuant to this article for developments shall include a minimum percentage of workforce housing units based on the following:</section><section>The number of WHUs to be provided shall be 5% of the total number of market rate units.</section><section>The percentage of WHUs to be provided shall be a percentage of the total number of units.</section><section>Office/Residential - One density category higher than that allowed in the adjoining or adjacent residentially designated area on the same side of the abutting principal roadway, or up to the density of existing adjoining or adjacent residential development, or zoning if the adjacent or adjoining land is undeveloped whichever is higher. If there is no adjacent or adjoining residential development existing, zoned or designated on the same side of the abutting principal roadway, then the allowable maximum residential density shall be based on that which exists or which the plan allows across the roadway. Where there is no residential use, zoning or designation on either side of the roadway, the intensity of residential development, including height, bulk and floor area ratio shall be no greater than that which would be permitted for an exclusively office use of the site.</section><section>Business and Office - One density category higher than the LUP - designated density of the adjacent or adjoining residentially designated area on the same side of the abutting principal roadway, or up to the density of any such existing residential development, or zoning if the adjacent or adjoining land is undeveloped, whichever is higher. If there is no adjacent or adjoining residential use existing, zoned or designated on the same side of the roadway, the maximum allowable residential density will be that which exists or which this plan allows across the roadway. Where there is no residential use, zoning or designation on either side of the roadway, the intensity of residential development, including height, bulk and floor area ratio shall be no greater than that which would be permitted for an exclusively commercial use of the site.</section><section prefix='(B)'>All applications for residential developments within Urban Centers depicted on the Land Use Plan (LUP) map of the CDMP that are zoned as an urban center as of the effective date of this article shall not be required to provide workforce housing units.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Applicants seeking to utilize the 12.5% density bonus shall not seek approval of any application or proffer any declaration of restrictive covenants providing for a density below 95% of the total maximum density permitted by the underlying zoning district regulations, all zoning actions approved on the property and the maximum allowable density bonuses.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>