<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. OFF-STREET PARKING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-122</section_number>
<catch_line>Required; definitions of parking space.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003987</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-122. Required; definitions of parking space.<section>Permanently maintained off-street parking for vehicles shall be provided in connection with any building or premises used or designed to be used for the purposes set forth in this article. Parking spaces on private roadways shall not be credited towards required parking. For the purpose of this article, each parking space shall be a minimum of eight and one-half (8.5) by eighteen (18) feet with the following exceptions:<section prefix='(1)'>Where parking spaces for the handicapped are to be provided, they shall be a minimum of eighteen (18) feet long and the width and quality shall be in accordance with the South Florida Building Code.</section></section><section>Parking stall and aisle dimensions shall conform to the charts entitled "Minimum Parking Stall Dimension" and "Striping Detail" hereby incorporated as part of this section.</section><section></section><section>MINIMUM PARKING STALL DIMENSIONS (IN FEET)AT VARIOUS ANGLES</section><section>For parallel parking minimum widths and length are 8.0′ × 23.0′.</section><section>** Driveways where there is no parking on either side shall be a minimum of twenty (20) feet in width for two-way traffic and fourteen (14) feet for one-way traffic. Access drives between the paved portion of the right-of-way and the property line shall comply with the Miami-Dade County public works manual.</section><section></section><section>For all occupancies other than residential, the parking spaces shall be marked with double striping on each side of the space to identify and facilitate their use. All striping shall be of a color (typically white) contrasting with the pavement. Dimension requirements, as noted elsewhere, shall be measured to the center point of the double stripe, as shown on the "Striping Detail" hereby incorporated as part of this section. Notwithstanding the above provisions and striping details, where striping is required for residential users, not less than a single four-inch stripe shall be provided, with parking stall dimensions to be measured to the center line of the strip. In all instances, adequate interior driveways and ingress and egress driveways shall be provided to connect all parking spaces with a public right-of-way or alley. Where a parking space heads into and abuts a walkway, the paved eighteen-foot length shall be provided a wheel stop or curb at sixteen (16) feet in order to prevent extension of the vehicle over any portion of the provided walkway width. Required and surplus parking shall comply with these provisions and such parking shall not be placed in dedicated or official rights-of-way.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 5(BB), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 69-71, § 1, 10-8-69; Ord. No. 80-116, § 1, 10-21-80; Ord. No. 83-40, § 1, 6-7-83; Ord. No. 85-19, § 1, 4-2-85; Ord. No. 91-36, § 1, 3-19-91)</history></law>