<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. PUBLIC CHARTER SCHOOL FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-158</section_number>
<catch_line>Cessation of charter school operation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004042</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-158. Cessation of charter school operation.<section>The owners of property where a charter school facility is proposed to be located shall, at time of public hearing application, submit a document in a form approved by the Director suitable for recording in the public records and assuring the following:</section><section>If the charter school facility is constructed but fails to begin operation and/or the charter school fails after establishment, that the property owner, within 36 months of the facility's failure to begin operation or closure shall cause:<section prefix='(a)'>The facility to be in full compliance with all zoning regulations applicable to the property on which the charter school is located and allowing a use other than the charter school use, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>The operation of the charter school facility to be transferred to another charter school operator or the School Board, approved through applicable processes of the Miami-Dade County School Board, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>The charter school facility to be converted to an allowable use within the zoning district, provided said allowable use has first been authorized through the issuance of the appropriate permits, or</section><section prefix='(d)'>Authorization to be obtained at public hearing by the appropriate zoning board to convert the charter school facility to a use not otherwise allowable within the zoning district.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-108, ยง 1, 6-8-04)</history></law>