<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Box lunches, distribution.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003898</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-14. Box lunches, distribution.<section>No person shall distribute box lunches in the unincorporated areas of the County until such person has obtained all required permits from the County and the State of Florida.</section><section>The distribution of box lunches shall be subject to the following restrictions:<section prefix='(1)'>A box lunch operation shall only be permitted to stop temporarily on private property and only when actively serving customers. Once all transactions are complete, the box lunch operation must vacate the premises. No selling to be conducted on, or from, the public right-of-way and such sales to be made only from private property on which is located the use whose employees desire the service, and then only with the consent of the owner of such private property. (In the event active construction prevents access to private property, a temporary stop may be made on right-of-way.)</section><section prefix='(2)'>The uses to be served to be confined to industrial and manufacturing plants, including commercial uses such as garages and the like, and such uses also to include the servicing of building projects under active construction.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Owners of the box lunch business to be responsible for the action of their drivers and salesmen, and that such drivers and salesmen to do everything possible to prevent and eliminate the scattering of food, cups, napkins, etc., at their stops.</section><section prefix='(4)'>That such business shall have a properly authorized and licensed place of business.</section><section prefix='(5)'>That if any time following the issuance of such permit it shall appear to the Director that the holder of same has willfully violated the above restrictions, such permit shall be canceled with approval of the County Commission.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 38, 10-22-57; Ord. No. 13-42, ยง 2, 5-7-13)</history></law>