<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XA. EDUCATIONAL AND CHILD CARE FACILITIES, NONPUBLIC</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-151.11</section_number>
<catch_line>Applicability and definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004023</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-151.11. Applicability and definitions.<section>Provisions of this article relating to day nurseries, kindergartens and after school care as defined herein shall be applicable in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and specifically in the incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. No municipality shall adopt physical standards governing day nurseries, kindergartens or after school care that are in conflict with or in addition to the standards contained in this article, whether more or less restrictive than the standards contained herein.</section><section>As used in this article, the term "private school" or "nonpublic educational facility" shall mean an institution which provides child care and/or instruction from the infant level through the college level and which does not come under the direct operation and administration of the Miami-Dade County School Board or the State of Florida; only such uses are intended to be controlled by this article and include, but are not limited to, the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Day nurseries: Child care for infants and children up to and including age six (6).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Kindergartens: Child care and preschool programs for children ages four (4) through six (6).</section><section prefix='(c)'>After-school care: Child care and recreation for children above the age of five (5) when no formal schooling program is conducted and where the care provided is generally after school, on weekends, school holidays and vacations.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Babysitting service for shoppers: Child care for limited time periods (maximum three (3) hours) provided within a shopping center solely for the convenience of the patrons, and limited to not more than forty (40) children at any one (1) time.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Private college/university: An institution of higher learning beyond the high school level.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Family day care homes: Child care and recreation with a maximum of five (5) children including the day care operator's own children.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Private school: This term as used herein refers to any private institution providing child care and/or instruction at any level from infants through the college level.</section><section prefix='(h)'>[Child, student, pupil:] The terms "child," "student," "pupil," and their plurals are used interchangeably in this article.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Elementary, junior and senior high schools: References to these schools are to be loosely interpreted to encompass any schools, graded or ungraded, whose students are within the age ranges typically found at these school levels.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-59, ยง 1, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 86-27, ยง 1, 4-1-86; Ord. No. 93-126, ยง 2, 11-16-93)</history></law>