<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. MOBILE HOMES AND MOBILE HOME PARKS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-175</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum setbacks of mobile home spaces from property line of park; landscaping and maintenance of setbacks.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004075</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-175. Minimum setbacks of mobile home spaces from property line of park; landscaping and maintenance of setbacks.<section>A minimum twenty-five-foot setback landscaped buffer area shall be provided and maintained along and extending inward from the property lines of the park which are adjacent to other private property; seventeen and one-half (17½) feet along property lines adjacent to rights-of-way of less than seventy (70) feet in official width; and thirty-five (35) feet along property lines adjacent to rights-of-way of seventy (70) feet or more in official width.</section><section>The buffer area shall be completely landscaped with a balanced arrangement of ground cover, shrubs, vines, hedges and trees or other landscape features such as walls, fences and berms, or a combination of any of the above items in accordance with of this Code.</section><section>Those buffer areas adjacent to other private properties shall be designed to provide at least seventy-five (75) percent visual barrier, after two (2) years growth along the entire such property line. Buffer areas adjacent to public rights-of-way shall be designed to provide at least fifty (50) percent visual barrier, after two (2) years growth along the entire such property line. Plant material and other such landscape features shall be arranged in such a way so as to prevent vehicular access through, or parking in such buffer areas. Additional requirements shall be as provided in of this Code.</section><section>Plant materials used shall conform in definition, quality, and size when planted, to the provisions of of this Code for each type of plant except that trees shall be a minimum of seven (7) feet tall by three and one-half-foot spread when planted. This minimum size tree shall be required for those trees placed seventy-five (75) feet on center, but additional smaller trees can be planted as part of the required landscaping.</section><section>Plants shall be spaced to provide the required visual screen within a two-year growing period.</section><section>Planting at street intersections of any vehicular or pedestrian exits shall be done in accordance with the safety standards specified in of this Code to prevent visual obstructions along street rights-of-way.</section><section>All plant material shall be installed in accordance with good planting practices to insure the survival and healthy growth of the plants. The buffer area shall be maintained in accordance with good landscape maintenance practices, including installation and use of sprinklers, to insure the good health and appearance of all planted material. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-54, § 1, 6-15-71; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>