<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.14</section_number>
<catch_line>Workforce housing agreement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004107</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.14. Workforce housing agreement.<section>Prior to the earlier of final plat approval or application for building permit for the first residential unit on the property subject to the requirements of this article applicant shall submit a declaration of restrictive covenants, approved in form by the Director and sufficient for recording in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, encumbering the individual WHUs in the entire development, specifying the restrictions of the WHU and such further arrangements, restrictive covenants, and resale restrictions as are necessary to carry out the purposes of, Article IX of the code, sections through inclusive, and shall include the following:<section prefix='(a)'>A binding commitment that the restrictions of this article shall run with the land for the entire control period, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>A binding commitment that the covenants will bind the applicant, any assignee, mortgagee, or buyer, and all other parties that receive title to or an interest in the property, and</section><section prefix='(c)'>These covenants shall be senior to all other liens or encumbrances on the property including all instruments securing permanent financing, except that tax and assessment liens shall be superior to these covenants, and</section><section prefix='(d)'>A binding commitment that incorporates all terms and conditions regarding WHUs, including without limitation, the required shared equity agreement, eligibility standards, appropriate sale and rental price standards and affordability controls required of purchasers of WHUs pursuant to Chapter 17, Article VIII of this code.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>