<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE IX. STREET NAMES AND NUMBERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-138</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004008</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-138. Definitions.<section>The following words and phrases are hereby defined as provided in this section, when used in this article:<section prefix='(1)'>Through streets. All thoroughfares making a continuous intersection across and extending for one (1) or more squares on both sides of Flagler Street and of Miami Avenue shall be deemed a through street.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Square. The side of a block lying between two (2) through streets shall be deemed a square.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Streets. All through streets running east and west shall be designated as streets.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Avenues. All through streets running north and south shall be designated as avenues.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Courts. All thoroughfares not deemed through streets located and running next parallel to an avenue shall be designated as courts.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Places. All thoroughfares not deemed through streets located and running next parallel to a court shall be designated as places.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Terraces. All thoroughfares not deemed through streets located and running next parallel to a street shall be designated as terraces.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Lanes. All thoroughfares not deemed through streets located and running next parallel to a terrace shall be designated as lanes.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Roads. All thoroughfares running diagonally and not a continuation of a north and south or east or west thoroughfare shall be designated as roads.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Number unit. Each twelve and one-half (12½) feet of every lot shall be deemed a number unit.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Base thoroughfares. Those certain streets herein named Miami Avenue and Flagler Street shall be deemed the base thoroughfare from which all street names and house numbers shall have their numerical beginning, running northerly, southerly, easterly and westerly.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 32(B), 10-22-57)</history></law>