<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Alternatives to on-site construction of WHUs; variances.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004100</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.8. Alternatives to on-site construction of WHUs; variances.<section prefix='(A)'>Alternatives. An applicant for a WHU application ("WHU applicant") may satisfy the requirement of on-site construction of all of the required WHUs or of a portion of required WHUs by one of the means described below upon demonstrating, after public hearing, that where, owing to special conditions, allowing the alternative will observe the spirit of this article, and that approving the alternative requested will further the development of housing for the workforce target income group in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County to an equal or greater extent than construction of the required WHUs on-site.<section prefix='(1)'>Off-site construction of WHUs. If an approval is obtained after public hearing in accordance with the standards in this section, a WHU applicant may comply with the requirements of this article by construction of 110% of the number of WHUs required by this article at one or more alternative sites within a 2 mile radius of the proposed location of the market rate units being proposed (the "Off-site WHUs"). The alternative site must contain both its market rate and workforce housing units and the Off-site WHUs. The alternative site shall be within the same Community Council jurisdiction as the market rate units being proposed and the construction of the Off-site WHUs on the alternative site shall occur concurrently with the market rate units on the primary site.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Monetary contribution in lieu of construction of WHUs. If an approval is obtained after public hearing in accordance with the standards in this section, or if permitted as of right pursuant to section 33-193.9, a WHU applicant may satisfy the requirements of this article by providing a monetary contribution to the affordable housing trust fund established in Chapter 17, Article VIII of this code, in lieu of construction of the required on-site workforce housing units. Any monetary contributions received by the County shall not be commingled with any other funds deposited into the affordable housing trust fund that are not associated with the WHU program, but shall be deposited into a separate account. The amount of such required monetary contribution shall be as established in section 33-193.9.1. All monetary contributions shall be made prior to the issuance of the first building permit on the market rate units.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Combination of off-site construction of WHUs and monetary contributions. If an approval is obtained after public hearing in accordance with the standards in this section, a WHU applicant may comply with the requirements of this article employing a combination of the alternatives (1) and (2) above in accordance with the standards of this section.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Variances. The following provisions of this article may be varied after public hearing, only upon demonstration that a literal enforcement of the provision of this article will result in an unnecessary hardship, that allowing the variance will observe the spirit of this article, that the degree to which the variance is granted is the minimum needed to avoid the hardship, and that the objectives of this article to increase the supply of housing for the workforce housing target group within the Community Council area will continue to be met if the requested variance is granted:<section prefix='(1)'>The applicable density bonus provisions or intensity standards;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The number of WHUs required for a WHU application;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The amount of the monetary contribution in lieu pursuant to Section 33-193.9.1</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>If zoning approval is required, the application for such approval shall be filed together with the application for approval of any off site WHUs and shall be considered and approved or denied at the same public hearing.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>