<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. OFF-STREET PARKING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-124.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Parking of commercial vehicles in residential or agricultural zones.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003994</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-124.1. Parking of commercial vehicles in residential or agricultural zones.<section prefix='(a)'>The following are hereby defined as commercial vehicles for the purpose of this section:</section><section>A vehicle that is a taxicab, a limousine under twenty (20) feet in length or any passenger vehicle truck or van with a maximum height of eight (8) feet from the ground marked with a sign, letters, identification numbers or emblem advertising or associating it in any way with a commercial enterprise other than those which identify the vehicle maker or dealer. A sport utility vehicle marked with a sign, letters, identification numbers or emblem advertising or associating it in any way with a commercial enterprise, other than those which identify the vehicle maker or dealer, shall be considered as a Category 1 vehicle. For purposes of this section, a passenger vehicle bearing an emblem or lettering of a government entity shall also be considered as a Category 1 vehicle.</section><section>A vehicle eight (8) feet or less in height that displays externally stored or mounted equipment either in a fixed or temporary manner which is visible of a commercial activity are visible including, but not limited to, food vending equipment, ladders, paint cans, lawn care equipment or fixtures and brackets necessary to carry such items. Trailers or utility trailers less than 20 feet in length which are enclosed or of an unenclosed design shall also be included as Category 2 vehicles.</section><section>A vehicle, other than a recreational vehicle as defined in(f), exceeding twenty (20) feet in length or more than eight (8) feet in height from the ground including, but not limited to, tow trucks, dump trucks, construction or earth moving vehicles or equipment and semi-tractors and trailers.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Storage or parking of certain commercial vehicles is allowed on private property in residential zones as follows:<section prefix='1.'>In agriculturally zoned areas (AU) where a bona fide agricultural use, as defined in Section 19-3(B) of this Code, exists on private property, parking or storage of commercial vehicles used for agricultural purposes or in the transport of agricultural products is allowed as otherwise provided in this chapter.</section><section prefix='2.'>In residentially zoned districts, only two Category 1 vehicles may be parked at a residence.</section><section prefix='3.'>In residentially zoned districts, only one Category 2 vehicle may be stored or parked provided that it is kept within an enclosed garage or behind the front building line within a completely enclosed, opaque fence, screening wall or landscaping 6 feet in height at least ten (10) feet from the rear property line. If a Category 2 vehicle is so stored or parked, then only one Category 1 vehicle may also be stored or parked at such residence.</section><section prefix='4.'>For residential properties of four (4) or more units, the parking allowances provided for herein shall be applied as to each unit.</section><section prefix='5.'>Storage or parking of Category 3 vehicles are prohibited in all residentially zoned districts.</section><section prefix='6.'>The temporary parking of a Category 2 or 3 vehicle in front of the building line or in front of the buffer screen shall only be permitted for the purpose of loading or unloading of materials or persons or engaged in providing a commercial service at the premises or for the purpose of the driver to make a temporary convenience stop at the residence. However, a temporary or convenience stop shall be limited to no more than one hour in any 24-hour period.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Parking of certain commercial vehicles on the right-of-way is prohibited in residential zones as follows:<section prefix='1.'>In areas zoned residential districts, it shall be unlawful for Category 2 or 3, vehicles, as herein defined, to be otherwise parked on the public right-of-way, unless actively engaged in the loading or unloading of materials or persons or engaged in providing a commercial service. Examples of providing commercial services include, but are not limited to, removal of disabled vehicles from private or public property presence at a construction site, delivery of goods, repair of household appliances and cleaning of household furniture.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Violations of these provisions are punishable as follows:<section prefix='1.'>Any violation of this section is punishable by a civil fine of five-hundred dollars ($500.00). Upon a repeat violation of subsection 33-124.1(c), in addition to civil penalties, such vehicle may be towed or immobilized until all outstanding violations and enforcement costs have been paid. After 35 days of storage or immobilization, such vehicle may be disposed of pursuant to the provisions contained in Section 713.585, Florida Statutes. Any enforcement officer is hereby authorized to secure the assistance of the Miami-Dade Police Department to effect enforcement of these provisions.</section><section prefix='2.'>Whoever opposes, obstructs or resists an enforcement officer in the discharge of duties as provided in this section, upon conviction, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree and shall be subject to punishment as provided by law.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-16, ยง 2, 2-2-99; Ord. No. 05-75, ยง 1, 4-19-05)</history></law>