<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-17</section_number>
<catch_line>Buildings for public assemblage—In districts other than business or industrial.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003906</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-17. Buildings for public assemblage—In districts other than business or industrial.<section>All building or other structures or any part thereof, intended for public assemblage, wherein provisions are made for fifty (50) or more persons to assemble in one (1) room or such structure as an auditorium, church, club, hospital, sanitarium, school, theater, night club, amusement park structure and similar structures, excluding hotels, motels and apartments shall be located or placed only in business or industrial districts, as herein provided, and shall comply with the following:<section prefix='(1)'>No building for public assemblage shall be located closer than twenty-five (25) feet to any property line which abuts on a public highway or alley, or closer than fifty (50) feet of any property line abutting a lot under different ownership than that on which the structure is to be placed, or closer than seventy-five (75) feet to an existing residential building.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A separate lot used to provide setback requirements shall not be occupied by another building, if it would reduce the clear space required.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In EU-1 and EU-2 Districts, where the setback from the front building line is greater than the minimum specified by this section, buildings for public assemblage shall set back at least the minimum distance required, namely, fifty (50) feet from the front property line.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No building for public assemblage in EU-M, EU-1 and EU-2 Districts shall be closer than seventy-five (75) feet to any property line abutting a lot under ownership other than that on which the structure is to be placed.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Ample parking facilities for buildings for public assemblage shall be provided off the highway right-of-way. Parking facilities for a church, school, or other buildings used for noncommercial purposes in a residential district may be permitted in the same district with said church, school or other buildings used for noncommercial purposes, provided no parking lot or special parking area is closer than twenty-five (25) feet to any property under different ownership which is zoned RU or EU unless the parking area is separated from such lot by a wall or hedge approved by the Director.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Philanthropic and eleemosynary institutions shall be classed as buildings for public assemblage, but if any building or its use is operated for profit, it shall be permitted only in districts where such business or industry is permitted.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 5(M)(1), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 02-255, § 1, 12-3-02)</history></law>