<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-19.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Display of vehicles for sale.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003909</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-19.1. Display of vehicles for sale.<section prefix='(a)'>No vehicle or boat shall be displayed for sale in a residential district unless affixed to the vehicle is a valid state license plate issued for the vehicle, except that a vehicle affixed with a lost tag may be displayed for a period not to exceed ten (10) days. A vehicle with a lost tag shall have the vehicle registration affixed to the rear window so as to be easily readable by law enforcement and code enforcement officials. As used in this section, the term "vehicle" shall include an automobile, motorcycle, truck, or recreational vehicle, a utility trailer, or a trailer for transporting off-highway vehicles or boats.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In residential districts no more than one (1) vehicle may be displayed for sale at any one (1) time on any one (1) premise and no more than two (2) vehicles may be displayed for sale at any one (1) premise for any one (1) calendar year, and the display shall only be permitted at the current address of the registered owner of the vehicle offered for sale on the subject premises.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No more than one sign shall be placed on the vehicle offered for sale. Such sign shall not exceed 8 inches by 12 inches.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All violations of this section shall be punishable by a fine of one hundred dollars ($100.00) for the first vehicle on a first offense and five hundred dollars ($500.00) per vehicle for each additional vehicle and any repeat violation of this section. The County may lien the vehicle and any real property owned by the violator in Miami-Dade County until all fines, enforcement costs, and administrative costs are paid by the violator. Any vehicle in violation of this section shall be towed if not removed immediately by the owner. (Vehicle owners will be responsible for all fines, towing fees, storage fees, and any administrative and enforcement fees that result from the enforcement of this section.)</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-211, ยง 3, 11-21-95; Ord. No. 98-36, ยง 1, 3-31-98; Ord. No. 01-85, ยง 1, 5-8-01; Ord. No. 05-190, ยง 1, 11-3-05)</history></law>