<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VIII. RIGHT-OF-WAY PLAN AND MINIMUM WIDTH</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-136</section_number>
<catch_line>Placing building near section line; construction on or in right-of-way.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004006</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-136. Placing building near section line; construction on or in right-of-way.<section>No permit shall be issued for the placing of any structure closer than forty (40) feet to any section line or closer than thirty-five (35) feet to any half section line plus, in either event, the building setback required by this chapter, except where greater or less distances are required by or. No building or structure shall be permitted on, or in, a right-of-way as described in, except that drip irrigation pump houses ("pump houses") may be permitted to be constructed in such rights-of-way providing prior written approval is obtained from the director of the Public Works Department pursuant to of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and further providing that a building permit is secured for such pump house placement. Additionally, wire fences without barbed wire may be permitted to be constructed on or in rights-of-way, as described in, provided that written approval is obtained from the director of the Public Works Department pursuant to, and further provided that a building permit is secured for such fence placement. Masonry walls, wood fences, or wire fences may be permitted to be constructed on or in a right-of-way as described in if approved as a non-use variance pursuant to the provisions of Sections(c)(1) and (2) and of the Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 31(C), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 92-94, ยง 1, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 94-29, ยง 2, 2-1-94; Ord. No. 94-50, ยง 2, 3-17-94)</history></law>