<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XIIA. WORKFORCE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-193.12</section_number>
<catch_line>Design and unit placement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004105</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-193.12. Design and unit placement.<section prefix='(A)'>Workforce housing units shall be comparable in design and materials to market-rate units within the development in terms of exterior appearance. Workforce housing units may be grouped or dispersed throughout the development.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Notwithstanding underlying zoning regulations that limit the number of residential units that may be constructed on a single platted lot, residential developments incorporating workforce housing units may utilize the following flexible design provisions, provided that the total development density shall not exceed that allowed by this article. Units to be developed in accordance with this section shall be approved only upon demonstration that a declaration of condominium has been filed in accordance with state law (if any unit is to be sold).<section prefix='(1)'>No more than 3 total residential units may be placed on a single platted lot, of which no more than one unit may be, but shall not be required to be, a market rate unit; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The entrance to each of the units on a single platted lot shall be:<section prefix='(a)'>Through a common hall/foyer area in the front of the building, which shall be concealed by a building wall with 1 entrance door, giving the appearance of a single-family residential unit; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>The entrance to the workforce housing unit(s) shall be clearly designed to be subordinate to the principal entrance of the building for the market rate unit. When the entrance is configured in this manner, the design shall incorporate architectural features and elements that clearly distinguish and develop the market rate unit entrance as the predominant entrance from the other entrances.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Buildings designed under these parameters shall not be located on the periphery of a development, adjacent to or across the street from previously established single-family residential neighborhoods.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The locations of the parking spaces for the units within the building shall be dispersed around the building so as not to create a parking field for all of the spaces in the front of the building.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-05, ยง 1, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, ยง 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>