<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. PUBLIC CHARTER SCHOOL FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-159</section_number>
<catch_line>Plan review standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004043</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-159. Plan review standards.<section prefix='(a)'>Scale. The scale of proposed public charter school facilities shall be compatible with the scale of surrounding proposed or existing uses and shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Compatibility. The design of public charter school facilities shall be compatible with the design, kind and intensity of uses and scale of the surrounding area.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Buffers. Buffering elements shall be utilized for visual screening and substantial reduction of noise levels at all property lines where necessary.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Landscape. Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing the removal of trees or the alteration of favorable characteristics of the site. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this code.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Circulation. Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the facility and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the facility.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Noise. Effective measures shall be provided to keep noise at acceptable levels.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Service areas. Wherever service areas are provided, they shall be screened and so located as to be compatible with the adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Parking areas. Parking areas shall be screened and so located as to be compatible with the adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Operating time. The operational hours of a public charter school facility shall be compatible with the activities of other adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Industrial and commercial. Where schools are proposed in or adjacent to, industrial or commercial areas it shall be clearly demonstrated in graphic form and otherwise, how the impact on the commercial or industrial area has been minimized through site design techniques and/or operational modifications.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Fences and walls. Outdoor recreation and/or play areas shall be enclosed with fences and/or walls.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-108, ยง 1, 6-8-04)</history></law>