<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. PUBLIC CHARTER SCHOOL FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-152</section_number>
<catch_line>Applicability, purpose and definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004036</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-152. Applicability, purpose and definitions.<section>Provisions of this article relating to public charter school facilities as defined herein shall be applicable in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>The purpose of this article is to provide standards for approval of public charter school facilities, pursuant to agreement with the School Board of Miami-Dade County pertaining to siting of such facilities. Any use proposed for a charter school site other than the charter school facility use provided in this article shall be subject to all other applicable provisions of this Chapter.</section><section>As used in this article, the term "public charter school" or "charter school" shall mean an educational institution which is authorized and maintained in accord with the provisions of Chapter 1002, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time. All such public charter schools shall be additionally authorized locally by the Miami-Dade County School Board through a process established by that entity for the approval of the charter. The terms "child," "student," "pupil," and their plurals are used interchangeably in this article. For purposes of this article, student educational opportunities within a public charter school shall include one or more of the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Kindergarten: preschool programs for children ages four (4) through six (6).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Elementary school: educational programs for children in grades 1 through 5.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Middle school: educational programs for children in grades 6 through 8.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Senior high school: educational programs for children in grades 9 through 12.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-108, ยง 1, 6-8-04)</history></law>