<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00056' order_by='00056' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIH. TRADITIONAL NEIGHBORHOOD DEVELOPMENT (TND) DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.50</section_number>
<catch_line>Review procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004366</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.50. Review procedure.<section>The TND review procedures are divided into four (4) steps: (A) preapplication conference; (B) initial TND review; (C) intermediate site plan review; and (D) final review.<section prefix='(A)'>Preapplication conference. It shall be the responsibility of the Developmental Impact Committee to coordinate with other affected departments, and where applicable, representatives of adjacent municipalities to a joint meeting for the purposes of participating in the review of the TND. Prior to said joint meeting, the applicant may confer with the Department, other affected departments and, where applicable, representatives of adjacent municipalities, in connection with the preparation of the TND District application. The applicant shall provide a general outline of the proposal through schematics and sketch plans including narrative information sufficient for the understanding of the proposed development. Thereafter and within ten (10) working days after the preapplication conference, the Developmental Impact Committee shall furnish the applicant with all written comments resulting from such conference including appropriate recommendations to inform and assist the applicant in the preparation of the components of the TND District application. The applicant shall have the right to apply for an additional preapplication conference prior to filing a formal application with the Department. The same procedure as above shall be followed.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Initial TND review.<section prefix='(1)'>Following the preapplication conference(s), the total development plan reviews shall be initiated by the applicant. Required exhibits listed below together with an application for public hearing shall be submitted to the Department in accordance with the requirements of Section 33-304, Code of Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='(a)'>Required exhibits—Written documents. The following written documents shall be submitted to the Developmental Impact Committee for review prior to the public hearing.<section prefix='1.'>Recordable agreement guaranteeing the development in accordance with promises made in the written and graphic documents listed below as approved by the Community Zoning Appeals Board. A draft of said agreement shall be submitted to the Developmental Impact Committee twelve (12) days prior to Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council review with final executed agreement received fifteen (15) days prior to Community Zoning Appeals Board review and action.</section><section prefix='2.'>A development schedule indicating the approximate date(s) when construction of the TND and phases thereof including the mix of residential and commercial, will be initiated and completed.</section><section prefix='3.'>Quantitative data in a table format indicating the intensity of the land uses proposed in the TND and the total maximum number of units.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Required exhibits—Graphic documents. Map, site plans and drawings, depicting the proposed TND shall be submitted as part of the development plan and shall contain the following minimum information:<section prefix='1.'>A certificated survey indicating the existing site characteristics including any major variations of elevations, watercourse(s), unique natural historical and archeological features, existing buildings and vegetation.</section><section prefix='2.'>A plan at a scale of 1″=300′ indicating all land uses on perimeter lots greenbelts, existing and proposed circulation systems for arterial, (i.e. through streets), and major points of ingress and egress to the development.</section><section prefix='3.'>Adequate information on land areas adjacent to the proposed TND at a scale of 1″=300′ to indicate the relationships between the proposed development and adjacent areas, including existing land uses, zoning districts, densities, vehicular, pedestrian and equestrian circulations systems, access for people with disabilities, and public facilities, as well as unique natural features of the landscape.</section><section prefix='4.'>The proposed treatment of the perimeter of the TND including materials and techniques to be used to provide transition to other developments.</section><section prefix='5.'>Any additional information required by the Developmental Impact Committee to evaluate the character and impact of the proposed TND.</section><section>It is provided, however, that the requirements of Subsections(B)(1)(a)(1) and (2), and(B)(1)(b)(4) shall not apply to applications of the Director or Zoning Official.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Upon the filing of a complete application, the Department shall submit the required exhibits for the TND to the Developmental Impact Committee for review in accordance with standards and review procedures of the Developmental Impact Committee as provided in Section 33-303.1. At a public hearing held by the Community Zoning Appeals Board, the applicant shall present the proposal. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall have the recommendations of the Developmental Impact Committee. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall consider the information presented by the applicant, the recommendations of the Developmental Impact Committee and viewpoints of the public expressed at the hearing. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall take formal action either approving the plan as presented, approving it subject to certain specified modifications, and/or conditions disapproving it, or a combination of the foregoing. Upon approval, plans, documents and recordable development agreements shall be filed with the Department and recorded in the official records and shall thereby constitute the TND District. If the TND is approved with specific modifications, as incorporated in the Community Zoning Appeals Board's resolution, those modifications shall be made by the applicant on all applicable documents and plans prior to filing the same with the Department. Such filing shall be completed within sixty (60) calendar days from date the decision becomes final including all appeals. Failure to do so shall nullify the Community Zoning Appeals Board's action unless waived by the Community Zoning appeals Board or if appealed, by the County Commission. The Director shall review all modifications in accordance with the Community Zoning Appeals Board's decision. The approved TND shall be indicated on the zoning maps as would any other district boundary change. Intermediate site plan review shall not be initiated until the above requirements have been met.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Intermediate site plan review.<section prefix='(1)'>Following final approval of the TND zoning district by the Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners, the following plans and documents shall be submitted for Developmental Impact Committee review and approval together with any other relevant information required by said Committee.<section>The site plan(s) to be reviewed and approved administratively by the Developmental Impact Committee shall include:</section><section prefix='(a)'>A master plan at a scale of no less than 1″=100′ which shall include the following information:<section prefix='1.'>All land use categories, blocks, squares and parks, greenbelts, greens, civic and/or public/semi-public building footprints, parking, and landscaped open space. In addition, the plan shall indicate existing and proposed circulation systems, including streets, alleys and major points of access.</section><section prefix='2.'>Drawings of typical street sections.</section><section prefix='3.'>A table shall be provided as part of the site plan in accordance with the following:</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Following administrative site plan approval by the Developmental Impact Committee, subsequent substantial modifications to the site plan with regard to land use including, but not limited to, the location of streets, parks and squares, civic use lots, greenbelts, greens and parking shall be required to be approved after a public hearing in accordance with the procedures contained in subsection (B) herein.</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Final review.<section prefix='(1)'>Final review for all or a portion of the TND shall be by the Department of Planning and Zoning in accordance with all plans and documents as approved by the Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners, the Developmental Impact Committee, and as filed with the Department. Said final review shall be completed prior to tentative plat approval. Upon approval by the Department, the applicant may proceed to develop any portion of the TND as approved under final review. The Building Department shall issue building permits in accordance with all previously approved plans and documents and in accordance with applicable requirements of the Florida Building Code and other applicable State and Miami-Dade County requirements. The following information shall be submitted to the Department of Planning and Zoning.<section prefix='(a)'>Master plan at a scale of not less than 1″=100′ which shall include the following information:<section prefix='1.'>All land use categories, blocks, squares and parks, greenbelts, greens, civic and/or public/semi-public building footprints, parking, and landscaped open space. In addition, the plan shall indicate existing and proposed circulation systems, including streets, alleys and major points of access.</section><section prefix='2.'>Footprint and height of existing and proposed civic use buildings, fences and walls.</section><section prefix='3.'>Building lots.</section><section prefix='4.'>Pedestrian, equestrian and vehicular circulation systems.</section><section prefix='5.'>Drawings of typical street sections at 1″=20′.</section><section prefix='6.'>Drawings indicating the type of street furniture, signage, and street lights proposed for the TND.</section><section prefix='7.'>Parking layouts and drives.</section><section prefix='8.'>Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='9.'>Building design control which will establish the design criteria for the TND referring to materials and methods of construction, proportions and conformance to regional environmental and design issues including the general use of roof overhangs, colonnades, porches, pergolas, trellises and the maximization of cross ventilation.</section><section prefix='10.'>A calculation of maximum potential lot coverage for stormwater drainage engineering purposes.</section></section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-41, § 1, 4-2-91; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 32, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-26, § 1, 5-4-99; Ord. No. 99-82, § 1, 7-13-99; Ord. No. 03-47, § 4, 3-11-03)</history></law>