<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(I). DOWNTOWN KENDALL URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.57</section_number>
<catch_line>Review procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004374</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.57. Review procedure.<section>Projects following the provisions of this Article and the Regulating Plans shall be processed and approved administratively. The Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning shall review the applications including exhibits listed below for completeness and compliance with the provisions of this Article and the Regulating Plans. All complete submissions to the Department shall be reviewed and approved or denied, within twenty-one (21) days from the date of submission. The applicant shall have the right to extend the twenty-one (21) day period by an additional twenty-one (21) days upon timely request made in writing to the Department. The Department shall have the right to extend the twenty-one (21) day period by written notice to the applicant that additional information is needed to process the site plan. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for the denial. Any final decision of the Director may be appealed in accordance with the public hearing procedure established in Article XXXVI of this Code and in accordance with the procedure established for appeals of administrative decision.</section><section>Exhibits prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects shall be submitted to the Department and shall include, but not be limited, to the following:<section prefix='(A)'>Site plan(s) including:<section prefix='(1)'>Lot lines and setbacks.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Location, shape, size and height of existing and proposed building construction and landscaping.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Location of on-street and off-street parking, loading facilities, waste collection areas, and all above ground utilities.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Indication of signage.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Indication of any site or building design methods used to conserve energy.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Street type designations as per this Article.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Indication of Sub-District boundaries as per this Article.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Landscape plans including specification of plant material, location and size.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including total gross square foot area of each floor and all dimensions relating to the requirements of this Article.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Figures indicating the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Gross and net acreage.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Amount of landscaped open space in square feet and percentage required and provided.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Total square footage of all land uses.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Amount of building coverage at ground level in square feet and percentage.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Total trees required and provided, indicating on site and off site contribution within the District.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Parking required and provided.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Total amount of paved area in square feet.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Total number of dwelling units.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project.</section><section>In the case of multiple-phase development, each phase of the development, whether standing independently or in conjunction with existing developed or proposed future contiguous phases, shall meet all the requirements of this Article. For future development outside the Center DRI Sub-District, expansions or additions to legal structures, if not in substantial compliance with previously approved plans, shall be subject to those requirements of this Article applicable to the entire block or blocks in the Regulating Plans for which the expansion or addition is proposed.</section><section>Notwithstanding the review procedure contained herein, all requests for the subdivision of property within the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District shall have previously received site plan approval in accordance with the requirements of this section or below.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-166, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 02-11, ยง 1, 1-29-02)</history></law>