<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00068' order_by='00068' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(T). PALMER LAKE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (PLMUC)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.56</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004471</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.56. Definitions.<section>Terms used throughout this Article shall take their commonly accepted meaning unless otherwise defined in or of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Terms requiring interpretation specific to this Article are as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Block: A combination of contiguous building lots, the perimeter of which abuts one or more public streets, private streets, easements or designated open spaces.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building Frontage: The portion of a building required to adjoin or be located within the frontage zone.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Building Frontage Zone: The portion of a lot adjoining a street or right-of-way. The width of the building frontage zone is established by the applicable street type and/or Sub-district.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Elevated Pedestrian Walkway: An enclosed structure located above private property and/or the public right-of-way allowing pedestrian access between and through buildings.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Floorplate: The total indoor and outdoor area of any given story of a building, measured to the exterior of the wall.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Forecourt: an open area where the building pedestal is recessed outside of the building frontage zone.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Frontage: The property line or lines of a lot which coincide with a right-of-way or other public open space line as shown on a Regulating Plan.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Habitable Space: Building space whose use involves human presence with direct view of the adjoining streets or open space, excluding parking garages, self-service storage facilities, and warehouses.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Mixed-use building: A building that includes a combination of two or more vertically integrated uses, such as, but not limited to retail and/or office uses on the ground story, with residential uses above.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Pedestal: The lower portion of the building including the ground story located adjoining or within the building frontage zone..</section><section prefix='(11)'>Retail Use: Premises used for the exchange of services or goods.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Storefront: Retail or office use areas, lobby areas or other habitable space located at the building frontage.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Story: A floor level within a building as described in this Article's General Requirements.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Street: A thoroughfare for the movement of pedestrians and vehicles, as provided in this Article.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Tower: The upper portion of a building above the pedestal.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Water-dependent Use: Activities that can be carried out only on, in, or adjacent to water areas because the use requires access to a water body, including without limitation: waterborne transportation hubs such as ports or marinas; or marine recreation.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Water-related Use: Activities that are not directly dependent upon access to a water body, but that provide goods and services that are directly associated with water-dependent uses.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Weather Protection Features: Architectural features that provide protection from the sun and rain, including without limitation, colonnades, awnings, or projecting roofs.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Work-force Housing Unit or WHU: A dwelling unit, the sale, rental or pricing which is restricted to households whose income is up to one-hundred forty (140) percent of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. HUD as maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-43, ยง 2, 5-7-13)</history></law>