<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.88</section_number>
<catch_line>Review Procedure/Administrative Site Plan and Architectural Review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004402</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.88. Review Procedure/Administrative Site Plan and Architectural Review.<section>Except for individual single-family homes and duplexes, all applications for development approval within an Urban Center District that are not otherwise permitted as nonconforming uses or structures shall comply with the requirements of this article and with the site plan and architectural review criteria contained herein. Developments shall be processed and approved administratively as follows:<section prefix='A.'>Administrative site and architectural plan review. The Department shall review plans, including the exhibits listed below for completeness and compliance with the provisions of this article, including the Regulating Plans, and for compliance with the site plan review criteria provided herein. Additionally, all applications shall be reviewed by the following departments of Miami-Dade County and other public entities for potential impacts on infrastructure and other services resulting from the application: Department of Public Works and Waste Management or its successor, Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or its successor, Miami-Dade Fire Rescue Department or its successor, and the Miami-Dade County School Board. In the event the application indicates impacts on services and infrastructure provided by any of the foregoing, the applicant shall meet with the affected department or entity to discuss potential mitigation of the impacts and shall submit evidence to the Department of such discussion. The Director shall issue a final decision within twenty-one (21) days of the date of submission of the completed application. The applicant shall have the right to extend the twenty-one (21) day period by an additional twenty-one (21) days upon timely request made in writing to the Department. The Department shall have the right to extend the twenty-one (21) day period by written notice to the applicant that additional information is needed. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for the denial. Any final decision of the Director may be appealed in accordance with the procedures established in this chapter for appeals of administrative decisions.</section><section prefix='B.'>Applications for administrative site plan and architectural review under this article shall be accompanied by exhibits prepared by registered architects and landscape architects which shall be submitted to the Department and shall include the following:<section prefix='1.'>Site plan(s) including:<section prefix='a.'>Sub-district location;</section><section prefix='b.'>Street layouts and designations as per this article;</section><section prefix='c.'>Locations, shape, size, and height of existing buildings;</section><section prefix='d.'>Building exterior finish material;</section><section prefix='e.'>Indication of street vistas;</section><section prefix='f.'>Lot lines, setbacks and build-to lines;</section><section prefix='g.'>Location of open spaces including anchor points if applicable;</section><section prefix='h.'>Location of on-street and off-street parking including type of permeable materials if used on parking lots, loading facilities, and waste collection areas;</section><section prefix='i.'>Indication of signage;</section><section prefix='j.'>Indication of any site or building design methods used to conserve energy;</section><section prefix='k.'>Locations of backflow prevention devices and connections; and</section><section prefix='l.'>Indication of the placement and type(s) of lighting fixtures illuminating roadways and parking areas.</section></section></section><section prefix='2.'>Landscape plans, including specifications of species of plant material, location, and size in accordance with this article and Chapter 18A of this code.</section><section prefix='3.'>Street cross-sections, including adjacent buildings and open space.</section><section prefix='4.'>Floor plans, elevations, and sections of all buildings, including total gross square feet of area for each floor and all dimensions relating to the requirements of this article. A pattern book may be submitted for detached and attached single-family units including, at a minimum, unit plans and elevations, elevation of unit groupings, and typical design details such as street lamps, benches, fencing, and paving details.</section><section prefix='5.'>Figures indicating the following:<section prefix='a.'>Gross and net acreage;</section><section prefix='b.'>Total square footage for each use by type;</section><section prefix='c.'>Total number of dwelling units;</section><section prefix='d.'>Amount of passive and active open space in square feet; and</section><section prefix='e.'>Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project's compliance with the requirements of this article and Chapter.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-143, ยง 8, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 12-86, ยง 7, 10-2-12)</history></law>