<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. AU, AGRICULTURAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-280.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Vested rights; property rezoned to AU.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004308</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-280.1. Vested rights; property rezoned to AU.<section prefix='(a)'>Any landowner whose property was rezoned to AU subsequent to December 28, 1984, as the result of an application by the Director and who claims a vested right to develop or use his property contrary to Section 33-280, may submit an application for a determination of vested rights to the Department within ninety (90) days after the later of: (1) the date that the official resolution of the zoning action by the Board of County Commissioners was transmitted to the owner; or, (2) the date of final judicial action.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person filing an application for a determination of vested rights with the Department shall attach an affidavit setting forth the facts upon which the applicant bases his claim for vested rights. The applicant shall include copies of any contracts, letters and other documents upon which a claim of vested rights is based. The mere existence of zoning prior to the effective date of said resolution transmittal or final judicial action shall not vest rights.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Department shall review the application and determine whether the applicant has demonstrated:<section prefix='(1)'>An act of development approval by an agency of Miami-Dade County,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Upon which the developer has in good faith relied to his detriment,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Such that it would be highly inequitable to deny the landowner the right to complete the previously approved development.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>A determination that a landowner is entitled to a vested right to develop or use property contrary to Section 33-280 shall entitle development or use in accord with said determination. However, the development or use shall not be excepted from compliance with other standards set forth in this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-96, ยง 2, 12-18-84; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>