<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. AU, AGRICULTURAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-279</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004305</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-279. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water and/or structure shall be maintained, used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter maintained, erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed or structurally altered or be permitted to be erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed or structurally altered for any purpose in an AU District which is designed, arranged, or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose other than the following:<section prefix='(1)'>All uses, except golf courses, permitted in the RU-1, EU-M or EU-1 Districts and subject to the restrictions thereof not inconsistent with this article.</section><section prefix='(1.1)'>A bed and breakfast establishment shall be permitted subject to the following limitations:<section prefix='(a)'>The facility shall be owner-occupied and located in property that is subject to a lawful agricultural property tax classification and designated in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Agriculture, except as provided in (k) below.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No more than six (6) bedrooms shall be allocated for rental and no more than six (6) bedrooms shall be rented out per 24-hour period.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The bed and breakfast establishment use may be conducted from both a principal residence and a legally established accessory guest house detached from the principal residence.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The maximum length of total stay for any bed and breakfast guest shall be 30 days per consecutive 12-month period.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No cooking facilities shall be permitted in any of the bedrooms available for rent.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Meals will be served only for overnight guests.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The property owner shall obtain a certificate of use from the Department and promptly renew the same annually.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Regarding compliance with the applicable provisions of Chapter 24 of this Code only, bed and breakfast establishments shall be considered residential establishments.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The property owner shall obtain and maintain the appropriate licenses for operating a bed and breakfast establishment from the State of Florida, including the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, Division of Hotels and Restaurants, or successor agency, if applicable.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The property owner will maintain the single-family residential appearance of the bed and breakfast establishment.</section><section prefix='(k)'>If designated historic by the Miami-Dade County Historic Preservation Board, structures located on a property designated Agriculture and situated outside the Urban Development Boundary of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan Map shall be exempt from the requirement of (a) above, except that the establishment shall be owner-occupied.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Barns and sheds used for cattle or stock and ancillary feed storage; provided such barns and sheds shall not be used for hogs and shall not be permitted unless approved after public hearing if located within two hundred fifty (250) feet of a residence under different ownership or if located within two hundred fifty (250) feet of an RU, or EU District.<section prefix='(b)'>Barns, sheds or other buildings used for the storage of equipment, feed, fertilizer, produce or other items ancillary with the use permitted in this section. Such use shall be accessory to the agricultural use conducted on the property upon which the barns, sheds, or other buildings are located unless approved after public hearing and shall be fifty (50) feet from any residence under different ownership and any RU or EU zoned property unless approved after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Small packing facilities used for the packing of fruit and vegetables upon compliance with the following conditions:<section prefix='a.'>Such use shall be accessory to an agricultural use conducted on the property upon which the packing facility is located and said agricultural use must encompass fifty-one (51) percent or more of the property.</section><section prefix='b.'>The packing facility shall be located at least one hundred (100) feet from any property line.</section><section prefix='c.'>The small packing facility shall not exceed three thousand five hundred (3,500) square feet.</section><section prefix='2.'>Large packing facilities used for the packing of fruit and vegetables upon compliance with all of the following conditions:<section prefix='a.'>Such use shall be accessory to an agricultural use conducted on the entire property upon which the packing facility is located, and said agricultural use must encompass fifty-one (51) percent or more of the property.</section><section prefix='b.'>The lot upon which the packing facility is located shall not be less than ten (10) acres.</section><section prefix='c.'>Packing operations shall be discontinued if the farm or grove use is abandoned.</section><section prefix='d.'>Incidental cleaning, storage and shipping of the fruit and vegetables is permitted.</section><section prefix='e.'>Outside storage of refrigerated containers is prohibited unless the refrigeration system is powered by electricity. The parking of trucks with refrigeration powered by means other than electricity is permitted on a temporary basis only until the truck is loaded for delivery.</section><section prefix='f.'>The packing facility shall be one hundred (100) feet from any property line.</section><section prefix='g.'>Site plan approval is secured from the Department.</section><section prefix='h.'>Upon compliance with all conditions enumerated, a certificate of use and occupancy is secured from the Building and Zoning Department.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>The term packing facility shall include any building, lean-to, pole barn or open area utilized by the farmer or grove owner in the course of packing fruit or vegetables as well as any areas whether or not within a building used for the cleaning of produce, storing of trucks, equipment, coolers, refrigerated containers, packing crates or other items used in the packing operation and parking of any vehicles including employee cars and trucks used by the farmer or grove owner to transport the produce to or from the site as well as any trucks on the property being loaded for the purpose of transporting the produce onto or off the property.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Outdoor storage of vehicles and equipment associated with agricultural, aquacultural or horticultural production occurring on property(ies) other than the property on which the storage is located, provided the storage is not a principal use but is ancillary to a use permitted in this section other than residential, subject to all of the following conditions:<section prefix='1.'>The storage of refrigerated containers is prohibited, unless such refrigeration is electrically powered. Storage within the containers or within other types of equipment is permitted only on a recurrent basis with each occurrence limited to a maximum of thirty (30) days.</section><section prefix='2.'>Such equipment, vehicles and the area of storage shall be maintained in compliance with Section 33-4 of this chapter. The vehicles and equipment shall be maintained in operable condition at all times, except as otherwise provided herein.</section><section prefix='3.'>Major repairs or overhaul shall be permitted on equipment or vehicles associated with agricultural, aquacultural or horticultural production.</section><section prefix='4.'>The equipment and vehicles shall be located on the property with the following setbacks:<section prefix='a.'>From front property line, fifty (50) feet;</section><section prefix='b.'>From rear property line, twenty-five (25) feet;</section><section prefix='c.'>From interior side property line, fifteen (15) feet; and</section><section prefix='d.'>From side street property line, twenty-five (25) feet.</section></section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Outdoor storage of vehicles and equipment associated with agricultural, aquacultural or horticultural production occurring on property(ies) other than the property on which the storage is located, provided the storage is not a principal use but is ancillary to a residential use permitted in this section subject to all of the following conditions:<section prefix='1.'>Such storage shall be limited to equipment and/or vehicles owned or leased by the occupant-owner or occupant-lessee of the site where the storage is located.</section><section prefix='2.'>The location for such parked equipment and vehicles shall be in the rear yard or in the side yard to the rear of a line established by the front building line farthest from the street and set back to at least the rear building line. Such equipment and vehicles shall be set back from side property lines a distance at least equivalent to the required side setback for the principal building and shall be set back from the rear property line at least ten (10) feet.</section><section prefix='3.'>Such equipment, vehicles and the area of storage shall be maintained in compliance with Section 33-4 of this chapter. The vehicles and equipment shall be maintained in operable condition at all times, except as otherwise provided herein.</section><section prefix='4.'>Major repairs or overhaul shall be permitted on equipment or vehicles associated with agricultural, aquacultural or horticultural production.</section><section prefix='5.'>The number of vehicles and amount of equipment stored on a residential site is limited by Section 33-4 of this chapter. The storage of refrigerated containers is prohibited, unless such refrigeration is electrically powered. Storage within commercial vehicles or within other types of equipment is permitted only on a recurrent basis with each occurrence limited to a maximum of thirty (30) days.</section></section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Cattle or stock grazing (not including hog raising).</section><section prefix='(3.1)'>Commercial Vehicle Storage as defined in Section 33-1 of this code, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>Commercial vehicle storage is limited to that portion of Open Land Subarea 1, as defined under the County's CDMP, that is located within the area of an arc no more than 7,000 lineal feet from the intersection of Okeechobee Road and Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike. Storage of agricultural equipment in connection with a bona fide agricultural use shall be permitted as provided in this Section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Minimum site size shall be 20 gross acres.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The site shall be under one ownership.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An annual operating permit from the Department of Environmental Resources Management and quarterly groundwater quality monitoring shall be required. A ground water monitoring plan and well locations shall be approved by DERM prior to installation of the wells.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Mechanical repair or maintenance of any kind, including truck washing, shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Notwithstanding any provisions of section 33-282, the following minimum setbacks shall apply to the paved area utilized for the storage and the parking area of commercial vehicles:<section prefix='1.'>50 feet from front and side street property line.</section><section prefix='2.'>25 feet from interior side and rear property line.</section><section>The setback area shall be landscaped in accordance with(C)(6).</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>A guard house and office may be permitted as an ancillary use to the commercial vehicle storage and parking facility provided that said guard house and office is set back at least 50 feet from the front property line and does not exceed 350 square feet of floor space.</section><section prefix='(h)'>An annual certificate of use shall be obtained from the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Landscaping shall comply with Section 33-283.1(C)(6).</section><section prefix='(j)'>Administrative site plan review shall be required in accordance with section 33-283.1</section><section prefix='(k)'>Building permits shall be obtained for the construction of any structures and other improvements as required under the Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Discharge and handling of waste and hazardous material: The storage, handling, use, discharge and disposal of liquid or hazardous wastes or hazardous materials shall be prohibited.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Raising or keeping of two hogs per site. Hog farms and hog raising, in excess of two hogs per site, shall be permitted only upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Dairy barns shall be subject to approval by public hearing, if to be located within fifty (50) feet of a residence under separate and different ownership or if to be located within five hundred (500) feet of an RU, EU-M, or EU District boundary.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Farms.</section><section prefix='(6.1)'>Fruit and vegetable stands may be permitted in the area designated agriculture on the Adopted Land Use Plan Map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan upon compliance with the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The property upon which the fruit and vegetable stand is located shall be not less than five (5) acres gross.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Such fruit and vegetable stand shall be accessory to a bonafide, actively farmed and harvested agricultural crop, and said agricultural crop must encompass 51 percent or more of the property. The fruit and vegetable stand shall be operated only by the party engaged in the production of the crop on that property. The stand shall be operated only during the period of time that the crop is being produced on the site, and the fruit and vegetable stand use shall be discontinued when farming on the property is abandoned. Farming on the property shall not be deemed abandoned if the property is fallow between seasonal growing periods. Fruit and vegetables sold shall not be limited to products grown on the property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Refrigerated storage area(s) are prohibited unless the refrigeration system is powered by electricity.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A minimum of six (6) parking spaces shall be provided; said spaces shall be located a minimum of thirty-five (35) feet from right-of-way pavement.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The stand shall be located on the property with the following setbacks:<section prefix='1.'>From right-of-way pavement sixty (60) feet;</section><section prefix='2.'>From rear property line, twenty-five (25) feet;</section><section prefix='3.'>From side street property line, twenty-five (25) feet; and</section><section prefix='4.'>From interior side property line, one hundred (100) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>The stand shall be on open-sided, non-self propelled vehicle or conveyance permanently equipped to travel upon the public highways; however, a mobile home shall not be utilized as a fruit and vegetable stand.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The maximum size of the stand shall not exceed one thousand (1,000) square feet. Refrigerated storage area(s) shall be included in computing the size of the stand.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Food products offered for retail sale shall be derived from the agricultural crop on the property where the fruit and vegetable stand is located and such food products shall be manufactured by the fruit stand operator.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The hours of operation of the fruit and vegetable stand shall be limited to between 6:30 a.m. and 9:00 p.m.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Groves.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Greenhouses, nurseries—commercial.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Dude ranches and riding academies shall be permitted only upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Horticultural farming—commercial.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Hydroponics or other chemical farming.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Nurseries—horticultural.</section><section prefix='(13)'>The raising of one hundred (100) poultry, or more, shall be considered as commercial poultry raising. Buildings housing poultry must be at least five hundred (500) feet from any EU or RU District boundary, and at least fifty (50) feet from any residence under separate ownership on any adjacent property.</section><section prefix='(13.1)'>Recreational vehicles as temporary watchman's quarters in accordance with Section 33-20(g) of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Truck gardens.</section><section prefix='(15)'>One single-family permanent or temporary structure to house farm labor personnel will be permitted on a farm site for the first ten (10) acres (or less, if smaller, but not less than five (5) acres) and an additional one-family structure for each five (5) acres of additional land in said farm site will be permitted under the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>Providing the structures are located a minimum of one hundred (100) feet from any property under separate and different ownership.</section></section><section prefix='(16)'>Except as permitted under item (15), temporary or permanent barracks or structures to house farm labor may be erected only upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Fish pools shall conform to setbacks for accessory buildings, as provided in Section 33-282(b).</section><section prefix='(18)'>Schools, including institutions of higher learning and primary and secondary schools only shall be permitted; provided, the school structures, buildings or improvements, as well as all incidental school uses, are at least two hundred fifty (250) feet from the boundary, property or lot line and further provided that such uses comply with the regulations of sections 33-151.11 through 33-151.22 of this code.</section><section prefix='(19)'>A group home shall be permitted in a dwelling unit provided:<section prefix='(a)'>That the total number of resident clients on the premises not exceed six (6) in number.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the operation of the facility be licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services and that said Department or sponsoring agency promptly notify the Director of said licensure no later than the time of home occupancy.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That the structure used for a group home shall be located at least one thousand (1,000) feet from another existing, unabandoned legally established group home. The 1,000-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use.</section></section><section prefix='(20)'>Seed drying facility on a parcel of land not less than ten (10) acres gross shall be permitted as a special exception upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Wineries, breweries and distilleries (farm related) as defined in Section 33-1, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The principal use of the property shall be a working farm producing products utilized in the winery, brewery, or distillation process.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The farm winery, brewery, or distillery shall be ancillary to the principal use of said farm.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The property upon which the farm and ancillary farm winery, brewery, or distillery is located shall not be less than ten (10) acres gross.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No more than 250,000 gallons of wine, and 250,000 gallons of malted beverage/beer, and 125,000 gallons of distilled spirits shall be produced in any one calendar year.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Such a farm winery, brewery, or distillery may be open to the public for events and activities related to the preserving, processing, packaging or selling of agricultural products from Florida including tours, product tasting, festivals, parties and other similar events.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Off-street parking requirements for the tasting and sales areas shall be calculated at one parking space for every 250 square feet of gross floor area or fractional part thereof. Office and other use areas shall have off-street parking spaces provided for such areas as otherwise provided in this code. In addition to the aforementioned parking requirements, at the time of application for ZIP, parking for indoor or outdoor farm-related festivals shall be determined by the Director and such requirements shall be based on the number of people that can reasonably be assumed to be on such premises at one (1) time. Said determination shall be calculated on a basis of one (1) parking space for each four (4) persons.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Food service, preparation and consumption shall be accessory to the production of wine, beer or distilled spirits.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The hours of retail sales operation for the farm-related winery, brewery, or distillery shall not extend beyond 11:00 p.m.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Outdoor farm-related festivals shall be allowable on properties having a current Certificate of Use for a farm-related winery, brewery, or distillery provided:<section prefix='a.'>No such outdoor farm-related festival shall be more than three (3) days long.</section><section prefix='b.'>A Zoning Improvement Permit (ZIP) for outdoor farm-related festivals shall be obtained for each festival. No more than a total of six (6) outdoor farm-related festivals shall be held per calendar year per farm. Such outdoor farm-related festivals shall be restricted to daylight hours only.</section></section><section prefix='(j)'>The use of mechanically amplified outdoor entertainment shall be prohibited from 11:00 p.m. to 9:00 a.m.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The winery, brewery, or distillery shall not be located in the East Everglades Area of Environmental Concern as that area is described in Chapter 33B, Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section prefix='(22)'>Uses ancillary to and directly supportive of agriculture.<section prefix='(a)'>The following uses shall be permitted on property meeting the requirements of this section when ancillary to an ongoing agricultural use:<section prefix='(1)'>The packing, processing and sale of agricultural goods or products from the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Farm tours, farm meals, cooking classes, agricultural workshops, agricultural education and agri-tourism.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Farmers' markets, restricted to the sale of fruits, vegetables, live farm animals, and plants, as well as products derived directly therefrom.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Uses determined by the Director to be similar to those enumerated above. In determining similarity between a proposed use and the uses enumerated above, the Director shall be guided by whether the proposed use is ancillary to and directly supportive of agriculture.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The following uses that are directly supportive of agriculture shall be permitted on property meeting the requirements of this section and subject to the provisions of Chapter 24 of this code:<section prefix='(1)'>The sale of farm supplies.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The sale and service of farm machinery and implements.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>All uses permitted in (a) and (b) above shall be subject to the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>The property shall be designated Agriculture in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan Map and shall be utilized for a bona fide agricultural use as evidenced by an agricultural property classification approved by the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser's Office.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The property or business owner shall obtain a certificate of use for the ancillary agricultural use from the Department and promptly renew the same annually.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 26(A), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 59-9, § 1, 4-28-59; Ord. No. 61-33, § 2, 7-19-61; Ord. No. 69-21, § 1, 4-1-69; Ord. No. 69-52, § 1, 9-3-69; Ord. No. 74-16, § 1, 4-2-74; Ord. No. 81-26, § 9, 3-17-81; Ord. No. 81-25, § 1, 3-17-81; Ord. No. 81-60, § 1, 6-2-81; Ord. No. 87-68, § 1, 10-6-87; Ord. No. 91-51, §§ 2, 3, 5-7-91; Ord. No. 91-94, § 1, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 92-48, § 2, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 94-159, § 1, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 94-160, § 1, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-219, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-2, § 2, 1-9-96; Ord. No. 02-46, § 7, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 04-215, § 2, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 10-19, § 2, 3-2-10; Ord. No. 10-20, § 3, 3-2-10; Ord. No. 10-21, § 1, 3-2-10; Ord. No. 10-73, § 2, 11-4-10; Ord. No. 11-59, § 1, 8-2-11)</history></law>