<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00044' order_by='00044' level='3'>ARTICLE XXX. IU-2 INDUSTRIAL, HEAVY MANUFACTURING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-262</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004270</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-262. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water or structure shall be used or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter constructed, reconstructed or structurally altered, maintained or moved in any IU-2 District, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used for any purpose, unless otherwise provided herein, except for one (1) of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>Every use permitted in IU-1 District, except adult entertainment uses as defined in Section 33-259.1, and private schools and nonpublic educational facilities as defined in Section 33-151.11 are prohibited in the IU-2 District.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Asphalt drum mixing plants which produce less than one hundred fifty (150) tons per hour in self-contained drum mixers.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Rock and sand yards.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Cement and clay products, such as concrete blocks, pipe, etc.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Soap manufacturing, vegetable byproducts, only.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Railroad shops.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Sawmills.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Petroleum products storage tank not exceeding 30,000-gallon capacity or a group of such tanks with an aggregate capacity not in excess of thirty thousand (30,000) gallons.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Petroleum products storage tank with a capacity of over thirty thousand (30,000) gallons or a group of such tanks with an aggregate capacity in excess of thirty thousand (30,000) gallons if approved after public hearing or if placed below the surface of the ground or in a rockpit.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Dynamite storage.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Construction debris materials recovery transfer facility, provided such use shall be conducted entirely within an enclosed building consisting of a minimum of 15,000 square feet. Counted toward this minimum floor area shall be areas set aside for office shop space and equipment storage associated with the construction debris materials recovery transfer facility.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 24(A), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 68-37, § 1, 6-4-68; Ord. No. 69-51, § 2, 9-3-69; Ord. No. 92-98, § 1, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 01-227, § 3, 12-20-01; Ord. No. 02-23, § 4, 2-12-02; Ord. No. 02-103, § 3, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 04-56, § 2, 3-16-04)</history></law>