<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(N). PERRINE COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (PECUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.11</section_number>
<catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004426</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.11. General Requirements.<section prefix='A.'>Lots and Blocks. In addition to the minimum lot requirements in Section 33-284.86(A), the following shall be permitted in areas designated Residential (R) areas south of SW 170 Street:</section><section prefix='B.'>Architectural Guidelines. To retain the character of the initial development of Perrine and to recognize the heritage of the early and current residents of the area, architectural elements typical of the Caribbean and the Southern United States as provided in this section shall be required.<section prefix='1.'>Architectural elements. New development within the Perrine Community Urban Center District shall, to the greatest extent practicable, utilize the following architectural elements illustrated herein:<section prefix='a.'>Projecting, roofed balconies</section><section prefix='b.'>Continuous, wraparound verandahs</section><section prefix='c.'>Vertically proportioned door and window openings</section><section prefix='d.'>Hip roofs, finished with wood-shingles, flat concrete tile, or metal standing seam</section><section prefix='e.'>Wood and masonry construction</section><section prefix='f.'>Shading devices such as Bahama shutters, louvers, latticework, and projecting roof eaves<section></section></section></section><section prefix='2.'>Architectural elements shall be required as follows:</section><section prefix='3.'>Prohibited elements. Arched, circular, and double-height openings are not permitted in areas designated Residential (R) and Residential Modified (RM) land use areas.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-127, ยง 6, 9-12-06)</history></law>