<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(J). NARANJA COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.66</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004384</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.66. Purpose and applicability.<section prefix='1.'>The Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) contains directives to promote urban centers in places where mass transit, roadways, and highways are highly accessible. The CDMP provides for three types of urban centers: community (CUC), metropolitan (MUC) and regional (RUC). CUCs are a mechanism by which those CDMP directives can be addressed, because CUCs are compact, mixed-use, and pedestrian-friendly areas. In the Naranja CUC area these CDMP directives are intended to be achieved by the following means:<section prefix='A.'>allocating development intensities within the Naranja CUC according to proximity to mass transit, and by creating Core, Center and Edge sub-districts to allocate the various development intensities within the CUC; and</section><section prefix='B.'>by organizing an interconnected network of tree-lined streets and sidewalks to improve pedestrian access to transit, jobs, and shopping; and</section><section prefix='C.'>by providing for open space with specific square, green and/or plaza locations, and by shaping the way buildings front onto open space and streets.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18-A, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='3.'>The Illustrative Plan (Figure 1), shall be used to assist in interpreting this article. Where there is conflict between the Illustrative Plan and the text of this article, the text shall govern.</section><section prefix='4.'>The boundaries shown in Figure 1 shall constitute the Naranja CUC Boundary Plan and are generally described as follows: from the northwest corner of the intersection of SW 137 Avenue and SW 272 Street, north along the west side of SW 137 Avenue to the south side of SW 256 Street, then west along the south side of SW 256 Street to the UDB line, as reflected on the maps on file with the Department of Planning and Zoning dated September 22, 2003, then south and west along the UDB to the centerline of SW 149 Avenue, then south along the centerline of SW 149 Avenue to the C-103N canal, then southeast along the canal to the north side of SW 272 Street, then east along the north side of SW 272 Street to the west side of SW 142 Avenue, then north along the west side of SW 142 Avenue to the south side of SW 270 Street, then east along the north side of SW 270 Street to the east side of the FEC easement, then southeast along the east side of the FEC easement to the north side of SW 272 Street, then east along the north side of SW 272 Street to the west side of SW 137 Avenue. The exact location of the UDB line as of the effective date of this ordinance is on file with the Department of Planning and Zoning. An approximate delineation of the UDB line is depicted in the Regulating Plans. Any amendment to the CDMP resulting in a movement of the UDB line following the effective date of this ordinance shall be followed by an amendment to this section of the code to reflect the new UDB line or the westernmost boundaries of the NCUC in compliance with the half-a-mile radius CDMP requirement for Community Urban Centers.</section><section>A more detailed legal description of the boundaries follows:<section>Begin at the NE corner of the SE ¼ of Section 27-56-39. Thence W. along the centerline of SW 256 St for a distance of 1877' + to the centerline of State Hwy. #5. Thence SW/ly along the centerline of State Hwy. #5 for 285'+/- to a point. Thence N47°-04'-12"W for 300'+/- to the centerline of SW 256 St. Thence W. along SW 256 St. centerline for 1600'+/- to a point. Thence S40°34'07"W for 2380'+/- to the theoretical W/ly R/wy of SW 147 Ave. Thence S. along the theoretical W/ly R/wy of SW 147 Avenue for 850'+/- to the N/ly R/wy of SW 264 St. Thence W. along the N/ly line of SW 264 St. for 1287'+/- to theoretical centerline of SW 149 Ave. Thence S. along SW 149 Ave for 1030'+/- to the N/ly R/wy of Canal C-103 N. Thence SE/ly along the N. line of canal for 2450'+/- to the centerline of SW 272 St. Thence E. along SW 272 St centerline for 2340'+/- to the centerline of SW 142 Ave. Thence N. along 142 Ave for 682'+/- to the centerline of SW 270 St. Thence E. for 1050'+/- to the W/ line of FEC EASEMENT. Thence SE/ly along the W. line of FEC EASEMENT 895'+/- to the centerline of SW 272 St. Thence E. 1080'+/- to SW 137 Ave. Thence N. along 137 Ave for a distance of 5280'+/- to the point of beginning.</section><section>Full scale maps of the Illustrative Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section></section><section prefix='5.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property except lands lying within the boundaries of the Naranja Community Urban Center District as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the Naranja Community Urban Center shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to the Naranja Community Urban Center District has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.<section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-217, § 1, 12-2-04)</history></law>