<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(O). OJUS URBAN AREA DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.20</section_number>
<catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004435</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.20. General Requirements.<section>In addition to the requirements in of this code, and to retain the character of the development within the OUAD, all new development and redevelopment shall comply with the following:<section prefix='A.'>Heights of Buildings.<section prefix='1.'>Except where exempted as depicted on the Building Heights Plan, where a proposed development abuts an area designated Residential (R) on the Land Use Regulating Plan, the height of the proposed development along the abutting property line, for a minimum depth of 50 feet, shall be no greater than the maximum height allowed in the abutting area designated R. Examples of the required height transition are shown herein.<section></section><section>Each story shall have a maximum height of 16 feet, as measured from floor to floor. Any height above 16 feet shall count as an additional story, except that a single story may have a maximum height of 30 feet, provided that no mezzanine area intended for commercial use exceeds 10 percent and no mezzanine area intended for residential use exceeds 80 percent of the floor area of that story.</section></section></section><section prefix='B.'>Architectural Guidelines.<section>To retain the character of the development in the OUAD area and to recognize its architectural history, all new single-family development within the OUAD area shall conform with either the Florida Vernacular or the Mission style as shown in the figures below. Specifically and at a minimum, all new single-family homes within the area shall include each of the required elements, respective to the chosen architectural style, described herein:<section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-86, ยง 7, 6-6-06)</history></law>