<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(N). PERRINE COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (PECUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose, intent and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004421</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.6. Purpose, intent and applicability.<section prefix='A.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Illustrative Master Plan (Figure 1) illustrates the citizens' vision and may be used to interpret this article. Where the Illustrative Master Plan conflicts with the text of this article, the text shall govern.</section><section prefix='C.'>The boundaries shown in Figure 1 shall constitute the Perrine Community Urban Center (PECUC) Boundary Plan and are generally described as follows: from the intersection of the centerline of the southbound U. S Highway 1 (US 1) and SW 168 Street, then west along the centerline of SW 168 Street to the centerline of SW 107 Avenue, then south along the centerline of SW 107 Avenue to the centerline of SW 184 Street, then west along the centerline of SW 184 Street to the east side of the Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike — State Road 821 (HEFT), then south and east along the east side of the HEFT to the centerline of SW 186 Street, Quail Roost Drive, then east along the centerline of SW 186 Street to the east side of the C-1N canal, then south and east along the east and north side of the C-1N canal to the centerline of Marlin Drive, the southeasterly along the centerline of Marlin Drive to the centerline of the South Miami-Dade Busway, then north along the centerline of the South Miami-Dade Busway to SW 186 Street, then east along the centerline of SW 186 Street the centerline of US 1, then north along the center1ine of US 1 to SW 183 Street, then north along the centerline of the southbound US 1 to the point of beginning.</section><section>A more detailed legal description of the boundaries follows:<section>Beginning at the intersection of the centerline of the southbound U.S. Highway 1 (US 1) and the centerline of SW 168 Street, thence West along the aforementioned centerline of SW 168 Street to the intersection with the centerline of SW 107 Avenue, thence South along the aforementioned centerline of SW 107 Avenue to the intersection with the centerline of SW 184 Street, thence West along the centerline of the aforementioned centerline of SW 184 Street to the intersection with the East Right-of-Way line of the Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike - State Road 821 (HEFT), thence South and Southeasterly along the afore mentioned East Right-of-Way line of the Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike - State Road 821 (HEFT) to the centerline of SW 186 Street (Quail Roost Drive), thence East along the centerline of the aforementioned centerline of SW 186 Street (Quail Roost Drive) to the intersection with the East Right-of-Way line of the C-1N Canal, thence South and East along the afore mentioned East and North Right-of-Way line of the C-1N Canal to the intersection with the centerline of Marlin Drive, thence Southeasterly along the aforementioned centerline of Marlin Drive to the intersection with the centerline of the South Miami-Dade Busway, thence Northeasterly along the aforementioned centerline of the South Miami-Dade Busway to the centerline of SW 186 Street, thence East along the aforementioned centerline of SW 186 Street to the intersection of the centerline of U.S. Highway 1 (US 1), thence Northeasterly along the aforementioned centerline of U.S. Highway 1 (US 1) to the intersection with the extension of the centerline of SW 183 Street, thence Northeasterly along the centerline of the southbound U.S. Highway 1 (US 1) back to the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section prefix='D.'>Full scale maps of the Illustrative Master Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='E.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the Perrine Community Urban Center District (PECUC) as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the PECUC shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to the PECUC has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.<section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-127, § 1, 9-12-06)</history></law>