<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. RU-3, FOUR UNIT APARTMENT HOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-203.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Site plan review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004137</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-203.1. Site plan review.<section>Multi-family housing developments, as permitted by(6.1) of this code, shall be subject to administrative site plan review as specified herein. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, innovation and variety in the design process and thereby ensure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. The Department shall review proposed plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. All plans submitted to the Department shall be reviewed and approved or denied within 30 days from the date of submission. The applicant shall have the right to extend the 30 day period by an additional 30 days upon timely request made in writing to the Department. The Department shall have the right to extend the 30 day period by written notice to the applicant that additional information is needed to process the site plan. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for denial. Decisions of the Director may be appealed to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board in accordance with procedure established for appeals of administrative decisions.</section><section>Procedure. Exhibits prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects shall be submitted to the Department and shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Site plan including the following information:<section prefix='(a)'>Lot lines and setbacks.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Location, shape, size and height of existing and proposed buildings, decorative walls and entrance features.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Landscaping in accordance with Chapter 18A of this code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Location of off-street parking and loading facilities and waste collection areas.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Indication of exterior graphics, as required.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Indication of any site design methods used to conserve energy.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including total gross square foot area of each floor.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Figures indicating the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Gross and net acreage.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Amount of landscaped open space in square feet required and provided.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Amount of building coverage at ground level in square feet.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Total trees required and provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this code.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Parking required and provided.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Total amount of paved area in square feet.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-189, ยง 3, 11-3-05)</history></law>