<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(I). DOWNTOWN KENDALL URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.65</section_number>
<catch_line>Nonconforming structures, uses and occupancies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004383</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.65. Nonconforming structures, uses and occupancies.<section>All legal nonconforming structures, uses, and occupancies in the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District that either: (1) were existing on December 16, 1999, or (2) on or before December 16, 1999, had received final site plan approval through a public hearing pursuant to of this Code or through administrative site plan review (ASPR), by the date specified in, shall be exempt from the provisions of(c) of this Code upon compliance with the requirements of this section. Such nonconforming structures shall be allowed to be rebuilt and such uses and occupancies resumed in compliance with plans of record and certificates of use and occupancy approved as of December 16, 1999. Such structures, uses and occupancies shall be in compliance with all other provisions of this Code in effect at the time of the application to rebuild or resume occupancy. Building permits for rebuilding pursuant to this section shall be obtained within one year after the date of damage or destruction of the nonconforming structure. If the building permits necessary to rebuild a nonconforming structure have not been obtained within one year after the date of damage or destruction, or if such permits expire or are revoked after that year has concluded, the structure shall be subject to the provisions of -35(c).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-129, ยง 1, 7-24-01)</history></law>