<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(S). NORTH CENTRAL URBAN AREA DISTRICT (NCUAD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.48</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose, intent and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004463</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.48. Purpose, intent and applicability.<section prefix='A.'>The NCUAD regulating plans were guided by the three Urban Centers located within the boundary and the major roadways provisions of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='B.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='C.'>Figure 1 shows the boundaries of the North Central Urban Area District (NCUAD).</section><section prefix='D.'>The NCUAD's Designated Urban Center shall consist of the areas designated as being the Core and Center Sub-districts on the Sub-districts Plan in Sec. 33-284.99.51 of this code. As provided in the Standard Urban Center District Regulations, the Workforce Housing requirement shall apply to the area included in the Designated Urban Center boundaries. The legal description of the boundaries of the NCUAD is on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='E.'>Full scale map of the boundaries presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='F.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the NCUAD as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the NCUAD shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to NCUAD has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section>Figure 1: North Central Urban Area Boundary</section><section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-65, ยง 1, 8-2-11)</history></law>