<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.83</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004397</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.83. Uses.<section>No land, body of water, or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved, structurally altered, or maintained for any purpose in the Urban Center (UC) or Urban Area (UA) Districts, except as provided in this article. The uses delineated herein shall be permitted only in compliance with the Regulating Plans and standards provided in this article. The following regulations outline permitted uses in the R (Residential), RM (Residential Modified), MC (Mixed-Use Corridor), MM (Mixed-Use Main Street), MO (Mixed-Use Optional), MCS (Mixed-Use Special), MCI (Mixed-Use Industrial), ID (Industrial District) and I (Institutional) Land Use Areas.<section prefix='A.'>Land Uses in General.<section prefix='1.'>Outdoor uses/enclosed uses. All uses shall be conducted within completely enclosed buildings, except outdoor uses expressly permitted in this article. Materials and products shall be stored within an enclosed building or within an area completely enclosed within walls having a life expectancy of twenty (20) years or more from the date of installation. Storage shall not be visible above the height of the walls. Commercial vehicles shall be stored or parked within an enclosed building or an area enclosed by a fence, wall, or hedge, and out of the view from adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='2.'>Density Calculation.<section prefix='a.'>Density averaging shall be permitted when a unified development is located on one or more parcels, with different land uses or Sub-district designations, under the same ownership.</section><section prefix='b.'>A single accessory dwelling unit permitted with a single-family residence shall not count towards the minimum required and maximum permitted density thresholds.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Work-force Housing. Unless otherwise specified in the District regulations, all residential or mixed-use developments that: (a) are located within the Core or Center Sub-districts of an urban center district adopted by the Board or County Commissioners after July 10, 2007, and (b) have more than four (4) residential units, shall provide a minimum of twelve and a half (12.5) percent of their units as Work-force Housing Units.</section><section prefix='4.'>Mixed Use. The vertical or horizontal integration of residential, business and office, and institutional uses shall be permitted as provided herein. Vertical integration allows any combination of primary uses, with business uses typically located on the ground floor and office and/or residential uses on the upper floors. Horizontal integration allows any combination of parcels with different primary uses within the same block.</section><section prefix='5.'>Temporary Uses. Temporary uses including seasonal tent sales; stands for the sale of flowers, fruit and similar uses; and festivals and farmers' markets are permitted in the MC, MO, MM, MCS, MCI, ID and I categories, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='a.'>Except for the following, no temporary use shall be permitted for more than fourteen (14) consecutive days and the time between temporary activities shall be at least three times as long as the duration of the last event.<section prefix='i.'>A temporary use for the sale of holiday related items such as holiday trees, fireworks, and similar items shall be permitted for thirty (30) consecutive days leading up to the holiday date.</section><section prefix='ii.'>A temporary use that occurs on two (2) or less consecutive days shall be permitted weekly.</section></section><section prefix='b.'>When applicable, a Zoning Improvement Permit (ZIP) and Certificate of Use shall be obtained. A site plan shall be submitted with the ZIP application indicating, at a minimum;<section prefix='i.'>Location of temporary activities and structures, which shall not be subject to the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article;</section><section prefix='ii.'>Anticipated number of patrons;</section><section prefix='iii.'>Location of parking facilities;</section><section prefix='iv.'>Temporary street closures;</section><section prefix='v.'>Hours of operation;</section><section prefix='vi.'>Location and description of lighting and amplification devices.</section></section><section prefix='c.'>Outdoor festivals and farmers' markets shall be restricted to daylight hours unless written waivers of objection for the specific use and hours of operation are obtained from all property owners within five hundred (500) feet. The Director may reduce or expand the notification requirement based on potential visual, noise or traffic impacts to adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='d.'>A carnival or circus, that involves an amusement ride, acrobatic apparatus, or trained animal, shall only be permitted if approved upon public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='6.'>Unusual and New Uses. Except as expressly permitted in this article, unusual and new uses, as outlined in Section 33-13 of this chapter, shall only be permitted if approved upon public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='B.'>Land Use Groups. The uses listed following each group in this section shall be permitted in the land use categories shown in Table (C) subject to the provisions noted for each land use category. Uses provided in Table (C) below not listed in this subsection shall be permitted subject to the provisions noted for each land use area. The Director shall have the authority to determine that a use not specifically enumerated below may nevertheless be permitted in a land use category because it is similar to an enumerated use.<section prefix='1.'>Accommodation Uses: Facilities that provide short-term lodging including hotels, motels, rooming houses, bed and breakfasts, and similar uses.</section><section prefix='2.'>Automotive Uses: Establishments specializing in the service or repair of automobiles; automobile tire sales and replacement; automobile parts sales and installation; sales of new and used automobiles; and gas stations or other form of stations used for the powering/charging of automobile vehicles.</section><section prefix='3.'>Child Care Facilities: Child care facilities shall be those defined in Article XA of this chapter and shall be subject to the requirements therein, as applicable; except that child care facilities shall provide recreation areas in accordance with Section 33-284.86(D)(2) of this article. Where conflicts exist, the provisions of this article shall apply.</section><section prefix='4.'>Civic Uses: Uses that are accessible to the public and serves the religious, recreational, educational, cultural and/or governmental needs of the community. Civic uses include, but are not limited to: convention halls or meeting halls; private clubs; libraries; schools; police stations; fire stations; post offices; clubhouses; religious buildings; museums; athletic facilities; auditoriums theaters, movie theaters, and other visual and performance arts buildings; and governmental facilities. The architecture of a civic use building shall reflect its civic nature. The sale of alcohol, if provided, shall be ancillary to the primary civic use and shall comply with Article X of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='5.'>Private Colleges/Universities: Facilities that serve the educational needs of the adult population. This group shall include universities; colleges; commuter colleges; trade schools; and similar uses.</section><section prefix='6.'>Commercial Parking Garage: Structures that provide parking as the primary on-site use. These facilities offer short-term parking of vehicles and may charge a fee for such use. This group includes: shared parking facilities; shuttle parking facilities; and transit park-and-ride facilities. This group shall not include parking facilities that are ancillary to another on-site use.</section><section prefix='7.'>Health Care Services: A facility that provides out-patient health care services to the local community. These facilities shall include: clinics; doctor's office; dentist's offices; federally qualified health centers; urgent care facilities; diagnostic centers including sleep centers; and similar uses. These facilities shall not provide in-patient care.</section><section prefix='8.'>Drive-Through Facilities: Drive-through facilities associated with a retail use, personal service establishment or restaurant.</section><section prefix='9.'>Entertainment Use: Uses in this group shall include: nightclubs; arcades; movie theaters; performance theaters; radio, movie and/or television studios; billiard halls; skating rinks; bingo halls; piano bars; adult entertainment uses (as defined in Section 33-259.1 of this chapter); bowling alleys; and similar uses. The sale of alcohol, if provided, shall be ancillary to the primary entertainment use and shall comply with Article X of this chapter.</section><section prefix='10.'>Food/Beverage Establishments: This group shall include: full service restaurants; fast food restaurants; bars and pubs; and similar uses. The sale of alcohol, if provided, shall comply with Article X of this chapter, except that full-service restaurants serving alcoholic beverages shall be exempt from Sections 33-150(A) and 33-150(B) of this chapter.</section><section prefix='11.'>General Retail/Personal Service Establishments: Establishments that provide goods and services geared toward an individual consumer. This group shall include businesses such as: banks; beauty parlors; adult day care; bakeries; bookstores; apparel stores; grocery stores; pharmacies; tailor shops; health clubs; gift shops; indoor pet care centers/boarding and indoor kennels (soundproofed and air-conditioned building required); vehicle retail showrooms; and similar uses. This group shall also include schools offering instruction in dance, music, martial arts and similar activities, but this group shall not include colleges/universities. Except as otherwise authorized in this article, uses enumerated in the BU-3 zoning district shall only be permitted in the MCS and MCI categories and shall be subject to the public hearing and spacing requirements set forth in Section 33-255 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='12.'>Group Residential Home: A dwelling unit licensed by the State of Florida Department of Children and Families that serves resident clients and provides a living environment for unrelated residents who operate as a functional equivalent of a family. Uses in this group shall include: nursing homes, assisted living facilities; congregate living facilities; foster care facilities; community residential homes; group homes; and other similar uses. Services that support the daily operation of group homes are permitted and shall include dining facilities, doctor's offices, nurse's offices, staff offices, recreation rooms, and similar facilities and services.</section><section prefix='13.'>Industrial Uses: The Industrial Use group shall include uses permitted in Section 33-259 of this chapter, unless specifically prohibited by this chapter. Residential spacing requirements shall not be required for uses in this group.</section><section prefix='14.'>Live/work Units: An individual residential unit integrated with a general retail/personal service establishment, professional business office, or workshop.</section><section prefix='15.'>Professional Business Offices: Facilities used primarily for the business of professionals with only limited transactions occurring on-site. This group shall include offices for: accountants; architects; appraisers; attorneys; consulates; financial firms; insurance adjusters; realtors; medical offices and other uses found by the Director to be similar.</section><section prefix='16.'>Residential Uses: Single-family detached homes, urban villas, courtyard houses, sideyard houses, duplexes, rowhouses, apartments (including student housing), and other similar uses. Home offices as provided in Section 33-25.1 of this chapter shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='17.'>Workshop: an enclosed workplace on the ground floor area of a building used as an office or for the manufacturing of artifacts and crafts utilizing only hand held and/or table mounted electrical tools.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Table of Permitted Uses. Unless the regulations for a specific urban center district provide otherwise, the Land Use Groups in paragraph (B) of this section shall be permitted in the R (Residential), RM (Residential Modified), MC (Mixed-Use Corridor), MM (Mixed-Use Main Street), MO (Mixed-Use Optional), MCS (Mixed-Use Special), MCI (Mixed-Use Industrial), ID (Industrial District) and I (Institutional) land use categories in accordance with the following table:</section><section prefix='P:'>Permitted Use, although specific uses may require approval as special exception</section><section prefix='SE:'>Special Exception - only permitted if approved upon public hearing</section><section prefix='[#]'>Footnote (as provided below)</section></section><section><section prefix='1.'>The vertical integration of uses shall be required in the MM category and shall be encouraged in the MC, MO, MCS, and MCI categories. When residential uses are provided in the MM category, uses other than residential shall be required on the first floor.</section><section prefix='2.'>Residential uses shall be permitted in noted categories, either alone or when vertically integrated with other lawful uses; except that developments with more than fifty (50) residential units shall provide a minimum of ten (10) square feet of retail space for each residential unit.</section><section prefix='3.'>Accessory structures shall be permitted as ancillary to the noted uses.</section><section prefix='4.'>For single-family homes in the R and RM categories, an accessory building may be used as a dwelling unit only if: (a) it contains a maximum of six hundred (600) square feet of habitable space; and (b) it is maintained under the same ownership as the single family home.</section><section prefix='5.'>The following limited residential uses shall be permitted in the ID category when fronting an "A" Street and when buffered from an industrial use by a street, a service road, or a live-work unit:<section prefix='a.'>In the Edge Sub-district, the residential uses permitted in the R category at a minimum density of six (6) dwelling units per net acre and a maximum density of eighteen (18) dwelling units per net acre.</section><section prefix='b.'>In the Center Sub-district, the residential uses permitted in the RM category at a minimum density of twelve (12) dwelling units per net acre and a maximum density of thirty-six (36) units per net acre.</section></section><section prefix='6.'>In the R category, group residential homes shall meet the requirements outlined in Section 33-199(10) of this chapter. In the RM, MC, MM, MO, MCS, and MCI categories, group residential homes shall meet the following requirements:<section prefix='a.'>Three (3) occupants shall be deemed to be one (1) dwelling unit, and the maximum number of dwelling units allowed shall be equal to the permitted residential density.</section><section prefix='b.'>The proposed group residential home shall not be located within a radius of one thousand two hundred (1,200) feet of another existing, unabandoned, legally established group residential home. The 1,200-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use.</section></section><section prefix='7.'>Schools shall be subject to the requirements of Article XA or XI of this chapter, as applicable; except that non-public educational facilities shall provide recreation areas in accordance with Section 33-284.86(D)(2) of this article. Where conflicts exist, the provisions of this article shall apply.</section><section prefix='8.'>General retail and personal service establishment shall be limited to forty thousand (40,000) square feet of ground floor area; a greater ground floor area for such uses shall only be permitted if approved as a special exception.<section prefix='a.'>Indoor pet kennels shall be permitted subject to the following conditions: (i) all kennel buildings shall be soundproofed and air-conditioned; (ii) where outside exercise runs are provided, a landscaped buffer or decorative masonry wall shall enclose the runs, and use of the runs shall be restricted to use during daylight hours; (iii) where outside exercise runs are not provided, an outside area shall be designated for dogs (or cats) to relieve themselves, and that area shall be enclosed by a landscape buffer or masonry wall; (iv) an administrative site plan review (ASPR) shall be required, and the site plan shall show all fencing, berms, and soundproofing designed to mitigate the noise impact of the kennel on the surrounding properties.</section><section prefix='b.'>Vehicle Retail Showrooms shall only be permitted in accordance with the conditions set forth in Section 33-253(9.5) of this chapter.</section><section prefix='c.'>The following uses shall only be permitted if approved as special exceptions: on-site storage of vehicles; and outdoor pet kennels subject to the conditions set forth in Section 33-255(9.1) of this chapter, except that ASPR shall not be required if a site plan is approved upon public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='9.'>Drive-through facilities shall be permitted in all Sub-districts, provided that such facilities are concealed from streets by buildings or walls. Said walls shall be six (6) feet in height (except that in the ID category, walls shall be eight (8) feet in height) and shall be placed at the build-to line.</section><section prefix='10.'>Gas/Service stations shall:<section prefix='a.'>Be permitted in the MCS category in all Sub-districts and in the MCI and Industrial (ID) categories in the Center and Edge Sub-districts; and</section><section prefix='b.'>Be exempt from the minimum height requirements; and</section><section prefix='c.'>Provide a continuous street facade consisting of buildings or walls along all streets except driveways. When provided, walls shall not exceed three and a half (3.5) feet in height and shall be a minimum of seventy-five (75) percent opaque. The main building shall provide a minimum of forty (40) percent of building frontage along the front property line.</section></section><section prefix='11.'>Liquor package stores shall be permitted only in the Core and Center Sub-district and only in compliance with Article X of this chapter and all other applicable regulations of this code.</section><section prefix='12.'>In the RM category, accommodation uses shall be permitted only in conjunction with an owner-occupied residence; the total number of units shall not exceed the density permitted by the land use designation. In the MM, MC, MO, MCS, MCI, and ID categories, hotel/motel uses shall not exceed seventy-five (75) units per net acre or the maximum density permitted by the land use category, whichever is greater. For all density calculations required by this subsection, one hotel room shall equal one dwelling unit.</section><section prefix='13.'>Outdoor table service and outside walk-up window service in conjunction with restaurants and coffee houses may be provided subject to the following requirements:<section prefix='a.'>The restaurant furniture located on the sidewalk shall maintain a minimum five (5) foot wide obstacle-free corridor for pedestrian circulation along the sidewalk.</section><section prefix='b.'>Alcoholic beverages may be served outdoors only where such service is strictly incidental to the service of food.</section></section><section prefix='14.'>Commercial parking garages shall meet the requirements of Section 33-284.86(F)(6) of this article.</section><section prefix='15.'>In the R and RM categories, child care uses shall be subject to the requirements for such uses in the RU-1 District, as set forth in Section 33-199 of this chapter, except that the total number of children may exceed five (5) if approved as a special exception.</section><section prefix='16.'>Adult entertainment uses, as defined in Section 33-259.1 of this chapter, shall be prohibited in all land use categories except MCI and ID. In the MCI and ID categories, such adult entertainment uses shall only be permitted if approved as special exceptions.</section><section prefix='17.'>Only the following uses shall be permitted in connection with a residence in a live-work unit in the MCI and ID land use categories:<section prefix='a.'>Antique shops</section><section prefix='b.'>Art goods stores, artist studios, galleries</section><section prefix='c.'>Artisanal use</section><section prefix='d.'>Bait and tackle shops</section><section prefix='e.'>Bakeries</section><section prefix='f.'>Cabinet shops</section><section prefix='g.'>Dance studios</section><section prefix='h.'>Dry cleaning and dyeing establishments</section><section prefix='i.'>Engines, sales and service</section><section prefix='j.'>Glass installation</section><section prefix='k.'>Health and exercise clubs</section><section prefix='l.'>Interior design shops</section><section prefix='m.'>Leather goods manufacturing, excluding tanning</section><section prefix='n.'>Locksmith shops, sharpening and grinding shops</section><section prefix='o.'>Mail order office, including storage of products</section><section prefix='p.'>Office uses</section><section prefix='q.'>Photography labs</section><section prefix='r.'>Pottery shops</section><section prefix='s.'>Printing shops</section><section prefix='t.'>Restaurants, excluding drive-through service</section><section prefix='u.'>Secondhand stores</section><section prefix='v.'>Shoe stores and shoe repair shops</section><section prefix='w.'>Upholstery and furniture shops</section><section prefix='x.'>Wholesale salesrooms</section><section prefix='y.'>Other similar uses as determined by the Director.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-143, § 3, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 07-93, § 2, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 08-102, § 1, 9-2-08; Ord. No. 12-86, § 2, 10-2-12; Ord. No. 13-82, § 3, 9-17-13)</history></law>