<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(M). PRINCETON COMMUNITY CENTER URBAN DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004416</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.1. Uses.<section>Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the PCUC shall comply with of this code,<section prefix='A.'>Permitted Uses. The following uses shall be permitted.<section prefix='1.'>On the west side of South Dade Busway right-of-way, Industrial (ID) lots abutting designated Mixed Use Corridor (MC) lots on at least one side, may have uses permitted in the MC area for a depth not to exceed 300 feet, as measured from the Busway right-of-way.</section><section prefix='2.'>In the Industrial District (ID) area, all uses permitted in the IU-2 zoning district after public hearing pursuant to Section 33-311(A)(3) of this code.</section><section prefix='3.'>The following uses in the Marketplace Special District (SD) area:<section prefix='a.'>outdoor produce markets</section><section prefix='b.'>all uses permitted in the IU-1 zoning district</section><section prefix='c.'>in the Core and Center Sub-districts only, on lots fronting on SW 244 Street or SW 137 Avenue, all uses permitted in the Arts District (AD)</section></section><section prefix='4.'>The following uses in the Arts District (AD) area:<section prefix='a.'>live-work buildings, only along A-Streets and with the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>for the residential area: multiple family apartment units when vertically integrated with other lawful uses in work space area</section><section prefix='(2)'>for the work space area:<section prefix='(i)'>all uses permitted in the workshop portion of a live-work unit in the ID area</section><section prefix='(ii)'>arts and crafts stores</section><section prefix='(iii)'>caterers</section><section prefix='(iv)'>drugstores</section><section prefix='(v)'>food preparation</section><section prefix='(vi)'>furniture manufacturing and refinishing</section><section prefix='(vii)'>hardware stores</section><section prefix='(viii)'>hotels/motels</section><section prefix='(ix)'>labs</section><section prefix='(x)'>micro-breweries</section><section prefix='(xi)'>movie theaters, excluding drive-in theaters</section><section prefix='(xii)'>police substations</section><section prefix='(xiii)'>post office substations</section><section prefix='(xiv)'>other similar uses that promote the arts and handcrafts as approved by the Director</section></section></section><section prefix='b.'>uses permitted in the Industrial District (ID) area.</section><section prefix='c.'>when contiguous to a property located in the Marketplace Special District (SD) that is under the same ownership, all uses permitted in the SD District.</section></section><section prefix='5.'>The following uses in the Utilities District (UD) area:<section prefix='a.'>all uses permitted in the GU zoning district, excluding residences and permanent storage.</section></section></section><section prefix='B.'>Conditionally Permitted Uses. An entertainment center shall be permitted after public hearing pursuant to Section 33-311(A)(3) of this code, provided that the following conditions are also satisfied:<section prefix='1.'>The site contains a minimum of 5 net acres and a maximum of 20 net acres.</section><section prefix='2.'>A landscaped buffer of 25 feet is provided along all property lines, allowing only access and egress therein, except that facilities with frontages along SW 244 Street and US 1/Busway shall comply with the Building Placement and Design Parameters.</section><section prefix='3.'>All buildings are setback a minimum of 30 feet from all property lines except along SW 244 Street.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-146, ยง 3, 7-7-05)</history></law>