<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00046' order_by='00046' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXII. IU-C, INDUSTRIAL DISTRICT, CONDITIONAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-268</section_number>
<catch_line>Permitted uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004285</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-268. Permitted uses.<section>No land, body of water, or structure in an IU-C District shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be erected, constructed, moved or reconstructed, structurally altered, used, occupied or maintained for any purpose (except as a legal nonconforming building or use), except for one (1) or more of the uses hereinafter enumerated, and then only in accordance with the conditions hereinafter set forth:<section prefix='(1)'>Every use permitted in the IU-1 District, except adult entertainment uses as defined in Section 33-259.1, and private schools and nonpublic educational facilities as defined in Section 33-151.11 are prohibited in the IU-C District, and every use permitted in the IU-3 Districts (uses permitted in IU-2 District specifically prohibited) and all other industrial uses similar in character shall be permitted in the IU-C District, and shall include utility plants and substations such as, but not limited to, sewage, water, power, communications and gas. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, commuter colleges/universities are permitted within the IU-C District.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All residential buildings and uses shall be prohibited in IU-C Districts, except for caretakers' quarters incidental to a permitted industrial use.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-40, § 2(B), 10-7-58; Ord. No. 69-51, § 4, 9-3-69; Ord. No. 01-227, § 5, 12-20-01; Ord. No. 02-23, § 6, 2-12-02; Ord. No. 02-103, § 5, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 09-102, § 5, 11-17-09)</history></law>