<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='3'>ARTICLE XIXB. RU-5A, SEMI-PROFESSIONAL OFFICE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-223.10</section_number>
<catch_line>Other specific requirements for the RU-5A District.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004200</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-223.10. Other specific requirements for the RU-5A District.<section prefix='(a)'>Open space. On each lot there shall be provided an open space equal to a minimum of twenty-five (25) percent of the total lot area. Said open space shall be unencumbered with any structure or off-street parking, and shall be landscaped and well maintained with grass, trees and shrubbery, excepting only areas used as pedestrian walks and water bodies provided said water bodies do not count for more than twenty (20) percent of the open space requirement. Open space areas may also include tree preservation zones of "natural forest communities" as defined in Section 26B-1, Miami-Dade County Code. Tree preservation zones shall be delineated on all plans submitted to Miami-Dade County for site plan review under Section 33-233.11 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, for the purposes of determining overall preservation area and percent of overall landscaped area. The requirements contained herein do not replace or substitute for any requirements contained within Chapter 18A, Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Maintenance. All landscaped areas shall be continuously maintained in a good, healthy condition, and sprinkler systems of sufficient size and spacing shall be installed to serve all required landscaped areas, except within trees preservation zones of "natural forest communities" as defined in Section 26B-1, Miami-Dade County Code. Tree preservation zones shall also be maintained in a healthy natural condition free from trash, debris and disturbance of understory vegetation.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Mixed uses. Depending on lot area available, it shall also be permissible for the occupant of an office to have an accompanying residential use in connection therewith.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Wall. A decorative wall of masonry, reinforced concrete, precast concrete, or wood fence or other like material that will be compatible with the main structure, five (5) feet in height, shall be erected along all interior property lines including the rear property line; provided, however, in the event that the rear property line abuts a secondary road, said wall shall be set in ten (10) feet from the official right-of-way of the secondary road and said ten-foot strip shall be landscaped; provided further, in the event that the interior side property line abuts property zoned RU-5, RU-5A, or a more liberal zoning district, the requirement for the wall along said common interior property line shall not apply.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Through lots. Where the building site is on a through lot, the structure shall front on the principal road, and if there is any question as to which of the two (2) roads is the principal road, the decision of the Director shall be adhered to.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Trees. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Minimum spacing between principal buildings and accessory buildings. Minimum spacing between principal buildings shall be twenty (20) feet to nearest portion of building(s) and for accessory buildings, ten (10) feet. Cantilevers may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than four (4) feet and the stairways may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than seven and one-half (7½) feet.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Accessory use. A snack bar for the convenience and use of the occupants and patrons of an office development shall be permitted; said snack bar shall not exceed five hundred (500) square feet in size and shall be permitted within an office facility of at least twenty thousand (20,000) square feet. Said snack bar shall be completely enclosed in the building(s) and have no outside advertising or entrance. The hours of operation for any such snack bar shall be limited to 7:00 a.m. to 3:30 p.m. The snack bar area shall be provided one parking space for each three hundred square feet or fractional part thereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 64-18, § 3, 5-5-64; Ord. No. 66-67, § 2, 12-20-66; Ord. No. 80-118, § 1, 10-21-80; Ord. No. 84-82, § 1, 10-2-84; Ord. No. 85-59, § 1, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 85-85, § 2, 10-1-85; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 02-57, § 1, 4-23-02)</history></law>