<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(I). DOWNTOWN KENDALL URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.60</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization of this article.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004377</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.60. Organization of this article.<section prefix='(A)'>This Article is organized into three (3) primary sections:<section prefix='(1)'>The Regulating Plans allocate Sub-Districts, street frontages, and designated open space that serve as the controlling factors of the plan;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Development Parameters are the instructions for implementing the Regulating Plans; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Additional Parameters address issues of quality in the design of buildings and their grounds.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>The controlling factors are the three (3) Regulating Plans which establish four Sub-Districts, five (5) street frontage types and a number of designated open spaces that interact. Each different interaction is illustrated as part of this Article.<section prefix='(1)'>The Sub-District Plan delineates four sub-districts, the Core, the Center, the Center DRI and the Edge. These Sub-Districts control land use and intensity of development in accordance with the County's Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Unless developed in accordance with Section 33-284.63.1 below, property in the Center DRI Sub-district shall be subject to the provisions of this article applicable to the Center Sub-district.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Street Frontage Plan establishes a hierarchy of street types in existing and future locations which shall be provided and shown in all future development. The five (5) street types are lettered "A" through "E." An "A" street is the most important street to accommodate pedestrian activity.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Designated Open Space Plan establishes essential open spaces which shall be provided in all future development and construction. The designated open spaces are controlled by anchor points which are shown on a larger map at a scale of one (1) inch equals two hundred (200) feet on file at the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning. The Downtown Kendall Urban Center District Designated Open Space Plan Map's legend contains colonnades, squares & greenspaces, and anchor point. The map, shown below, specifies the exact location and size of all squares and greenspaces required within the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District.</section></section><section><section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-166, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 02-11, ยง 2, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 06-114, ยง 1, 7-18-06)</history></law>