<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00039' order_by='00039' level='3'>ARTICLE XXV. BU-1A, LIMITED BUSINESS DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-247</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004228</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-247. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water and/or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved, maintained or occupied for any purpose in any BU-1A District, except for one (1) or more of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>All uses permitted in the BU-1 District except that residential uses are subject to approval at a public hearing.</section><section prefix='(1.1)'>Amusement center as defined in Section 33-1(5.1).</section><section prefix='(2)'>Auditoriums.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Automobile new parts and equipment, sales only. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-251.2 to the contrary, as an ancillary service, a facility selling new automobile parts and equipment may perform minimal automobile maintenance repairs in that facility's on-site designated parking area, provided that all of the following conditions are satisfied:<section prefix='(a)'>Such repairs are performed at no charge, solely as a courtesy for which no payment is charged or received;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The sum of the repairs performed on an individual vehicle shall take no more than a total of twenty (20) minutes to perform;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Such repairs shall not include oil changes, oil filter changes, transmission fluid changes, transmission fluid filter changes, engine coolant or engine anti-freeze changes, brake fluid changes, power steering fluid changes, tire repair, tire installation, tire rotation, or any other repair that falls within the scope of the repair certification categories set forth in Section 8A-161.25(2)(a)—(e) and (g) of this Code:</section><section prefix='(d)'>The price(s) charged by the facility for automobile parts or equipment is not increased because of the performance of such repairs;</section><section prefix='(e)'>The repairs are performed by an employee of the facility; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>All residual, discarded, or waste products, parts, equipment, packaging, fluids, and other materials left over from such repairs are stored or disposed of by the facility immediately after the completion of the repairs, in compliance with all applicable laws, ordinances, and regulations governing the storage, handling, and disposal of such items.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Automobile and light truck, new sales agency or rental shall be permitted only upon approval after public hearing and subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That a continuous, densely planted greenbelt of not less than fifteen (15) feet in width, penetrated only at points approved by the Director and the Director of the Public Works Department for ingress or egress to the property, shall be provided along all property lines abutting public rights-of-way or properties zoned residential. Said greenbelt shall have shade trees planted at a maximum spacing of thirty (30) feet on center. The shade trees shall have a minimum caliper of two and one-half (2½) inches at time of planting.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That a decorative masonry wall at least five (5) feet in height shall enclose the vehicle storage area and repair area approved through public hearing. The placement of said wall and openings through same shall comply with the requirements contained elsewhere in this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That all outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited.</section><section prefix='(d)'>That no repair work of any type is permitted on premises unless approved after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(e)'>That accessory used vehicle sales shall be permitted providing said vehicles are late model and in operable condition.</section><section prefix='(f)'>That the applicant obtain a certificate of use and occupancy which shall be automatically renewable yearly upon compliance with all terms and conditions applicable.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Automobile gas stations/mini marts (which may include facilities available for sale of other retail products and services related to the servicing of automobiles) including rental of single axle hauling trailers. Plans for paved areas, driveways or curb cuts of gas stations shall be submitted to and approved by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management and, where required, the Florida State Department of Transportation before a permit can be issued. Gas stations providing self-service dispensing of fuel with attendant control of pumps shall ensure that the attendant-control area has clear visibility to all pumps. The use of signs on windows of the attendant-control area that would obstruct the clear visibility to all pumps are prohibited. As an accessory use, the gas stations may perform minor automobile repairs as herein listed:<section prefix='(a)'>Sale and servicing of spark plugs and batteries.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Tire repair and servicing, but no recapping.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Replacement of mufflers and tailpipes, water hose, fan belts, brake fluids, light bulbs, floor mats, seat covers, wiper blades, arms for windshields and replacement of grease retainers and wheel bearings.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Radiator cleaning and flushing.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Washing and polishing.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Greasing and lubrication.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Exchanging fuel pumps and installing fuel lines.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Minor servicing or replacement of carburetors.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Emergency wiring repairs.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Adjusting brakes and installing or exchanging brake shoes.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Tuning engines, with the exception of grinding valves, cleaning carbon or removing the head of engines and/or crankcases.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Wheel balancing and aligning.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Shock absorbers.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Automobile storage within a building.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Automobile tires, batteries and accessories (new) retail only installation permitted.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Automobile washing.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Bait and tackle shops.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Banks, including drive-in teller service.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Billiard rooms and pool rooms.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Boats carrying passengers on excursion, sightseeing, pleasure or fishing trips.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Bowling alleys, provided that such establishments are not located closer than five hundred (500) feet to an RU, or EU District, unless such building is so constructed as to prevent the emission of sound and vibration.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Convention halls.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Dancing halls or dancing academies in air conditioned buildings providing no intoxicating beverages of any kind are served, providing that such establishments are not located closer than five hundred (500) feet to an RU, or EU District, unless such building is so constructed as to prevent the emission of sound and vibration.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Dog and pet hospitals in air-conditioned buildings.</section><section prefix='(17.1)'>Donated goods centers, including drive-through drop-off facilities, for the acceptance and sale of new or used merchandise, excluding furniture and major appliances, upon compliance with the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The donated goods center must be operated by an organization which has been incorporated as a not-for-profit organization under the laws of Florida for a charitable purpose and which has been declared exempt from the payment of federal income taxes by the United States Internal Revenue Service;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The donated goods must be accepted by personnel directly employed by or volunteers for the not-for-profit organization;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The monetary proceeds resulting from the sale of said merchandise must be used in accordance with the organization's charitable purpose to benefit persons within the boundaries of Miami-Dade County or outside of Miami-Dade County to provide emergency relief for victims of natural, man-made or economic disasters;</section><section prefix='(d)'>The operation of the donated goods center, the collection and use of donations and proceeds thereof must be conducted by said not-for-profit organization and not by a licensee, subtenant, subcontractor or agent of the not-for-profit organization;</section><section prefix='(e)'>The merchandise sold in the donated goods center must be neatly sorted and displayed.</section></section><section prefix='(18)'>Dry cleaning establishments, using noninflammable solvents in self-contained dry cleaning units of the Prosperity type or Dedrick type or an equal approved by the Director, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Electrical appliance and fixtures stores including related repair shops.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Employment agencies.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Furniture stores, retail of new merchandise only.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Grocery stores.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Handcrafted-products shop.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Health and exercise clubs, including bath and massage parlors.</section><section prefix='(24.1)'>Home improvement centers, subject to the conditions enumerated below. As used herein, a home improvement center is a facility engaged in the retail sale of a variety of home improvement products, including hardware, appliances, cleaning supplies, construction supplies, electrical and plumbing fixtures and supplies, paint and wall coverings, lumber, pool supplies, and tools as well as lawn and graden supplies. As an accessory use, a home improvement center may offer the short-term rental of tools, compressors, chain saws, ladders, post-hole diggers, hand trucks and similar light equipment as well as trucks (subject to the limitations set forth below). Additionally, a home improvement center may perform customer-requested cutting of pre-cut wood products and other products offered for sale, provided such cutting is done within the roofed area of the principal building.<section prefix='(a)'>Lawn, garden and pool supplies may also be stored, displayed and sold from attached areas with or without a solid roof, subject to the following limitations:<section prefix='(1)'>such storage, display and sales areas does not exceed thirty-five percent (35%) of the home improvement center's gross building floor area; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>all such storage, display and sales areas must be enclosed by a solid masonry wall or ornamental metal picket fence or combination thereof, a minimum of eight (8) feet in height. The items stored within these areas shall not exceed the height of the wall or metal picket fence. Openings for ingress and egress purposes, restricted to the narrowest width necessary, are permitted, subject to site plan review; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>setbacks as required for the principal building shall apply to all storage, display and sales areas; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>parking for the home improvement center, including such storage, display and sales areas, shall be provided in accordance with Section 33-124(h)(3.1) herein.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The rental of trucks for the convenience of customers purchasing items only shall be permitted at home improvement centers with greater than one hundred thousand (100,000) square feet of gross floor area, subject to the following limitations:<section prefix='(1)'>The total number of trucks available for rental shall not exceed five (5);</section><section prefix='(2)'>The location of storage areas for rental trucks shall be subject to site plan review;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Storage areas for rental trucks shall not utilize any of the facility's minimum required parking spaces; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>No repairs or maintenance of rental trucks shall take place on the premises.</section></section><section>Loading dock facilities for the purpose of supplying the home improvement center shall be oriented away from adjacent residential zoning districts unless screened from view by a masonry wall of not less than six (6) feet in height but not more than eight (8) feet in height.</section></section><section prefix='(25)'>Junior department stores.</section><section prefix='(26)'>Lawn mowers, retail, sales and service.</section><section prefix='(26.1)'>Medical observation dormitory as defined in Section 33-1(69.05) subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That such uses on sites of ten (10) net acres or more shall be approved only after public hearing;</section><section prefix='(b)'>That such uses shall be located on sites having frontage on a major access road, including major roadways (three (3) or more lanes) and frontage roadways serving limited access highways and expressways;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Minimum five (5) foot high masonry wall be provided along all perimeter property lines abutting residentially zoned property, penetrated only at points approved by the Directors of the Planning and Zoning Department and the Public Works Department for ingress and egress;</section><section prefix='(d)'>That the facility is located on a site consisting of at least three (3) or more net acres;</section><section prefix='(e)'>That research conducted at the property shall be limited to testing of normal healthy volunteers and of clinically stable representatives of the diseased states for which medications being tested are ultimately intended;</section><section prefix='(f)'>That protocols that require treating of mentally ill subjects, including persons with any mental or psychological disorder, such as intellectual disability, organic brain syndrome, emotional or mental illness, and specific learning disabilities, shall not be performed at the research facility;</section><section prefix='(g)'>That such use shall be located no less than twenty-five hundred (2,500) feet from any other such establishments. For the purposes of this subsection, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the front door of the proposed place of business to the nearest property line of the existing place of business. For the purpose ofestablishing the distance between such establishments, the operator shall furnish a certified sketch of survey from a registered engineer or surveyor. Such sketch shall indicate the distance between the proposed place of business and any existing establishment within 2,500 feet. Each sketch shall indicate all such distances and routes. In case of dispute, the measurement scaled by the director shall govern;</section><section prefix='(h)'>That the operator obtains an annually renewable certificate of use and occupancy for such use on the property.</section></section><section prefix='(27)'>Mortuaries or funeral homes.</section><section prefix='(28)'>Motorcycles sales and repair.</section><section prefix='(29)'>Natatoriums.</section><section prefix='(30)'>Open-air theaters.</section><section prefix='(31)'>Package stores in shopping centers provided the shopping center is in full compliance with all provisions of Section 33-150(E)(9) of this Code.</section><section prefix='(32)'>Pet shops, pet care centers and dog beauty parlors in air-conditioned buildings.</section><section prefix='(33)'>Post office stations and branches, operated by postal service employees or agents, which directly serve the public.</section><section prefix='(34)'>Printing shops.</section><section prefix='(35)'>Private clubs.</section><section prefix='(36)'>Propagating and growing plants for sale. Fertilizers, manure, compost and soil shall be limited for sale. Fertilizers, manure, compost and soil shall be limited in quantities for immediate use and shall be kept at least two hundred (200) feet from residential buildings in RU and EU Districts.</section><section prefix='(37)'>Pubs and bars if approved at public hearing.</section><section prefix='(37.1)'>Restaurants providing an accessory children's outdoor playground facility subject to the following requirements:<section prefix='(a)'>The restaurant providing such an accessory use shall contain not less than two thousand five hundred (2,500) square feet of improved building area;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The total outdoor playground area shall not exceed thirty-five (35) percent of the square footage of the subject restaurant structure;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The playground equipment shall be the non-mechanical type and shall be designed and intended for children two (2) through twelve (12) years of age;</section><section prefix='(d)'>The playground shall be immediately adjacent to, visible from, and accessible from the indoor patron area;</section><section prefix='(e)'>The playground area shall be enclosed with a masonry wall or fence not less than four (4) feet in height and any gates shall be of the spring lock type, so that they shall automatically be in a closed and fastened position at all times; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>The playground area shall not reduce required parking or landscaping for the site and shall be set back no less than ten (10) feet from any property line and in compliance with all Code requirements;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Site plan review and approval shall be required as provided in Section 33-251.5</section></section><section prefix='(37.2)'>Restaurants with an accessory cocktail lounge-bar use, subject to compliance with Article X, Alcoholic Beverages, of this code.</section><section prefix='(38)'>Self-service storage facility. Use will only be permitted upon the submission of a site plan which shall be approved at public hearing. "Self-service storage facility" shall be defined as a fully enclosed space used for warehousing which contains individual storage units with floor area no greater than four hundred (400) square feet and an interior height not to exceed twelve (12) feet. No wholesale or retail sales are permitted.</section><section prefix='(39)'>Skating rinks, provided same are not located closer than one thousand (1,000) feet to an RU or EU District, or any lawful existing residential use, provided that such building is so constructed as to prevent the emission of sound and vibration. The 1,000-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the skating rink structure to the nearest residential property line. For purposes of establishing such distances, the applicant for skating rink use shall furnish a certified survey from a registered surveyor, which shall indicate such distances. In case of dispute, the measurement scaled by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning shall govern.</section><section prefix='(40)'>Supermarkets.</section><section prefix='(41)'>Tailor shops.</section><section prefix='(42)'>Telegraph stations.</section><section prefix='(43)'>Telephone exchange.</section><section prefix='(44)'>Theaters for live stage production and motion pictures.</section><section prefix='(45)'>Variety stores.</section><section prefix='(46)'>Rentals of trucks other than light trucks are allowed in conjunction with and ancillary to self-storage facilities, providing the following conditions are met in addition to those specified in sub-articles (4)(a) and (4)(c)—(f) above:<section prefix='(i)'>That a decorative masonry wall at least eight (8) feet in height shall enclose the vehicle storage area and repair area. The placement of said wall and openings through same shall comply with the requirements contained elsewhere in this article. Prior to the granting of any building permit for such wall, the permit applicant shall post with the director a bond in the amount of two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500.00) to provide for the costs of removal of graffiti from the wall by the department as provided in Section 21-30.1(d)(6), Code of Miami-Dade County, as amended, should the applicant fail after notice to remove such graffiti.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>There shall be a landscaped buffer between the masonry wall and any abutting roads which may be a hedge, and/or trees at least forty-eight (48) inches high at the time of planting, or other reasonable landscape plans acceptable to the department.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>That there be no rental of any truck having a net vehicle weight exceeding twelve thousand six hundred pounds (12,600) pounds.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>That for each one hundred (100) self-storage units there shall be no more than one (1) rental truck stored, e.g., 1—100 units: 1 rental truck; 101—200 units; 2 rental trucks, etc.; provided however, no more than eight (8) rental trucks may be stored on the premises.</section><section prefix='(v)'>That no building in the area enclosed by the wall shall exceed two (2) stories in height.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>That no loading or unloading of trucks is permitted outside the enclosed area and all trucks must be stored inside the enclosed area at all times.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>That there shall be no repairs or maintenance work on vehicles on the premises of the self-storage facility.</section><section prefix='(viii)'>That the area of self-storage facilities be not less than 2.5 acres.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-23, § 1, 4-16-74; Ord. No. 76-5, §§ 3, 4, 1-20-76; Ord. No. 77-45, § 1, 7-5-77; Ord. No. 77-69, § 3, 9-20-77; Ord. No. 80-35, § 1, 5-6-80; Ord. No. 81-58, § 2, 5-19-81; Ord. No. 85-37, § 1, 6-6-85; Ord. No. 87-6, § 2, 2-17-87; Ord. No. 90-118, § 1, 11-6-90; Ord. No. 91-92, § 1, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 95-105, § 1, 6-20-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 15, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 01-131, § 2, 9-13-01; Ord. No. 02-4, § 2, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 02-176, § 2, 10-8-02; Ord. No. 02-227, § 1, 11-19-02; Ord. No. 03-80, § 2, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 04-60, § 2, 3-16-04; Ord. No. 09-103, § 1, 11-17-09; Ord. No. 13-76, § 4, 9-4-13; Ord. No. 13-83, § 8, 9-17-13)</history></law>