<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(P). CUTLER RIDGE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (CRMUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.28</section_number>
<catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004443</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.28. General Requirements.<section>Except as provided herein, all developments within the CRMUC shall comply with the requirements provided in of this code.<section prefix='A.'>Buildings. In addition to the requirements of Section 33-284.86 of this Code, all buildings within the CRMUC shall comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='1)'>Where colonnades are provided, the colonnade shall be placed along the property line.</section><section prefix='2)'>Minimum spacing between towers within any one contiguous property line shall be 60 feet.</section><section prefix='3)'>Aggregate tower frontage facing any street may not exceed 225 feet per block or 70 percent of street frontage; whichever is greater.</section><section prefix='4)'>Vehicular entry gates at garage entries shall be positioned a minimum of 20 feet behind the front wall of the building. At colonnaded frontages, this distance shall be measured from the interior/rear wall of the colonnade. To increase safety during off-hours, the setback area between the entry gate and the public sidewalk may be gated at the sidewalk edge during times when the garage is closed.</section><section prefix='5)'>Drop off drives and porte-cocheres may only occur in the rear, on the side, and/or along service roads.</section><section prefix='6)'>Loading and service entries shall be allowed only in the rear along service roads and/or within parking lots and structures.</section><section prefix='7)'>Vehicular entries to garages shall be allowed only from service roads and/or minor streets. Along minor streets, vehicular entries shall have a maximum width of 33 feet and a minimum separation of 70 feet between entries. Along service roads, vehicular entries shall not be limited.</section><section prefix='8)'>The penthouse shall occur above the tower level and shall be limited to 50 percent of the largest tower floorplate.</section><section prefix='9)'>A cornice line shall be required at the top of the third story of MM, MO, MC, and ID buildings, as provided in Section 33-284.86 of this code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-152, ยง 6, 10-10-06)</history></law>