<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00066' order_by='00066' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(R). MODEL CITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (MCUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.42</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004457</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.42. Uses.<section>Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the MCUCD shall comply with of this code.<section prefix='A.'>Permitted uses. In addition to the uses provided in Section 33-284.83(A), the following shall be permitted:<section prefix='1.'>In the Mixed-Use Corridor Special (MCS) area, all uses provided in Section 33-284.83(A)(3) and the following uses:<section prefix='(a)'>Automobile and truck services and facilities including:<section prefix='(1)'>Open lot car and truck sales new or used, including, as ancillary uses, automobile repairs, body and top work and painting, provided that no more than fifteen (15) percent of the gross building area is devoted to such ancillary uses, and subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='a.'>That attention attractive devices, such as blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers and all fluttering, spinning advertising devices (either mobile or stationary) are prohibited.</section><section prefix='b.'>That outdoor lighting shall be designed to avoid spilling beyond the site boundaries.</section><section prefix='c.'>That no vehicular test drives shall be conducted on residential local traffic streets (fifty-foot right-of-way or less).</section><section prefix='d.'>That the applicant obtains a certificate of use, which shall be automatically renewable yearly upon compliance with all terms and conditions.</section><section prefix='e.'>All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited. This provision shall also apply to all establishments in existence as of September 10, 1996.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Open lot car rental.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Automobile parts, secondhand from store building only.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Automobile body and top work and painting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Automobile self-service gas stations. When provided, gas stations shall be exempt from the provisions of this article and shall conform to the BU-1A development standards provided in Article XXV of this code.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Engines, steam and oil; sales and service.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Garage or mechanical service, including automobile repairs, body and top work and painting. All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited. This provision shall also apply to all establishments in existence as of September 10, 1996.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Glass installation.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Tire vulcanizing and retreading or sale of use tires.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Truck storage, only within an enclosed building or an area enclosed by a CBS wall.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Automobile washing.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Self-service mini-warehouse storage facility in compliance with Section 33-255(23.1) of this code.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>In the Industrial District (ID) area, the following uses:<section prefix='(a)'>MC uses at maximum residential densities shown on the Density Regulating Plan in Section 33-284.99.43 of this code.</section></section></section><section prefix='B.'>Conditionally permitted uses. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-284.83(B), only the following conditional uses shall be permitted, subject to the administrative approval of a site plan pursuant to Section 33-284.88 of this code:<section prefix='1.'>Liquor package stores only in the Core and Center Sub-districts, and only in compliance with Article X of this code.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Workforce housing requirement alternative. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-284.83(A)(1), all residential or mixed-use developments within the MCUCD that have more than four (4) residential units shall provide one of the following:<section prefix='1.'>A minimum of 12.5 percent of their units as workforce housing units; or</section><section prefix='2.'>A minimum of 10 percent of their units as affordable housing units. "Affordable housing unit" means a dwelling unit, the sale, rental, or pricing of which is restricted to households whose income range is up to 80 percent of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. HUD and maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-13, ยง 3, 2-2-10)</history></law>