<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00068' order_by='00068' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(T). PALMER LAKE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (PLMUC)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.66</section_number>
<catch_line>Legal description and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004481</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.66. Legal description and applicability.<section>A portion of Sections 28 and 29, Township 53 South, Range 41 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>BEGINNING AT A POINT being the intersection of NW 37th Avenue and NW 21st Street also being a point 436 feet north of the southwest corner of Township 53 Range 41, thence west along the centerline of said NW 21st Street 720 feet to a point, thence north to a point being the southwest corner of TRACT F of MIAMI INTERMODAL CENTER (PB 168 PG 53), thence north 237.5 feet along the west line of said TRACT F to a point, thence east 55.92 feet east to a point being ±16 feet west of the southwest corner of TRACT D of MIAMI INTERMODAL CENTER (PB 168 PG 53), thence north along and parallel of the west line of said TRACT D to a point being 7.5 ft west of the northwest corner of said TRACT D, thence ±83 feet northeasterly to a point being the southwest corner of TRACT J of MIAMI INTERMODAL CENTER (PB 168 PG 53), thence north 842 feet along the west line of said TRACT J to a point, thence west ±59.5 feet to a point, thence northwesterly for a curvilinear distance of ±923 feet along the north right of way line of the south wye track of the SEABOARD AIR LINE RAILROAD to a point, thence northeasterly for a curvilinear distance of ±882 feet along the south right of way line of the north wye track of the SEABOARD AIR LINE RAILROAD to a point, thence north to ±203 feet to a point being the intersection of the centerline of NW South River Drive and SEABOARD AIR LINE RAILROAD, thence northwesterly ±283 feet to a point being the intersection of NW 31st Street and NW South River Drive, thence northeasterly 255 feet to a point, thence meandering southeasterly 6,340 feet along the centerline of MIAMI CANAL to a point being the northeast corner of CANAL POINT (PB 30 PG 63), thence southeasterly 697 feet along the centerline of MIAMI CANAL to a point being 84 feet west of the southeast corner of the SW 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of Township 53 Range 41, thence west 2,055 feet along the south line of Township 53 Range 41 to a point, thence north 47 feet to a point being southwest corner of LOT 486 of GRAPELAND HEIGHTS (PB 14 PG 63), thence north along the west line of said LOT 486 to a point being the northwest corner of said LOT 486, thence north 40 feet to a point being the centerline of TAMIAMI CANAL, thence meandering westerly ±2,553 feet along the centerline of said TAMIAMI CANAL to a point being 191 feet north of the southwest corner of Township 53 Range 41, thence north 245 feet along the west line of Township 53 Range 41 to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section><section>Full scale maps of the Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center boundary are on file with the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources.</section><section>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property except lands lying within the boundaries of the Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to the Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-43, § 12, 5-7-13)</history></law>