<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. AU, AGRICULTURAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-283.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Site plan review for commercial vehicle storage.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004312</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-283.1. Site plan review for commercial vehicle storage.<section prefix='(a)'>Procedures. The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The purpose of the site plan criteria is to insure compatibility and adequate buffering of the uses with the surrounding area. All plans submitted to the Department shall be reviewed and approved or denied by the Department within fifteen (15) days from the date of submission. The applicant shall have the right to extend the fifteen-day period by an additional fifteen (15) days upon timely request made in writing to the Department. The Department shall have the right to extend the fifteen-day period by written notice to the applicant that additional information is needed to process the site plan. Denials should be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for denial.</section><section>The written decisions of the Department in relation to the site plan review criteria may be appealed by the party(ies) which filed the application for the project to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board within thirty (30) days of the date the project was denied approval in writing. Appeals will be heard as expeditiously as possible. All final plans submitted for building permits shall be substantially in compliance with plans approved under the plan review procedure herein established.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Required Exhibits. Exhibits prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects shall be submitted to the Department of Planning and Zoning and shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Schematic site plan at a scale of not less than one (1) inch equals one hundred (100) feet containing the following information:<section prefix='a.'>Proposed commercial vehicle and equipment storage area.</section><section prefix='b.'>Location of proposed paved area and driveway connections.</section><section prefix='c.'>Parking and driveway layouts.</section><section prefix='d.'>Proposed grades.</section><section prefix='e.'>Existing and proposed fences, signs, architectural accents, guard house (if provided) and location of advertising or graphic features.</section><section prefix='f.'>Landscaping and trees.</section><section prefix='g.'>Plans showing the location, height, lights, shades, deflectors and beam directions.</section><section prefix='h.'>Stormwater management improvements.</section><section prefix='i.'>Other information and plans as deemed necessary by the Director to evaluate compliance with the CDMP and Chapters 33 and 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Criteria. The following criteria shall be considered in the review process:<section prefix='(1)'>Parking and storage: All vehicles and equipment shall be stored or parked only on paved impervious surfaces. The drainage system shall be approved by the Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Emergency access: Unobstructed access for on-site access for emergency equipment shall be considered.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Site enclosure: The subject site shall be enclosed by an eight (8) foot high masonry wall, vinyl coated chain link fence, or a chain link fence with visual screening. Said wall/fence shall be located on all property lines.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Lighting: All outdoor lighting, or outdoor signs or identification features shall be designed as an integral part of the surrounding landscape. Light fixtures shall be designed with a maximum height of 35 feet. Shielding shall be provided to prevent light from projecting upward. Any overspill of lighting onto adjacent properties shall not exceed one-half (½) foot-candle (vertical) and shall not exceed one-half (½) foot-candle (horizontal) illumination on adjacent properties or structures. Lighting shall comply with the standards in Section 8C-3 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Visual screening: Buffer and visual screening shall be provided to make the use compatible with rural and agricultural land uses and to prevent negative visual impact to surrounding areas. The following minimum landscaping shall be provided along all property lines within the required setback area:<section prefix='a.'>A continuous extensively landscaped buffer which shall be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner. The required buffer shall be located on the interior side of the required fence or wall along rights-of-way within required setback areas. The landscape buffer shall contain the following plant materials:<section prefix='1.'>Ground Cover. Ground cover shall consist of grass or plants. Plants used in lieu of grass, in whole or in part, shall be planted in such a manner as to present a finished appearance and reasonably complete coverage within one (1) year after planting.</section><section prefix='2.'>Continuous Hedge. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting, shall be planted at a maximum average spacing of 48 inches on center and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting. Of the provided hedge at least:<section prefix='(i)'>Thirty (30) percent shall be native species; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Fifty (50) percent shall be low maintenance and drought tolerant; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Eighty (80) percent shall be listed in the Miami-Dade Landscape Manual, the Miami-Dade Street Tree Master Plan and/or the University of Florida's Low-Maintenance Landscape Plants for South Florida list.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Trees. Trees shall be of a species typically grown in Miami-Dade County which normally mature to a height of at least twenty (20) feet. Trees shall have a clear trunk of four (4) feet, an overall height of twelve (12) feet and a minimum caliper of two (2) inches at time of planting, and shall be provided within the buffer area along all property lines at a maximum average spacing of thirty-five (35) feet on center. Of the required trees at least:<section prefix='(i)'>Thirty (30) percent shall be native species; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Fifty (50) percent shall be low maintenance and drought tolerant; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>No more than thirty (30) percent shall be palms.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Eighty (80) percent of the trees shall be listed in the Miami-Dade Landscape Manual, the Miami-Dade Street Tree Master Plan and/or the University of Florida's Low-Maintenance Landscape Plants for South Florida list.</section></section></section><section prefix='b.'>A stormwater management plan shall be approved by the Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section prefix='c.'>Stormwater retention/detention facilities may be located within the required setback provided all landscaping requirements are met.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-73, § 3, 11-4-10)</history></law>