<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00022' order_by='00022' level='3'>ARTICLE XVA. RU-TH, TOWNHOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-202.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Definition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004126</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-202.2. Definition.<section>As used herein, a "townhouse" is a one-family dwelling unit of a group of three (3) or more such units separated by a common party fire wall; provided, however, that up to ten (10) percent of the total number of units on any individual site plan may be developed in two-unit groupings. Said common party fire wall shall extend to the roof line or above the roof of units which it serves and shall have no openings therein. Where units are offset from one (1) another and a common party wall is used, the wall may be placed equidistant on each side of the lot line not exceeding the length of the offset. Each townhouse unit shall be constructed upon a separate platted lot; provided, however, that the roof lines may overhang onto adjacent lots or common areas a maximum of twenty-four (24) inches, subject to the approval of and determination by the Director that the roof or drainage system is designed so that runoff of water from the roof does not adversely affect adjacent units or lots. Each townhouse unit shall be serviced with separate utilities and other facilities and shall otherwise be independent of one (1) another; provided, however, that the electrical lines or telephone lines or cables which service a particular unit may be placed through other lots where approved by the Director. The Director's approval shall be based upon his finding that the placement of said lines or cables will not adversely affect the lots through which they are placed.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 65-72, § 1-II, 11-9-65; Ord. No. 70-31, § 1, 4-22-70; Ord. No. 82-29, § 1, 4-20-82; Ord. No. 85-43, § 1, 6-18-85; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>