<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00044' order_by='00044' level='3'>ARTICLE XXX. IU-2 INDUSTRIAL, HEAVY MANUFACTURING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-263</section_number>
<catch_line>Location of industrial use; use confined to building; location of petroleum tanks; residential uses limited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004271</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-263. Location of industrial use; use confined to building; location of petroleum tanks; residential uses limited.<section prefix='(a)'>No establishment or industrial use permitted in this district, however, shall be located within five hundred (500) feet of any RU, EU, or BU-1 District, except after a public hearing. Provided that the spacing limitation shall be two hundred fifty (250) feet if the use is confined within a building and an exterior wall or walls of the building located on the establishment is not penetrated with any openings directly facing the RU, EU or BU-1 District. It is further provided that, except for exterior uses, such distances shall be measured from the closest point of the subject use in the building to the RU or EU or BU-1 District. In connection with exterior uses, the distance of five hundred (500) feet shall be measured from the closest point of the IU District to the RU or EU or BU-1 District. For purposes of establishing such distances, the applicant for such use shall furnish a certified survey from a registered surveyor, which shall indicate such distances. In case of dispute, the measurement scaled by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning shall govern.</section><section prefix='(b)'>At all manufacturing establishments or rebuilding, processing, packaging, storage or repair places permitted in an IU-2 District, all materials and products shall be stored and all manufacturing, rebuilding, processing, packaging, storing or renovating operations shall be carried on entirely within an enclosed building or confined and completely enclosed within masonry walls not less than six (6) feet in height, excepting only shipyards, dry docks, boat slips, and the like, where necessary frontage on the water may be open.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In no case shall petroleum storage tanks be located closer than three hundred (300) feet to a residential building.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No residential uses will be permitted, except a watchman's or caretaker's quarters used in connection with industrial use on the premises concerned.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 24(B), (C), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 68-3, § 2, 2-6-68; Ord. No. 69-51, § 2, 9-3-69; Ord. No. 96-129, § 1, 9-10-96; Ord. No. 00-74, § 1, 6-6-00)</history></law>