<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00056' order_by='00056' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIH. TRADITIONAL NEIGHBORHOOD DEVELOPMENT (TND) DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.47</section_number>
<catch_line>Design criteria.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004363</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.47. Design criteria.<section prefix='(A)'>The following design criteria and requirements shall be applicable in the TND District. Terms used throughout this ordinance shall take their commonly accepted meaning unless otherwise defined in Chapter 33 or Chapter 28 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Terms requiring interpretation specific to this ordinance are as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Alley: A vehicular passageway providing primary, secondary and/or service access to the sides or rear of building lots. Posted speed shall not exceed fifteen (15) miles per hour.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Artisanal use: The manufacture and sale of artifacts utilizing only handheld and/or table mounted electrical tools contained within an enclosed structure.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Block: A combination of building lots serviced by an alley, the perimeter of which abuts public use lands (in most cases public right-of-way).</section><section prefix='(4)'>Building lot: A separately platted portion of private land, not including the specified sidewalk area.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Civic building: Any permitted or required civic use building when located in a civic use lot.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Clear zone: An area beyond the curb radius, so specified, which shall be kept clear of all objects to provide emergency vehicle clearance.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Colonnade: A roof or building structure, extending over the sidewalk, open to the street and sidewalk except for supporting columns or piers. Colonnades shall have, at the sidewalk, a minimum clear height of ten (10) feet (excluding signage or lighting) and a minimum clear width of eight (8) feet (from frontage line to inside column face). Colonnades shall be constructed eighteen (18) inches to twenty-four (24) inches from the face of the curb. Awnings are permitted within the TND but are not considered colonnades. Colonnades shall not cause roof drainage into the public right-of-way.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Congregate living facilities: A group home for a maximum of six (6) resident clients who are cared for by the owner who permanently resides in the residential unit. The facility must be licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services and meet Code criteria for such use. In the shopfront use location the total residents may be in excess of six (6) if the use meets the other requirements of the shopfront use category. Congregate living facilities shall include homes for the aged.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Cornice line: A molded and projecting horizontal member that crowns an architectural composition. A cornice line shall project a minimum of two (2) inches from the front elevation of the structure.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Curb radius: The curved edge of the street at intersections, measured at the edge of the travel lanes. Curbs at intersections shall not intrude into the intersection beyond the specified maximum curb radius. Where streets of different use categories intersect, the requirements of the higher intensity use shall govern.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Front porch: A front porch is an unairconditioned roofed structure attached to the front of the unit. A front porch shall have a minimum depth of six (6) feet and a minimum width of twelve (12) feet and, except for insect screening, shall only have supporting columns visible above forty-two (42) inches from the finished porch floor level. Side and rear porches are not subject to these requirements. All or a portion of the front porch may encompass a ramp providing access for people with disabilities.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Frontage line: The shorter building lot line which coincides to the right-of-way of the street or square. In the case of a building lot abutting upon only one (1) street, the frontage line is the line parallel to and common with the edge of sidewalk. In the case of a corner lot, that part of the building lot having the narrowest frontage on any street shall be considered the frontage line.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Greenbelt: An optional open space area adjoining the neighborhood proper and no less than one (1) hundred fifty (150) feet wide at any place. The area shall be preserved in perpetuity in its natural condition, or enhanced by the owner, as determined by the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management. The greenbelt area may be used for non-row crop farming, wetlands, water retention, animal husbandry, bulky waste site (for the exclusive use of the TND), golf courses, or subdivided into house lots no smaller than five (5) acres. Roadways, exclusive of through streets, may penetrate greenbelts in order to provide access to areas outside the TND.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Green: A public open space located within the neighborhood proper and bounded by streets. Paved areas in greens shall not exceed twenty percent (20%) of the green area exclusive of dedicated rights-of-way. Greens shall have a length to width ratio no greater than four to one (4:1). A green may be enclosed with a wrought iron or electrostatic plated aluminum fence not exceeding five (5) feet in height.</section><section prefix='(14a)'>Habitable space: building space whose use involves human presence and entertainment, excluding balconies and terraces.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Height: Building height shall be measured from the average elevation of the finished exterior building site to the eave line or to the top of the parapet. Flat roofs shall have parapet walls on all sides.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Home occupation use: Premises used for the transaction of business or the supply of professional services excluding medical and dental. Home occupation shall be limited to the following: Architect, artist, broker, consultant, dressmaker, draftsman, engineer, interior decorator, lawyer, manufacturer's agent, notary public, teacher (excluding group instruction), and other similar occupations. Such use shall not simultaneously employ more than two (2) persons, one (1) of whom must reside on the property. The total gross area of the home occupational use shall not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the gross square footage of the residential unit. Certificates of use and occupancy shall be reviewed annually.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Limited lodging use: The provision of no more than four (4) bedrooms for letting. Food service may be included between the hours of 6:00 a.m. to 11:00 a.m. The maximum length of stay shall not exceed fourteen (14) days.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Limited office use: The transaction of business or the supply of professional services, employing no more than eight (8) persons.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Lodging use: Buildings providing food service and bedrooms for letting.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Maintenance easement: A perpetual four-foot wide wall maintenance easement shall be provided on a lot adjacent to a zero lot line property line, which, with the exception of walls and/or fences, shall be kept clear of structures. This easement shall be shown on the plat and incorporated into each deed transferring title to the property. The wall shall be maintained in its original color and treatment unless otherwise agreed to in writing by the affected lot owners. Roof overhangs may penetrate the easement on the adjacent lot a maximum of twenty-four (24) inches but the roof shall be so designed that water runoff from the dwelling placed on the lot line is limited to the easement area. The easement shall be maintained unless otherwise agreed to, in writing, by the two (2) affected lot owners.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Meeting hall: A building(s) or an area or room within a building located on a civic use lot, designed for public assembly and equivalent in size to four (4) square feet per dwelling unit or twenty-four hundred (2,400) gross square feet, whichever is greater. The total number of dwelling units shall be established at the time of the TND approval.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Neighborhood proper: The built-up area planned for development within a TND, including blocks, streets, squares greens and parks, but excluding greenbelts or other open green periphery areas.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Outbuilding: An accessory use building, for residential, parking, or storage use only, contiguous with the rear lot line, of a maximum of twenty-four (24) feet in height and having a maximum building footprint of five hundred (500) gross square feet.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Park: An area of land designated for active or passive recreation.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Pedestrian pathways: Pedestrian pathways are interconnecting paved walkways that provide pedestrian passage through blocks running from street to street. Said pathways shall not be less than ten (10) feet, nor more than twenty (20) feet in width, with a minimum pavement width of ten (10) feet. Pedestrian pathways shall provide an unobstructed view, from street to street, no less than ten (10) feet wide.</section><section prefix='(26)'>Plaza: An open space area within a town center on which all shopfront lots front. Plazas shall include landscaping, permanent architectural features and/or water oriented features. Parking may be included, but shall be limited to seventy-five percent (75%) of the total area of the plaza.</section><section prefix='(26a)'>Porte-cochere: A house use category feature consisting of a roofed structure attached to a building and erected over a driveway. It shall be open on three (3) sides and may have a part of the main or principal building over it.</section><section prefix='(27)'>Private open space: That space on each building lot that is for the private use of the inhabitants of such lot. Said space shall be unenclosed, and open to the sky except for roofed porches. Atriums, gardens, garden courts, walks, ramps, patios, and other similar spaces shall count as private open space. Up to one-third () of the private open space area may be a roofed porch.</section><section prefix='(28)'>Prohibited uses: The following uses are not permitted anywhere within a TND: Vending machines, including newspaper, except as an accessory use within a commercial building; detached signs; chemical manufacturing, storage or distribution as a primary use; gun shops, pawn shops, chicken hatcheries, packing houses, tire vulcanizing and retreading, automobile sales and rental, any commercial use in which patrons remain in their automobiles while receiving goods or services, except service stations; on-site enameling, painting or plating, of materials for off-site use, except artist's studios and as provided in the workshop land use category; outdoor advertising or billboard; terminal or yard used for the business of carting, moving, or hauling goods, except delivery of goods to businesses within a TND; prisons, or detention centers, except as accessory to police station; manufacture, storage or disposal of hazardous waste materials; scrap yards; mobile homes; sand, gravel, or other mineral extraction; kennels.</section><section prefix='(29)'>Residential use: The term residential is applied herein to any lot, plot, parcel, or piece of land or any building used for dwelling purposes.</section><section prefix='(30)'>Setback: An absolute distance between the building lot line and the outside of the facade closest to said building lot line of the enclosed portion of the building. Front porches and ramps for people with disabilities are exempt from setback requirements. On curvilinear lots only, the required front setback shall be measured at the closest point to the lot line and may exceed the required front setback along the curvilinear property line.</section><section prefix='(31)'>Shared parking: Any parking spaces intended to be utilized for more than one (1) use occurring on a single lot or within a single building, where persons utilizing the spaces are unlikely to need the spaces at the same time of day.</section><section prefix='(32)'>Square: An outdoor public tract defined by streets on at least three (3) sides. Squares shall be at least seventy-five percent (75%) paved and surrounded by shopfront use lots or rowhouse use lots on at least sixty percent (60%) of its perimeter (perimeter being defined as the aggregate of the frontage lines of the surrounding lots). Squares shall have a length to width ratio no greater than three to one (3:1).</section><section prefix='(33)'>Streetedge: A masonry wall, wood fence, or electrostatic plated black aluminum or wrought iron fence, no less than fifty percent (50%) opaque, or a hedge on thirty-inch centers, between two and one-half (2½) and four (4) feet in height, at time of planting positioned along the frontage line. Any wall, or fence built or hedge planted built between the frontage line and a point even with the nearest enclosed edge of the house shall not be of greater height than the streetedge.</section><section prefix='(34)'>Streetwall: A masonry or wood wall, or electrostatic plated black aluminum or wrought iron fence between six (6) feet and twelve (12) feet in height, no less than twenty-five percent (25%) and no more than fifty percent (50%) opaque, except for service yards which require no less than fifty percent (50%) opacity, built along the frontage line. Any openings shall be gated. The percent opacity shall be calculated including all openings.</section><section prefix='(35)'>Streetlamp: A light standard not to exceed fifteen (15) feet in height. Streetlamps shall be installed on both sides of streets at no more than seventy-five-foot intervals measured parallel to the street. Any streetlights in alleys shall be designed in accordance with the standards developed by the Illumination Engineering Society. The installation and maintenance of the street light system will be through a special taxing district. Street lighting design shall meet the minimum standards developed by the Illumination Engineering Society.</section><section prefix='(36)'>Street vista: A view through or along a street centerline.</section><section prefix='(37)'>Through street: A street constructed in accordance with major and minor roadways as depicted on the adopted comprehensive development land use plan map. A TND may be located adjacent to, but shall not be bisected by a through street.</section><section prefix='(38)'>Town center: A town center is an optional and accessory use to the TND providing for larger scale commercial shopfront uses in buildings that front a plaza. A portion of the town center plaza may be used for parking. The town center buildings shall surround the plaza on at least thirty-five percent (35%) of its perimeter. The town center shall meet all requirements of said shopfront use category, except as modified below, and all other requirements of the TND, including requirements for parking lots, if any part of the plaza is used for parking.<section>A maximum of seventy-five percent (75%) of the TND's allocation for shopfront use lots may be transferred to the town center. Any additional commercial area shall only be permitted where designated on CDMP, land use plan map.</section><section>A town center shall only be located where through streets or any street adjacent to the neighborhood proper intersect. There shall be no more than one (1) town center in a TND. Town center plazas shall extend no further than six hundred (600) feet along the through street from the centerline of the intersection and shall have a maximum area of fourteen hundred (1,400) square feet per TND acre in area to a maximum of two hundred thousand (200,000) square feet. There shall be a direct street connection between the mandatory square or green and the town center plaza. A minimum of thirty-five percent (35%) of the gross leasable building area (taken in sum) of the lots fronting the plaza shall be for residential use. A maximum of four (4) lots fronting the town center plaza may be consolidated. Colonnades are required on all shopfront use buildings fronting the town center plaza. At least ten percent (10%) of the plaza shall be devoid of parking and developed with permanent architectural and/or water features as a focal point for the town center. Said focal point shall be in addition to other landscape requirements as provided in the TND. Town centers may include, in addition to uses provided in the shopfront use category, one (1) grocery and/or department store use, each not exceeding forty thousand (40,000) square feet of building area.</section></section><section prefix='(39)'>Warranted traffic control device: A device (typically a yield or stop sign, or a traffic signal) that has met the minimum criteria for installation based on the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices; National Manual, 1988 Edition.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-41, § 1, 4-2-91; Ord. No. 99-26, § 1, 5-4-99; Ord. No. 99-82, § 1, 7-13-99; Ord. No. 03-47, § 2, 3-11-03; Ord. No. 11-83, § 1, 11-15-11)</history></law>