<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. AU, AGRICULTURAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Agricultural disclosure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004314</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.1. Agricultural disclosure.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Affected land for the purpose of this section means:<section prefix='a.'>Any parcel of land that is located outside of the Urban Development Boundary (UDB) delineated on the Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan Map and either designated Agriculture, zoned AU or zoned interim (GU) and determined by the director to be subject to an agricultural (AU) trend of development pursuant to Section 33-196, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida; or</section><section prefix='b.'>Any parcel of land that is located inside the UDB and designated Agriculture, or zoned AU, or abutting any AU zoned parcel.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Interest in real property means a nonleasehold, legal or equitable estate in land or any severable part thereof created by deed, contract, mortgage, easement, covenant or other instrument.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Purchaser means a buyer, transferee, grantee, donee or other party acquiring an interest in real property.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Real property transaction means the sale, grant, conveyance, mortgage or transfer of an interest in real property.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Seller means a transferor, grantor, donor [or] other party conveying an interest in real property.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Disclosure statement for real property transactions involving Affected land. The seller shall provide the purchaser with the following statement, which shall be set forth on a separate sheet of paper and shall be signed by the prospective purchaser prior to the execution of any other instrument committing the purchaser to acquire title to such real property or any other interest in any Affected land, as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For all Affected land, the statement shall include the following language:<section>LAND INVOLVED IN THIS TRANSACTION IS ZONED AGRICULTURAL (AU) OR LIES ADJACENT TO LAND THAT IS ZONED AU, OR IS DESIGNATED FOR AGRICULTURAL USE BY THE MIAMI-DADE COUNTY COMPREHENSIVE DEVELOPMENT MASTER PLAN (CDMP), OR IS SUBJECT TO AU REGULATIONS.</section><section>AGRICULTURAL ACTIVITIES WHICH MAY BE LAWFULLY CONDUCTED WITHIN THIS AREA INCLUDE BUT MAY NOT BE LIMITED TO CULTIVATION AND HARVESTING OF CROPS; PROCESSING AND PACKING OF FRUIT AND VEGETABLES; BREEDING OF LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY; OPERATION OF IRRIGATION PUMPS AND OTHER MACHINERY; GROUND OR AERIAL SEEDING OR SPRAYING; APPLICATION OF CHEMICAL FERTILIZERS, CONDITIONERS, PESTICIDES AND HERBICIDES; GENERATION OF TRACTOR AND TRUCK TRAFFIC AND OF NOISE, ODORS, DUST AND FUMES ASSOCIATED WITH THE CONDUCT OF THE FOREGOING ACTIVITIES; AND THE EMPLOYMENT AND USE OF AGRICULTURAL LABOR. SUCH AGRICULTURAL ACTIVITIES MAY BE PROTECTED FROM NUISANCE SUITS BY THE "FLORIDA RIGHT TO FARM ACT," SECTION 823.14, FLORIDA STATUTES.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>In addition to the language set forth in Section 33-284.1(b)(1) the statement for all AU land not in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall include the following language:<section>Miami-Dade COUNTY ZONING REGULATIONS REQUIRE A MINIMUM OF TWO HUNDRED (200) FEET OF STREET FRONTAGE AND A MINIMUM OF FIVE (5) ACRES OF LAND AREA (INCLUDING RIGHT-OF-WAY DEDICATIONS) AS PREREQUISITES TO ANY USE OF AU LAND, INCLUDING DEVELOPMENT OF ANY SINGLE-FAMILY RESIDENCE THEREON.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>In addition to the language set forth in Section 33-284.1(b)(1) the statement for all AU land in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall include the following language:<section>AU LAND IN THE EAST EVERGLADES AREA OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN IS SUBJECT TO RESTRICTIONS LIMITING DENSITY TO NO GREATER THAN ONE (1) DWELLING UNIT PER FORTY (40) ACRES, OR UNDER CERTAIN CONDITIONS TO ONE (1) DWELLING UNIT PER TWENTY (20) ACRES, AS PROVIDED BY, CODE OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>In addition to the language set forth in Section 33-284.1(b)(1) the statement for all nonresidential AU land served or to be served by a septic tank shall include the following language:<section>ALL NONRESIDENTIAL AU LAND SERVED OR TO BE SERVED BY A SEPTIC TANK SHALL BE SUBJECT TO THE FOLLOWING PROVISIONS:</section><section>THE ONLY LIQUID WASTE (EXCLUDING LIQUID WASTES ASSOCIATED WITH THE PROCESSING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCE IN AGRICULTURAL PACKING HOUSES AND LIQUID WASTES ASSOCIATED WITH AGRICULTURAL VEHICLE OR AGRICULTURAL EQUIPMENT MAINTENANCE FACILITIES WHICH REPAIR OR MAINTAIN VEHICLES OR EQUIPMENT ANCILLARY TO AND DIRECTLY SUPPORTIVE OF A BONA FIDE AGRICULTURAL PURPOSE AND WHICH VEHICLE OR EQUIPMENT ARE OWNED OR OPERATED BY THE OWNER OR LESSEE OF THE AGRICULTURAL VEHICLE OR AGRICULTURAL EQUIPMENT MAINTENANCE FACILITY) WHICH SHALL BE GENERATED, DISPOSED OF, DISCHARGED, OR STORED ON THE PROPERTY SHALL BE DOMESTIC SEWAGE DISCHARGED INTO A SEPTIC TANK.</section><section>NON DOMESTIC WASTE, INCLUDING WASTE RESULTING FROM AN AGRICULTURAL VEHICLE OR AGRICULTURAL EQUIPMENT MAINTENANCE FACILITY SHALL NOT BE DISCHARGED TO A SEPTIC TANK AND MUST BE DISPOSED OF IN ACCORDANCE WITH APPLICABLE REGULATIONS.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>For all AU land, the statement shall conclude with the following language:<section>THE ZONING CODE OF Miami-Dade COUNTY ENUMERATES CERTAIN EXCEPTIONS WHERE SMALLER COUNTY LOT SIZES ARE PERMITTED. IF THE LAND WHICH IS THE SUBJECT OF THIS TRANSACTION DOES NOT QUALIFY FOR AN EXCEPTION, AND DOES NOT MEET BOTH THE LOT FRONTAGE AND AREA REQUIREMENTS NOTED ABOVE, NO SINGLE-FAMILY RESIDENTIAL USE OR ANY OTHER USE OF THE PROPERTY MAY BE PERMITTED UNLESS FIRST APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC HEARING.</section><section>I HEREBY CERTIFY THAT I HAVE READ AND UNDERSTAND THE FOREGOING STATEMENT.</section><section>   </section><section>Signature of Purchaser   Date</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Acknowledgment of agricultural disclosure statement on instrument of conveyance. It shall be the seller's responsibility that the following statement shall appear in a prominent location on the face of any instrument conveying title to or any other interest in Affected land. The seller shall record the notarized statement with the Clerk of the Court:<section>I HEREBY CERTIFY THAT I HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND AND HAVE SIGNED THE AGRICULTURAL DISCLOSURE STATEMENT FOR THE SALE OF OR OTHER TRANSACTION INVOLVING THIS PARCEL OF AFFECTED LAND AS REQUIRED BY, CODE OF Miami-Dade COUNTY, FLORIDA.</section><section>    </section><section>Signature of Purchaser    Date</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Penalties. Any seller who violates any provision of this section, or fails to comply therewith, or with any lawful rule, regulation or written order promulgated under this section, shall be subject to the penalties, civil liability, attorney's fees and enforcement proceedings set forth in Sections 33-39 through 33-39.3, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and to such other penalties, sanctions and proceedings as may be provided by law. Miami-Dade County shall not be held liable for any damages or claims resulting from the seller's failure to comply with provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Exceptions. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, real property that is zoned AU (agriculture) or that is zoned GU (interim) and determined by the Director to be subject to an agricultural trend of development, and which property or property interest is being transferred to the South Florida Water Management District, shall be exempt from all disclosure requirements pertaining to AU land.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-162, § 2, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 97-89, § 1, 7-17-97; Ord. No. 98-29, § 3, 2-19-98; Ord. No. 00-162, § 1, 12-7-00)</history></law>