<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(O). OJUS URBAN AREA DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.18</section_number>
<catch_line>The Regulating Plans.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004433</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.18. The Regulating Plans.<section>The Regulating Plans shall consist of the following controlling plans, as defined and graphically depicted in this section.<section prefix='A.'>The Street Types Plan, which establishes a hierarchy of street types in existing and future locations. The five Street Types and the hierarchy of streets (from most important to least important in accommodating all types of activity) are U.S. 1, Main Street, Boulevard, Minor Street, and Service Road.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Sub-districts Plan, which delineates 3 Sub-districts: Core, Center and Edge. These Sub-districts shall regulate the allowable intensity of development in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and this article.</section><section prefix='C.'>The Land Use Plan, which delineates the areas where specified land uses and development of various types and intensities shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='D.'>The Building Heights Plan, which establishes the minimum and maximum allowable number of stories.</section><section prefix='E.'>The Designated Open Space Plan, which designates open spaces. The designated open spaces shall be controlled by anchor points.</section><section prefix='F.'>The New Streets Plan, which shows the location and the number of new streets needed to create the prescribed network of streets within the Ojus Urban Area. All new A streets shall be required in the same general location as shown on the New Streets Plan. All B streets shall be located as provided in Section 33-284.86(F) of this code.</section><section prefix='G.'>The Bike Route Plan, which depicts the designated bike routes, including the bike facility requirements if any, which shall be shown in all development plans.<section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-86, ยง 5, 6-6-06; Ord. No. 07-94, ยง 3, 7-10-07)</history></law>