<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00047' order_by='00047' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIA. BIRD ROAD DESIGN AND INDUSTRIAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-278.7</section_number>
<catch_line>General requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004302</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-278.7. General requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Building Placement and Design Parameters. Each use shall comply with the building content, setback, area, height, and landscape requirements for the IU-1 zoning district set forth in Section 33-49 (Table of minimum widths, area of lots; maximum lot coverage, and minimum building sizes), Section 33-51 (Setbacks in business and industrial districts), Section 33-58 (Height of building limited to width of street in certain districts), and Section 33-261 (Minimum landscaped open space, greenbelts, trees, and maintenance).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Outdoor Display Areas. Products sold on the premises may be displayed against the front facade of the bay or building.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Parking.<section prefix='(1)'>For all uses except for banquet halls, bars, lounges, breweries, restaurants, and coffeehouses, parking shall be provided at a minimum of 1.25 parking spaces for each 1,600 square feet of gross floor area in the building, or fractional part thereof. Live-work units shall provide an additional 1.75 parking spaces per unit.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Parking for banquet halls, bars, lounges, breweries, restaurants, and coffeehouses shall be provided in accordance with Section 33-124 of this chapter. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if the required amount of parking is not available on the same lot, parcel, or premises as the banquet hall, bar, lounge, brewery, restaurant, or coffeehouse to be served, then parking may be provided on a lot or parcel of land that is in a BRDI, IU, or BU District and is within 300 feet from the site of the use to be served by submitting a covenant in accordance with Section 33-128(a) of this chapter. It is further provided that, if the availability of parking on the other lot or parcel is dependent on the hours of operation of the uses, then parking may be provided through such a covenant where the covenant specifies that the uses on the lot or parcel providing the parking are not in operation at the same time that the use to be served is in operation.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-71, ยง 1, 9-1-09)</history></law>