<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIV. BU-1, NEIGHBORHOOD BUSINESS DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-238</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004217</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-238. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water or structure shall be used or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed or structurally altered or maintained in any BU-1 District, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, except for one (1) or more of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>Residential uses may be permitted as a combination of permitted business uses and residential uses housed in the same building; the floor area of the residential use shall not exceed fifty (50) percent of the floor area of the building.</section><section prefix='(1.1)'>Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of this section and Article XIIA of this code.</section><section prefix='(1.2)'>Allied health care clinical colleges/universities.</section><section prefix='(1.3)'>Adult day care center.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Antique shops.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Apparel stores selling new and/or used merchandise, provided such establishments offering used merchandise contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of gross floor area. The incidental sales of used jewelry, used toys, and used furniture shall be permitted in conjunction with the sales of used apparel, provided that the floor area devoted to the display of those incidental sales items does not exceed thirty (30) percent of the total gross floor area of the apparel store.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Art good stores, artist studios and photograph shops and galleries.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Attended, nonmotorized donation collection vehicles as described in Section 33-19; provided, however, that such attended non-motorized donation collection vehicles are placed only on improved property on sites of not less than one-half acre in size, in compliance with required setbacks, and not in required landscape areas or required parking areas and not in an area which would impede traffic circulation. It is further provided, that no attended non-motorized donation collection vehicle shall be placed within twenty-six hundred (2600) feet of another non-motorized donation collection vehicle; the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest property line where the proposed attended, non-motorized donation collection vehicle is to be located to the nearest property line of an existing attended, non-motorized donation collection vehicle. Notwithstanding any ordinance, resolution or administrative order to the contrary no fee shall be charged for the issuance of a certificate of use and occupancy.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Banks, excluding drive-in teller service.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Beauty parlors.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Bakeries, retail only (baking permitted on premises).</section><section prefix='(9)'>Barber shops.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Bicycle sales, rentals and repairs (nonmotorized).</section><section prefix='(10.1)'>Computer, video, videogame and DVD stores, including the retail sale or rental of new hardware, software, players, videotapes and videogames, consoles, and related computer, video, videogame and DVD products, and the ancillary resale or exchange of pre-played computer, video, videogame and DVD products, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Confectionery, ice cream stores and dairy stores.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Conservatories and music and dance schools, provided no such establishment is located within five hundred (500) feet of any RU, or EU District except after approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Dairy stores.</section><section prefix='(13.5)'>Drugstores.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Donated goods centers for the acceptance only of new or used merchandise, upon compliance with the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The portion of the donated goods center which is open to the public shall not exceed 2000 square feet;</section><section prefix='(b)'>A solid wall shall separate the public area of the donated goods center from the balance of the said center and shall prevent public access to the balance of said center;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The donated goods center must be operated by an organization which has been incorporated as a not-for-profit organization under the laws of the State of Florida for a charitable purpose and which has been declared exempt from the payment of federal income taxes by the United States Internal Revenue Service;</section><section prefix='(d)'>The donated goods must be accepted by personnel directly employed by or volunteers for the not-for-profit organization;</section><section prefix='(e)'>The monetary proceeds resulting from the sale of donations collected at a donated goods center must be used in accordance with the organization's charitable purpose pursuant to Section 33-238(14)(c) to benefit persons within the boundaries of Miami-Dade County or outside of Miami-Dade County to provide emergency relief for victims of natural, manmade or economic disasters;</section><section prefix='(f)'>The operation of the donated goods center, the collection and use of donations and proceeds thereof must be conducted by said not-for-profit organization and not by a licensee, subcontractor or agent of the not-for-profit organization;</section><section prefix='(g)'>A declaration of use in a form meeting with the approval of the Director shall be submitted to the Department prior to the issuance of a certificate of use and occupancy specifying compliance with the foregoing conditions. Said declaration of use shall include a floor plan for the intended use as required by the Department.</section></section><section prefix='(15)'>Florist shops.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Grocery stores, fruit stores, health food stores, delicatessen, meat and fish markets and other similar food stores, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Hardware stores.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Information booth, gate house and security station. The structure housing these uses shall comply with principal building setback requirements but need not comply with any minimum square foot requirements for the districts.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Interior design shops, office and display only.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Jewelry stores, including incidental sales and purchases of used jewelry.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Leather goods and luggage shops.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Mail order offices, without storage of products sold.</section><section prefix='(22.1)'>Museum.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Newsstand.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Office buildings.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Optical stores.</section><section prefix='(25.1)'>Outdoor dining as an ancillary use in conjunction with restaurants, snack shops and other food service facilities where the primary use is the preparation of food for consumption on premises shall be permitted, subject to the following restrictions:<section prefix='(a)'>The outdoor dining area shall be managed, operated and maintained as an integral part of the immediately adjacent food service facility; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>The outdoor dining area shall not reduce required parking or landscaping for the site; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>The outdoor seating area shall be included in the calculations for required parking; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>There shall be no outdoor cooking or food preparation; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>No outdoor dining area shall obstruct or impede pedestrian traffic; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>The outdoor dining area shall comply with handicapped accessibility requirements; and</section><section prefix='(g)'>No outside public address system shall be permitted. Unamplified music shall be permitted in the outdoor dining area, subject to compliance with Section 21-28 of this Code; and</section><section prefix='(h)'>Blinking and flashing type lighting shall be prohibited; and</section><section prefix='(i)'>Alcoholic beverages may be served where such service is strictly incidental to the service of food and is from a service bar only, subject to compliance with the regulations specified in Article X (Alcoholic Beverages) of this chapter; and</section><section prefix='(j)'>The use shall be subject to plan review and approval through the building permit review process. The plans for such use shall include all restrooms, furniture, umbrellas, lighting, and other related services and functions associated with the proposed use, together with all required and provided parking calculations. Plans shall be subject to all the applicable building and zoning code regulations; and</section><section prefix='(k)'>The use shall require a Certificate of Use which shall be renewed annually and shall be subject to revocation upon violation of any applicable building and zoning code regulations, or when a continuation of the permit would constitute a hazard or nuisance.</section></section><section prefix='(26)'>Paint and wallpaper stores.</section><section prefix='(27)'>Photograph galleries.</section><section prefix='(28)'>Pottery shops.</section><section prefix='(29)'>Restaurants and coffee houses or dining room where kitchen is screened or located altogether within an enclosed building or room and with ample provisions for carrying away or dissipating fumes, odors, smoke or noise and where premises are so arranged and the business is so conducted as not to be offensive or obnoxious to occupants of adjoining premises or to passersby. Restaurants and outdoor (where approved by public hearing) cafes may serve alcoholic beverages where such service is strictly incidental to the service of food and from a service bar only provided no entertainment of any kind is furnished. No sign of any type or character shall be exhibited or displayed to the outside denoting that alcoholic beverages are obtainable within.</section><section prefix='(29.1)'>Religious facilities located inside the Urban Development Boundary. Religious facilities outside the Urban Development Boundary will be permitted only upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(30)'>Schools, subject to compliance with the requirements of Sections 33-151.11 through 33-151.22 of this code.</section><section prefix='(31)'>Self-service post office which contains mechanical or computer equipment designed to provide limited postal service for walk-up trade.</section><section prefix='(32)'>Shoe stores and shoe repair shops.</section><section prefix='(33)'>Sporting goods stores.</section><section prefix='(34)'>Tailor shops, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.</section><section prefix='(35)'>Tobacco shops.</section><section prefix='(36)'>Variety stores, provided such establishments contain not more than four thousand (4,000) square feet of floor area.</section><section prefix='(37)'>Any property in a BU District may be used as access for egress and ingress only to property zoned in any BU classification or in any IU classification provided that both properties are under the same ownership.</section><section prefix='(38)'>Outside walk-up window service (no outside stools, chairs or tables), in connection with establishments where the principal use is selling food and drink products, and where a sidewalk of at least seven (7) feet in width abuts the store unit concerned.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-22, § 1, 4-16-74; Ord. No. 76-45, § 1, 5-18-76; Ord. No. 77-60, § 2, 9-6-77; Ord. No. 77-69, § 2, 9-20-77; Ord. No. 92-144, § 1, 11-17-92; Ord. No. 95-80, § 1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-123, § 1, 7-11-95; Ord. No. 96-129, § 1, 9-10-96; Ord. No. 97-13, § 1, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 98-46, § 1, 4-21-98; Ord. No. 99-99, § 2, 9-9-99; Ord. No. 02-46, § 5, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 02-123, § 1, 7-9-02; Ord. No. 07-05, § 17, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 09-47, § 2, 6-2-09; Ord. No. 10-08, § 3, 2-2-10; Ord. No. 11-04, § 5, 2-1-11)</history></law>