<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. AU, AGRICULTURAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-279.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Agricultural Uses Permitted in Open Land Subareas Areas 1 and 4 of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP).</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004306</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-279.1. Agricultural Uses Permitted in Open Land Subareas Areas 1 and 4 of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP).<section>Notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary in or of this Code, the agricultural uses provided in this Section are permissible in areas zoned AU or GU with an AU trend in the Open Land Subareas 1 and 4, as designated in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, to the extent such uses are permissible under of this Code. No additional agricultural uses shall be permitted in these areas.</section><section>The CDMP acknowledges that the lands within these Subareas have special hydrologic conditions and are prone to flooding, and these lands are subject to wetlands regulation (where applicable) and stormwater management regulation pursuant to and floodplain regulations pursuant to of this Code.</section><section>The County does not provide flood protection for properties in these areas, nor does the County have plans to provide flood protection in the future. Property owners should consider the risks of flooding in these areas.<section prefix='(a)'>Residential uses are only permitted to the extent otherwise allowed under this Code. This Section does not provide any additional residential uses.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The following uses are permissible, to the extent that such uses are permissible under Section 33-279 of this Code:<section prefix='a.'>Barns and sheds for cattle or stock.</section><section prefix='b.'>Barns and sheds for storage of equipment.</section><section prefix='c.'>Beekeeping.</section><section prefix='d.'>Farms.</section><section prefix='e.'>Fish pools.</section><section prefix='f.'>Fruit and vegetable stands.</section><section prefix='g.'>Groves.</section><section prefix='h.'>Greenhouses or nurseries, commercial.</section><section prefix='i.'>Horticultural farming, commercial.</section><section prefix='j.'>Hydroponics or other chemical farming.</section><section prefix='k.'>Nurseries, horticultural.</section><section prefix='l.'>Seed drying facilities.</section><section prefix='m.'>Truck gardens.</section><section prefix='n.'>Raising or keeping of 2 hogs per site.</section><section prefix='o.'>Raising or keeping of 2 of any of the following per acre: cows, horses or other equine animals.</section><section prefix='p.'>Raising or keeping of 3 of any of the following per acre: goats or sheep.</section><section prefix='q.'>Raising or keeping of 40 of any of the following per acre: chickens, poultry or fowl.</section><section prefix='r.'>Raising or keeping of 40 rabbits per acre.</section><section prefix='s.'>Raising or keeping of cows, horses or other equine animals, goats, sheep, chickens, poultry, rabbits or fowl in excess of any of the above thresholds, only upon issuance of a Certificate of Use (CU) for the property where the uses are to be conducted, subject to site plan approval by the Department. The site plan shall indicate, at a minimum, onsite stormwater retention and waste stream management.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The following uses are permissible only upon approval after public hearing, as provided in Section 33-279 of this Code, and for floodplain management purposes, the application package must include a site plan which indicates 1) existing and proposed locations of structures, fences or buffers; 2) onsite stormwater retention; and 3) waste stream management.<section prefix='a.'>Dude ranch.</section><section prefix='b.'>Hog farm or hog raising, except for the raising of 2 hogs.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-59, ยง 2, 8-2-11)</history></law>