<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. RU-3, FOUR UNIT APARTMENT HOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-203</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004136</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-203. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water and/or structure shall be used or permitted to be used and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, or moved or structurally altered or maintained for any purpose in an RU-3 District, unless otherwise provided herein, excepting for one (1) or more of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>Every use permitted in RU-1, RU-1M(a), RU-1M(b) and RU-2 Districts.</section><section prefix='(1.1)'>Workforce housing units in compliance with the provisions of Article XIIA of this code.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Rooming houses.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Day nurseries serving the adjacent neighborhood.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Garage apartments.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Churches, schools, colleges and universities, including dormitories.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Not more than four (4) families shall occupy a building in an RU-3 District.</section><section prefix='(6.1)'>Multiple family housing developments. Multiple family housing developments on sites zoned RU-3 prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall be permitted only after staff review of the site plan to insure compliance with (i) the following, and (ii) with the site plan review criteria contained within Section 33-203.7 of this code, except that interior side setbacks and spacing requirements shall not apply.<section prefix='(a)'>Housing types and building facades. The development shall contain either a minimum of 3 housing types, or where a single housing type is proposed, the model plans shall include a minimum of 4 different building facades.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Minimum lot area. The minimum size of the site to be developed shall be 2 net acres.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Lot coverage. The maximum area covered by all buildings on the site shall be 30% of the site, including accessory buildings.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Setback requirements. The setbacks shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Minimum setback from front property line shall be 25 feet.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Minimum setback from interior side property line shall be 20 feet.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Minimum setback from side street property line shall be 25 feet.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Minimum setback from rear property line shall be 25 feet.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Minimum spacing between buildings shall be 20 feet, except where doors, windows or other openings in the building wall of a living unit face a wall of the same building or a wall of another building on the same site, then there shall be provided a minimum clear distance of not less than 30 feet. Said distance shall be measured on a line projected at right angles at the opening to the opposite wall. Cantilevers and open porches may project from the building wall into the required open space of the courtyard only not more than 4 feet and that stairways may project from the building wall in to the required open space of the courtyard only not more than 7½ feet. When located in the required open space of the courtyard, stairways shall be supported by the necessary columns only; support by a wall is strictly prohibited.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Minimum setbacks for accessory buildings shall conform to the same requirements as provided for accessory buildings in the RU-1 District.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Height. No building or structure, or part thereof shall be erected or altered to a height exceeding 3 stories, and shall not exceed 40 feet.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Floor area ration (FAR). The floor area ratio shall not exceed the following:</section><section prefix='(g)'>Maximum number of dwelling units. The maximum number of dwelling units shall be 23 dwelling units per net acre.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Open space. On each site there shall be provided an open space equal to at least 25 percent of the net lot area; said space shall be unencumbered with any structure or off-street parking and shall be landscaped and well maintained with grass, trees and shrubbery. Areas used as (i) pedestrian walks and (ii) the throat of ingress and egress drives consisting of the first 25 feet of said ingress and egress drives shall be accredited towards open space requirements.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Parking. Parking shall be provided in accord with Article VII of this code. Attached individual garages shall not be credited towards parking requirements. Accessory structures shown on the plan as covered parking areas shall not be enclosed for nonparking purposes. This requirement shall be acknowledged in the form of a recordable declaration of restrictive covenant which shall be provided for each multiple family housing development constructed in accordance with the provisions of the subsection.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Trees. Landscaping and trees shall meet or exceed the minimum requirements provided in Chapter 18A of this code.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Enclosed community prohibited. The walling off of the community from arterial roadways shall be prohibited. Entrance features which control ingress and egress shall be prohibited. Relief from this requirement may only be permitted pursuant to the standards and requirements of Section 33-311(A)(4)(a) of this code.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Community residential home. A community residential facility as defined in Section 33-1(30.1) shall be permitted in a dwelling unit upon establishing the following:<section prefix='(a)'>That the total number of resident clients on the premises not exceed fourteen (14) in number. Facilities for more than fourteen (14) resident clients must be approved through public hearing pursuant to Section 33-13</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the operation of the community residential home be licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services;</section><section prefix='(c)'>That the community residential home not be located within a radius of one thousand two hundred (1,200) feet of another existing, unabandoned legally established community residential home in a multi-family zone. The one thousand two hundred-foot distance requirement shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest portion of the structure of the proposed use to the nearest portion of the structure of the existing use;</section><section prefix='(d)'>That the community residential home conform to existing zoning regulations applicable to other multiple family uses permitted by this section;</section><section prefix='(e)'>That the sponsoring agency of the community residential home notify the Director in writing of its intention to establish and facility. Such notice shall contain the address and legal description of the site, the number of resident clients, as well as a statement from the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services indicating the need for and licensing status of the proposed facility. Absence of this notification and statement shall prohibit the use and occupancy of any structure for use as a community residential home; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>Nothing in this section shall permit persons to occupy a community residential home who would constitute a direct threat to the health and safety of other persons or whose residency would result in the substantial physical damage to the property of others.</section></section></section><section>All uses listed above shall conform to all the requirements listed in the applicable sections that apply to the four-unit apartment building, except that RU-1 and RU-2 standards shall apply to RU-1 and RU-2 uses, and except that schools, churches, colleges and universities, including dormitories shall conform to the setback requirements of the section on buildings for public assemblage, and further provided that day nurseries, private schools, private colleges and universities shall comply with the requirements of sections through of this code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 10, 10-22-57; Ord. No. 91-51, § 4, 5-7-91; Ord. No. 91-81, § 1, 7-23-91; Ord. No. 95-135, § 11, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 02-46, § 4, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 05-189, § 1, 11-3-05(3); Ord. No. 07-05, § 6, 1-25-07; Ord. No. 08-51, § 1, 5-6-08)</history></law>