<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='3'>ARTICLE XXVI. BU-2, SPECIAL BUSINESS DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-253</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004239</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-253. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water and/or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved, occupied or maintained for any purpose in any BU-2 District except for one (1) or more of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>All uses permitted in the BU-1 and BU-1A Districts except that residential uses are subject to approval at a public hearing.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Automobile parking lots and garages as a primary use. Automobile parking garages, not over six (6) stories in height, shall be permitted provided they are not located closer than two hundred (200) feet to an RU-1, RU-2, RU-TH or EU District or to a hospital, church or building used for public assemblage. Automobile parking garages shall meet all open space, lot coverage and other applicable requirements of this article. Parking lots shall comply with all applicable off-street parking requirements as set forth in Article VII of this chapter and all applicable landscaping requirements as set forth in Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(2.05)'>Commuter Colleges/Universities.</section><section prefix='(2.1)'>Hospitals (other than animal hospitals), subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That such uses shall be on sites of at least ten (10) net acres;</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the facility shall have capacity for a minimum of one hundred (100) beds.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The certificate of use for the hospital shall be annually renewed.</section><section prefix='(d)'>That the hospital operates a 24 hour emergency room.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-253.3 of this Code, the net lot coverage permitted for all buildings on the site shall not exceed 50% of the total lot area; the floor area ratio shall be fifty one-hundredths (0.50) at one (1) story and shall be increased by fourteen-one hundredths (0.14) for each additional story up to eight (8) stories, and thereafter the floor area ratio shall be increased by six-one-hundredths (0.06) for each additional story. Structured parking shall not count as part of the floor area, but shall be counted in computing building height and number of stories. Enclosed or nonenclosed mall areas shall not count as part of the floor area, for floor area ratio computation purposes, nor as part of the lot coverage.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-253.4 of this Code, the minimum landscaped open space at one (1) story shall be fourteen percent (14%).<section>The minimum landscaped open space shall be increased by one (1) percent for each additional story or part thereof, up to eight (8) stories, thereafter the landscaped open space shall increase by two (2) percent for each additional story or part thereof. For the purpose of computing the amount of required landscaped space where the building height varies, the number of stories shall be equal to the sum of the products of the number of stories of each part of the building(s) of a different height times its floor area divided by the sum of the floor area of all parts of the building(s). Said open space shall be extensively landscaped with grass, trees and shrubbery. Water areas may be used as part of the required landscaped open space provided such water areas do not exceed twenty (20) percent of the required landscaped open space. The specific areas within enclosed or nonenclosed malls which are landscaped with grass, trees and/or shrubbery, water areas therein, and areas therein with permanent art display may be used as part of the required landscaped open space provided such areas do not exceed ten (10) percent of the required landscaped open space. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with of this Code.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>That such uses shall be located within sites having frontage on a major access road, including major roadways (three (3) or more lanes), section or half section line roads and/or frontage roadways serving limited access highways and expressways.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The site shall meet and comply with the provisions of Section 33-253.7 of this Code, except that the wall may be penetrated at points approved by the Directors of the Planning and Zoning Department and the Public Works Department for ingress and egress to afford pedestrian or vehicular access between the sites, and if the property where the facility is located is separated from the AU, GU, RU or EU zoned property by a canal or a previously existing, dedicated and improved roadway, then a wall shall not be required on that portion of the property which is separated by the canal or roadway.</section></section><section prefix='(2.2)'>Hotel and motel uses, subject to all provisions of the RU-4A District pertaining to such uses.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Liquor package stores.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Major department stores.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Marinas for the following purposes only: Commercial boat piers or slips for docking purposes; yacht or boat storage, for laying up, but not for repairs or overhaul; and boats carrying passengers on excursion, sightseeing, pleasure or fishing trips.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Night clubs located no closer than five hundred (500) feet of any RU or EU District, if approved at a public hearing.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Office parks.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Pubs and bars.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Regional shopping centers.</section><section prefix='(9.5)'>Vehicle Retail Showroom, provided that:<section prefix='(1)'>No on-site vehicle storage/stock beyond the showroom is allowed; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>No more than six (6) vehicles on site to be used for test drives purposes; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>No test drive shall be conducted on residential local streets (fifty-foot wide rights-of-way); and</section><section prefix='(4)'>No new, purchased vehicle deliveries at showroom are allowed.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Warehouse, membership.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-24, § 1, 4-16-74; Ord. No. 96-129, § 1, 9-10-96; Ord. No. 03-129, § 1, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 06-33, § 1, 3-7-06; Ord. No. 09-102, § 3, 11-17-09; Ord. No. 13-15, § 1, 2-5-13; Ord. No. 13-40, § 1, 5-7-13; Ord. No. 13-82, § 2, 9-17-13)</history></law>