<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00049' order_by='00049' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIA. CLUSTERED DEVELOPMENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.9.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Site plan review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004320</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.9.1. Site plan review.<section>Cluster developments shall be reviewed by the Department for compliance with all applicable requirements, including the site plan review exhibits and criteria hereinafter provided. The recommendation of the Department shall be transmitted to the Community Zoning Appeals Board for their consideration. If after approval of the site plan review exhibits a substantial change therein is desired, application may be filed as a special exception with the Community Zoning Appeals Board to modify or change such exhibits, all in accordance with this article and Article XXXVI of of this Code.</section><section>In approving a development plan, the Community Zoning Appeals Board may, by special exception, vary, amend or modify the following otherwise applicable zoning district regulations and/or subdivision regulations in order to effectuate the plan, provided the elements affected by such special exceptions are specifically noted upon the site plan review exhibits and provided the same are in harmony with the general purpose and intent thereof:<section>Lot area, width and depth.</section><section>Street frontage.</section><section>Setbacks.</section><section>Structure height and cubic content.</section><section>Sidewalks.</section><section>Street rights-of-way and improvements.</section><section>Off-street parking location and improvements.</section><section>Walls and fences, including their height.</section><section>Lot coverage of principal and accessory buildings.</section><section>Spacing between buildings, including attachment of units.</section></section><section>Exhibits which the applicant shall submit to the Department of Planning and Zoning shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Aerial photograph or map indicating site and development in the immediate area within at least five hundred (500) feet of the site at no less than one (1) inch equals three hundred (300) feet (one (1) copy only).</section><section prefix='(2)'>A location map indicating existing zoning on the site and adjacent areas within at least five hundred (500) feet of the site at no less than one (1) inch equals three hundred (300) feet.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Site plan at no less than one (1) inch equals one hundred (100) feet, with a typical section at one (1) inch equals sixty (60) feet, including the following information:<section prefix='(a)'>Lot lines.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Location, shape, size and height of existing and proposed buildings, decorative walls and elements and entrance features.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Landscaping in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Recreation facilities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Fire lanes.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Stages of development, if any.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Floor plans, section and elevations of all the different proposed buildings including all typical dwelling units at no less than one (1) inch equals sixteen (16) feet [and] including the following information:<section prefix='(a)'>Location, shape, size and height of all enclosed and unenclosed spaces within the proposed buildings.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Design of the outdoor surfaces of the proposed buildings.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Models or three-dimensional drawings of typical portions of the proposed development. Perspectives may be provided as three-dimensional drawings.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Figures indicating the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Gross and net acreage.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Net density.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Building heights.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Amounts and percentages of the different categories of common open space.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Number of parking spaces required and provided. If the development is proposed to be developed in stages, all the above figures shall be indicated for each stage. In addition, the method(s) used to determine all the above shall be clearly demonstrated.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Proposed alternatives, modifications and/or additions to the design of the common facilities and/or to the design of the individual dwelling units may be indicated where appropriate in the above exhibits, such as enclosed or nonenclosed spaces, walks, fences, patios and/or swimming pools.</section></section><section>The following criteria shall be utilized in the site plan review process:<section prefix='(1)'>Purpose and intent. The proposed development fulfills the purpose and intent of this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Studies. Design studies, planning studies and/or neighborhood area studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the plan review process.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Clustering. The major site planning elements, buildings, open space, both common and private, and automobile areas including roads and parking shall be so arranged as to group the dwelling units into physically definable clusters.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Buffers. Architectural and landscape elements that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Exterior spatial relationships. The three-dimensional airspace created by the arrangement of structures and landscape shall produce spatial relationships that function with the intended use and occupancy of the project and are compatible with the development or zoning in the adjoining area. Spacing between buildings shall provide ample access for emergency equipment.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Scale. Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses or shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Circulation. Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Parking areas. Parking areas shall be so designed as to appropriately relate to the development, its environs, and adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Storage areas for boats and trailers. Storage areas for boats and trailers, when provided, shall be screened and so designed as to appropriately relate to the development, its environs and adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Trash containers. Trash containers shall be screened and so designed as to be conveniently accessible to their users.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Landscape. Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, enhance architectural features, relate the design of the structure to the site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by major roadways and intense-use areas.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Common open space. Common open spaces shall be provided, appropriate to the needs of the particular type of development. Common open space shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible, shall be so located and developed as to be accessible by all residents of the development, and clearly define the physical structuring of the units.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Private open space. Open space intended for the private use of each individual dwelling unit should be so located and designed as to maximize its utility to the dwelling unit it serves and maximize its privacy, especially in relation to adjacent dwelling units.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Privacy. Aural and visual privacy shall be considered in the design of the development.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Subtropic architectural characteristics. Site design and building design should incorporate consideration of the subtropical characteristics of the area. The provision of sun control devices, shaded areas, vegetation, roof terraces and similar features characteristic of subtropical design shall be encouraged.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Energy conservation. The design of the site and buildings shall be such as to reduce energy consumption. Energy conservation methods may include, but not be limited to, siting of structures in relation to sun angles and wind direction, natural ventilation of structures, provision of shading devices including landscaping and insulation of structures.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Visual screening for decorative walls. In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:<section prefix='(a)'>Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:<section prefix='(1)'>Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-43, § 2, 7-5-78; Ord. No. 95-19, § 17, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 23, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-38, § 18, 4-27-99)</history></law>