<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(M). PRINCETON COMMUNITY CENTER URBAN DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.98</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose, intent and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004414</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.98 Purpose, intent and applicability.<section prefix='A.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Illustrative Master Plan (Figure 1), illustrates the citizens' vision and may be used to interpret this article. Where the Illustrative Master Plan conflicts with the text of this article, the text shall govern.</section><section prefix='C.'>The boundaries shown in Figure 1 shall constitute the Princeton Community Urban Center Boundary Plan and are generally described as follows: from the northwest corner of the intersection of SW 256 Street and SW 127 Avenue, then north along the west side of SW 127 Avenue to the south side of SW 240 Street, then west along the south side of SW 240 Street to the Urban Development Boundary (UDB) line, as of the effective date of this ordinance, then south, east and west along the UDB to the north side of SW 256 Street, then east along the north side of SW 256 Street to the west side of SW 127 Avenue. The exact location of the UDB line as of the effective date of this ordinance (July 17, 2005) is on file with the Department of Planning and Zoning. An approximate delineation of the UDB line is depicted in the Illustrative Master Plan and in the Regulating Plans.</section><section>A more detailed legal description of the boundaries follows:<section>Beginning at the centerline of the intersection of SW 127th Avenue and SW 256th Street of section 26-56-39, thence North, along the centerline of SW 127th avenue to the intersection with the centerline of SW 240th Street, thence west along the centerline of SW 240 Street to the intersection with the centerline of SW 137 AVE the (UDB). Thence continue west along the centerline of SW 240 Street for 542' + to a point (theoretical UDB). Thence on an assumed bearing S00-44-41W for 1440' + to a point. Thence N89-26-32E for 542' + to the centerline of SW 137 AVE. Thence south along the centerline of SE 137 AVE to the intersection with the centerline of SW 248 Street. Thence west along centerline of SW 248 Street to the intersection with the centerline of SW 139 AVE. Thence south along the centerline of SW 139 AVE to the intersection with the centerline of SW 252 Street. Thence west along the centerline of SW 252 Street to the intersection with the centerline of SW 142 AVE. Thence on an assumed bearing S41-03-51W for approximately 1737' + to the centerline of the intersection of SW 256 Street. Thence east along the centerline of SW 256 Street for 1563' + to the intersection with the Centerline of Packing House Road. Thence on an assumed bearing S50-44-50E for approximately 371.65' + to the centerline of State Hwy # 5. Thence NE/ly along the centerline of the State HWY # 5 for 334.99 + to a point. Thence east for 427.30 + to the centerline of SW 139 Ave. Thence east along the centerline of SW 256 ST to the point of beginning. (The intersection with the centerline of SW 127 AVE).</section></section><section prefix='D.'>Full scale maps of the Illustrative Master Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='E.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the Princeton Community Urban Center District (PCUC) as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the PCUC shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to PCUC has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.<section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-146, ยง 1, 7-7-05)</history></law>