<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-20.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Permanently installed generators.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003911</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-20.1. Permanently installed generators.<section>A permanent generator installation shall be permitted as an ancillary use in all zoning districts, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>Setbacks for permanent generators. In those zoning districts permitting accessory buildings, compliance with accessory building rear, interior side and side street setbacks shall be required for a permanent generator. The front setback shall be behind the front building line of the principal building. There shall be no spacing requirements from the principal building to the generator.<section>In those zoning districts not permitting accessory buildings, the permanent generator shall comply with principal building setbacks, except that there shall be no spacing requirement from the principal building to the generator.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Setback exception for certain residential districts. Permanently installed generators fueled by propane gas or natural gas not exceeding five (5) feet in height from finished grade to the top of the generator shall be permitted as an accessory use in conjunction with a permitted residential use in accordance with the following setback requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Front—behind the front building line</section><section prefix='(2)'>Rear—five (5) feet</section><section prefix='(3)'>Interior side—three (3) feet in RU districts; five (5) feet in EU, AU and GU districts</section><section prefix='(4)'>Side street—behind the side street building line, unless completely screened from view by a wall or hedge. In no event shall a permanently installed generator be placed closer than ten (10) feet to the side street property line.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Spacing—there shall be no spacing requirement between the principal building and the permanently installed generator.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Number permitted in residential districts. A maximum of one permanent generator shall be permitted as an ancillary use to a single-family residence, duplex unit or townhouse unit. A maximum of one generator per structure shall be permitted for multi-family developments, with the exception of condominium units, which shall be permitted one permanent generator per condominium unit.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In all residential districts, a permanent generator shall be screened from view by a wall or hedge.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A permanent generator installation shall not be counted as part of maximum lot coverage, maximum floor area ratio, or parking requirement calculations. Permanent generator installations on improved properties may encroach into the required landscaped open areas.</section><section prefix='(f)'>There shall be no variance from the provisions of this section.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-83, § 1, 6-6-06)</history></law>