<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(I). DOWNTOWN KENDALL URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.56</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004373</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.56. Definitions.<section>Terms used throughout this Article shall take their commonly accepted meaning unless otherwise defined in or of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Terms requiring interpretation specific to this article are as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Anchor Point: The location depicted on the Designated Open Space Plan on which some portion of the required plaza or square must be situated.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Block: A combination of building lots, the perimeter of which abuts streets.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Block face: The right-of-way line or easement line which delineates a block edge.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Build-to line: A line parallel to the block face, along which a building shall be built.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Building Height: A limit to the vertical extent of a building measured in stories above grade. Building height shall be measured in stories from the average elevation of the enfronting curb to the eave line.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Civic Use: Premises used primarily for public education, cultural performances, gatherings and displays administered by non-profit cultural, educational, governmental, and religious organizations.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Clear Zone: An area within the curb radius, which shall be kept clear of all objects to a prescribed height to provide vehicle clearance.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Colonnade: A roofed structure, extending over the sidewalk, open to the street that is supported by columns or piers.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Courtyard Garden: A grade-level garden which may be included as part of the open space requirement and is described in this Article's General Requirements.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Curb Radius: The curved edge of street paving at an intersection, measured at the inside travel edge of the travel lane.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Designated Open Space: Colonnades, Squares, and Plazas as indicated on the Designated Open Space Plan.</section><section prefix='(11.5)'>Electric Vehicle Retail Showroom: Retail showroom for electric vehicles provided that:<section prefix='(a)'>No on-site vehicle storage/stock beyond the showroom and vehicles for test drives is allowed: and</section><section prefix='(b)'>No more than six (6) electric vehicles, outside of the showroom, to be used for test drive purposes: and</section><section prefix='(c)'>No test drive shall be conducted on residential local streets (fifty-foot wide rights-of-way): and</section><section prefix='(d)'>Vehicles used for test drives and display in the showroom are not permitted to be sold on-site.</section></section><section prefix='(12)'>Expression Line: A horizontal line, the full width of a facade, expressed by a material change or by a continuous projection not less than three (3) inches nor more than one (1) foot.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Floorplate: The total indoor and outdoor area of any given story of a building, measured to the exterior of the wall.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Frontage: The property line or lines of a lot which coincide with a right-of-way or other public open space line as shown on the Regulating Plan.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Garden Wall: A wall separating a courtyard garden from a public open space.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Habitable Space: Building space whose use involves human presence with direct view of the enfronting streets or open space, excluding parking garages, self-service storage facilities, warehouses, and display windows separated from retail activity.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Open Space: An outdoor, at grade space which is accessible to the public all or most of the time, including parks, plazas, squares, canal-walks, colonnades, courtyard gardens, paseos (when designed predominantly for pedestrians), and pedestrian paths and/or associated ornamental or shading landscaped areas.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Paseo: A cross-block, primarily pedestrian passage connecting one (1) right-of-way or paseo to another. Paseos shall be designed for pedestrian comfort, but may serve vehicles when minimum standards set forth in this Article are met. Also known as a C Street.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Penthouse: Topmost built area of a building with a floorplate area less than that of the tower below.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Pedestal: The bottom portion of a building that creates the street frontage.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Plaza: An open space with a majority of paved surface. Plazas are fronted with buildings that continue the adjacent street frontage requirements and uses.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Retail Use: Premises used for the exchange of services or goods.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Square: An open space surrounded by streets or other vehicular passages.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Shared Parking: Parking used by more than one (1) use or building.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Storefront: The portion of a building at the first story of a retail frontage that is made available for retail use.</section><section prefix='(26)'>Story: A floor level within a building as described in this Article's General Requirements.</section><section prefix='(27)'>Street: A thoroughfare for the movement of pedestrians and/or vehicles, as provided in this Article.</section><section prefix='(28)'>Streetwall: The vertical surface of a building or structure that faces public open space.</section><section prefix='(29)'>Tower: The middle portion of a building above the pedestal and below the penthouse.</section><section prefix='(30)'>Turnout Radius: the inside turning radius between intersecting travel lanes, which may be independent from the actual curb of the street edge.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-166, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 09-81, ยง 1, 9-1-09; Ord. No. 13-41, ยง 1, 5-7-13)</history></law>