<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVB. RU-RH, ROWHOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-202.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Design Standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004132</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-202.8. Design Standards.<section prefix='(1)'>Front Elevation. The front elevation of rowhouse units shall face a street or green and shall contain the front door and windows covering at least fifteen (15) percent of the front elevation, not including the roof.</section><section>The front elevation of rowhouse units shall be differentiated and articulated by at least two (2) of the following design variations; (a) varying front elevations; (b) varying roof pitches and/or directions; (c) articulating front elevations with fenestration, bay windows and/or balconies; (d) varying building heights; (e) staggering of the front elevation(s) so that fifty (50) percent of the elevation(s) are setback a minimum of ten (10) feet from the front property line and the remaining fifty (50) percent of the elevation(s) are setback a minimum of fifteen (15) feet.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Front porch and stoop. Front porches shall be required for a minimum of fifty (50) percent of all rowhouse units. A front porch shall consist of a roofed structure attached to the front of the unit. The porch shall be open on three (3) sides except for structural columns or low walls or railings not exceeding forty-two (42) inches in height from the porch floor. The front porch openings may be covered with insect screening but not with glazing. Front porches shall have a minimum width of twelve (12) feet and a minimum depth of six (6) feet, except that side and rear porches shall not be subject to these requirements. A stoop may be a covered landing placed at the side or rear entrance to a dwelling unit with a maximum area of thirty-six (36) square feet. All or a portion of a porch or stoop may encompass a handicap ramp providing access.<section prefix='(a)'>Encroachments into front setback area: Front porches may encroach a maximum of six (6) feet into the front setback. Roof eaves of such front porches may encroach another two (2) feet but not within four (4) feet of the front roadway pavement. Awnings, second story balconies and handicap ramps may encroach up to six (6) feet into the front setback; bay windows may encroach up to four (4) feet into the front setback.<section>When rowhouse units front on a green or other common open space, front porches may encroach a maximum of eight (8) feet into the front setback. Roof eaves of such front porches may encroach another two (2) feet. Awnings, second story balconies and handicap ramps may encroach up to six (6) feet into the front setback; bay windows may encroach up to four (4) feet into the front setback.</section></section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Street system, right-of-way width, and improvements. The right-of-way width of public streets and private streets and alleyways serving a group of rowhouses and the improvements therein shall conform to all applicable minimum Miami-Dade County standards and requirements for such streets. Cul-de-sacs and T-turnarounds should be avoided. The street system of a rowhouse development shall be designed to connect directly to adjacent street systems.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Street edge. Sidewalks with a minimum width of five (5) feet and curbs and gutters shall be provided along all roadways and shall be in accordance with the Public Works Manual. Street lamps of a maximum height of ten (10) feet shall be provided at an average spacing of twenty-five (25) feet on center along the roadway edge.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Alleys. Alleys are permitted and shall be a minimum of fifteen (15) feet in width, with a minimum twelve (12) feet of paved surface and a twenty-two (22) foot clear opening at the throat.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Pedestrian path. Pedestrian pathways are intersecting paved walkways that provide pedestrian passage from street to street and from a green to a street. A pedestrian pathway between streets or from a green to a street shall be provided every two hundred forty (240) feet when there is no intervening street between building groups. A pedestrian path shall be a minimum of fifteen (15) feet in width that shall contain a minimum pavement width of six (6) feet. The balance of the pedestrian path shall be landscaped open space, except where interrupted by alleyways.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-96, ยง 1, 6-20-06)</history></law>