<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIX. IU-1, INDUSTRIAL, LIGHT MANUFACTURING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-259.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004264</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-259.1. Additional uses permitted.<section prefix='(a)'>In the development and enforcement of this section it is recognized that there are uses which because of their very nature are recognized as having serious objectionable characteristics, particularly when several of them are concentrated in any given location, thereby having a deleterious effect upon the adjacent business and residential areas. It is desirable, therefore, to locate these adult oriented activities away from residential areas and public facilities that are used frequently by minors such as schools, churches, parks, libraries, day care centers or nurseries.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For the purpose of this section the following definitions for terms used herein shall apply:<section prefix='(1)'>Adult bookstore. Any business engaged in displaying, distributing, bartering, renting or selling printed matter, pictures, films, graphic or other materials which activity requires the exclusion of minors pursuant to Chapter 847, Florida Statutes, unless such activity comprises no more than fifteen (15) percent of the total floor area and is kept from clear view of minors.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Adult theater. Any business engaged in presenting films, theatrical productions, performances, recitals, displays, printed matter or other entertainment which activity requires the exclusion of minors pursuant to Chapter 847, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Adult entertainment club. Any business which features live entertainment requiring the exclusion of minors pursuant to Chapter 847, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Adult video store. Any business engaged in displaying, renting or selling videotapes which activity requires the exclusion of minors pursuant to Chapter 847, Florida Statutes, unless such activity comprises no more than fifteen (15) percent of the total floor area and is kept from clear view of minors.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Massage establishment.<section prefix='a.'>Any shop, parlor, establishment or place of business wherein all or any one (1) or more of the following named subjects and methods of treatments are administered or practiced: Body massage either by hand or by any mechanical or electrical apparatus or device (excluding fever therapy), applying such movements as stroking, friction, rolling, vibration, kneading, cupping, petrissage, rubbing, effleurage or tapotement.</section><section prefix='b.'>Nothing in this section shall be construed as applying to State of Florida licensed massage therapists, barbers, cosmetologists, manicurists, pedicurists, physical therapists' assistants, midwives, practical nurses, agents, servants or employees in licensed hospitals or nursing home or other licensed medical institutions, licensed physicians, osteopaths, chiropractors, podiatrists, naturopathic physicians or other licensed medical practitioners, or their agents, servants, or employees acting in the course of such agency, service or employment under the supervision of the licensee.</section><section prefix='c.'>Provided, however, that, for the purpose of this section, the term "massage establishment" shall not include any massage establishment wherein at least one (1) State of Florida licensed massage therapist is employed and on duty full time during the hours open for business.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Adult modelling establishments. Any establishment offering nude or partially nude modelling sessions or lingerie, swimwear or photography modelling sessions between two (2) or more persons requiring the exclusion of minor pursuant to Chapter 847, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Encounter studio. All establishments offering nude or partially nude encounter sessions between two (2) or more persons, nude or partially nude dance encounter sessions between two (2) or more persons, and sexual consultation requiring the exclusion of minors pursuant to Chapter 847, Florida Statutes.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The following additional uses shall be permitted in the IU-1 zone:<section prefix='(1)'>Adult bookstore;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Adult theater;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Adult entertainment club;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Adult video store;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Massage establishment;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Adult modelling establishment;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Encounter studio.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Unless approved as a special exception, none of the uses set forth in Subsection 33.259.1(c) shall be permitted (i) within one thousand (1,000) feet of a private school as defined in Section 33-151.11, public school, church, public park, public library, day care center or nursery for children; (ii) within one thousand two hundred (1,200) feet of any of the uses described in Subsection 33.259.1(c); and (iii) within seven hundred fifty (750) feet of any residential zoning (with the exception of AU) district located within either the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County or within a municipality; provided, however, that the spacing requirements above shall not apply where the adult entertainment use is separated from the uses set forth at Subsection 33.259.1(d)(i) and Subsection 33.259.1(d)(iii) above by a county or state road of not less than six (6) lanes, or an expressway. All other distance and spacing requirements pursuant to the Code shall apply, as well as those spacing requirements imposed by State Statute, if such State spacing requirements are more restrictive than the regulations contained herein. Any application seeking a variance from State imposed spacing requirements shall be heard directly by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to Section 33-314(C)(8).</section><section prefix='(e)'>The distance and spacing requirements set forth in Subsection (d) shall be measured as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>From a church, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest point of the proposed place of business, whether it is the structure itself or the parking lot used by the patrons of the proposed place of business, to the nearest point on the church property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>From a private or public school, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest point of the proposed place of business, whether it is the structure itself or the parking lot used by the patrons of the proposed place of business, to the nearest point on the school grounds.</section><section prefix='(3)'>From another Subsection 33.259.1(b) use, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the front door of the proposed place of business to the nearest point of the existing Subsection 33.259.1(b) use.</section><section prefix='(4)'>From residential zoning districts, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest point of the proposed place of business, whether it is the structure itself or the parking lot used by the patrons of the proposed place of business, to the nearest boundary of the residential zoning district.</section><section prefix='(5)'>From a public park, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest point of the proposed place of business, whether it is the structure itself or the parking lot used by the patrons of the proposed place of business, to the nearest point on park grounds.</section><section prefix='(6)'>From a public library, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest point of the proposed place of business, whether it is the structure itself or the parking lot used by the patrons of the proposed place of business, to the nearest point of the library property.</section><section prefix='(7)'>From day care centers or nurseries for children, the distance shall be measured by following a straight line from the nearest point of the proposed place of business, whether it is the structure itself or the parking lot used by the patrons of the proposed place of business, to the nearest point on the property of the day care center or the nursery.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>For the purposes of establishing the distance between the uses set forth in Subsection 33.259.1(b), and between such uses and private schools as defined in Section 33-151.11, public schools, churches, public parks, public libraries, day care centers or nurseries for children, or residential zoning districts, the applicant for such use shall furnish a certified survey from a registered surveyor. Such sketch shall indicate the distance between the proposed place of business, and any existing Subsection 33.259.1(b) use, any church, public school, private school, public park, public library, day care center or nursery for children or residential zoning district. Each sketch shall indicate all such distances and routes. In case of dispute, the measurement, scaled by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning shall govern.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Exemptions to spacing requirements. This section shall not apply to accredited universities, accredited colleges or other accredited educational institutions, museums, art exhibits, arts and cultural performance theaters and playhouses or commercial professional photography and portrait studios which may use nude subjects for their photographs or portraits.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Legally existing nonconforming uses. The following uses shall be deemed legally existing, whether or not such uses comply with the regulations enacted by this section, provided however, that nothing contained herein shall exempt such uses from complying with Section 33-35 of the Code Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='(1)'>Any adult entertainment use for which a building permit has been issued to establish such use prior to January 1, 2002, provided the work authorized by the building permit is completed and a Certificate of Use and Occupancy ("CO") is issued within the time prescribed by applicable regulations; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any adult entertainment use for which a CO has been issued prior to January 1, 2002, provided such CO is valid (not expired or revoked) as of January 1, 2002.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-23, ยง 2, 2-12-02)</history></law>