<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(P). CUTLER RIDGE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (CRMUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.30</section_number>
<catch_line>Non-conforming Structures, Uses, and Occupancies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004445</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.30. Non-conforming Structures, Uses, and Occupancies.<section>All legal nonconforming structures, uses, and occupancies in the CRMUC that either (1) were existing as of the date of the district boundary change on the property to CRMUC or (2) on or before said date, had received final site plan approval or had a valid building permit, shall be exempt from the provisions of(c) of this Code upon compliance with the requirements of this section for a period of 10 years from the date of the district boundary change on the property to CRMUC. Such nonconforming structures shall be allowed to be rebuilt and such uses and occupancies resumed in compliance with plans of record and certificates of use and occupancy approved as of the date of the district boundary change on the property to CRMUC. Such structures, uses and occupancies shall be in compliance with all other provisions of this Code in effect at the time of the application to rebuild or resume occupancy. Building permits for rebuilding pursuant to this section shall be obtained within one year after the date of damage or destruction of the nonconforming structure. If the building permits necessary to rebuild a nonconforming structure have not been obtained within one year after the date of damage or destruction, or if such permits expire or are revoked after that year has concluded, the structure shall be subject to the provisions of(c).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-152, ยง 8, 10-10-06)</history></law>