<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='3'>ARTICLE XXVII. BU-3 LIBERAL BUSINESS DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-255</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004250</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-255. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water and/or structure in the BU-3 District shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, arranged or intended to be used, occupied or maintained for any purpose, unless otherwise provided for, excepting for one (1) or more of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>All uses permitted in the BU-1, BU-1A and BU-2 Districts except that residential uses shall not be permitted.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Airports, airport hangars and airplane repair facilities.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Automobile and truck services and facilities including:<section prefix='(a)'>Open lot car and truck sales new and or used, including as ancillary uses, automobile repairs, body and top work and painting, provided that no more than fifteen (15) percent of the gross building area is devoted to such ancillary uses, and subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>That a continuous, densely planted greenbelt of not less than fifteen (15) feet in width, penetrated only at points approved by the Directors of the Planning and Zoning and Public Works Departments for ingress and egress to the property, shall be provided along all property lines abutting public rights-of-way or properties zoned residential. Said greenbelt shall have shade trees planted at a maximum spacing of thirty (30) feet on center and a hedge of a minimum of six (6) feet in height abutting residentially zoned property and a minimum of three (3) feet in height abutting public rights-of-way. The shade trees shall have a minimum caliper of two and one-half (2 ½) inches at time of planting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A minimum of twenty (20) percent of the net lot area of the site shall be developed as landscaped open space.</section><section prefix='(3)'>That such uses be located only on major access roads, including major roadways (three (3) or more lanes) and frontage roadways serving limited access highways and expressways.</section><section prefix='(4)'>That such uses be conducted on sites consisting of at least one (1) net acre.</section><section prefix='(5)'>That attention attracting devices, such as blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers and all fluttering, spinning advertising devices (either mobile or stationary) are prohibited, except as permitted under point of sale sign regulations.</section><section prefix='(6)'>That outdoor lighting shall be designed to avoid spilling beyond the site boundaries.</section><section prefix='(7)'>That no vehicular test drives shall be conducted on residential local traffic streets (fifty-foot right-of-way or less).</section><section prefix='(8)'>That the applicant obtains a certificate of use, which shall be automatically renewable yearly upon compliance with all terms and conditions.</section><section prefix='(9)'>All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited. This provision (9) shall also apply to all establishments in existence as of September 10, 1996..</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Open lot car rental.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Automobile parts, secondhand from store building only.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Automobile body and top work and painting.</section><section>All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited. This provision shall also apply to all establishments in existence as of the effective date of this ordinance.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Bakeries, retail and wholesale.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Barbecue stands or barbecue pits provided that establishments using wood burning for cooking are permitted only upon approval at a public hearing.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Bottling of beverages.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Cabinet working and carpentry shops.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Cold storage warehouse and pre-cooling plants.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Contractor's plants and storage yards.</section><section prefix='(9.1)'>Dog kennels, as an exception to Section 33-256.5, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>All outdoor exercise runs shall be set back fifty (50) feet from property lines and shall not be located closer than five hundred (500) feet from residentially zoned or residentially developed property. Where outside exercise runs are provided, a landscaped buffer or decorative masonry wall shall enclose the runs, and use of the runs shall be restricted to use during daylight hours.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Where outside exercise runs are not provided, an outside area shall be designated for dogs (or cats) to relieve themselves, and that area shall be enclosed by a landscape buffer or masonry wall. Additionally such area shall be set back fifty (50) feet from property lines and shall not be located closer than five hundred (500) feet from residentially zoned or residentially developed property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All kennel buildings shall be soundproofed and air-conditioned.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An administrative site plan review (ASPR) shall be required. The site plan shall show all fencing, berms, and soundproofing designed to mitigate the noise impact of the kennel on the surrounding properties.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Dry cleaning and dyeing establishments.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Engines, gas, gasoline, steam and oil; sales and service.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Feed, hay and other livestock supplies.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Fertilizer stores.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Garage or mechanical service. * including automobile repairs, body and top work and painting. All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited. This provision shall also apply to all establishments in existence as of September 10, 1996.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Glass installation.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Gun shops.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Leather goods manufacturing, excluding tanning.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Locksmith shops, sharpening and grinding shops.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Lumber yards.*</section><section prefix='(20)'>Pawnbrokers shall be permitted only upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Poultry markets and commercial chicken hatcheries.*</section><section prefix='(22)'>Railroad motor truck and water freight and passenger stations.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Secondhand stores for the disposal of furniture, fixtures and tools.</section><section prefix='(23.1)'>Self-service mini-warehouse storage facility. "Self-service mini-warehouse storage facility" shall be defined as a fully enclosed space used for warehousing which contains individual storage units with floor area no greater than four hundred (400) square feet and an interior height not to exceed twelve (12) feet. No business or business activity, and no wholesale or retail sales are permitted in an individual storage area within a self-service mini-warehouse storage facility.<section prefix='(a)'>Ancillary rentals of trucks other than light trucks are permitted in conjunction with a self-service mini-warehouse storage facility, providing such facility is situated on a site containing not less than 2.5 acres gross, subject to compliance with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>That a decorative masonry wall at least 8 feet in height shall enclose the rental truck storage area; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>There shall be a landscaped buffer between the masonry wall and any abutting roads which may be a hedge, and/or trees at least 48 inches high at the time of planting, or other reasonable landscape plans acceptable to the department; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>That there be no rental of any truck having a net vehicle weight exceeding 12,600 pounds; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>That for each 100 self-storage units there shall be no more than two rental trucks stored, e.g., 1-100 units: 2 rental trucks; 101-200 units; 4 rental trucks, etc.; provided however, no more than ten rental trucks may be stored on the premises; and</section><section prefix='(5)'>That no loading or unloading of trucks is permitted outside the enclosed area and all trucks must be stored inside the enclosed area at all times; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>That there shall be no repairs or maintenance work on the rental trucks on the premises of the self-service mini-warehouse storage facility.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Ancillary storage of recreational vehicles and boats is permitted in conjunction with a self-service mini-warehouse storage facility, subject to compliance with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>That a decorative masonry wall at least 8 feet in height shall enclose the recreational vehicle and boat storage area; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>There shall be a landscaped buffer between the masonry wall and any abutting roads which may be a hedge, and/or trees at least 48 inches high at the time of planting, or other reasonable landscape plans acceptable to the department; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>That there shall be no repairs or maintenance work on the recreational vehicles or boats on the premises of the self-service mini-warehouse storage facility.</section></section></section><section prefix='(24)'>Television and broadcasting stations, including studio, transmitting station and tower, power plants and other incidental and unusual uses permitted to such a station.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Tire vulcanizing and retreading or sale of used tires.*</section><section prefix='(26)'>Truck storage, only within an enclosed building or an area enclosed by a CBS wall.</section><section prefix='(27)'>Upholstery and furniture repairs.</section><section prefix='(28)'>Wholesale salesroom and storage rooms.</section><section prefix='(29)'>Other similar uses as approved by the Director.</section></section><section>*NOTE: Provided no such establishment is located within five hundred (500) feet of any RU or EU District except after approval after public hearing. Provided, that, this spacing limitation shall be two hundred fifty (250) feet if the use is confined within a building and an exterior wall or walls of the building located on the establishment is not penetrated with any openings directly facing the RU or EU District. It is further provided that, except for exterior uses, such distances shall be measured from the closest point of the subject use in the building to the RU or EU District. In connection with exterior uses, the distance of five hundred (500) feet shall be measured from the closest point of the IU District to the RU or EU District. For purposes of establishing such distances, the applicant for such use shall furnish a certified survey from a registered surveyor, which shall indicate such distances. In case of dispute, the measurement scaled by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning shall govern.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-25, § 1, 4-16-74; Ord. No. 85-37, § 2, 6-6-85; Ord. No. 88-122, § 1, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-129, § 1, 9-10-96; Ord. No. 00-74, § 1, 6-6-00; Ord. No. 03-78, § 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 03-238, § 1, 11-4-03; Ord. No. 08-11, § 3, 1-22-08)</history></law>