<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00066' order_by='00066' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(R). MODEL CITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (MCUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.40</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose, intent and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004455</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.40. Purpose, intent and applicability.<section prefix='A.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Illustrative Master Plan (Figure 1) illustrates the citizens' vision and may be used to interpret this article. Where the Illustrative Master Plan conflicts with the provisions of this article, the provisions of this article shall govern.</section><section prefix='C.'>Figure 1 also shows the boundaries of the Model City Urban Center District (MCUCD), as well as the boundaries of the Designated Urban Center. The MCUCD's Designated Urban Center shall consist of the areas designated as being the Core and Center Sub-districts on the Sub-districts Plan in Section 33-284.99.43 of this code. As provided in Standard Urban Center District Regulations, the Workforce Housing requirement shall apply to the area included in the Designated Urban Center boundaries. The legal descriptions of the boundaries of the MCUCD and the Designated Urban Center are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='D.'>Full scale maps of the Illustrative Master Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='E.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the MCUCD as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the MCUCD shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to MCUCD has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section>Figure 1. Illustrative Master Plan</section><section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 10-13, ยง 1, 2-2-10)</history></law>