<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00068' order_by='00068' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(T). PALMER LAKE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (PLMUC)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.60</section_number>
<catch_line>Development parameters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004475</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.60. Development parameters.<section prefix='(A)'>Building Standards.<section prefix='(1)'>The below diagram illustrates the building placement standards for all Sub-districts:</section></section><section><section prefix='(2)'>The below table provides minimum requirements for building and site development by Street Type:</section><section prefix='(3)'>The minimum sidewalk width may be provided in the right-of-way and building frontage zone in combination. The building pedestal shall be located adjoining or within the building frontage zone for the minimum linear distance required by the above table.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The building pedestal shall be permitted to encroach into the building frontage zone such that the minimum sidewalk width is provided.</section></section><section></section><section prefix='(B)'>General Requirements. All new development and redevelopment shall comply with the following parameters, irrespective of Sub-District and frontage categories:<section prefix='(1)'>Lots and Buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Minimum lot size is two thousand (2,000) square feet, with a minimum frontage of twenty (20) feet.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All lots shall share a frontage with a street.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The maximum height of buildings shall be as provided in Article XXXVII - Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field) Zoning of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Minimum front and side street building setbacks shall be determined by the table in paragraph (A) above. Minimum building interior side and rear setbacks shall be zero (0) feet. Lot coverage and floor area of buildings shall not be limited.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All buildings shall have their main pedestrian entrance opening to the street of highest pedestrian activity. Where storefronts are required, pedestrian entrances shall be provided at maximum intervals of seventy-five (75) feet. Where ground story uses have entries from more than one street frontage, the primary entrance shall be from the street of highest pedestrian activity.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Building design shall use energy conservation measures, including but not limited to self-shading, natural lighting, natural ventilation, outdoor circulation, and reduced dependence on artificial lighting and air conditioning. Porches, balconies, breezeways, pergolas, deep eaves, eyebrows, and other elements promoting natural ventilation and shading are encouraged. Each building shall dedicate a specific location for recycling separation, storage, and access.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Vehicular entry gates at garage entries shall be positioned a minimum of twenty (20) feet behind the front wall of the building. At colonnaded frontages, this distance is measured from the interior/rear wall of the colonnade. To increase safety during off-hours, the setback area between the entry gate and the public sidewalk may be gated at the sidewalk edge during times when the garage is closed.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Glazing, Transparency and Storefront Requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Portions of buildings facing or adjoining the building frontage zone shall be glazed as follows: office, hotel, and residential, minimum thirty (30) percent; retail, minimum twenty (20) percent; industrial and marine, minimum ten (10) percent. Storefronts shall be glazed as provided below and may count toward the overall building glazed area. Glazing shall be clear or tinted, except where used for screening garages, where it may be translucent.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where required, storefronts shall occupy the ground story and be directly accessible from the building frontage zone and/or sidewalk. Storefronts shall be a minimum of sixty (60) percent clear-glazed for the height of the ground story.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Storefront security screens, if any, shall be of the mesh type that pedestrians can see through and shall be located behind storefront displays. Storefronts shall remain open to view and be lit from within at night.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Parking garages shall have all architectural expression facing public streets and open spaces and shall be consistent and harmonious with that of habitable space. Architectural expression shall include vertically proportioned openings, balconies, glazing, awnings, or other similar architectural elements. Ramping is encouraged to be internalized wherever possible. Exposed spandrels are prohibited. The exposed top level of parking structures shall be covered a minimum of sixty (60) percent with a shade producing structure such as a vined pergola or retractable canvas shade structure. All garage lighting installations shall be designed to minimize direct spillage, sky glow, and hazardous interference with vehicular traffic on adjacent rights-of-way and all adjacent properties; this may be achieved through the use of down-turned building beams, garage screening, landscaping, or other similar architectural elements.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Elevated pedestrian walkways shall be permitted subject to the following:<section prefix='i.'>Walkways shall be permitted to extend over the public right-of-way.</section><section prefix='ii.'>The bottom of the walkway shall be a minimum of sixteen (16) feet six (6) inches above the street. Street and pedestrian lighting shall be provided at the underside of the walkway.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Walkways and connecting corridors shall have a minimum interior clear width of fourteen (14) feet. The exterior width of the Walkway structure shall be no wider than thirty (30) feet.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Walkways shall be single story and designed to be horizontally level with the street. Changes in grade between buildings shall be accommodated so that the walkway appears level from the exterior.</section><section prefix='v.'>At least eighty (80) percent of the vertical enclosure of the walkway shall be transparent or open. Windows, if provided, shall be of clear or lightly tinted glass that allow views into and out of the walkway. Louvers or other shade structures are permitted for shading and weather protection within the walkway.</section><section prefix='vi.'>Walkways shall be designed to facilitate access between street and walkway levels. Elevators, stairs and escalators linking the street and walkway levels shall be conveniently located with clear directional signs.</section><section prefix='vii.'>Signage providing directional information on destinations accessible through the walkway shall be required within the walkway structure, along pedestrian routes connecting to the walkway in adjoining buildings, and at street level building entrances. Signage at building entrances leading to a walkway shall state that the walkways are open to the public and their hours of operation.</section><section prefix='viii.'>The walkway shall be open to the general public seven (7) days a week from at least seven (7) AM to ten (10) PM.</section><section prefix='ix.'>The walkway shall be maintained in good order for the life of the principal structure.</section><section prefix='x.'>An agreement shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County between affected property owners and public entities establishing public access, maintenance, operation, and removal of the Walkway structure and adjoining accessways consistent with this article.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>Fixtures, including but not limited to backflow preventers, pumps, underground ventilation exhausts, and electrical vaults, shall be located within or to the side or rear of buildings; such fixtures shall not be located within the required building frontage zone.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Backflow preventers shall be shielded from view, as required by Sec. 32-157(d) of this code.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Colonnades and cantilevered building elements shall be permitted in the building frontage zone. Colonnades shall be a minimum clear width of ten (10) feet. Colonnades shall be designed to maximize visibility from the street through the colonnade area and into building interiors.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Awnings, balconies, roof eaves, open steps, pedestrian ramps, landscape planters and fountains may extend into or be located in the building frontage zone or forecourt area.</section><section prefix='(o)'>The maximum width of a forecourt shall be fifty (50) percent of the minimum required building frontage. Where multiple forecourts are provided, their total width in aggregate shall be a maximum of fifty (50) percent of the minimum required building frontage. The maximum depth of a forecourt shall be fifty (50) percent of its width.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Streets.<section prefix='(a)'>Streets shall provide access to all building lots and tracts.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All streets shall connect to other streets. Dead-end streets and T-turnarounds shall only be permitted temporarily for new streets when the adjacent property is not platted, not developed or both. When the adjacent property is platted or developed, a street shall connect to existing development and the dead-end street or T-turnaround removed.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All streets shall have curb and gutter and have sidewalks on both sides of the travel lanes. Where possible, there shall be parking lanes, which, in addition to on-street parking, may be used for "drop off" areas, valet stands, or bus stops.<section prefix='i.'>All sidewalks shall have a minimum width as required by the table in paragraph (A) above and a continuous unobstructed area of a width no less than sixty (60) inches.</section><section prefix='ii.'>On-street parking lanes shall not be closer than twenty-five (25) feet to intersections measured from the intersecting lot lines.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Designated bicycle facilities shall be provided along NW South River Drive, NW 37th Avenue, and NW 25th Street.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Awnings, balconies, roof eaves and signs may encroach into rights-of-way; however, they shall not extend a distance closer than six (6) inches from the curb face. All right-of-way encroachments shall be a minimum one hundred thirty-two (132) inches above the sidewalk. Building encroachments in the right-of-way shall require review and approval from the Public Works and Waste Management Department.</section><section prefix='(f)'>New utility installations shall run underground, and above-ground projections of utilities shall be placed in or along rights-of-way of streets of lower pedestrian activity, wherever practicable.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Street lighting shall be required along all streets. The type and spacing of light fixtures shall be approved by the Public Works and Waste Management Department. Approval shall be based on uniformity of types, location, right-of-way width, and luminosity.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Right-of-way improvements necessary to meet the requirements of this Article shall be constructed concurrently with any development activity. For multiple-phase developments, right-of-way improvements shall be constructed concurrently with those phases or portions of a property being developed.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Street development standards. The diagrams below illustrate the sidewalk, bicycle facility, landscaping, and parking elements for streets within the Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center District. Right-of-way improvements are subject to the review and approval of the Public Works and Waste Management Department and may vary from the below diagrams due to right-of way limitations, recorded easements, roadway geometry, or other constraints.<section prefix='1.'>"A" Street:</section></section></section></section><section><section prefix='2.'>"B" Street with bicycle facility:</section></section><section><section prefix='3.'>"C" Street with bicycle facility:</section></section><section><section prefix='4.'>"C" Street with bicycle facility and truck parking/waiting area:</section></section><section><section>The truck parking/waiting area illustrated may occur on either or both sides of the street.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Walls, Fences, and Hedges. Walls, fences, and hedges may be placed within the building frontage zone, provided that the minimum sidewalk width for the applicable street type is satisfied. Walls, fences, and hedges shall not exceed ninety-six (96) inches in height. Chain link fences shall not be permitted facing or within the Building Frontage Zone.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Open Space and Recreation Areas.<section prefix='(a)'>A minimum of ten (10) percent of net lot area shall be reserved for private open space. Colonnades, landscape areas, water features, pedestrian areas in the building frontage zone, landscaped roof terraces on buildings or garage structures may be counted towards this requirement. Up to twenty (20) percent of the area required for private open space may consist of submerged land areas.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Development on lots adjoining the Miami River, Tamiami Canal, and/or Palmer Lake that contain uses permitted subject to the requirements of Section 33-284.99.59(B)(4) shall provide a waterfront setback as provided below:<section prefix='1.'>Lots with less than 150 feet of distance as measured perpendicular from the adjoining street right of way to the mean high water line or bulkhead for more than 50 percent of the width of the lot shall provide a waterfront setback of ten (10) feet.</section><section prefix='2.'>Lots with less than 150 feet of frontage along the Miami River, Tamiami Canal, or Palmer Lake as measured along the mean high water line or bulkhead shall provide a waterfront setback of ten (10) feet.</section><section prefix='3.'>All other lots shall provide a waterfront setback of twenty (20) feet.</section><section prefix='4.'>Any portion of a lot with less than 50 feet of distance as measured perpendicular from the adjoining street right of way to the mean high water line or bulkhead shall not be required to provide a waterfront setback for that portion of the lot.</section><section prefix='5.'>Within the setback area, a hard-surfaced walkway area shall be provided with a minimum width of sixty (60) percent of the required setback width. The setback area shall be furnished with seating areas, lighting, decorative trash receptacles, and landscaping as appropriate. Colonnades and/or cantilevered building elements shall be permitted to encroach into the setback area. Walkways shall be designed to permit connections to existing or future walkways located on adjoining waterfront lots. The setback area and walkway shall be accessed from the street by exterior walkways or through building interiors, courtyards, or breezeways. The setback area, walkway and accessways shall permit general public access seven (7) days a week from at least seven (7) AM to ten (10) PM. For lots adjoining Palmer Lake, docks or boardwalks located over the lake providing similar amenities shall satisfy the setback requirement. That portion of a lot occupied by a water-dependent use shall be exempt from the requirements of this sub-section.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Along the Miami River Greenway, as shown in the "Greenway and Bicycle Plan" above, the following shall be required: sidewalk, multi-use path, and/or bicycle path.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>Parking shall be provided as per Section 33-124 of this Code, except as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>The minimum parking for the following types of development shall be as follows:<section prefix='i.'>Residential—One (1) parking space per dwelling unit.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Office—One (1) parking space per four-hundred (400) square feet of gross floor area.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Hotel—One (1) parking space for the first forty (40) guest rooms and one (1) additional parking space for every two (2) guest rooms or suites thereafter.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Parking reduction. Development meeting the following criteria shall be permitted to reduce the number of parking spaces required in accordance with the following table:</section></section></section></section><section>Developments meeting more than one of the use, location, and parcel criteria shall be permitted to combine each permitted reduction; the combined reduction shall be calculated by reducing the first applicable criteria from each group in the order of the table above.<section prefix='(3)'>Off-street parking areas shall be located:<section prefix='i.'>On the same lot as the use to be served; or</section><section prefix='ii.'>On a lot within the PLMUC that is within seven hundred fifty (750) feet of the site of the use(s) to be served, provided that such use(s) shall immediately terminate in the event such parking area therefor is not available, and provided that all parties having any right, title, or interest in and to the property being served shall execute and place on the public records of this County a covenant approved by the Director that such use(s) shall cease and terminate upon the elimination of such parking area, and that no use shall be made of such property until the required parking area is available and provided.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>On-street parking spaces directly abutting a lot shall count toward the parking requirement for development of that lot. In the event that on-street parking spaces are removed due to roadway improvements, those removed spaces that were counted toward a development's parking requirement shall not cause that development to become nonconforming.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Surface parking lots shall be located a minimum of twenty (20) feet from the front property line along "A" and "B" Streets. Along all streets, surface parking lots shall not be permitted within the building frontage zone or forecourt areas. Walls and/or habitable space shall be built adjoining the building frontage zone to screen parking from view.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Parking garages adjoining the building frontage zone along "A" street frontages shall be entirely screened by habitable space for a minimum depth of twenty (20) feet and the entire height of the garage structure.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Parking garages adjoining the building frontage zone along "B" and "C" street frontages shall be entirely screened by habitable space for a minimum depth of twenty (20) feet at the ground story of the garage structure; except that lots with more than one street frontage shall be required to provide screening for fifteen (15) percent of the garage structure's ground story frontage along the lower-ranking streets.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Parking garages facing "A" streets that have a lot depth at any one (1) point of less than one hundred fifty (150) feet shall be required to provide habitable space only at the ground floor. However, architectural expression shall comply with the requirements of this article.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Drop-off drives and porte-cocheres shall not adjoin an "A" street frontage.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Loading and service entries shall be allowed only on "C", "D" and "E" streets, alleys and within parking lots and structures. For those lots with frontages only on one street, loading and servicing shall be allowed from the street frontage.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Pedestrian entries to parking garages shall be directly from the street frontage as well as from the contiguous building.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Parking lots shall provide for pedestrian and vehicular cross access to existing and prospective adjacent parking lots.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Parking stall dimensions and spaces for persons with disabilities and/or strollers shall comply with Article VII of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Bicycle racks shall be provided in accordance with Section 33-122.3 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Mechanized parking shall be allowed for residential multi-family and non-residential buildings and, when provided, shall be exempt from the provisions of Section 33-122 of this chapter. For the purposes of this article, mechanized parking shall be defined as a mechanism with vertical and horizontal transport capability that provides for automobile storage or retrieval. Mechanized parking spaces may be counted toward the minimum number of parking spaces required in this section, provided that:<section prefix='i.'>A queuing analysis is submitted and approved during the Administrative Site Plan and Architectural Review; and</section><section prefix='ii.'>Mechanized parking shall be located within an enclosed building/garage which shall be screened as provided in (c) and (d) above.</section></section><section prefix='(m)'>The provisions of Section 33-131 of this chapter shall not apply to the required parking for any permitted use.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Child care facilities located within mixed-use buildings shall be exempt from the auto-stacking requirements of Section 33-151.18(c) of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Landscape. With the exception of Sections 18A-7, 18A-8, 18A-9, 18A-11, 18A-12 and 18A-13, the provisions of Chapter 18A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall not apply to properties in the PLMUC, except as provided herein. Trees and landscape shall be required for streets, medians, squares, plazas, and private property in accordance with the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Street Trees: Street trees shall be placed along "A", "B", "C" and "E" Streets at a maximum average spacing of thirty-five (35) feet on center. Street trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches and shall have a minimum clear trunk of eight (8) feet at the time of planting. Where palms are used as street trees they shall be placed at a maximum average spacing of twenty-five (25) feet on center. Street trees shall be planted in one or more of the following methods of installation:<section prefix='(1)'>Tree grates. Trees are planted within openings in the sidewalk. The openings shall be covered by permanently installed grates perforated to permit natural irrigation. The grates shall be installed flush with the surrounding sidewalk.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Tree planters. Trees are planted within a raised planter located on the sidewalk. The planter shall be defined on all sides by a permanent masonry structure to consist of a minimum six (6) inch raised curb. The area within the planter, in addition to the required trees, shall be planted with ground cover, shrubs, or other appropriate plant material.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Continuous landscape strips. Trees are planted in the area between the curb or roadway edge and the sidewalk. This area, in addition to the required trees, shall be planted with grass. Continuous landscape strips shall not be permitted along street frontages where the ground story of buildings are occupied by storefronts.</section><section>Street trees shall not be required where colonnades are provided and the sidewalk area outside of the colonnade is less than eight (8) feet in width. Where colonnades are provided and the sidewalk area outside the colonnade is between five (5) and eight (8) feet in width, one or more of the following shall be provided: landscaped planters located above the colonnade; a trellis attached to the colonnade structure and planted with climbing foliage; landscaped planters located adjoining the colonnade columns. On streets designated "Miami River Greenway" on the Greenway and Bicycle Plan, street trees shall not be planted within the required unobstructed sidewalk area.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Median Trees: Median trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches and shall have a minimum clear trunk of eight (8) feet at time of planting. Median planting shall provide a one hundred (100) percent canopy coverage within two (2) years of installation. Median trees may be a maximum of twenty (20) percent flowering trees or palms, which at time of planting shall have a minimum height of fifteen (15) feet, a minimum spread of ten (10) feet, and a minimum caliper of three (3) inches.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Tree requirements for private property shall be based on fifteen (15) trees per net acre of lot area. Trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches and shall have a minimum clear trunk of eight (8) feet at time of planting.</section><section prefix='(d)'>At grade parking lots shall follow all requirements of Section 18A(6)(J) of this Code.</section><section>All landscaped areas shall be continuously maintained in a good, healthy condition, and sprinkler systems of sufficient size and spacing shall be installed to serve all required landscaped areas and parking lots. Irrigation shall supply a minimum of the equivalent one and one-half (1½) inch rainfall per week. Rain sensors shall be installed in all systems.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Signs. Except as provided herein, the definitions set forth in Section 33-84 of this chapter shall apply. In the event of a conflict, the provisions of this section shall govern.<section prefix='(a)'>Temporary signs. Temporary signs (Class A) shall be permitted in compliance with Section 33-99 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Permanent Point of Sale Signs. Permanent point of sale signs (Class B) shall be permitted as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='i.'>Digital technology (signs): Electronic technology that allows for changes to a sign copy resulting from digital data input. Included in this technology are signs that use series of lights, including light emitting diodes (LED), fiber optics, or other similar technology.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Nits: Luminance is the measure of the light emanating from an object with respect to its size and is the term used to quantify electronic sign brightness. The unit of measurement for luminance is nits (nt), which is the total amount of light emitted from a sign divided by the surface area of the sign [candelas per square meter (cd/m2)].</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The following permanent point of sale signs are permitted in all sub-districts in conjunction with permitted business and industrial uses: monument sign, pylon, flat attached, hanging, awning, cantilever, and projecting. No other detached sign shall be permitted except monument signs.<section prefix='i.'>Projecting signs shall be mounted and perpendicular to the building.</section><section prefix='ii.'>The copy of an awning sign shall only be located on the valance of the awning.</section><section prefix='iii.'>The bottom of a hanging sign shall be located at a minimum height of eight (8) feet from the finished floor.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Monument signs, which are freestanding, 2-faced signs, shall have a base at least seventy-five (75) percent of the horizontal width of the sign and located directly on the ground or a maximum of twelve (12) inches above grade.</section><section prefix='v.'>Cantilever signs are mounted on that portion of the building projecting horizontally, whether it be on the same plane as the roof line or not.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Maximum size, location, and number of signs shall be as follows:</section><section prefix='(4)'>Illumination/lighting shall comply with the following: Where digital technology is allowed, it shall be provided in compliance with the following:<section prefix='i.'>No auditory message or mechanical sounds shall be emitted from the sign.</section><section prefix='ii.'>The sign shall not display any illumination that moves, appears to move, blinks, fades, rolls, dissolves, flashes, scrolls, shows animated movement, or changes in intensity during the static display period.</section><section prefix='iii.'>All digital signs shall be modulated so that, from sunset to sunrise, the brightness shall not be more than 500 Nits. Sunset and sunrise times are those times established by the Miami office of the National Weather Service. At all other times, the maximum brightness levels shall not exceed 5,000 Nits. All digital signs shall have installed ambient light monitors and at all times shall allow such monitors to automatically adjust the brightness level of the sign based on ambient light conditions.</section><section prefix='iv.'>The message display shall not change more often than once each eight seconds, with all moving parts or illumination moving or changing simultaneously.</section><section prefix='v.'>Any digital sign that malfunctions, fails, or ceases to operate in its usual or normal programmed manner shall immediately revert to a black screen and shall be restored to its normal operation conforming to the requirements of this section within twenty-four (24) hours.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Commercial signs. Commercial signs (Class C) shall be permitted as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>In the MIC Core Sub-district and along A, B, and C streets: Class C signs shall be permitted attached to buildings of at least seventy-five feet in height. Freestanding Class C signs shall not be permitted.<section prefix='i.'>The lowest portion of the sign shall be at least thirty (30) feet above grade.</section><section prefix='ii.'>The total sign area shall not occupy more than ten (10) percent of the wall area.</section><section prefix='iii.'>The sign shall not obstruct balconies or terraces; signs located in front of building windows shall be perforated so as not to obstruct visibility from within.</section><section prefix='iv.'>The sign shall not be oriented toward any residential zoning district adjacent to PLMUC.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>In all other areas:<section prefix='i.'>Class C signs shall be permitted within bus shelter structures and pedestrian information displays located in the building frontage zone and/or the right-of-way.</section><section prefix='ii.'>The maximum size of Class C signs within such structures or displays shall be thirty-two (32) square feet. Two-sided signs shall be permitted with one side counting toward the permitted sign area.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Bus shelter structures and pedestrian information displays containing Class C signs shall be spaced at least one hundred (100) feet apart as measured parallel to the street centerline.</section><section prefix='iv.'>The design, location, and construction of such structures or displays located in the right-of-way shall be approved by the Director of the Public Works and Waste Management Department and the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Directional signs. Directional signs, to direct traffic flow and locate entrances and exits shall be permitted on private property in connection with any permitted use. Directional signs shall not exceed thirty-two (32) square feet in area. The maximum height above grade of a detached directional sign shall be twelve (12) feet. The number, setback, and locations of the signs shall be determined for each facility as part of the site plan review process. Directional signs shall be shown on site plans indicating sign size, location, and copy.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-43, § 6, 5-7-13)</history></law>