<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(O). OJUS URBAN AREA DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.17</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004432</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.17. Uses.<section>Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the OUAD shall comply with of this Code.<section prefix='1.'>As provided in the Land Use Regulating Plan, no duplexes shall be permitted in areas designated:<section prefix='a.'>Residential (R) with a maximum permitted density of 6 dwelling units per net acre; and</section><section prefix='b.'>Residential Modified (RM) with maximum permitted densities greater or equal to 36 units per net acre.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>No municipal recreation building, playground, or park owned and operated by a municipality, county, state, or the federal government shall be permitted in areas designated R on the Land Use Regulating Plan.</section><section prefix='3.'>No civic uses shall be permitted in areas designated R on the Land Use Regulating Plan, except for educational facilities on properties not to exceed 5 acres.</section><section prefix='4.'>Industrial uses. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-284.83 (A)(4), only the following uses shall be permitted in the Industrial District (ID) area. These uses shall be allowed in conformance with the Land Use Regulating Plan and the Street Type Development Parameters.<section prefix='a.'>All uses permitted in the IU-1 zoning district</section><section prefix='b.'>All uses permitted in the IU-2 zoning district after public hearing pursuant to Section 33-311(A)(3) of this code.</section><section prefix='c.'>MC uses at a maximum density of 52 units net acre or at a maximum density of 60 units per net acre with the purchase of the appropriate number of Severable Use Rights pursuant to Sections 33B-41 to 33B-47 of this code.</section><section prefix='d.'>live-work units as provided in Sec. 33-284.83(A)(4)(b).</section><section prefix='e.'>On lots fronting West Dixie Highway and south of NE 195 Street, all uses permitted in the Mixed Use Main Street (MM), at a minimum density of 12 units per net acre and at a maximum density of 52 units net acre, or a maximum density of 60 units per net acre with the purchase of the appropriate number of Severable Use Rights as permitted by Section 33B-41 to Section 33B-47 of this code.</section><section prefix='f.'>On lots fronting NE 26th Avenue, all uses permitted in the Residential Modified (RM), at a minimum density of 12 units per net acre and a maximum density of 36 units net acre.</section></section><section prefix='5.'>Institutional uses. The following additional uses shall be permitted in the Institutional (I) area in accordance with the Land Use Regulating Plan and the Street Types Development Parameters.<section prefix='a.'>Civic uses in accordance with the Street Types Development Parameters.</section><section prefix='b.'>On lots located west of NE 25th Avenue, all uses permitted in the Residential (R), with a minimum density of 6 units per net acre and a maximum density of 13 units per net acre.</section><section prefix='c.'>On lots located east of NE 25th Avenue, all uses permitted in the Residential Modified (RM), with a minimum density of 12 units per net acre and a maximum density of 36 units per net acre.</section></section><section prefix='6.'>Conditionally Permitted Uses. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-284.83 (B), only the following conditional uses shall be permitted subject to the administrative approval of a site plan, pursuant to Section 33-284.88 of this code.<section prefix='1.'>Liquor package stores shall be permitted only in the Core Sub-district and only in compliance with all applicable regulations of this code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-86, ยง 4, 6-6-06; Ord. No. 07-94, ยง 2, 7-10-07)</history></law>