<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='3'>ARTICLE XVIII. RU-4, HIGH DENSITY APARTMENT HOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-208.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Criteria.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004158</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-208.2. Same—Criteria.<section>The following criteria shall be utilized in the plan review process:<section prefix='(1)'>Purpose and intent: The proposed development fulfills the objectives of this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Planning studies: Design, planning studies or neighborhood area studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the plan review process.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Landscape: Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, enhance architectural features, related structure design to site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by the major roadways and intense-use areas.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Buffers: Buffering elements in the form of architectural design and landscape design that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Scale: Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses or shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Circulation: Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Energy considerations: Site design methods to reduce energy consumption shall be encouraged. Energy site conservation methods may include siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles and use of landscape materials for shade and transpiration.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Parking areas: Building wall extensions, planting, berms or other innovative methods shall be used as a means of minimizing the adverse effect of the visual impact of parking areas. This requirement is in addition to the requirements of the landscape regulations of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Open spaces: Open spaces shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Graphics: Graphics, as required, shall be designed as an integral part of the overall design of the project.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Art display: Permanent interior and exterior art displays and water features should be encouraged in the overall design of the project.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:<section prefix='(a)'>Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:<section prefix='(1)'>Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 82-5, § 1, 2-2-82; Ord. No. 95-19, § 5, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 99-38, § 6, 4-27-99)</history></law>