<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-20.1.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Prima facie evidence of illegal multiple use or illegal subdivision of a residence.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003912</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-20.1.1. Prima facie evidence of illegal multiple use or illegal subdivision of a residence.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be presumed that a multi-family use has been established when one (1) or more of the following conditions are observed:<section prefix='(1)'>There are two (2) or more electrical, water gas or other types of utility meters, or mailboxes on the premises.</section><section prefix='(2)'>There is evidence of a liquid propane (LP) gas tank installed in an unauthorized detached structure on the premises.</section><section prefix='(3)'>There is more than one (1) cooking area in the primary structure.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All living areas in the dwelling are not interconnected.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Multiple paved numbered parking spaces.</section><section prefix='(6)'>An unauthorized detached building with air conditioning, interior cooking areas or utility meters.</section><section prefix='(7)'>There is more than one (1) different house address unit number posted on the premises.</section><section prefix='(8)'>An advertisement indicating the availability of more than one (1) living unit on the premises.</section><section prefix='(9)'>An unpermitted exterior door.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>For duplex or triplex structures, the terms "structure" and "dwelling" as used herein shall apply as to each unit.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The presumption may be rebutted by the submission of a current floor plan prepared by an engineer or architect, surveying the residence and accessory structures and showing all rooms are interconnected as a single-family dwelling accompanied by a notarized affidavit from the property owner attesting that the residence or accessory structure is being maintained for single-family occupancy and/or substantiated by an interior inspection of the dwelling by a compliance officer. If the compliance officer is able to enter the interior of the property and verify its use as a single-family dwelling, the property owner is exempt from the above submission.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Nothing contained in this section shall prevent the enforcement actions authorized by the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida independent of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-22, ยง 1, 3-4-99)</history></law>