<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00050' order_by='00050' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIB. PLANNED DEVELOPMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.21</section_number>
<catch_line>Plan review procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004336</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.21. Plan review procedure.<section>The application for a planned development shall be reviewed by the Department to determine its compliance with applicable regulations and review criteria contained herein. An instrument, suitable for recording, shall be submitted prior to the advertising of the public hearing, which covenants that development will occur substantially in accordance with plans approved at the public hearing.</section><section>The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall review the plans and documents, and may approve, approve with modifications, or disapprove the application.</section><section>If a Community Zoning Appeals Board incorporates specific modifications to the planned development in its resolution of approval, those modifications shall be made by the applicant prior to filing documents and plans with the Department. Such filing shall be completed within sixty (60) working days from date of a Community Zoning Appeals Board's action. Failure to do so shall nullify the Community Zoning Appeals Board's action unless waived by formal vote of the Community Zoning Appeals Board.</section><section>Subsequent to the public hearing, minor design modifications may be granted by approval of the Director, provided that such modifications do not result in an increase in the approved number of dwelling units or approved maximum commercial floor area and provided that the design modifications are in general agreement with the intent of this article.</section><section>The following exhibits shall be prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects and shall be filed with the application for a planned development:<section prefix='(1)'>A plan indicating existing zoning on site and adjacent areas.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Aerial photograph or map indicating site and development in the immediate area.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A plan and cross section(s), at the same scale, of the height envelope.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The use, height, bulk, dwelling unit per net acre and location of all buildings and other structures including specific locations for all commercial activities—models may be required when needed for adequate review.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Aerial perspective sketches of the total project.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Pedestrian and vehicular circulation systems.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Landscape development plan in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The design for entrance features and the signage system.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Parking layouts and drives.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Figures indicating the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Net density per acre for the total project and the total number of residential units, including hotel and motel units.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The total amount of gross retail floor area or the total amount of gross convenience retail facilities as provided in Section 33-284.20</section><section prefix='(c)'>Amount and percentage of common open space by categories provided in Section 33-284.15.1</section><section prefix='(d)'>Amount and percentage of private open space as required in Section 33-284.16</section><section prefix='(e)'>Number of parking spaces as related to the amount of residential and commercial development.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In addition, the methods used to determine the above figures shall be provided. Where practicable, such material shall be prepared in a table format.</section></section><section prefix='(11)'>Other material required for an adequate plan review by the Department.</section></section><section>The following criteria shall be utilized in the plan review process:<section prefix='(1)'>Purpose and intent—The proposed development fulfills the purpose and intent of this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Planning studies—Design or planning studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the plan review process.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Exterior spatial relationships—The three-dimensional airspace created by the arrangement of the structures and landscape shall produce spatial relationships that function with the intended use and occupancy of the project and are compatible with the development or zoning in the adjoining area.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Landscape—Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscaping shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, provide shade, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to the site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by the major roadways and intense-use areas.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Buffers—Buffering elements that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Scale—Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding proposed or existing uses or shall be made compatible by the use of buffering elements.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Privacy—Due consideration of aural and visual privacy shall be evidenced in the design of the overall development and in the design of individual units.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Building configuration—Access for emergency equipment to various parts of the building shall be considered in the design of the project. Buildings shall be arranged in a manner that allows sufficient light and air to penetrate the development. The elimination of the first floor of structures for purposes of improved ventilation at ground level shall be encouraged.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Circulation—Pedestrian, bicycle trails and equestrian trails shall be separated from auto circulation insofar as is practicable and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional in its relationship to circulation systems outside the development.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Energy conservation—Design methods to reduce energy consumption shall be encouraged. Energy conservation methods may include, but not be limited to, natural ventilation of structures, siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles, insulation of structures, use of landscape material for shade, direction of breezes and transpiration.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Subtropic characteristics—Subtropic characteristics of the area should be considered in the architectural design and site planning of the project. The provision of sun control devices, shaded areas, vegetation, roof terraces, and similar features characteristic of subtropical design shall be considered.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Parking areas—Parking areas shall be provided that are screened and so located as not to interfere with the livability of the development, its environs, and adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Service areas—Service areas shall be provided that are screened and so located as not to interfere with the livability of the development or adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Building height—Building height shall be in scale with the development in surrounding areas. As a maximum, building heights shall not exceed the height limitations hereinabove established.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Open space—A variety of open spaces shall be provided, appropriate to the needs of the particular type of development. Open space shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible and shall be so located and developed as to be easily accessible to all residents of the development.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Visual screening for decorative walls—In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:<section prefix='(a)'>Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:<section prefix='(1)'>Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-28, § 2, 3-20-73; Ord. No. 74-21, § 3, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 74-41, § 1, 6-4-74; Ord. No. 78-39, § 13, 6-6-78; Ord. No. 95-19, § 18, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 26, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-38, § 19, 4-27-99; Ord. No. 06-23, § 1, 2-21-06)</history></law>