<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(P). CUTLER RIDGE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (CRMUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.25</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004440</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.25. Uses.<section>Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the CRMUC shall comply with of this code.<section prefix='A.'>Permitted Uses. The following uses shall be permitted in areas designated Industrial (ID).<section prefix='1.'>In addition to all uses permitted in the Industrial area under Section 33.284.83, all uses permitted in the Mixed-Use Corridor (MC).</section></section><section prefix='B.'>Conditionally Permitted Uses. In addition to the conditionally permitted uses in Section 33-284.83(B) of this Code, the following conditional use shall be permitted subject to the administrative approval of a site plan, pursuant to Section 33-284.88 of this code, to assure compliance with the requirements established herein:<section prefix='1.'>Automobile new sales agency shall be permitted only upon approval after public hearing, provided that the following conditions are also satisfied:<section prefix='a.'>The building shall comply with the Building Placement and Street Type Development Parameters and the General Requirements in Section 33-284.85-86 of this Code and as established by the land use and sub-districts regulating plans provided in Section 33-284.99.17 of this code.</section><section prefix='b.'>All outdoor paging or speaker systems shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='c.'>Repair work of any type shall not be permitted on premises unless approved after public hearing and maintained within an enclosed building and screened from the street.</section><section prefix='d.'>The applicant shall obtain a certificate of use and occupancy, which shall be automatically renewable yearly upon compliance with all applicable terms and conditions.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-152, ยง 3, 10-10-06)</history></law>