<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXV. HOMESTEAD AIR FORCE BASE ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-294</section_number>
<catch_line>Heights limitations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004490</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-294. Heights limitations.<section>Except as otherwise provided in this article, any structure which is erected, increased in height or tree allowed to grow so as to project above the height of the controlling imaginary surface as specified hereunder will be considered a flight hazard and in violation of this article.<section prefix='(a)'>Approach-departure clearance surfaces. There is only one (1) runway at Homestead Air Force Base. This runway has a true north bearing of 49 degrees, 03 minutes, 29 seconds east. The magnetic declination at the Homestead Air Force Base is 1 degree, 10 minutes east. A height limitation within each surface is hereby established which will provide a clear space above the entire area of the approach-departure clearance surface, the height limitations being represented by a sloping plane, the base of which is two thousand (2,000) feet wide and begins two hundred (200) feet beyond the ultimate length of the runway and extends outward and upward on a ratio of eighty (80) feet horizontal to one (1) foot vertical for a horizontal distance of forty thousand (40,000) feet, at which point it reaches a vertical height of five hundred seven (507) feet above the mean sea level and a horizontal width of thirteen thousand two hundred (13,200) feet. This plane continues at a vertical height of five hundred seven (507) feet above MSL until it reaches a horizontal distance of fifty thousand (50,000) feet and horizontal width of sixteen thousand (16,000) feet. The maximum permissible heights within the approach-departure clearance surface zone, based on mean sea level, shall be listed in the following tabulation:</section><section prefix='(b)'>Inner horizontal surface. The height limitation within the inner horizontal surface zone is one hundred fifty (150) feet above the established airfield elevation or one hundred fifty-seven (157) feet above mean sea level.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Conical surface. The height limitations within the conical surface zone are given in the following tabulations:</section><section prefix='(d)'>Outer horizontal surface. The height limitation within the outer horizontal surface zone is five hundred (500) feet above the established airfield elevation or five hundred seven (507) feet above mean sea level.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Transitional surfaces. The height limitation along the intersection of the transitional surface zones and the approach-departure clearance surface are given in the following tabulations:</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-33, ยง 1, 5-21-68)</history></law>