<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVB. RU-RH, ROWHOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-202.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Development standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004131</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-202.7. Development standards.<section>A rowhouse development shall be designed in accordance with the following standards, and in accordance with the design standards contained in:<section prefix='(1)'>Lot size. The minimum lot size of a rowhouse lot shall be one thousand two hundred and fifty (1,250) square feet.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Density. The maximum number of dwelling units shall be twelve (12) units per net acre.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Common open space. Open space in the form of green(s) shall be provided in accordance with the following:<section>As used in this subsection, a rowhouse green(s) shall be a common open space placed to create focal point(s) in the neighborhood and shall be easily accessible. A rowhouse green shall include amenities such as landscaping, benches, pedestrian paths, gazebos, band shells, swimming pools, tennis courts, shuffleboards, community buildings, recreation buildings, maintenance buildings for common areas, lakes, canals and lagoons, other recreational uses, or entrance features. Entrance features that were not included or approved in the original site plan are permissible but shall require entrance feature review and approval by the Department and by a homeowners association or similar entity. Greens shall front on roads and/or residential development on at least three sides. Greens shall have a minimum width of thirty-five (35) feet and a maximum length of two hundred and seventy (270) feet, except a green may be up to four hundred and eighty (480) feet in length when rowhouse lots directly front the green along the lateral sides. Buildings shall not cover more than twenty (20) percent of a green. No parking shall be permitted on the green. Greens may be enclosed with wrought iron or electroplated aluminum picket fencing not exceeding forty-two (42) inches in height, which shall be seventy five (75) percent opaque.</section><section>Common open space, other than greens, may include, without limitation, recreational areas, sidewalks, water bodies, and tree preservation zones as defined by of this code.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Grouping length. A grouping of rowhouses shall not exceed two hundred forty (240) feet in length.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Frontage on Roads or Greens. Each rowhouse lot shall have a clear, direct frontage on public streets, private streets or to accessways complying with private street requirements, or on a green as defined in Section 33-202.7. No more than two rowhouse groupings may front on a green without an intersecting roadway. All rowhouse groupings fronting on a green shall be developed with a rear alley, public street or private street conforming to private street requirements. Greens that immediately abut the front of rowhouse groupings shall be designed to provide access for emergency vehicles. The design and surface material of such emergency accessways shall meet with the approval of the Miami-Dade County Fire Department.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Building height. The maximum height for any rowhouse unit shall be and forty (40) feet and the maximum number of stories shall be three (3) stories.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Setbacks.<section prefix='(a)'>Front. The front setback shall be a minimum of ten (10) feet, provided, however, that a front porch, bay window, awning, balcony, roof overhang, or handicap ramp may encroach into the front setback at varying dimensions up to eight (8) feet, as provided in Section 33-202.8(1) for optional setbacks and in Section 33-202.8(2)(a) for encroachments. No garages shall front on, nor shall parking spaces be located in, the front setback.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Rear. The rear setback shall be a minimum of five (5) feet. No structures including walls or fences shall be permitted within this setback area, except that an additional twenty four (24) inch roof overhang or stoop and utility equipment may encroach into the rear setback.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Side street. The minimum side street setback shall be ten (10) feet, of which half (50%) of the width shall be unencumbered by walls, fences or other structures or buildings. An additional twenty four (24) inch roof overhang, stoop or handicap ramp may encroach into the side street setback.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Spacing between buildings. A fifteen (15) foot unencumbered space shall be provided between groupings of rowhouses.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>Accessory buildings.<section>Accessory buildings shall not be permitted, except for detached private garages.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>Private garages.<section prefix='(a)'>All private garages shall be accessed from the rear of the unit. Garages may be credited toward required parking if, at the time of zoning or administrative site plan approval, a restrictive covenant approved in form and legal sufficiency by Miami-Dade County is recorded that permanently prohibits the enclosure of vehicular storage space on the first floor to create habitable living space.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Detached private garages shall be limited to two (2) stories in height. Within this height limit, habitable space for occupants of the unit may occur above the vehicular storage space on the first floor; no kitchen facilities shall be permitted.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Private open space. There shall be provided on each platted rowhouse lot at least three hundred (300) square feet of outdoor open space exclusive of parking and service area. Open roofed areas, balconies designed and planned for outdoor space, screened enclosures with a screened roof, patio slabs, swimming pools, decks, garden features, hot tubs, porches and stoops may be credited toward this open space requirement.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Parking. Parking requirements shall be in accordance with Section 33-124 of this code, provided that a minimum of two (2) spaces shall be provided for each rowhouse unit plus an additional one-quarter (.25) space per unit for guest parking. On-street parallel parking may be used for guest parking. Parking shall be prohibited in the front setback area. No perpendicular parking shall be permitted on roadways. Garages shall be credited toward required parking and garages shall be accessed from the rear of the lot.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Landscaping. Landscaping shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this code.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Utilities and services. Each rowhouse shall be independently served by separate heating, air conditioning, water, sewer, electricity, gas, or other utility services, and no rowhouse unit shall be in any way dependent upon such services or utility lines located within another unit or on or in another rowhouse site, except as may be installed in public easements. All water and sewer lines and all electrical and telephone lines in a rowhouse development site shall be placed underground. Proper and adequate access for fire fighting purposes, and access to service areas to provide garbage and waste collection, and for other necessary services shall be provided.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Additions. A homeowners' association shall review and approve, or deny, additions and exterior modifications to a rowhouse unit.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-96, ยง 1, 6-20-06)</history></law>