<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(J). NARANJA COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.69</section_number>
<catch_line>Regulating Plans.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004387</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.69. Regulating Plans.<section>The Regulating Plans consist of the following controlling plans as defined and graphically depicted in this section.<section prefix='A.'>The Street Types Plan establishes a hierarchy of street types in existing and future locations that shall be provided and shown in all development plans. The five (5) Street Types and the hierarchy of streets (from most important to least important in accommodating pedestrian traffic) are U.S. 1, Boulevard, Main Street, Minor Street, and Service Road.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Sub-districts Plan delineates three (3) sub-districts: the Core, Center and Edge. These sub-districts regulate the allowable intensity of development in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and this article.</section><section prefix='C.'>The Land Use Plan delineates the areas where specified land uses and development of various types and intensities will be permitted.</section><section prefix='D.'>The Building Heights Plan establishes the minimum and maximum allowable number of floors.</section><section prefix='E.'>The Designated Open Space Plan designates open spaces, which shall be shown in all development plans. The designated open spaces are controlled by anchor points.</section><section prefix='F.'>The New Streets Plan shows the location and the number of new streets needed to create the prescribed network of streets within the NCUC District. All new A streets are required in the same general location as shown on the New Streets Plan. All B streets shall be located as provided in Section 33-284.86(F) of this code.</section><section prefix='G.'>The Bike Route Plan depicts the designated bike routes, which shall be shown in all development plans.<section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-11, ยง 1, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 07-96, ยง 1, 7-10-07)</history></law>