<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(I). DOWNTOWN KENDALL URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.62</section_number>
<catch_line>Development parameters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004379</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.62. Development parameters.<section prefix='(A)'>Placement Diagrams. The following diagrams in this section identify design parameters specifically for the thirteen (13) Sub-district and frontage type situations.</section><section><section></section></section><section><section></section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section><section></section></section><section><section></section></section><section><section></section></section><section><section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>General Requirements. All new development and redevelopment shall comply with the following parameters irrespective of Sub-District and frontage categories:<section prefix='(1)'>Permitted Uses.<section prefix='(a)'>Permitted uses in Core and Center Sub-Districts shall be as follows:<section>All business and civic uses permitted in the BU-1, BU-1A, BU-2 Districts, and the following:</section><section prefix='i.'>Area for residential uses shall not require public hearing.</section><section prefix='ii.'>The following BU-3 uses shall be permitted:<section prefix='a.'>Bakeries, retail and wholesale.</section><section prefix='b.'>Cabinet working and carpentry shops.</section><section prefix='c.'>Locksmith shops.</section><section prefix='d.'>Secondhand stores.</section><section prefix='e.'>Television and broadcasting stations.</section><section prefix='f.'>Upholstery and furniture repairs.</section></section><section prefix='iii.'>Outside food sales and services including, but not limited to, outdoor dining, cart vendors, and merchandise displays shall not require public hearing.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Drive-in services shall be concealed from "A", "B" and "C" streets by buildings or garden walls.</section><section prefix='v.'>The provisions of Section 33-150(A) and (B) of this Code regarding alcoholic beverages shall not apply.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Land uses permitted in Edge Sub-Districts shall be as follows:<section prefix='1.'>Edge Sub-district west of SW 72nd Avenue and north of Snapper Creek Canal.<section prefix='i.'>All residential and civic uses permitted in the RU-4, RU-4A, and RU-4M Districts.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Up to one (1) percent of each building's floor area may be BU-1 business uses. Up to four (4) percent of each building's floor area that fronts a street or a square may have BU-1 business uses facing the street or square.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>Edge Sub-district east of U.S. Highway 1.<section prefix='i.'>All residential and civic uses permitted in the RU-4, RU-4M and RU-4A Districts.</section><section prefix='ii.'>All business and civic uses permitted in the BU-1, BU-1A, BU-2, BU-3, RU-5, RU-5A Districts, except as follows:</section><section prefix='iii.'>Area for residential uses shall not require public hearing.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Outside food sales and service including, but not limited to, outdoor dining, cart vendors, and merchandise displays shall not require public hearing.</section><section prefix='v.'>Drive-in services shall be concealed from "A", "B" and "C" streets by buildings or garden walls.</section></section><section>For Edge Sub-District properties east of US Highway 1 that border an adjacent residential zone, the buildings located within of one hundred (100) feet of the affected rear or side of the property boundary shall not exceed the adjacent district height restrictions by more than two (2) stories.</section><section>Primary access to all retail uses fronting on both a street and a paseo, or on both a street and a courtyard garden, shall be from the street.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Lots and Buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Minimum lot size is two thousand (2,000) square feet with a minimum frontage of twenty (20) feet.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All lots shall share a frontage line with a street or square.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each story shall be between eight (8) feet and fourteen (14) feet high from floor to ceiling. Floors more than fourteen (14) feet, as measured from floor to ceiling, will count as additional floors. Within the pedestal, one (1) story may exceed fourteen (14) feet, up to thirty (30) feet, provided no mezzanine area intended for commercial use exceeds ten (10) percent and no mezzanine area intended for residential use exceeds eighty (80) percent of the area of the floor immediately below.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No replatting or subdivision shall serve as a basis for deviating from this Article.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All buildings shall have their main pedestrian entrance opening to an "A", "B", "C", or "E" street, courtyard garden or square. There shall be pedestrian entrances at maximum intervals of seventy-five (75) feet along "A," and "B" Streets. When ground level uses have entries from both streets and other public open space, the primary entrance will be from the street. Doors facing streets shall remain operational during business hours.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Maximum building floorplates above eight stories for all uses shall be twenty thousand (20,000) square feet. Cantilever balconies six (6) feet or less in depth shall not be counted towards the maximum building floorplate area.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Minimum spacing between towers within any one (1) continuous property line is sixty (60) feet.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Aggregate tower frontage facing any street may not exceed two hundred twenty-five (225) feet per block or seventy (70) percent of street frontage, whichever is greater.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Where an "A" "B" or "D" street intersects with another street, the corner of the building may need to be chamfered (angled) or rounded to satisfy view triangle and minimum sidewalk width requirements, and to make room for traffic signal poles (see diagram 1). The angled wall of the building shall count toward frontage requirements for both streets that it fronts. In situations where the view triangle causes the front facade to "bend" at a shallow angle from the street, the angled or rounded wall may set back farther from the street intersection for esthetic and structural reasons. However, the setback shall not be farther than twenty (20) feet measured from the intersection of the two (2) property lines perpendicularly to the front plane of the angled wall. For curved walls this will be measured to the midpoint of the curve. The depth of the colonnade underneath the angled wall of the building shall also be a minimum of fifteen (15) feet.</section></section></section><section><section></section><section prefix='(j)'>Building design shall use energy conservation measures including, but not limited to, self-shading, natural lighting, natural ventilation, outdoor circulation, and reduced dependence on artificial lighting and air conditioning. Porches, balconies, breezeways, pergolas, deep eaves, eyebrows and other elements promoting natural ventilation and shading are encouraged. Each building shall dedicate a specific location for recycling separation, storage and access.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Vehicular entry gates at garage entries shall be positioned a minimum of twenty (20) feet behind the front wall of the building. At colonnaded frontages, this distance is measured from the interior/rear wall of the colonnade. To increase safety during off-hours, the setback area between the entry gate and the public sidewalk may be gated at the sidewalk edge during times when the garage is closed.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Exterior finish material shall be limited to concrete, stucco, quarried stone, cast stone, decorative concrete block, terra cotta, tile, metal, and glass. Wood and marble door and window surrounds are permitted, as are wood pergolas and trellises. Fabric awnings are permitted without back lighting.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Glazing and Transparency Requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Building streetwall surfaces shall be a minimum thirty (30) percent glazed. Mirror-type glass shall not be allowed. All glazing shall be of a type that permits view of human activities and spaces within. Glazing shall be clear or very lightly tinted, except where used for screening garages, where it may be translucent.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Storefronts shall be provided on the first floor, directly accessible from Public Space. Storefronts shall be a minimum of sixty (60) percent clear-glazed except for jewelry stores, which may be a minimum of twenty (20) percent, and for residential uses which may be a minimum of forty (40) percent. Except for entrance doors, the bottom edge of the glazed areas shall be between eighteen (18) and thirty-six (36) inches above the sidewalk.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Storefront security screens, if any, shall be of the mesh type that pedestrians can see through and shall be located behind storefront displays. Storefronts shall remain open to view and lit from within at night.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Parking garage and loading area security screens and gates shall be a minimum of fifty (50) percent transparent.</section></section><section prefix='(n)'>Colonnade column spacing, windows, and doors shall have a vertical proportion. The spacing of the columns of a colonnade, measured from the centerline of the columns, shall not be greater than the height of the colonnade.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Cantilevers and moldings shall not exceed three (3) feet in extension beyond the vertical wall surface, unless visibly supported by brackets or other supports.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Parking garages shall have all architectural expression facing public open space consistent and harmonious with that of habitable space. The architectural expression shall include vertically proportioned openings, balconies, glazing, awnings, or other similar architectural elements. Ramping is encouraged to be internalized wherever possible. Exposed spandrels are prohibited. The exposed top level of parking structures shall be covered a minimum of sixty (60) percent with a shade producing structure such as a vined pergola or retractable canvas shade structure. All garage lighting installations shall be designed to minimize direct spillage, sky glow and hazardous interference with vehicular traffic on adjacent rights-of-way and all adjacent properties; this may be achieved through the use of down-turned building beams, garage screening, landscaping, or other similar architectural elements.</section><section prefix='(q)'>No building fixtures such as backflow preventers, pumps, underground ventilation exhausts, substations or similar shall be permitted above the ground within colonnades, sidewalks and open spaces.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Streets, Alleys, and Paseos. New streets shall be located according to the Street Frontage Plan. These locations are schematic to allow flexibility in the design of the site plan. The design of new streets and modifications to existing streets shall follow the requirements below:<section prefix='(a)'>Streets shall provide access to all building lots and tracts.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All streets, alleys and paseos shall connect to other streets. Cul-de-sacs, and T-turnarounds are not permitted. Dead-end streets are only permitted for those shown on the Street Frontages Plan when the adjacent property has not been developed or redeveloped.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No block face shall have a length greater than three hundred and twenty-five (325) feet without a street, paseo, courtyard garden or alley providing through access to another street, alley, or paseo.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All new "A", "B" and "D" streets, both public and private, shall have a minimum right-of-way width of fifty-four (54) feet. All new "A", "B" and "D" streets shall have curb and gutter, and have sidewalks on both sides of the travel lanes. Where possible, there shall be parking lanes which in addition to on-street parking may be used for "drop off" areas, valet stands, or bus stops.<section prefix='i.'>All sidewalks shall have a minimum width of ten (10) feet, and a continuous unobstructed area of a width no less than sixty (60) inches. This area shall be unobstructed by utility poles, fire hydrants, benches or any other temporary or permanent structures. Free and clear public use of sidewalk area outside of the right-of-way shall be protected by a public access easement.</section><section prefix='ii.'>On-street parking lanes shall not be closer than twenty-five (25) feet to intersections measured from the intersecting property lines (see diagram 2).</section><section prefix='iii.'>All streets, except "C" streets, shall have at least two (2) travel lanes, one (1) in each direction; however, streets around squares may have one (1) travel lane with one-way traffic.</section></section></section></section><section><section></section><section prefix='(e)'>In addition to the required "D" streets designated in the Street Frontage Plan, "D" streets or alleys are encouraged to the rear of building lots.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Curb radii at intersections shall be thirty-four (34) feet six (6) inches or less.</section><section prefix='(g)'>A minimum turning radius of thirty-six (36) feet shall be provided at street intersections. A clear zone is required when the curb extends beyond the turnout radius.</section></section><section><section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Awnings, balconies, roof eaves, signs, porches stoops and ramps may encroach into setbacks. Awnings, balconies, roof eaves and signs may encroach into rights-of-way; however, they shall not extend a distance closer than six (6) inches from the curb face. All right-of-way encroachments shall be a minimum one hundred thirty-two (132) inches above the sidewalk. Encroachments shall not be taller than the building or pedestal, whichever is lower.</section><section prefix='(i)'>With the exception of fire hydrants, utilities shall run underground and above-ground projections of utilities shall be placed in or along rights-of-way of streets of lower pedestrian quality, wherever practicable.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Courtyard Gardens, Street and Garden Walls, Fences and Hedges. Street and garden walls, fences and hedges may be placed along property lines, at a height not to exceed ninety-six (96) inches, except in the Edge Sub-District, where side and rear yard walls are limited to seventy-two (72) inches in height. At street frontages, street and garden walls and fences shall be minimum fifty (50) percent transparent, and between thirty-six (36) inches and seventy-two (72) inches above grade for at least eighty (80) percent of the length. Pillars and posts shall average no more than ten (10) feet apart. Chain link fences are not permitted, except for temporary construction fences.<section>Only where necessary, walls, fences and hedges along street frontages shall angle away from street intersections and driveways to avoid obstructing the sight visibility triangles or to provide the minimum eight (8) foot sidewalk width at the intersecting streets.</section><section>A courtyard garden shall have at least two (2) sides enclosed by building walls; the remaining sides shall be enclosed by either fences or garden walls, and a minimum thirty (30) percent of its area shall be landscaped. The street opening to the courtyard garden shall not exceed the width of the street or square that it opens on to.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Open Space and Recreation Areas.<section prefix='(a)'>Private Open Spaces. A minimum of fifteen (15) percent of each net site shall be reserved for private open space. Colonnades, greens, landscaped roof terraces on buildings or garage structures can be counted towards this requirement.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Designated Open Spaces. Designated open space in the form of colonnades, squares and plazas shall be located according to the Designated Open Space Plan. All designated open spaces shall be at grade level and shall be accessible to the public. No replatting or other land division shall divide property in such a way that the provision of the required designated open space is avoided or its location changed. Designated open space areas provided in compliance with this section of the code shall count towards the private open space requirement provided herein.<section>Location, area and dimensions of the designated open spaces shall conform with the Designated Open Space Plan. Total square area must be in accordance with the Designated Open Space Plan; and the square must include the anchor point specified on the Designated Open Space Plan. At least three (3) corners of a square shall have a street intersection; and squares shall have a minimum dimension of one hundred fifty (150) feet between surrounding vehicular access ways.</section><section>Squares and plazas shall be densely shaded and provide seating. Trees and shrubs (shrubs are not permitted in plazas) shall be of sufficient quantity and located as to define a specific geometry of open space and shall promote security by allowing visibility through all areas. Ground surface shall be a combination of paving, lawn or ground cover integrated in design with trees and shrubs. Fountains, sculpture, and works of art are encouraged. Street furniture in squares such as trash containers and bus benches shall be permanently secured to the sidewalk. Street furniture shall not obstruct sight visibility triangles at street intersections.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Recreation Areas. Educational and child care facilities located within an Urban Center District shall be exempt from the outdoor recreation area requirements of Section 33-151.18(a) of this Code and shall be required to provide indoor and/or outdoor recreation areas subject to the following requirements:</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>Parking shall be provided as per Section 33-124 of this Code, except as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>In the Core Sub-District, for all single use projects, the minimum parking permitted shall be:<section prefix='i.'>Residential—One (1) parking space per dwelling unit.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Office—One (1) parking space per four-hundred (400) square feet of gross floor area.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Hotel—One (1) parking space for every two (2) guest rooms.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Other uses—Use parking standard as specified in Section 33-124 of this Code.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>In the Core Sub-District, required parking for mixed-use projects shall be calculated by applying the Urban Land Institute (ULI) Shared Parking Methodology, on file with the Director, to the parking standards above. Required parking shall fulfill between ninety (90) percent and one hundred ten (110) percent of the calculated requirement.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In the Center and Edge Sub-Districts, parking requirements for mixed-use projects shall be calculated by applying the (ULI) Shared Parking Methodology to the parking standards as specified in Section 33-124 of this Code. Parking shall fulfill between ninety (90) percent and one hundred ten (110) percent of the ULI calculated requirement.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Off-street parking areas shall be located on the same lot, parcel or premises as the use to be served; or may be on a lot or parcel of land that is in the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District and is within three hundred (300) feet from the site of such use(s) to be served; provided such use(s) shall immediately terminate in the event such parking area therefor is not available and all those having any right, title or interest in and to such property site shall execute and place on the public records of this County a covenant approved by the Director that such use(s) shall cease and terminate upon the elimination of such parking area, and that no use shall be made of such property until the required parking area is available and provided.</section><section prefix='(5)'>On-street parking spaces directly abutting a lot shall count toward the parking requirement for development of that lot, except that such spaces shall not count toward parking requirements for disabled persons or persons transporting baby strollers. All such on-street spaces shall be designed in accordance with the requirements of Section 33-284.62(C) of this code.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Surface parking lots shall be located a minimum of twenty (20) feet from the front property line along "A" and "B" Streets. Streetwalls and/or habitable space shall be built at the frontage line or at the build-to line to screen parking from view.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Parking garages shall be screened at all frontages except "D" streets by a minimum setback of twenty (20) feet of habitable space.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Parking garages on parcels of record as of the date of approval of this Article facing "A" streets that have a lot depth at any one (1) point of less than one hundred fifty (150) feet are required to provide habitable space only at the colonnade levels. However, architectural expression shall remain required as per this article.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Drop off drives and porte-cocheres fronting onto "A" or "B" street frontages may only occur behind habitable space, in courtyard gardens, on "C" and "D" streets, and alleys.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Loading and service entries shall be allowed only on "D" streets, alleys and within parking lots and structures. For those properties with frontages only on "A", "B" and "C" streets loading and servicing shall be allowed on the street frontage.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Pedestrian entries to parking garages shall be directly from the street or paseo as well as from the contiguous building. Pedestrian entries to garages shall be linked to cross-block paseos wherever possible.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Vehicular entries to garages shall be allowed only from rights-of-way, paseos and alleys. Vehicular entries on "A", "B", "C", and "E" frontages shall have a maximum width of thirty-three (33) feet with a minimum separation of seventy (70) feet between entries. On "D" streets they shall not be limited.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Parking lots shall provide for pedestrian and vehicular cross access to existing and prospective adjacent parking lots.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Parking stall dimensions and spaces for persons with disabilities and/or strollers shall be in accordance with Article VII of the Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Bicycle racks shall be provided on all sites as per Ordinance No. 99-81.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Mechanized parking shall be allowed for residential multi-family and non-residential buildings and when provided it shall be exempt from the provisions of Section 33-122 of this Code. For the purpose of this article, mechanized parking shall be defined as a mechanism with vertical and horizontal transport capability that provides for automobile storage or retrieval. A mechanized parking space may be counted as a parking space required in this section provided that:<section prefix='a.'>A queuing analysis is submitted and approved during the Administrative Site Plan and Architectural Review.</section><section prefix='b.'>Mechanized parking shall be located within an enclosed building/garage which shall be screened along all frontages, except along a service road or a pedestrian passage, by a liner building containing a minimum depth of 20 feet of habitable space.</section></section><section prefix='(m)'>The provisions of Section 33-131 of this Code shall not apply to the required parking for mixed-use developments.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Child care facilities located within a mixed-use building shall be exempt from the auto-stacking requirements of Section 33-151.18(c) of this Code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-166, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-156, §§ 1, 2, 9-25-01; Ord. No. 01-161, § 2, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-11, § 3, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 02-152, § 1, 9-12-02; Ord. No. 09-81, § 4, 9-1-09)</history></law>