<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(P). CUTLER RIDGE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (CRMUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.23</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose, intent and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004438</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.23. Purpose, intent and applicability.<section prefix='A.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Illustrative Master Plan (Figure 1), illustrates the citizens' vision and may be used to interpret this article. Where the Illustrative Master Plan conflicts with the text of this article, the text shall govern.</section><section prefix='C.'>The boundaries shown in Figure 1 that are labeled as 'Miami-Dade County' shall constitute the Cutler Ridge Metropolitan Urban Center Boundary Plan and are generally described as follows: from the intersection of the centerline of the SW 112 Avenue with the centerline of US 1, then south along the centerline of SW 112 Avenue to the north side of the C-1 Canal (Black Creek Canal), then west along the north side of the Black Creek Canal to the west side of the South Miami-Dade Busway, then north along the west side of the South Miami-Dade Busway to the centerline of SW 117 Avenue, then northwest along the centerline of SW 117 Avenue to the centerline of SW 114 Court, then north along the centerline of SW 114 Court to the centerline of SW 203 Terrace, then east along the centerline of SW 203 Terrace to the centerline of SW 112 Court, then south and southeast along the centerline of SW 112 Court to point of beginning.</section><section>A more detailed legal description of the boundaries follows:<section>Beginning at the intersection with the centerline of Black Creek Canal (C-1) and the west line of the Southeast one quarter of Section 7, Township 56 South, Range 40 East, Miami-Dade County Florida lying in SW 112th Avenue (Allapattah Road), thence westerly along the center line of Black Creek Canal (C-1) to the intersection with the East Right-of-Way of South Miami-Dade Bus way; thence north-easterly along the East Right-of-Way of South Miami-Dade Bus way to the intersection with theoretical extension of the Southwest Lot Line of Lot 1, block 12, of South Miami-Heights PB.72-PG.87; thence northwest along the theoretical extension of the Southwest Lot Line of Lot 1, block 12, of South Miami Heights PB.72-PG.87 to the intersection with the West Property Line of Lot 1 (SW Cor. of lot 1) Block 12, of South Miami Heights PB.72-PG.87; thence northeast along the West lot line of lot 1, block 12, South Miami Heights, PB.72-PG.87 to the intersection of the East Boundary Line of block 12, South Miami Heights PB.72-PG87; thence north along said Boundary Line to the intersection of the West Lot Line of Lot H of the Re-Subdivision of Cutler Gate PB.70-PG.100; then northeast along Lot Lines H, G, F, E of Re-Subdivision of Cutler Gate PB.70-PG.100 and Lot Lines 1 through 7, block 5, and Lot Lines 1 &amp; 2 block 4, of Cutler Gate PB.64-PG.77 to the intersection with the East Right-of-Way Line of SW 113 Road; thence northwesterly along the East Right-of-Way of SW 113 Road to a point on the West Right-of-Way of SW 114 Ave; thence south on the West Right-of-Way of SW 114 Ave. to the intersection of the North Lot Line of lot 15, block 1, of Cutler Gate PB.64 — PG.77; thence northwest along the North lot line of said lot 15, block 1 to the intersection with the East boundary line of block 12, of South Miami Heights PB.72-PG.87; thence north along the East boundary line of said block 12 to the intersection of the North boundary line of Tr.A and Tr.B of Old Cutler Ridge Crossing PB.148-PG.90; thence east along the North Boundary line of TR.A and TR.B. to the intersection with the East Boundary line of TR. B. of Old Cutler Crossing, plat book 148 at page 90; thence south along the East Boundary line of TR.B of Old Cutler Crossing plat book 148 at page 90 and a Southerly prolongation of the East Boundary line of TR.B. with the West line of the Northeast one quarter of Section 7 and the West line of the Southeast one quarter (SW 112 Avenue Allapattah Road) to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>Full scale maps of the Illustrative Master Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='D.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the Cutler Ridge Metropolitan Urban Center District (CRMUC) as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the CRMUC shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to CRMUC has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.<section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-152, § 1, 10-10-06)</history></law>