<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(I). DOWNTOWN KENDALL URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.63</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional parameters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004380</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.63. Additional parameters.<section>The following are required irrespective of frontage and Sub-District categories:<section prefix='(A)'>Landscape. With the exception of Sections 18A-7, 18A-8, 18A-9, 18A-11, 18A-12 and 18A-13, the provisions of Chapter 18A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall not apply, except as provided for below. Trees and landscape shall be required for streets, medians, squares, plazas, and private property in accordance with the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Street Trees: Street trees shall be placed along "B", "C" and "E" Streets at a maximum average spacing of twenty (20) feet on center. Street trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches and shall have a minimum clear trunk of eight (8) feet at the time of planting. Palms shall not be used as street trees. Street trees are not required when colonnades are provided along the street.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Median Trees: Median trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches and shall have a minimum clear trunk of eight (8) feet at time of planting. Median planting shall provide a one hundred (100) percent canopy coverage within two (2) years of installation. Median trees may be a maximum of twenty (20) percent flowering trees or palms, which at time of planting shall have a minimum height of fifteen (15) feet, a minimum spread of ten (10) feet, and a minimum caliper of three (3) inches.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Square and Plaza Trees: Trees on squares and plazas shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches and shall have a minimum clear trunk of eight (8) feet. Trees on squares and plazas shall provide a one-hundred (100) percent canopy coverage for eighty (80) percent of the entire square within five (5) years of installation. Trees for squares and plazas may be ten (10) percent palms of the following species: phoenix canariensis (Canary Island Date Palm); phoenix dactylifera (North African Date Palm); 'Medjool' (Date Palm); and 'Zahidi' (Date Palm); phoenix sylvestris (Wild Date Palm); roystonea elata (Florida Royal Palm) and regia (Cuban Royal Palm).</section><section prefix='(4)'>With the exception of squares as provided in Section 33.284.62 (C)(6) above, no shrubs are required.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Tree requirements for private property shall be based on sixteen (16) trees per net acre of lot area and, in addition to the lot, may be placed in squares, plazas and medians within the District. Trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches and shall have a minimum clear trunk of eight (8) feet at time of planting.</section><section prefix='(6)'>At grade parking lots shall follow all requirements of Section 18A(6)(J) of this Code.</section><section prefix='(7)'>All landscaped areas of squares and required setbacks shall be continuously maintained in a good, healthy condition, and sprinkler systems of sufficient size and spacing shall be installed to serve all required landscaped areas and parking lots. Irrigation shall supply a minimum of the equivalent one and one-half (1½) inch rainfall per week. Rain sensors shall be installed in all systems.</section><section prefix='(8)'>To ensure quality and longevity, the following additional conditions for tree planting in streets, medians, squares, and plazas shall apply:<section prefix='i.'>All trees shall be Florida Grade #1 or better.</section><section prefix='ii.'>All trees shall be shaped and branched typical for the species and variety.</section><section prefix='iii.'>A signed and sealed "Professional Preparer's Statement of Compliance" shall be submitted by the Project Landscape Architect at time of submission for Administrative Site Plan Approval (ASPR), zoning, or other approval.</section><section prefix='iv.'>A signed and sealed "Professional Preparer's Certification at time of Final Inspection" shall be submitted by the project Landscape Architect before a Certificate of Occupancy may be issued.</section><section prefix='v.'>A minimum of thirty (30) percent of the total of all trees or palms planted shall be of a native species.</section><section prefix='vi.'>A minimum six (6) foot by six (6) foot opening, clear of utilities, shall be provided for all trees.</section><section prefix='vii.'>Root barriers shall be provided for all tree plantings.</section><section prefix='viii.'>Tree grates or other approved devices shall be provided around all trees in hard surfaced areas to ensure adequate water and air penetration.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Signage. Three (3) types of signs are allowed: temporary signs, point of sale signs and directional signs. Outdoor advertising signs, automatic electric changing signs, and entrance features are not permitted. All signs shall not obstruct sight visibility triangles at street intersections. Lawful freestanding signs existing on December 16, 1999, shall be permitted to remain, and shall be permitted to be updated and maintained in substantial compliance with plans approved as of that date.<section prefix='(1)'>Temporary Signs.<section prefix='(a)'>Real Estate for sale, lease, or rent.<section prefix='(i)'>Size: One hundred fifty (150) square inches maximum.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Number: One (1) sign per street frontage.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Setback and Spacing: The outer edge of real estate signs shall be no closer than: five (5) feet to an official right-of-way line unless attached to an existing building; fifteen (15) feet to an interior side property line; or they shall be centered on a lot between interior side property lines.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Illumination: Section 33-96, Illumination, of this Code, shall apply, except that revolving, rotating and otherwise moving signs shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Maximum Height: Maximum height to top of sign shall be six (6) feet above grade for detached signs. For attached signs, minimum height shall be five (5) feet above grade.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Special Conditions: No permit shall be required for signs that are no larger than one hundred fifty (150) square inches and which are not electrically illuminated. Real estate signs shall only be permitted on premises advertised for lease or sale. Upon sale or lease, the sign shall be immediately removed.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Construction Signs.<section prefix='(i)'>Size: Thirty-two (32) square feet maximum for a detached sign. When construction signs are painted on an approved construction shed or trailer, there is no size limitation.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Number: One (1) per street frontage.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Setback and Spacing: The outer edge of the sign shall be no closer than zero (0) feet from official right of way, and five (5) feet minimum from property under different ownership.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Illumination: Section 33-96, Illumination, of this Code, shall apply, except that revolving, rotating and otherwise moving signs shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Maximum Height: Maximum height to top of sign shall be six (6) feet above grade for detached signs.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Special Conditions: No permit shall be required for signs that are no larger than thirty-two (32) square feet and which are not electrically illuminated. Construction signs shall only be permitted on premises visibly under construction. Upon sale or lease, the sign shall be immediately removed.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Special Event Signs.<section prefix='(i)'>Size: Thirty-two (32) square feet maximum for a detached sign.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Number: One (1) per street frontage.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Setback and Spacing: The outer edge of the sign shall be no closer than zero (0) feet from official right-of-way and five (5) feet minimum from property under different ownership.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Illumination: Section 33-96, Illumination, of this Code, shall apply, except that revolving, rotating and otherwise moving signs shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Maximum Height: Maximum height above grade to top of sign shall be six (6) feet for detached signs, except for suspended fabric signs.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Special Conditions: Back lit awnings and balloon signs are not allowed. Special event signs require permits and shall be removed within five (5) days after the special event or last election which candidate or issue was on ballot. Promoters, sponsors and candidates shall be responsible for compliance with the provisions of this section and shall remove signs promoting or endorsing their respective special events or candidacies when such signs are displayed or used in violation of this section. Additionally, any private owner who fails to remove an unlawful special events sign from his or her property shall be deemed in violation of this section.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>No sign shall exhibit thereon any lewd or lascivious matter.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Permanent Point of Sale Signs.<section prefix='(a)'>Permanent point of sale signs in the Edge Sub-District North of Snapper Creek Canal and west of US Highway 1: Detached, flat, awning, projecting, pylon signs are all allowed:<section prefix='(i)'>Size: Maximum six (6) square feet except for churches, schools and universities which are permitted twenty-four (24) square feet. Cantilever projecting signs shall be mounted perpendicular to buildings.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Number: One (1) sign per tenant per street frontage.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Setback and spacing: The outer edge of the sign shall be no closer than zero (0) feet from right-of-way, and five (5) feet minimum from interior side property.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Illumination: Section 33-96, Illumination, of this Code, shall apply, except that revolving, rotating and otherwise moving signs shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Maximum Height: Four (4) feet maximum height above grade to top of sign for detached signs; nine (9) feet minimum from bottom of sign to grade for awning and projecting signs; no limits for flat attached signs, or signs painted on the facade of a building.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Special Conditions: No permit required for awnings following these regulations. Letters attached or painted to fabric shall be limited to the identification of the occupant and/or use of the property. Back-lit awnings and balloon signs are not allowed. Decorative neon may be used only inside windows. Building name and quotations carved in stone or stucco relief may occupy up to ten (10) percent of facade.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>No sign shall exhibit thereon any lewd or lascivious matter.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Permanent point of sale signs in the Core and Center Sub-Districts and in the Edge Sub-District north of Snapper Creek Canal and East of US Highway 1: Detached, flat, awning, projecting, pylon and marquee are all allowed:<section prefix='(i)'>Size: Twenty-four (24) square feet maximum, except eight (8) square feet maximum for cantilever projecting signs, which shall be mounted perpendicular to buildings. Further, in the Edge Sub-District north of Snapper Creek Canal and East of U.S. Highway 1 flat wall signs are permitted at a maximum size no greater than seven and one half (7.5) percent of the wall area for the first fifteen (15) feet of building height and 1.5 percent for each foot of building height above the 15 feet measured to the bottom of the sign.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Number: One (1) of each sign type, up to a total of three (3) per street frontage for each tenant.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Building identification wall signs shall be permitted in the Core and Center Sub-Districts above the eighth floor. One (1) sign per frontage is permitted, each sign shall be a maximum of three hundred (300) square feet.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Setbacks and Spacing: The outer edge of the sign shall be no closer than zero (0) feet from right-of-way and five (5) feet minimum from side or rear property line.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Illumination: Section 33-96, Illumination, of this Code, shall apply, except that revolving, rotating and otherwise moving signs shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Maximum Height: Four (4) feet maximum height above grade to top of sign for detached signs.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Special Conditions: No permit required for awnings following these regulations. Letters attached or painted to fabric shall be limited to the identification of the occupant and/or use of the property. Back-lit awnings and balloons signs are not allowed. Decorative neon may be used only inside windows. Building name and quotations carved in stone or stucco relief may occupy up to ten (10) percent of a facade.</section><section prefix='(viii)'>No sign shall exhibit thereon any lewd or lascivious matter.</section></section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Directional Signs. Directional signs, to direct traffic flow and locate entrances and exits shall be permitted on private property in connection with any permitted use provided they do not exceed three (3) square feet in area and do not exceed four (4) feet in height above grade; and providing they are shown and approved on site plans which indicate sign size, location, copy, etc. Logos, names and advertising are not permitted on such signs.<section>Maintenance: In addition to the general maintenance requirements for this section, the owner and/or the tenant of the sign shall be responsible for maintaining the landscaping and the signs concerned in good condition and appearance and the site free from trash or debris. Failure to do so shall constitute cause for cancellation of the permit and removal of the sign, if owner and/or tenant fails to correct same within ten (10) days after written notice of nonconformance.</section><section>Removal of dilapidated signs. The Director may cause to be removed any sign which shows neglect or become dilapidated or where the area around such sign is not maintained as provided herein after due notice has been given. The owner and/or tenant of the sign and/or the property shall be financially responsible for the removal of the sign.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-166, § 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 02-11, § 4, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 05-197, § 2, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 09-81, § 5, 9-1-09)</history></law>