<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00046' order_by='00046' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXII. IU-C, INDUSTRIAL DISTRICT, CONDITIONAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-273</section_number>
<catch_line>Setbacks.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004290</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-273. Setbacks.<section prefix='(1)'>Minimum building setback from front property line shall be twenty-five (25) feet on parcels of up to two (2) acres (net) in size. For parcels of two (2) acres (net) or more, the minimum building setback from front property line shall be fifteen (15) percent of the lesser dimension of the property proposed for use, but the maximum front setback need not be greater than fifty (50) feet and the minimum such setback shall be not less than twenty-five (25) feet.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Minimum building setback from side property line abutting a highway right-of-way shall be twenty-five (25) feet.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Minimum building setback from interior side property line shall be ten (10) feet.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Minimum setback from rear property line on a through lot shall be the same as required for the front setback of the particular lot concerned.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Rear setbacks shall be as follows: twenty (20) feet from a residential district boundary, provided that credit shall be given for full width of dedicated alleys in computing this setback; five (5) feet from a business or industrial district boundary where any openings are provided int he wall of a proposed structure adjacent to the rear lot line; zero feet from a business or industrial district boundary where no openings are proposed in the wall of a proposed structure adjacent to the rear lot line. The rear setbacks established above shall also apply to accessory buildings.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-40, § 2(C)(5), 10-7-58; Ord. No. 68-8, § 1, 2-21-68; Ord. No. 69-51, § 4, 9-3-69; Ord. No. 79-100, § 1, 11-20-79; Ord. No. 80-89, § 2, 9-2-80; Ord. No. 83-56, § 1, 7-5-83)</history></law>