<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00062' order_by='00062' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(N). PERRINE COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (PECUCD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004423</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.8. Uses.<section>Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the PECUC shall comply with of this code.<section prefix='A.'>Permitted Uses. The following uses shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='1.'>In the Residential (R) area, all uses provided in Section 33-284.83(A)(1), except that rowhouses shall be permitted only in those areas specifically designated as permitting rowhouses in the Land Use Regulating Plan, as provided in Section 33.284.99.9 of this article.<section prefix='2.'>In the Mixed-Use Corridor (MC) area, all uses provided in Section 33-284.83(A)(3) and the following uses:<section prefix='(A)'>Automobile and truck services and facilities including:<section prefix='(1)'>Open lot car and truck sales new or used, including as ancillary uses, automobile repairs, body and top work and painting, provided that no more than fifteen (15) percent of the gross building area is devoted to such ancillary uses, and subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That attention attractive devices, such as blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers and all fluttering, spinning advertising devices (either mobile or stationary) are prohibited.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That outdoor lighting shall be designed to avoid spilling beyond the site boundaries.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That no vehicular test drives shall be conducted on residential local traffic streets (fifty-foot right-of-way or less).</section><section prefix='(d)'>That the applicant obtains a certificate of use, which shall be automatically renewable yearly upon compliance with all terms and conditions.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Open lot car rental.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Automobile parts, secondhand from store building only.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Automobile body and top work and painting.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Engines, gas, gasoline, steam and oil; sales and service.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Garage or mechanical service. Including automobile repairs, body and top work and painting. All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Glass installation.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Self-service mini-warehouse storage facility in compliance with Section 33-255(23.1) of this code.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Tire vulcanizing and retreading or sale of use tires.</section><section prefix='(G)'>Truck storage, only within an enclosed building or an area enclosed by a CBS wall.</section><section prefix='(H)'>Automobile washing.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Industrial uses. Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 33-284.83(A)(4), only the following uses shall be permitted in the Industrial District (ID) area. These uses shall be allowed in conformance with the Land Use Regulating Plan and the Street Type Development Parameters.<section prefix='(A)'>All uses permitted in the IU-1 zoning district.</section><section prefix='(B)'>All uses permitted in the IU-2 zoning district after public hearing pursuant to Section 33-311(A)(3) of this code.</section><section prefix='(C)'>All uses permitted in the Mixed-Use Corridor (MC) on lots located north of SW 184 Street and east of the Busway.</section><section prefix='(D)'>All uses permitted in the Mixed-Use Optional (MO) on lots located north of SW 184 Street and west of the Busway.</section></section><section prefix='4.'>In the Mixed-Use Corridor/Industrial (MCI) area, all uses permitted in the MC and ID areas, as provided in this section. Development in the MCI area shall comply with the Mixed-Use Building or Industrial Building placement standards provided in Section 33-284.85. Notwithstanding any other provisions to the contrary, Industrial uses in the MCL area shall be exempt from minimum height and density requirements.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-127, ยง 1, 9-12-06; Ord. No. 07-97, ยง 1, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 11-30, ยง 1, 5-3-11)</history></law>