<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00050' order_by='00050' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIB. PLANNED DEVELOPMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.14</section_number>
<catch_line>Densities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004325</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.14. Densities.<section>Total dwelling units permitted in the planned development shall be determined by multiplying the net acreage of each differently zoned parcel by the number of units permitted by the underlying residential zoning for said parcel, and adding the resulting number of units for each differently zoned parcel. The resulting number of dwelling units is the total permitted dwelling units unless otherwise modified by provisions included herein. If a prior density limitation was set by County Commission, Zoning Appeals Board or Community Zoning Appeals Board resolution or other document(s) filed for public record, then the total densities shall not exceed densities established by said documents.</section><section>If an RU-4A Zone is part of a planned development, and hotels and/or motel units are proposed in the planned development, the total number of units used in computing the units per acre permitted in the RU-4A Zone shall be fifty (50) or any number less than fifty (50) established by County Commission or Community Zoning Appeals Board resolution or other documents filed for public record which have previously limited density. If fewer than the permitted maximum number of hotel/motel units are proposed in the planned development, the remaining hotel/motel units can be converted to other types of residential dwelling units in the planned development. If an RU-4A parcel is to be used as part of a planned development, the proposed uses shall not be other than hotel, motel, and/or apartment units.</section><section>The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall have the authority to approve an increase in the total number of dwelling units established above by ten (10) percent provided that:<section prefix='(a)'>The total densities do not exceed fifty (50) units per net acre.</section><section prefix='(b)'>An increase in densities will not violate any criteria established in planning studies approved by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The increase in densities will not overcrowd the proposed development.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The increase in densities will not violate any recorded restriction(s) which has (have) been established byCounty Commission or Community Zoning Appeals Board resolution or other documents that previously established density limitations.</section></section><section>The fact that a parcel is divided by or contains within the parcel platted streets shall not disqualify the parcel for a planned development under this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-28, § 2, 3-20-73; Ord. No. 73-80, § 1, 9-18-73; Ord. No. 74-41, § 1, 6-4-74; Ord. No. 78-39, § 5, 6-6-78; Ord. No. 96-127, § 24, 9-4-96)</history></law>