<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00053' order_by='00053' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIE. OFFICE PARK DISTRICT (OPD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.30</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004345</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.30. Uses permitted.<section prefix='(A)'>No land, body of water and/or structures shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, moved, reconstructed, or structurally altered or maintained in any OPD District, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, unless otherwise herein provided, excepting for one (1) or more of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>Principal uses. Principal uses are those permitted uses that will form the major use concentration within the office park complex and include the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Office buildings for business, professional and secretarial uses that cater to the provision of services. Retail and industrial activities are not permitted as principal uses.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Laboratories for scientific and industrial research and development, including the use of scientific laboratory equipment and devices, shall be permitted. Assembly of precision instruments requiring a clinical environment in conjunction with scientific and medical research and development is also permitted upon approval of the Director. Any dust, fumes, gases, noises, odors and vibrations resulting from industrial or scientific research shall be completely contained within an enclosed building. It shall be the applicant's responsibility to provide sufficient data demonstrating that all potential impacts as listed above are so contained.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Commuter colleges/universities.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Accessory uses. Accessory uses are those uses that are associated with the principal use(s) and which provide service primarily to employees and patrons of the office park. The accumulative total of all accessory uses shall be limited to a maximum of fifteen (15) percent of the total gross interior square footage of the buildings proposed for the site. Such uses shall have no outside advertising. Areas devoted to structure parking shall not be included in the above calculations. Service facilities shall constitute the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Auditorium(s).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Eating establishments such as a cafeteria, coffee shop, food carry-out, restaurant and sandwich shop. Liquor, beer and wine, if associated with normal restaurant operation, shall be permitted under the terms specified in the BU-1 District. Drive-in facilities are prohibited.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Office and stationery supplies.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Personal services such as:<section prefix='(i)'>Banks and savings and loans;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Barbershop;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Beauty shop;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Chapel;</section><section prefix='(v)'>Day care center, nursery and kindergarten, subject to compliance with the requirements of sections 33-151.11 through 33-151.22 of this code;</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Dry cleaning and laundry (pickup only, no cleaning or washing on premises);</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Newsstands;</section><section prefix='(viii)'>Shoe repair shop and shoeshine parlor;</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Tobacco shops;</section><section prefix='(x)'>Adult day care center.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Pharmacies restricted to the preparation and sale of drugs and medicines and other pharmaceutical supplies.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Print shops.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Private clubs.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Recreational facilities within enclosed structures:<section prefix='(i)'>Court games;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Putting greens;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Saunas;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Swimming pool.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>Other similar uses as approved by the Director, provided such uses are primarily accessory uses to the principal office park use(s).</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>All uses shall be within enclosed building(s) except for approved passive and active recreational uses.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 77-64, § 1, 9-20-77; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 02-46, § 8, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 09-102, § 6, 11-17-09; Ord. No. 11-04, § 8, 2-1-11)</history></law>