<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIX. IU-1, INDUSTRIAL, LIGHT MANUFACTURING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-259</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004263</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-259. Uses permitted.<section>No land, body of water or structure shall be used or permitted to be used and no structure shall be erected, constructed, moved or reconstructed, structurally altered, or maintained, which is designed, arranged or intended to be used or occupied for any purpose, unless otherwise provided herein, in IU-1 District, excepting for one (1) or more of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Residential uses as a watchman's or caretaker's quarters in connection with an existing industrial use located on the premises concerned.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Adult entertainment uses as defined in Section 33-259.1, subject to all the restrictions and spacing requirements contained in said Section 33-259.1</section><section prefix='(2.1)'>Adult day care center.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Aircraft hangars and repair shops, aircraft assembling and manufacturing.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Animal hospitals within soundproof, air-conditioned buildings.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Armories, arsenals.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Auditoriums.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Auto painting, top and body work.*</section><section prefix='(7.2)'>Automobile self-service gas stations shall be permitted only on major access roads, including major roadways (three or more lanes) and frontage roadways serving limited access expressways, and shall be subject to the conditions enumerated in Section 33-247(6) of this code.</section><section prefix='(7.3)'>Automobile service stations shall be permitted only on major access roads, including major roadways (three or more lanes) and frontage roadways serving limited access expressways, and shall be subject to the conditions enumerated in Section 33-247(5) of this code.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Automobile and truck sales for new and/or used vehicles including as ancillary uses automobile and truck rentals, wholesale distribution and automobile repairs, provided that no more than fifteen (15) percent of the total gross building area is devoted to repair/service bays, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That a continuous, densely planted greenbelt of not less than fifteen (15) feet in width, penetrated only at points approved by the Directors of the Planning and Zoning and Public Works Departments for ingress and egress to the property, shall be provided along all property lines abutting public rights-of-way or properties zoned residential. Said greenbelt shall have shade trees planted at a maximum spacing of thirty (30) feet on center and a hedge of a minimum of six (6) feet in height abutting residentially zoned property and a minimum of three (3) feet in height abutting public rights-of-way. The shade trees shall have a minimum caliper of two and one-half (2½) inches at time of planting.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A minimum of twenty (20) percent of the net lot area of the site shall be developed as landscaped open space.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That such uses be located only on major access roads, including major roadways (three (3) or more lanes) and frontage roadways serving limited access highways and expressways.</section><section prefix='(d)'>That such uses on sites of ten (10) acres or more shall be approved only after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(e)'>That such uses be conducted on sites consisting of at least two (2) acres.</section><section prefix='(f)'>That attention attracting devices, such as blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers and all fluttering, spinning advertising devices (either mobile or stationary) are prohibited, except as permitted under point of sale sign regulations, or as approved at public hearing.</section><section prefix='(g)'>That outdoor loudspeakers are prohibited.</section><section prefix='(h)'>That outdoor lighting shall be designed to avoid spilling beyond the site boundaries.</section><section prefix='(i)'>That no vehicular test drives shall be conducted on residential local traffic streets (fifty-foot right-of-way or less).</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>Automotive repairs.*</section><section prefix='(10)'>Automobile and truck rentals and wholesale distribution.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Bakeries—wholesale only with incidental retail uses.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Banks.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Blacksmith, gas steam fitting shops.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Boat or yacht repairing or overhauling, or boat building.*</section><section prefix='(15)'>Boat slips used for the tying up of boats for the purpose of overhauling or repairing.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Bottling plants.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Brewery.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Cabinet shops.*</section><section prefix='(19)'>Canning factories.*</section><section prefix='(20)'>Carpet cleaning.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Caterers.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Clubs, private.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Cold storage warehouses and precooling plants.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Commercial chicken hatcheries.*</section><section prefix='(24.1)'>Commuter colleges/universities.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Concrete, clay or ceramic products, hand manufacture or involving only small mixer where all such manufacturing and equipment is within an approved building and storage and drying areas are enclosed as provided in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(26)'>Contractors' offices and yards.</section><section prefix='(27)'>Day nursery, kindergarten, schools and after school care licensed by the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services and established in accordance with the requirements of Article XA provided, however, that schools may only be located on a site consisting of at least five (5) acres and adjacent to a major roadway (three (3) or more lanes).</section><section prefix='(27.1)'>Dog kennels, as an exception to Section 33-260, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>All outdoor exercise runs shall be set back fifty (50) feet from property lines and shall not be located closer than five hundred (500) feet from residentially zoned or residentially developed property. Where outside exercise runs are provided, a landscaped buffer or decorative masonry wall shall enclose the runs, and use of the runs shall be restricted to use during daylight hours.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Where outside exercise runs are not provided, an outside area shall be designated for dogs (or cats) to relieve themselves, and that area shall be enclosed by a landscape buffer or masonry wall. Additionally such area shall be set back fifty (50) feet from property lines and shall not be located closer than five hundred (500) feet from residentially zoned or residentially developed property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All kennel buildings shall be soundproofed and air-conditioned.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An administrative site plan review (ASPR) shall be required. The site plan shall show all fencing, berms, and soundproofing designed to mitigate the noise impact of the kennel on the surrounding properties.</section></section><section prefix='(28)'>Dredging base or place where dredging supplies are kept and where dredges or boats or machinery are stored, repaired or rebuilt.*</section><section prefix='(29)'>Dry cleaning and dyeing plants.</section><section prefix='(29.1)'>Electric substation.</section><section prefix='(30)'>Engine sales and service, gas, oil, steam, etc.</section><section prefix='(31)'>Fertilizer storage.*</section><section prefix='(32)'>Food products, including the grinding, cooking, roasting, preserving, drying, smoking or airing of meats, fish, fruits or vegetables (where more than five (5) persons are employed on premises).</section><section prefix='(33)'>Fruit packing and fruit preserving.</section><section prefix='(34)'>Furniture manufacturing.*</section><section prefix='(35)'>Furniture refinishing.</section><section prefix='(36)'>Garages—storage mechanical, including trucks, buses, heavy equipment.</section><section prefix='(37)'>Glass installations.</section><section prefix='(38)'>Grinding shops.*</section><section prefix='(39a)'>Hotel and motel use (freestanding); the use shall comply fully with all provisions, pertaining to the use, of the RU-4A District.</section><section prefix='(39b)'>Hotel and motel use (mixed use, i.e., connected with, and attached to a structure containing another use permitted in the industrial district); subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>Minimum lot width and area: The minimum lot width shall be three hundred thirty (330) feet and the minimum lot area five (5) acres including right-of-way dedications made from the property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Lot coverage: There shall be no restriction on lot coverage except as it might be controlled by other specific requirements.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Setbacks: The setbacks shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Thirty-five (35) feet from all property lines to that portion of the structure not exceeding three (3) stories in height and not exceeding thirty-five (35) feet in height.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A distance from all property lines to any portion of the tower structure above three (3) stories in height equal to seventy (70) percent of the overall height of the tower, the height being measured from the third-floor level (but not exceeding thirty-five (35) feet) to the top of the tower structure.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Height: There shall be no limitation as to height except those applicable under the airport zoning regulations.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Floor area ratio: No limitation.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Maximum number of units: The number of dwelling units shall not exceed a density of seventy-five (75) dwelling units per net acre, based on thirty-three and one-third (33) percent of the entire building site.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Parking: Parking shall be provided for the combined uses in a total number as may be required elsewhere in the Code for each of the uses on the property.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Open space: There shall be provided open landscaped space equal to a minimum of fifteen (15) percent of the lot area (entire site) in all the industrial districts except that in the IU-C District a minimum of twenty (20) percent shall be provided.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Accessory uses:<section prefix='(a)'>Business or commercial establishments of the BU-1 type, bars and cabarets shall be permitted in motels and hotels provided they are located within the principal building, which contains at least one hundred (100) units, and provided the exterior of any such principal building shall not have storefronts or give the appearance of commercial or mercantile activity as viewed from the highway: in the event the use contains windows which may be seen from the street or highway, said windows shall be of fixed, obscure glass. Such business or commercial establishments and bars in this district shall be entered only through the lobby, and no additional entrances shall be permitted except when the same opens into a courtyard or patio (away from the street side) which is enclosed and which is not visible from the street, and except that a fire door or emergency exit shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Hotels and motels with one hundred fifty (150) or more guest rooms may contain liquor package use on the premises for the accommodation and use of their guests only, provided the establishment housing such use is entered only through the lobby within the building and does not have the appearance of commercial or mercantile activity as viewed from the highway. No advertisement of the use will be permitted which can be seen from the outside of the building.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Hotels and motels with two hundred (200) or more guest rooms under one (1) roof may contain a night club on the premises, provided the exterior of any such building shall not have storefronts or give the appearance of commercial or mercantile activity as viewed from the highway. In the event the use contains windows which may be seen from the highway, said windows shall be of fixed obscure glass. Such night club shall be entered only through the lobby, and no additional entrance shall be permitted except when the same opens into a courtyard or patio (away from street side) which is enclosed and which is not visible from the street, and except that a fire door or exit shall be permitted.</section></section></section><section prefix='(40)'>Ice manufacturing.</section><section prefix='(41)'>Insecticide, mixing, packaging and storage.*</section><section prefix='(42)'>Laboratories, material testing.</section><section prefix='(43)'>Leather goods manufacturing, excluding tanning.</section><section prefix='(44)'>Livery stables, for riding clubs, or a stable for sheltering horses, not closer than three hundred (300) feet to an RU or EU District.</section><section prefix='(45)'>Locksmiths.</section><section prefix='(46)'>Lumberyards.*</section><section prefix='(47)'>Machine shops.</section><section prefix='(48)'>Marine warehouses.</section><section prefix='(49)'>Mattress manufacturing and renovating.</section><section prefix='(50)'>Metalizing processes.</section><section prefix='(51)'>Milk or ice distributing station from which extensive truck or wagon deliveries are customarily made.</section><section prefix='(52)'>Millwork shops.*</section><section prefix='(53)'>Motion picture production studios.</section><section prefix='(54)'>Novelty works.</section><section prefix='(55)'>Office buildings.</section><section prefix='(56)'>Ornamental metal workshops.*</section><section prefix='(56.1)'>Outdoor dining as an ancillary use in conjunction with restaurants, snack shops and other food service facilities where the primary use is the preparation of food for consumption on premises, shall be permitted subject to the following restrictions:<section prefix='(a)'>The outdoor dining area shall be managed, operated and maintained as an integral part of the immediately adjacent food service facility; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>The outdoor dining area shall not reduce required parking or landscaping for the site; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>The outdoor seating area shall be included in the calculations for required parking; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>There shall be no outdoor cooking or food preparation; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>No outdoor dining area shall obstruct or impede pedestrian traffic; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>The outdoor dining area shall comply with handicapped accessibility requirements; and</section><section prefix='(g)'>No outside public address system shall be permitted. Unamplified music shall be permitted in the outdoor dining area, subject to compliance with Section 21-28 of this Code; and</section><section prefix='(h)'>Blinking and flashing type lighting shall be prohibited; and</section><section prefix='(i)'>Alcoholic beverages may be served where such service is strictly incidental to the service of food and is from a service bar only, subject to compliance with the regulations specified in Article X (Alcoholic Beverages) of this chapter; and</section><section prefix='(j)'>The use shall be subject to plan review and approval through the building permit review process. The plans for such use shall include all restrooms, furniture, umbrellas, lighting, and other related services and functions associated with the proposed use, together with all required and provided parking calculations. Plans shall be subject to all the applicable building and zoning code regulations; and</section><section prefix='(k)'>The use shall require a Certificate of Use which shall be renewed annually and shall be subject to revocation upon violation of any applicable building and zoning code regulations, or when a continuation of the permit would constitute a hazard or nuisance.</section></section><section prefix='(57)'>Oxygen storage and filling of cylinders.</section><section prefix='(58)'>Parking lots—commercial and noncommercial.</section><section prefix='(59)'>Passenger and freight—stations and terminals—boats, trucks, buses, and railroads.</section><section prefix='(60)'>Pharmaceutical storage, subject to compliance with the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That the applicant secure a license from the State of Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services (HRS) for such pharmaceutical storage.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the pharmaceutical storage area shall be air conditioned to continuously control temperature and humidity as required by HRS for pharmaceutical products.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That the premises be secured with a security system as required by HRS for the storage of pharmaceutical products.</section><section prefix='(d)'>That a declaration of use be provided permitting a building and zoning enforcement officer to enter the premises to conduct inspection to assure compliance.</section><section prefix='(e)'>That upon compliance with the conditions enumerated above, a certificate of use and occupancy is secured from the Department.</section></section><section prefix='(61)'>Police and fire stations.</section><section prefix='(62)'>Post offices, which shall include self-service post offices, stations and branches, and mail processing centers.</section><section prefix='(63)'>Power or steam laundries.</section><section prefix='(64)'>Printing shops.</section><section prefix='(65)'>Radio and television transmitting stations and studios.</section><section prefix='(66)'>Religious facilities located inside the Urban Development Boundary. Religious facilities outside the Urban Development Boundary will be permitted only upon approval after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(67)'>Restaurants.</section><section prefix='(67.1)'>Restaurants with an accessory cocktail lounge-bar use, subject to compliance with Article X, Alcoholic Beverages, of this Code.</section><section prefix='(68)'>Salesrooms and storage show rooms—wholesale.</section><section prefix='(69)'>Salesrooms and showrooms, subject to the prohibitions and limitations in Subsection (b), incorporated as a part of a permitted industrial use upon compliance with the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>Any industrial use and its related retail sales/showroom uses in different units or bays within the same building must be under one (1) certificate of use and occupancy, and all areas under one (1) such certificate must be connected by communicating doors between units or bays.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Only merchandise which is warehoused, stored, manufactured or assembled on the premises can be sold on a retail basis.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The size of retail sales/showroom floor area must be less than fifty (50) percent of the total floor area of the subject premises under a single certificate of use and occupancy. Outside storage areas are to be excluded from consideration in determining the percentage of uses.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A solid wall shall separate retail sales/showroom area from the balance of the industrial area which shall prevent public access to the industrial portion of the building. The industrial use area shall not be accessible to the general public.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Required parking is to be calculated based upon the floor area assigned to the use classifications within the building in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-124</section><section prefix='(6)'>A declaration of use in a form meeting with the approval of the Director shall be submitted to the Department prior to the issuance of a certificate of use and occupancy specifying compliance with the foregoing conditions. Said declaration of use shall include a floor plan for the intended use as required by the Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Subsection (a) above is intended to permit retail salesrooms and showrooms in recognition of the compatibility and reasonableness of incorporating certain retial uses into the other uses permitted in this district. To assure said compatibility and reasonableness, the retail uses hereinafter enumerated, and uses similar thereto, shall be subject to the following additional conditions: (1) the primary and permitted industrial use shall be the manufacture or assembly of the products being offered for sale; and (2) the retail sales area shall not exceed fifteen (15) percent of the total floor area of the subject premises under a single certificate of use and occupancy. The retail uses subject to the conditions of this subsection are:<section prefix='(1)'>Antique and secondhand goods shops.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Apparel stores.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Art and crafts supplies and finished products.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Art galleries.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Bait and tackle shop.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Bakeries.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Bicycle sales, rentals and repairs (nonmotorized).</section><section prefix='(8)'>Card shops.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Confectionery, ice cream stores and dairy stores.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Drugstores.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Florist shops.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Furniture stores less than ten thousand (10,000) square feet.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Gift stores.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Grocery stores, supermarkets, fruit stores, health food stores, meat and fish markets and other similar food stores.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Hardware stores less than ten thousand (10,000) square feet.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Jewelry stores.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Leather goods and luggage shops.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Liquor package stores.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Optical stores.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Paint and wallpaper stores less than ten thousand (10,000) square feet.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Photograph studio and photo supply.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Pottery shops.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Shoe stores and shoe repair shops.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Sporting good stores.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Tobacco shops.</section><section prefix='(26)'>Variety stores and junior and major department stores.</section><section prefix='(27)'>Retail uses determined by the Director to be similar to those enumerated above. In determining similarity between a proposed use and the uses enumerated above the Director shall be guided by the intent of this Subsection and shall consider common characteristics including the nature of products offered for sale, the generation of pedestrian and vehicular traffic, and incompatibility with the primary uses permitted in this district.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Failure to comply with any of the provisions of Subsection (a) or (b) shall be deemed a change in use from an industrial to retail business use for which a use variance shall be required.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any ancillary retail sales use pursuant to a lawful, valid, permanent certificate of use and occupancy issued by the Department prior to July 29, 1983, which use is in compliance with the Department's percentage of use and parking requirements on said effective date will be considered a legal, nonconforming use. Legal, nonconforming use status will also be granted to any ancillary retail sales use for which a certificate of use and occupancy has not been issued as of July 29, 1983, where the property owner or tenant:<section prefix='(1)'>Has obtained a building permit based on the submission of plans on which the intended retail sales area has been clearly represented by physical separation from the industrial use through placement of a solid wall, and adequate parking for the retail sales use and landscaping has been provided, and said permit remains valid in accordance with the provisions of the South Florida Building Code; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Has submitted a declaration of use, parking plan and floor plan for an existing building which have been approved by the Department provided that a physical separation of the retail and industrial uses has been effected through placement of a solid wall and a temporary certificate of use and occupancy as provided in the South Florida Building Code has been obtained from the Department before July 29, 1983. Legal nonconforming use status will not be perfected if the temporary certificate of use and occupancy is not converted to a permanent certificate of use and occupancy before it expires.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Has a covenant, accepted and approved by Miami-Dade County on or before July 5, 1983, and recorded in the public records, providing assurances to Miami-Dade County to comply with the provisions of Subsection (a) above and has materially changed his position in reliance thereon. The property owner or tenant shall be permitted sixty (60) days to obtain a building permit and an additional sixty (60) days to complete construction in compliance therewith.</section></section></section><section prefix='(70)'>School—technical trade schools, such as, but not limited to aviation, electronic, mechanics; also physical training schools, such as, but not limited to gymnastics and karate. (All school uses shall be subject to compliance with off-street parking requirements and shall comply with Sections 33-151.12.1 through 33-151.22 of this Code.)</section><section prefix='(71)'>Ship chandlers.</section><section prefix='(72)'>Shipyards and dry docks.</section><section prefix='(73)'>Sign painting shops.</section><section prefix='(74)'>Steel fabrication.</section><section prefix='(75)'>Storage warehouse for food, fodder, etc.</section><section prefix='(76)'>Taxidermy. Use will be permitted only within a fully enclosed, air-conditioned building.*</section><section prefix='(77)'>Telecommunications hubs:*<section prefix='(1)'>At least eighty-five (85) percent of the gross floor area of a telecommunications hub building shall be designated for equipment or machinery; no more than fifteen (15) percent of the gross floor area shall be designated for employees and support personnel;</section><section prefix='(2)'>A declaration of use in a form meeting with the approval of the Director and specifying compliance with the conditions set forth in subsection (1), above, shall be submitted to the Department prior to the issuance of a building permit. Said declaration of use shall include a floor plan and site plan for the intended use as required by the Department.</section></section><section prefix='(78)'>Telephone exchanges.</section><section prefix='(79)'>Telephone service unit yards.</section><section prefix='(80)'>Textile, hosiery and weaving mills not closer than two hundred (200) feet to an RU or EU District.</section><section prefix='(81)'>Upholstery shops.</section><section prefix='(82)'>Utility work centers—power and telephone, etc.</section><section prefix='(83)'>Vending machine sales and service.</section><section prefix='(84)'>Veterinarians.</section><section prefix='(85)'>Vulcanizing.*</section><section prefix='(86)'>Warehouses for storage or products in the form sold in a BU District.</section><section prefix='(87)'>Warehouse, membership, subject to the following minimum standards, unless otherwise approved by public hearing as a non-use variance:<section prefix='(a)'>The area of such occupancy shall contain no less than one hundred thousand (100,000) square feet of gross floor area;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The subject use shall be located on a major or minor roadway as depicted on the adopted Land Use Plan map and shall be within one quarter (¼) mile of that roadway's intersection with another major or minor roadway; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Site plan review criteria set forth in Section 33-261.1 shall be met.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Subject to compliance with Article X (Alcoholic Beverages) of this Code, liquor package sales shall be permitted. Package sales areas shall be divided from the rest of the membership warehouse area by a solid floor-to-ceiling wall and shall have a separate exterior entrance.</section></section><section prefix='(87.1)'>Home Improvement Warehouses—the sale of a variety of home improvement products, including hardware, construction supplies, electrical and plumbing fixtures, lumber, tools, and lawn and garden supplies to contractors, developers, and wholesale and retail consumers, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The subject use shall be located on a site having access on a major access road, including major roadways (three (3) or more lanes) and frontage roadways serving limited access highways and expressways, or on a minor roadway as depicted on the adopted Comprehensive Development Master Plan, Land Use Plan map, within one-quarter (¼) mile of that roadway's intersection with a major roadway;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The short term rental of tools, compressors, chainsaws, ladders, post hole diggers, hand trucks and similar equipment and trucks (for the convenience of customers purchasing items) may only be provided as an accessory use;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The subject use is permitted only as a freestanding structure on a site of twenty (20) acres or less and containing no less than 100,000 square feet of gross building floor area;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Setbacks as required for the principal building shall apply to all storage, display, and sales areas;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Parking shall be provided in accordance with Section 33-124(h)(3.1) of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Site plan review shall meet the criteria set forth in Section 33-261.1 of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(88)'>Welding shops.*</section><section prefix='(89)'>Welding supplies.</section><section prefix='(89.1)'>Plant nurseries are authorized in utility easements and railroad rights-of-way, with the consent of the property owner, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The nursery use shall be conducted by a not-for-profit corporation and shall be incidental to an on-site educational program that provides career training or medical or educational therapy programs.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No on-site sales shall be permitted;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The use shall be conducted on sites with a minimum of one (1) acre net lot area;</section><section prefix='(d)'>A Certificate of Use shall be obtained, and shall be renewed annually subject to the conditions contained in this subsection; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>The use shall not be permitted on property abutting residentially zoned properties or properties designated on the Land Use Plan (LUP) map for residential use.</section></section><section prefix='(90)'>Wood and coal yards.</section><section prefix='(91)'>The operation of an equipment and appliance center for the testing, repairing, overhauling and reconditioning of any and all equipment, appliances, and machinery sold by the operator/occupant; provided such may be manufactured at the location of the operation and in connection therewith individual customers bringing equipment to the site for such repairing, overhauling or reconditioning, may purchase parts for such equipment, appliances, or machinery.</section></section><section>*NOTE: Provided no such establishment is located within five hundred (500) feet of any RU or EU District except after approval after public hearing. Provided that this spacing limitation shall be two hundred fifty (250) feet if the use is confined within a building and an exterior wall or walls of the building located on the establishment is not penetrated with any openings directly facing the RU or EU District. It is further provided that, except for exterior uses, such distances shall be measured from the closest point of the subject use in the building to the RU or EU District. In connection with exterior uses, the distance of five hundred (500) feet shall be measured from the closest point of the IU District to the RU or EU District. For purposes of establishing such distances, the applicant for such use shall furnish a certified survey from a registered surveyor, which shall indicate such distances. In case of dispute, the measurement scaled by the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning shall govern.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 23(A), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 67-84, § 1, 11-7-67; Ord. No. 69-51, § 1, 9-3-69; Ord. No. 70-8, §§ 1, 2, 2-11-70; Ord. No. 76-20, § 1, 2-3-76; Ord. No. 76-80, § 1, 9-21-76; Ord. No. 76-90, § 1, 10-5-76; Ord. No. 77-69, § 1, 9-20-77; Ord. No. 80-36, § 1, 5-6-80; Ord. No. 83-62, § 1, 7-19-83; Ord. No. 92-81, § 2, 7-21-92; Ord. No. 93-62, § 1, 6-15-93; Ord. No. 93-126, § 5, 11-16-93; Ord. No. 95-123, § 1, 7-11-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-103, § 1, 7-2-96; Ord. No. 96-129, § 1, 9-10-96; Ord. No. 97-197, § 1, 11-4-97; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-74, § 1, 6-6-00; Ord. No. 01-41, § 1, 3-8-01; Ord. No. 01-99, § 2, 6-5-01; Ord. No. 01-227, § 2, 12-20-01; Ord. No. 02-46, § 6, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 02-23, § 3, 2-12-02; Ord. No. 02-103, § 2, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 02-176, § 3, 10-8-02; Ord. No. 03-79, § 1, 4-8-03; Ord. No. 03-116, § 1, 5-6-03; Ord. No. 06-85, § 1, 6-6-06; Ord. No. 08-11, § 4, 1-22-08; Ord. No. 09-47, § 3, 6-2-09; Ord. No. 09-69, § 1, 9-1-09; Ord. No. 09-102, § 4, 11-17-09; Ord. No. 11-04, § 6, 2-1-11; Ord. No. 11-85, § 1, 11-15-11)</history></law>