<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(J). NARANJA COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.68</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004386</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.68. Uses.<section>Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the NCUC shall comply with of this code.<section prefix='A.'>Permitted Uses. In addition to the uses provided in Section 33-284.83(A), the following shall be permitted:<section prefix='1.'>On the east side of U.S. 1, Residential Modified (RM) lots abutting designated Mixed Use Corridor (MC) lots on at least one side are allowed to have uses permitted in the MC area for a depth from U.S. 1 not to exceed that of the MC lots.</section><section prefix='2.'>In the Industrial District (ID) area:<section prefix='a.'>all uses permitted in the IU-C zoning district after public hearing pursuant to Section 33-311(A)(3) of this code.</section><section prefix='b.'>in the Core and Center sub-districts only, on lots fronting on US 1, all uses permitted in Mixed-Use Corridor (MC) at a minimum residential density of 12 dwelling units per acre net to a maximum density of 52 dwelling units per acre net without the use of Severable Use Rights (SUR's) or a maximum density of 60 dwelling units per acre net with the use of SUR's.</section><section prefix='c.'>in the Edge and Center sub-districts, except for properties along US 1, automobile service stations when in compliance with the requirements of Section 33-284.83(B) of this code.</section><section prefix='d.'>in the Edge and Center sub-districts, except for properties along US 1, drive-through facilities when in compliance with the requirements of Section 33-284.83(B)(3) of this code.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>In the Market District (MD) area:<section prefix='a.'>outdoor produce markets, and</section><section prefix='b.'>all uses permitted in the Mixed-Use Corridor (MC) except for residential.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-11, ยง 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>