<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(O). OJUS URBAN AREA DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.14</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose, intent and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004429</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.14. Purpose, intent and applicability.<section prefix='A.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Illustrative Master Plan (Figure 1), illustrates the citizens' vision and may be used to interpret this article. Where the Illustrative Master Plan conflicts with the text of this article, the text shall govern.</section><section prefix='C.'>The regulations contained in this chapter address portions of the Ojus/Aventura Metropolitan Urban Center and its surrounding area. Specifically it addresses an area with the boundaries shown in the Boundary Plan, hereafter the Ojus Urban Area District (OUAD) and generally described as follows: from the crossing of the Oleta River with the west side of the Florida East Cost (FEC) railroad easement, then north along the west side of the FEC railroad easement to the south side of NE 203 Street, then west along the south side of NE 203 Street to the west side of NE 26 Avenue, then north along the west side of NE 26 Avenue to the south side of theoretical NE 206 Street then west along the south side of theoretical NE 206 Street to the eastern boundary of the Highland Oaks Park, then north and west along the boundary of Highland Oaks Park to the east side of NE 23 Avenue, then south on the east side of NE 23 Avenue to the north side of NE 207 Street, then east along the north side of NE 207 Street to the east side of NE 24 Avenue, then south along the east side of NE 24 Avenue to the south side on NE 203 Street, then east along the south side of NE 203 Street to the Oleta River, then south along the Oleta River to the point of beginning.</section><section>A more detailed legal description of the boundaries follows:<section>Beginning at the intersection of the East Right-of-Way line of the Oleta River with the West Right-of-Way line of the Florida East Coast railroad, thence North along the aforementioned West Right-of-Way line of the Florida East Coast railroad to the intersection with the centerline of NE 203 Street, thence West along the aforementioned centerline of NE 203 Street to the intersection with the centerline of NE 26 Avenue, thence North along the aforementioned centerline of NE 26 Avenue to the intersection with the theoretical extension of the North Property line of Tract "A" of BETH TORAH ADATH YESHURUN as recorded in Plat Book 147, Page 50 of the Miami-Dade County Public Records, thence West along the aforementioned North Property line of Tract "A" to the intersection with the East Right-of-Way line of the Oleta River, thence North along the aforementioned East Right-of-Way line of the Oleta River to the intersection with the East Property line of Highland Oaks Park, thence North along the aforementioned East Property line of Highland Oaks Park to the intersection with the North Property line of Highland Oaks Park, thence West along the aforementioned North Property line of Highland Oaks Park to the theoretical intersection with the centerline of NE 23 Avenue, thence South along the aforementioned centerline of NE 23 Avenue to the intersection with the Northern boundary of Highland Oaks Elementary School, thence East along the aforementioned Northern boundary of Highland Oaks Elementary School for a distance of 546 feet (+/-) to a point, thence Southeast along the Northeast boundary of Highland Oaks Elementary School for a distance of 125 feet (+/-) to a point, thence East to the intersection with the centerline of NE 24 Avenue, thence South along the aforementioned centerline of NE 24 Avenue to the intersection with the centerline of NE 203 Street, thence East along the aforementioned centerline of NE 203 Street to the intersection with the East Right-of-Way line of the Oleta River, thence South along the aforementioned East Right-of-Way line of the Oleta River to the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section prefix='D.'>Full scale maps of the Illustrative Master Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='E.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the OUAD as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the OUAD shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to OUAD has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.<section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-86, ยง 1, 6-6-06)</history></law>