<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXI. IU-3, INDUSTRIAL, UNLIMITED MANUFACTURING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-266.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum landscaped open space, greenbelts, trees, maintenance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004280</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-266.2. Minimum landscaped open space, greenbelts, trees, maintenance.<section prefix='(a)'>Landscaped open space. A minimum of ten (10) percent of the net lot area of the site shall be developed as landscaped open space; provided, however, that an industrial-zoned site that abuts residentially zoned or developed property shall provide fifteen (15) percent of the net lot area as landscaped open space. It is further provided, however, that if the industrial-zoned site abuts property which is depicted as "Industrial & Office" on the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, is zoned GU and no building permit has been issued for a residence at the time of the approval of the building permit for the industrial use, the landscape open space requirement shall be ten (10) percent of the net lot area. Said landscaped open space may include entrance features, greenbelts, unpaved passive and active recreation areas, and other similar landscaped open space at ground level. Open space areas may also include tree preservation zones of "natural forest communities" as defined in Section 26B-1, Code of Miami-Dade County. Tree preservation zones shall be delineated on all plans submitted to Miami-Dade County for site plan review under Section 33-266.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, for the purpose of determining overall preservation area and percent of overall landscaped area. The requirements contained herein do not replace or substitute for any requirements contained within Chapter 18A, Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>Water bodies may be used as part of the required landscaped open space, but such water areas shall not be credited for more than twenty (20) percent of the required open space. The specific areas within enclosed or unenclosed malls which are landscaped with grass, trees and/or shrubbery, water areas therein and areas therein with permanent landscaped open space, but such areas shall not be credited for more than ten (10) percent of the required landscaped open space. For approved structures exceeding four (4) stories in height, additional landscaped open space shall be provided equivalent to twenty-five (25) percent of the gross floor area of each floor above four (4) stories.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Greenbelts. Continuous, extensively planted greenbelts, penetrated only at approved points for ingress or egress to the property, shall be provided along all property lines abutting public rights-of-way or properties zoned residential, in accordance with the following minimum standards:</section><section>It is provided, however, this greenbelt requirement shall not apply along property lines abutting property which is depicted as "Industrial &amp; Office" on the Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, is zoned GU and no building permit has been issued for a residence at the time of the approval of the building permit for the industrial use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Trees. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Maintenance. All landscaped areas shall be continuously maintained in a good, healthy condition, and sprinkler systems of sufficient size and spacing shall be installed to serve all required landscaped areas except within tree preservation zones of "natural forest communities," as defined in Section 26B-1, Code of Miami-Dade County. Tree preservation zones shall also be maintained in a healthy natural condition free from trash, debris and disturbance of understory vegetation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 79-99, ยง 1, 11-20-79; Ord. No. 85-87, ยง 6, 10-1-85; Ord. No. 95-223, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 03-76, ยง 3, 4-8-03)</history></law>