<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00068' order_by='00068' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(T). PALMER LAKE METROPOLITAN URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (PLMUC)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.59</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004474</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.59. Uses.<section>No land, body of water and/or structure shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, reconstructed, moved, occupied, or maintained for any purpose in Palmer Lake Metropolitan Urban Center District except for one (1) or more of the following uses. All uses are subject to the airport safety uses and height restrictions provided in of this chapter. The uses delineated herein shall be permitted only in compliance with the development parameters provided in of this article. Water-dependent uses delineated herein shall be subject to the permit requirements of of this code and be consistent with the Coastal Management Element of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.<section prefix='(A)'>Permitted uses in the MIC Core and Center Sub-Districts shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>All uses permitted in the IU-1, IU-2, and BU-2 Districts.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The following BU-3 uses:<section prefix='i.'>Bakeries, retail and wholesale.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Secondhand stores.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Television and broadcasting stations.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Upholstery and furniture repairs.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Residential uses shall be permitted up to two hundred fifty (250) units per acre. Developments having more than four (4) residential units shall provide a minimum of twelve and one-half (12.5) percent of their units as work-force housing units.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Hotels, motels, and apartment hotels developed for transient residential usage shall be permitted up to three hundred seventy five (375) units per acre.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Mobile food sales and services, including but not limited to outdoor dining, cart vendors, and merchandise displays, shall be permitted in accordance with Section 33-13(h) of this code.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Commercial parking garages shall be permitted either alone or in conjunction with other permitted uses and shall comply with the storefront and screening requirements of this article.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Drive-through services, provided that they shall be concealed from "A", "B" and "C" streets by buildings or walls.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Alcoholic beverage uses shall be permitted in accordance with Article X of this chapter, except that such uses shall not be subject to the spacing/distance requirements set forth in Section 33-150(A) and (B) therein.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Permitted uses in the Riverside Sub-District shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>All uses permitted in the IU-1 and IU-2 Districts.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The following water-dependent uses:<section prefix='i.'>Storage of recreational boats, including rack storage facilities. A masonry wall at least ninety-six (96) inches in height shall enclose the boat storage area except along an adjoining lake, canal, or river.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Marinas, non-live aboard, marine commercial. No permanent occupancy of private watercraft shall be permitted, except as required for a watchman's quarters. The following accessory uses shall be permitted at a commercial marina: Bait and tackle shop; Charter boat service; Dock master's office; Dry stack boat storage facility; Pleasure craft fueling facility; Pleasure craft rentals; Restaurants including therein any accessory outdoor dining area(s). Marinas shall provide electrical, water, and sewage disposal connections to each vessel berth.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Other water-dependent uses not specifically enumerated in this section or in the IU-1 and IU-2 districts as approved by resolution of the County Commission.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>The following water-related uses:<section prefix='i.'>Fish market and accessory seafood restaurant.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Seafood products and by-products collection, cooking, processing, and wholesale distribution, including accessory eating and drinking establishments related to such operations.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Vessel sales, wholesale or retail, and the following accessory uses: Marine supplies and equipment, retail and or wholesale distribution; Marine sporting goods and supplies, retail and or wholesale distribution.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Other water-related uses not specifically enumerated in this section or in the IU-1 and IU-2 districts as approved by resolution of the County Commission.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>The additional uses listed below shall be permitted only in conjunction with one or more of the following water-dependent uses occurring on the same lot: marinas; marine terminals, passenger, freight; boat slips for the purpose of repair; boat and yacht repair, overhaul, manufacturing; shipyards. An annual certificate of use shall be required for the water dependent use when built as part of a mixed-use development that includes one of the uses listed in paragraphs (i) through (iii) below. Development shall comply with the waterfront setback and access requirements set forth in Section 33-284.99.60(B)(4)(b). The following additional uses shall be permitted only when the Director determines that such use: will not have an adverse impact on operation of the Port of the Miami River; will not substantially reduce or inhibit existing public access to marine or tidal waters; and will not interfere with the activities or operation of adjacent water-dependent uses or significantly impede access to vessel berthing or other access to the water by water-dependent uses.<section prefix='i.'>Hotels, motels, and apartment hotels developed for transient residential use shall be allowed up to one hundred eighty-seven (187) units per acre, provided that such uses shall be constructed so that the Day Night Noise Level (DNL) within guest rooms are no greater than forty-five (45) decibels (db). Submitted plans for such uses shall include an acoustical analysis demonstrating that the proposed construction complies with the noise limit indicated, including documentation of noise levels at the development site, noise insulation measures to be utilized in building construction, and the predicted performance of the proposed measures. An annual certificate of use shall be required for these uses.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Retail uses shall be allowed, provided that such use is limited to less than fifty (50) percent of the building gross floor area on the same lot, except that retail uses provided as accessory to permitted hotel uses shall not be subject to this limitation.</section><section prefix='iii.'>On lots adjoining the Tamiami Canal, residential uses shall be permitted above the ground story and limited to less than fifty (50) percent of the building gross floor area on the same lot, except that hotels, motels, and apartment hotels shall not be subject to this limitation.</section></section></section><section prefix='(C)'>In all sub-districts, public recreation buildings, playgrounds, and parks or reservations owned and operated by a municipality, County, State or the United States Government shall be permitted. No minimum building frontage shall be required for such recreation building.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-43, ยง 5, 5-7-13)</history></law>