<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00056' order_by='00056' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIH. TRADITIONAL NEIGHBORHOOD DEVELOPMENT (TND) DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.51</section_number>
<catch_line>Land use categories.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004367</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.51. Land use categories.<section prefix='(A)'>Public and/or semi-public use.<section prefix='(1)'>Land use.<section prefix='(a)'>Land designated for public and/or semi-public use shall be tracts consisting of parks, squares, greens, greenbelts, and civic use lots and buildings.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The only buildings permitted in public and/or semi-public use tracts shall be civic use buildings.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A maximum of fifteen percent (15%) of a park, green or square may be used as a civic use lot.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Large area recreational uses such as golf courses and multiple game fields shall be located outside the neighborhood proper.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Land allocation.<section prefix='(a)'>A minimum of five percent (5%) of the gross area of the neighborhood proper, or five (5.0) acres, (whichever is greater) shall be permanently allocated to tracts totally comprised of parks, squares or greens. Each neighborhood proper shall contain at least one (1) square or green, no less than forty-five thousand (45,000) square feet and no greater than ninety thousand (90,000) square feet. This mandatory square or green shall be within a six-hundred-foot radius of the geometric center of the neighborhood proper.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The remaining required public use tracts shall be divided into lesser tracts and distributed such that no part of the neighborhood proper is further than a six-hundred-foot radius from a park, square or green.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Squares, parks and waterfronts shall have at least fifty (50.0) percent of their perimeter abutting public or semi-public tracts or streets.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Lots and buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Setbacks for civic use buildings shall be indicated on the master plan at the time of intermediate and final review.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>Parking on public use tracts shall be restricted to required parking for civic use facilities located thereon. Such parking shall be graded, compacted and paved in accordance with the requirements of sections 33-122 through 33-132 of this Code.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Civic use.<section prefix='(1)'>Land use.<section prefix='(a)'>Land designated for civic use shall be lots containing community buildings, including meeting halls, libraries, schools, child care centers, police stations, fire stations, post offices, clubhouses, religious buildings, playgrounds, museums, cultural societies, visual and performance arts buildings, and governmental buildings.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The construction of commonly owned buildings on civic use lots shall be supported by a permanent assessment dedicated to this purpose and administered according to the common maintenance provisions provided in Section 33-284.53</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Land allocation.<section prefix='(a)'>Civic use building lots shall constitute a minimum of two (2.0) percent of the gross area of the neighborhood proper.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Civic use lots shall be located within or adjacent to a square, park, green or on a lot terminating a street vista.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The developer shall covenant to construct a minimum of one (1) meeting hall on a civic use lot upon the sale or lease of fifty (50) percent of the lots and/or units of the neighborhood proper.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The developer shall designate a minimum of any one (1) of the following use lots or an area within a building placed on said use lots for a day care center: civic, shopfront or workshop. The developer shall covenant that a building for said use shall be constructed for a day care center or an area within a building constructed on said use lots be reserved for a day care center when building permits have been obtained for fifty (50) percent of the residential units. Day care centers shall be in accordance with the sections 33-122 through 33-132 of this Code. The developer shall have the option of selling, leasing or transferring title of the lot and building reserved for day care center.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Lots and buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Buildings located on civic use lots shall not exceed forty (40) feet in height excluding spires, cupolas, monuments, flag poles, and chimneys.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>The number of required parking spaces for civic uses shall be in accordance with sections 33-122 through 33-132 of this Code; however, required parking may be provided within a six hundred-foot radius of the civic use facility provided that the required parking is under common lease or ownership with the civic use building it serves.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Civic uses within or adjacent to a public use tract may utilize the on-street parking fronting the public use tract toward its parking requirement.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When on-site parking is provided, no less than seventy-five percent (75%) of the off-street parking spaces shall be placed to the rear of the building. Access may be through the frontage.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Signage.<section prefix='(a)'>Two (2) wall signs shall be permitted for each structure not to exceed a combined total of eight (8) square feet.</section></section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Shopfront use.<section prefix='(1)'>Land use.<section prefix='(a)'>Land designated for shopfront use shall be on lots containing buildings for residential use, including lodging, and commercial uses as provided below, and other similar uses as approved by the Director at the time of the TND approval, except those listed as prohibited uses in the design criteria. At least twenty-five percent (25%) of the gross square footage shall be restricted to residential use, including lodging and commercial uses as provided below. The following uses shall be permitted on shopfront use parcels. No building for a single use shall exceed four thousand (4,000) square feet of interior floor area.<section prefix='1.'>Antique shops, architects, interior designers, offices.</section><section prefix='2.'>Apparel stores.</section><section prefix='3.'>Art goods stores, artist studios and photograph shops and galleries.</section><section prefix='4.'>Banks, excluding drive-in teller service.</section><section prefix='5.'>Beauty parlors.</section><section prefix='6.'>Bakeries, retail only (baking permitted on premises).</section><section prefix='7.'>Barber shops.</section><section prefix='8.'>Bicycle sales, rentals and repairs (nonmotorized).</section><section prefix='9.'>Book stores.</section><section prefix='10.'>Confectionery, ice cream stores and dairy stores.</section><section prefix='11.'>Conservatories and music and dance schools.</section><section prefix='11a.'>Day care center.</section><section prefix='12.'>Drugstores.</section><section prefix='13.'>Floral shops.</section><section prefix='14.'>Galleries.</section><section prefix='15.'>Grocery stores, fruit stores, health food stores, delicatessen, meat and fish markets and other similar food stores.</section><section prefix='16.'>Hardware stores.</section><section prefix='17.'>Insurance and Bonds.</section><section prefix='18.'>Jewelry stores.</section><section prefix='19.'>Leather goods and luggage shops.</section><section prefix='20.'>Liquor package store.</section><section prefix='21.'>Medical equipment and supply stores.</section><section prefix='22.'>Mail order offices, without storage of products sold.</section><section prefix='23.'>Music, tape, CD and record stores.</section><section prefix='24.'>Museum.</section><section prefix='25.'>Newsstand.</section><section prefix='26.'>Office.</section><section prefix='27.'>Office supply stores.</section><section prefix='28.'>Optician/Optometrist.</section><section prefix='29.'>Paint and wallpaper stores.</section><section prefix='29a.'>Police sub-stations.</section><section prefix='30.'>Post office.</section><section prefix='31.'>Pottery shops.</section><section prefix='32.'>Pubs, bars, and mini-breweries.</section><section prefix='33.'>Real Estate.</section><section prefix='34.'>Restaurants and coffee houses including outdoor dining and including alcoholic beverage service. A minimum of forty-two (42) inches clearance shall be reserved along the outside edge of a sidewalk for pedestrian passage.</section><section prefix='35.'>Religious facilities.</section><section prefix='36.'>Schools.</section><section prefix='37.'>Shoe stores and shoe repair shops.</section><section prefix='38.'>Sporting goods.</section><section prefix='39.'>Tobacco shops.</section><section prefix='40.'>Travel Agencies.</section><section prefix='41.'>Variety stores.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Residential uses, except for entries and lobbies to residential uses, are not permitted on the ground floors of shopfront use buildings.</section><section prefix='(c)'>An outbuilding is permitted on each lot.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Land allocation.<section prefix='(a)'>Shopfront use lots shall comprise a minimum of two percent (2%) and a maximum of twenty percent (20%) of the gross area of the neighborhood proper.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A maximum of three (3) shopfront use lots may be consolidated for the purpose of constructing a single building.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A maximum of fifty (50.0) percent of all shopfront use lots may be consolidated.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A minimum of two (2) shopfront use lots may front on a mandatory square or be placed within two hundred (200) feet of a mandatory green.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Lots and buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Shopfront use lots shall have a maximum width of fifty (50) feet and a minimum width of sixteen (16) feet.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Street-front entries shall be at grade to allow access for people with disabilities.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Buildings on shopfront use lots shall have the facade, including colonnades if provided, built directly on the frontage line along at least seventy percent (70%) of its linear frontage. For lots at street intersections, the building shall be built directly on the side street frontage for at least fifty percent (50%) of its linear frontage.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The unbuilt portion of the frontage line shall have a streetwall built directly upon it.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Buildings on shopfront use lots shall have a setback of zero (0) feet along at least one (1) side property line. For buildings without a side setback, a perpetual four foot maintenance easement shall be provided on the lot adjacent to the shopfront property line. There shall be no required rear setback.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Buildings on shopfront use lots shall cover no more than fifty percent (50%) of the net lot area. Outbuildings shall not count against lot coverage.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Buildings on shopfront use lots shall not be less than twenty-four (24) feet in height and shall not exceed forty (40) feet in height (excluding chimneys and elevator towers). When fronting a square, buildings shall be no less than thirty (30) feet in height. A cornice line shall define the first floor.</section><section prefix='(h)'>At least twenty-five percent (25%) of the net lot area shall be reserved for private open space.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Unenclosed balconies with a minimum of nine (9) feet of clearance above grade shall be permitted to extend up to six (6) feet over the sidewalk.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Colonnades, are required when shopfront use lots front on the mandatory square. Enclosed space shall be permitted directly above the sidewalk.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Streets and alleys.<section prefix='(a)'>Shopfront use lots shall front on streets of sixty (60) feet maximum width consisting of two (2) twelve-foot wide travel lanes, and an eight-foot wide parallel parking lane on at least one (1) side. Parallel parking shall be located adjacent to all shop front lots when such lots front a square, park, green and/or plaza. If the parking lane is provided on only one (1) side, there shall be a planting strip, at least four (4) feet wide, between the opposite travel lane and the sidewalk. Two (2) sidewalks are required and shall be no less than ten (10) feet wide. A public access easement shall provide for public passage—excepting an area within four (4) feet of the shopfronts which may be occupied by furniture for restaurants. (As an example, refer to Figures 1 and 2). Shopfront use lots may also front on a square, park, or green.</section></section></section><section></section><section><section prefix='(b)'>Posted vehicle speed for shopfront use streets shall not exceed twenty-five (25) miles per hour.</section><section prefix='(c)'>At intersections, the curb radius shall be twenty (20) feet, with a clear zone radius of twenty-five (25) feet. Parking lanes shall not be closer than twenty-five (25) feet to the nearest intersecting building lot line.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Signs in colonnades shall have a minimum clearance of eight (8) feet above the sidewalk.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Shopfront use lots shall have their rear or side lot lines coinciding with an alley twenty-four (24) feet wide, containing a vehicular pavement width of at least nine (9) feet one-way, and a maximum of eighteen (18) feet two-way.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>No less than seventy-five (75.0) percent of the parking spaces shall be to the rear of the building. Access may be through the frontage only if an alley or side street providing access to the alley is not within two hundred (200) linear feet of the lot.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Signage.<section prefix='(a)'>All signs shall be wall signs or cantilever signs and shall not exceed a total of twenty-four (24) square feet per building with no more than three (3) signs. Individual cantilever signs shall be mounted perpendicular to the building face and shall not exceed eight (8) square feet. No sign shall be mounted above the first floor of the structure.</section></section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Rowhouse use.<section prefix='(1)'>Land use.<section prefix='(a)'>Land designated for rowhouse use shall be on lots containing buildings for residential uses including townhouse, apartment, limited office as permitted in the RU-5A Zoning District, limited lodging, congregate living facilities, family day care, and artisanal use. Where nonresidential uses are proposed, at least fifty percent (50%) of the gross square footage shall be restricted to residential use as demonstrated by the submittal of floor plans identifying the use of each room.</section><section prefix='(b)'>One hundred (100) percent of the building area above the ground floor shall be designated for residential use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>An outbuilding is permitted on each lot.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Land allocation.<section prefix='(a)'>Rowhouse use lots shall constitute a minimum of twenty percent (20%) and a maximum of fifty percent (50%) of the gross area of the neighborhood proper.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Rowhouse use lots may be consolidated for the purpose of constructing multifamily dwellings.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A maximum of fifty (50.0) percent of all rowhouse use lots may be consolidated.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Lots and buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Rowhouse use lots shall have a maximum width of thirty-two (32) feet.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Rowhouse use buildings with the minimum setback shall have their front entry set to one (1) side of the facade. This is to preserve the possibility of retro-fitting a ramp for wheelchair access.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Rowhouse use buildings shall be attached (built with no side setback or as a single building) at not less than five-unit segments. Lots comprising the end of the block adjacent to the street or alley or along street curves may be attached in segments of two (2) to five (5) units.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Buildings on rowhouse use lots shall be setback eight (8) or fifteen (15) feet from the frontage line. Buildings at street intersections shall be set back eight (8) feet from the frontage line and six (6) feet from the side street line. Setback requirements shall apply to the enclosed portion of the buildings only.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Buildings on rowhouse use lots shall have a setback of zero (0) feet from at least one (1) side property line. There shall be no required rear setback.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Outbuildings shall have no required setbacks.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Setbacks on consolidated rowhouse use lots shall apply as in a single lot.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Buildings on rowhouse use lots shall cover no more than sixty (60) percent of the net lot area. Outbuildings shall not count towards the lot coverage when the principal buildings do not cover more than fifty (50%) percent of the net lot area. Front porches and covered stoops without habitable space above shall not count towards the lot coverage.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Buildings on rowhouse use lots shall not exceed thirty-five (35) feet in height (excluding chimneys and elevator towers) and a cornice line shall be used to define the first floor.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Buildings on rowhouse use lots shall have a minimum first floor front elevation eighteen (18) inches above finished sidewalk grade, except that an apartment building(s), as defined in Section 33-1(6.1) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, in rowhouse use lots shall not be subject to the elevation requirement. Rear entrance(s) shall be accessible for people with disabilities by grading or ramping. Space shall be provided in the front yard area for the construction of a ramp.</section><section prefix='(k)'>A minimum of thirty percent (30%) of the net lot area shall be developed as private open space.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Rowhouse use lots shall have a streetedge built along the unbuilt parts of the frontage line.</section><section prefix='(m)'>A minimum of twenty-five percent (25%) of the buildings on rowhouse use lots shall have front porches. Said front porches may encroach into the front setback and shall not count against lot coverage requirements but shall count towards private open space requirements.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Streets and alleys.<section prefix='(a)'>Rowhouse use lots shall front on streets consisting of a fifty-foot maximum width, including two (2) ten-foot wide travel lanes and an eight-foot wide parallel parking lane on at least one (1) side. If the parking lane is provided on only one (1) side there shall be a planting strip, at least five (5) feet wide, provided between the opposite sidewalk and travel lane. Two (2) sidewalks are required and shall be no less than six (6) feet wide. (As an example, refer to Figures 3 and 4). Rowhouse use lots may also front on squares or park tracts.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No parking shall be permitted in the front setback area.</section></section></section><section></section><section><section prefix='(b)'>Posted vehicle speed for rowhouse use streets shall not exceed twenty (20) miles per hour.</section><section prefix='(c)'>At intersections, the curb radius shall be fifteen (15) feet with a clear zone radius of twenty-five (25) feet. Parking lanes shall not be closer than twenty-five (25) feet from the lot line adjoining intersecting streets.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Rowhouse use lots shall have their rear or side lot lines coinciding with an alley twenty-four (24) feet wide containing a vehicular pavement width of at least ten (10) feet one-way and sixteen (16) feet two-way.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>All off-street parking places shall be to the rear of the building. Access shall be through a vehicular alley only.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No parking shall be permitted in the front setback area.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Signage.<section prefix='(a)'>All signs shall be wall signs and limited to two (2) signs and shall not exceed a cumulative total of four (4) square feet. No signs shall be mounted above the first floor of a structure.</section></section></section><section prefix='(E)'>House use.<section prefix='(1)'>Land use.<section prefix='(a)'>Land designated for house use shall be on lots containing buildings for residential uses including single-family houses, guest houses as outbuildings, home occupation, and family day care.</section><section prefix='(b)'>One hundred (100) percent of the building area above the ground floor shall be designated for residential use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>An outbuilding is permitted on each lot.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Land allocation.<section prefix='(a)'>House use lots shall constitute a maximum of thirty percent (30%) of the gross area of the neighborhood proper.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A maximum of two (2) house use lots may be consolidated for the purpose of constructing a single residence.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A maximum of fifty (50.0) percent of all house use lots may be consolidated.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Lots and buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Houses on house use lots shall be raised a minimum of eighteen (18) inches from finished exterior sidewalk grade. At least one (1) entrance shall be accessible for people with disabilities either by grading or ramping, and the other entrance shall have sufficient space to construct a possible future ramp</section><section prefix='(b)'>Buildings on house use lots shall be set back ten (10) or twenty (20) feet from the frontage line. Buildings at street intersections shall be set back ten (10) feet from the frontage line and the side street frontage line.</section><section prefix='(c)'>House use lots shall have a minimum width of thirty-six (36) feet and a minimum lot size of three thousand six hundred (3,600) square feet with a minimum average lot size of five thousand (5,000) square feet.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Setbacks on consolidated house use lots shall apply as on a single lot.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Buildings on house use lots shall be set back from the side lot lines equivalent (in total) to no less than twenty percent (20%) of the width of the building lot. The entire setback may be allocated to one (1) side. If buildings have a zero (0) foot setback on one (1) side, a four-foot maintenance easement shall be provided on the adjacent lot.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Buildings on house use lots shall be set back no less than five (5) feet from the rear lot line. Outbuildings on house use lots shall have a setback no less than five (5) feet from the rear lot line except on an alley where it shall have a zero-foot setback.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Buildings on house use lots between 3,600 square feet and 4,999 square feet shall cover no more than forty (40%) percent of the lot area. Buildings on 5,000 square foot and greater house use lots shall cover no more than fifty (50%) percent of the lot area. Outbuildings shall not count towards the lot coverage when the principal buildings do not cover more than forty (40%) percent of the net lot area. Front porches, porte-cocheres and covered stoops without habitable space above shall not count towards the lot coverage.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Buildings on house use lots shall not exceed twenty-four (24) feet in height (excluding chimneys).</section><section prefix='(i)'>Buildings on house use lots shall have a streetedge built along the frontage line.</section><section prefix='(j)'>A minimum of twenty-five percent (25%) of the buildings on house use lots shall have front porches which may encroach into the front setback not closer than eight (8) feet from the inside edge of the sidewalk.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Streets and alleys.<section prefix='(a)'>House use lots shall front on streets of a forty-six-foot maximum width consisting of two (2) ten-foot travel lanes, two (2) planting strips of at least six (6) feet wide each, and two (2) sidewalks which shall be no less than five (5) feet wide. A parallel parking lane eight (8) feet wide may be used in place of either planting strip. (As an example, refer to Figures 5 and 6.)</section></section></section><section></section><section><section prefix='(b)'>Posted vehicle speed for house use streets shall not exceed twenty (20) miles per hour.</section><section prefix='(c)'>At intersections, the curb radius shall be fifteen (15) feet with a clear zone radius of twenty-five (25) feet. Parking lanes shall not be closer than twenty-five (25) feet from the lot line adjoining intersecting streets.</section><section prefix='(d)'>House use lots may have their rear or side lot lines coinciding with an alley twenty-four (24) feet wide containing a pavement width of at least ten (10) feet one-way and sixteen (16) feet two-way, except where the rear lot adjoins a greenbelt, lake or canal.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>No parking shall be permitted in the front setback area of residential lots of less than fifty (50) foot frontage.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All off-street parking places shall be to the side or the rear of the building. Where no alley access exists and vehicular access is through the frontage, garages shall be located a minimum of twenty (20) feet behind the front building setback. Porte-cocheres may be located at the front building setback line. Porte-cocheres without habitable space above may encroach into the front setback a maximum of eight (8) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Signage.<section prefix='(a)'>One wall, or streetedge mounted, sign not to exceed one (1) square foot shall be permitted.</section></section></section><section prefix='(F)'>Workshop use.<section prefix='(1)'>Land use.<section prefix='(a)'>Land designated for workshop use shall be in land containing buildings for the following uses: No building for a single use shall exceed thirty thousand (30,000) square feet of interior floor area.<section prefix='1.'>Artists studios and accessory gallery use.</section><section prefix='2.'>Artisanal use.</section><section prefix='3.'>Automobile and motorcycle body shops.</section><section prefix='4.'>Automobile parking garages.</section><section prefix='5.'>Automobile service and repairs.</section><section prefix='6.'>Bait and tackle shops.</section><section prefix='7.'>Bakeries (wholesale).</section><section prefix='8.'>Banks excluding drive-in teller services.</section><section prefix='9.'>Bottling of beverages.</section><section prefix='10.'>Cabinet shops.</section><section prefix='11.'>Cold storage warehouse.</section><section prefix='12.'>Dance studios.</section><section prefix='12a.'>Day care centers.</section><section prefix='13.'>Dog and pet hospitals in air conditioned buildings.</section><section prefix='14.'>Dry cleaning and dyeing establishments.</section><section prefix='15.'>Engines, sales and services.</section><section prefix='16.'>Gasoline service stations excluding markets.</section><section prefix='17.'>Glass installation.</section><section prefix='18.'>Health and exercise clubs.</section><section prefix='19.'>Interior design shops.</section><section prefix='20.'>Leather goods manufacturing, excluding tanning.</section><section prefix='21.'>Locksmith shops, sharpening and grinding shops.</section><section prefix='22.'>Lumber yards.</section><section prefix='23.'>Mail order offices and storage.</section><section prefix='24.'>Medical equipment and supplies.</section><section prefix='25.'>Office supply stores.</section><section prefix='26.'>Office buildings.</section><section prefix='27.'>Post office substations and police substations.</section><section prefix='28.'>Photography labs.</section><section prefix='29.'>Pottery shops.</section><section prefix='30.'>Printing shops.</section><section prefix='31.'>Residential use shall be permitted on the second and/or third floor above workplace use. A second floor residential unit must provide access to people with disabilities.</section><section prefix='32.'>Restaurants excluding drive-in service.</section><section prefix='33.'>Secondhand stores and antique shops.</section><section prefix='34.'>Upholstery and furniture shops.</section><section prefix='35.'>Wholesale salesroom and storage rooms.</section><section prefix='36.'>Other similar uses as approved by the Director.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Land allocation.<section prefix='(a)'>Workshop use lots shall constitute a minimum of three percent (3%) and a maximum of seven percent (7%) of the gross area of the neighborhood proper. When a TND borders land designated in the CDMP as agriculture or open land, the land allocation for workshop use lots may constitute only one and one-half (1.5%) percent of the gross area of the neighborhood proper.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Workshop use lots shall not be within three hundred (300) feet of the geometric center of the neighborhood proper or the mandatory square or green. When a TND borders land designated in the CDMP as agriculture or open land, then workshop use lots shall not be permitted within three hundred thirty (330) feet of said TND boundary except if necessary to maintain consistency with the Goals, Objectives and Policies of the CDMP including the Guidelines for Urban Form.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All workshop use lots shall be contiguous and located within one (1) area with no intervening uses, provided however, in TNDs exceeding one hundred (100) acres in size, two (2) workshop use areas shall be permitted.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Lots and buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Buildings on workshop use lots shall have a setback of zero (0) or five (5) feet from the frontage line. The setback at street intersections shall not exceed five (5) feet from the frontage line and the side street line.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Street-front entries shall be at grade to allow access for people with disabilities.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Buildings on workshop use lots shall cover no more than seventy percent (70%) of the net lot area.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A minimum of fifteen percent (15%) of the net lot area shall be developed as landscaped open space.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Buildings on workshop use lots shall not exceed thirty-five (35) feet in height.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Workshop use lots shall be separated from other use types at the side and rear lot lines (excepting an entry on the alley) by a continuous masonry wall no less than six (6) feet in height.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Workshop use lots shall have a maximum width of three hundred (300) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Streets and alleys.<section prefix='(a)'>Workshop use lots shall front on streets of a sixty (60) feet maximum width consisting of two (2) twelve-foot wide travel lanes, and eight-foot wide parallel parking on at least one (1) side of the road. If the parking lane is provided on only one (1) side there shall be a planting strip of at least eight (8) feet wide between the opposite lane and the sidewalk. Sidewalks shall be no less than eight (8) feet wide and are required on both sides of the street. (As an example, refer to Figures 7 and 8).</section></section></section><section></section><section><section prefix='(b)'>Posted vehicle speed for workshop use streets shall not exceed twenty-five (25) miles per hour.</section><section prefix='(c)'>At intersections the curb radius shall be twenty (20) feet, with a clear zone radius of twenty-five (25) feet. Parking lanes shall not be closer than twenty-five (25) feet to the nearest intersecting building lot line.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Workshop use lots shall have their rear or side lot lines adjacent to an alley twenty-four (24) feet wide containing a vehicular pavement width of at least ten (10) feet one-way and eighteen (18) feet two-way, except where the rear lot line adjoins a greenbelt, lake or canal.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Parking.<section prefix='(a)'>Off-street parking shall be placed to the side or the rear of the building.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Signage.<section prefix='(a)'>All signs shall be wall mounted perpendicular to the building face with an eight-foot clearance to the sidewalk and shall not exceed a total of twenty-four (24) square feet and shall be limited to three (3) signs.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-41, § 1, 4-2-91; Ord. No. 96-127, § 32, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-26, § 1, 5-4-99; Ord. No. 02-46, § 9, 4-9-02; Ord. No. 03-47, § 5, 3-11-03; Ord. No. 11-83, § 2, 11-15-11)</history></law>