<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XVB. RU-RH, ROWHOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-202.9</section_number>
<catch_line>Ownership and maintenance of common open space.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004133</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-202.9. Ownership and maintenance of common open space.<section>All land designated on approved plans as common open space, except public rights-of-way, including green(s) and all structures, roads and permitted drives devoted to the common use of the inhabitants of this district shall be owned and maintained as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Any such common open space shall either be owned by a property homeowners' association, a special taxing district or a similar entity. In the case of a homeowners' association, the ownership shall be subject to covenants providing for the maintenance of the common facilities in a manner that assures its continuing use for its intended purpose and provided that a homeowners' association shall comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(a)'>A homeowner's association shall be established before the units or individual building lots are sold.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Membership shall be mandatory for each property owner and said association shall have the authority to adjust the assessment to meet the needs of maintaining the open space.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any assessments levied by the homeowner's association shall be a lien superior to all other liens, except tax liens and mortgage liens are first liens against the property encumbered thereby.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The homeowner's association shall be responsible for maintenance of common elements and local taxes on such common elements.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No amendment(s) shall be permitted to the homeowner's association documents which would have the effect of modifying or eliminating requirements for the common areas without the prior written consent of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-96, ยง 1, 6-20-06)</history></law>