<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-25.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Home office.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003918</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-25.1 Home office.<section prefix='(A)'>A home office shall be permitted as an ancillary use to all lawful residential uses subject to the following limitations:<section prefix='1.'>The area of the dwelling unit devoted to a home office shall not exceed two hundred (200) square feet of the living area of the dwelling unit, including garages.</section><section prefix='2.'>The home office shall not be conducted in any accessory building or other structure detached from the residence except that a home office may be allowed in the habitable space on the second floor of a detached garage on a rowhouse lot in the RU-RH district.</section><section prefix='3.'>The home office use must be conducted by a member of the household residing in the dwelling unit, and no person shall be employed at any time in connection with the home office use who is not a member of the household residing in the dwelling unit except that a disabled individual may employ a personal care attendant as necessary to accommodate a home use office on the site by such individual.</section><section prefix='4.'>No sign relating to the home office may be posted or displayed on the site and no vehicle with any sign displaying the home office use or home office residential address, which might serve to indicate that the dwelling unit is being used for a home office, may be located on the site.</section><section prefix='5.'>No customer, vendee, client or other patron shall be served in person on the site, nor shall the home office use be conducted in any way which would necessitate the presence of suppliers or patrons on the site, with the exception of deliveries customary to residential use.</section><section prefix='6.'>There shall be no display, manufacturing, distribution, or repair of any type of materials, merchandise or other products on the premises. Storage of such items shall be confined to the home office area.</section><section prefix='7.'>There shall be no change in the outside residential character of the building or premises as a result of the conduct of such home office use, or any visible evidence thereof.</section><section prefix='8.'>More than one (1) home office may be permitted at any one (1) time in a dwelling unit, provided that each such home office complies with each of the aforestated requirements and further provided that the combined total square footage of all home office uses in the dwelling unit does not exceed the provisions of (1) above.</section><section prefix='9.'>An annually renewable certificate of use and occupancy shall be obtained for any home office.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>No variances shall be granted through provisions of other applicable regulations which will in any way conflict with or vary the provisions of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-208, ยง 2, 11-18-97; Ord. No. 06-96, ยง 3, 6-20-06)</history></law>