<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.87</section_number>
<catch_line>Signs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004401</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.87. Signs.<section>Except as provided herein, the definitions set forth in of this chapter shall apply. In the event of a conflict, the provisions of this section shall govern.<section prefix='A.'>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='1.'>Digital technology (signs): Electronic technology that allows for changes to a sign copy resulting from digital data input. Included in this technology are signs that use series of lights, including light emitting diodes (LED), fiber optics, or other similar technology.</section><section prefix='2.'>Nits: Luminance is the measure of the light emanating from an object with respect to its size and is the term used to quantify electronic sign brightness. The unit of measurement for luminance is nits (nt), which is the total amount of light emitted from a sign divided by the surface area of the sign [candelas per square meter (cd/m2)].</section></section><section prefix='B.'>Temporary Signs in MUCs and CUCs. Temporary signs (Class A) shall be permitted in compliance with Section 33-99 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='C.'>Permanent Point of Sale Signs. Permanent point of sale signs (Class B) shall be permitted as follows:<section prefix='1.'>The following permanent point of sale signs are permitted in all Sub-districts in conjunction with permitted business and industrial uses: flat attached, hanging, awning, cantilever, projecting, and monument. No other detached sign shall be permitted except monument signs.<section prefix='a.'>Projecting signs shall be mounted and perpendicular to the building.</section><section prefix='b.'>The copy of an awning sign shall only be located on the valance of the awning.</section><section prefix='c.'>The bottom of a hanging sign shall be located at a minimum height of eight (8) feet from the finished floor.</section><section prefix='d.'>Monument signs, which are freestanding, 2-faced signs, shall have a base at least seventy-five (75) percent of the horizontal width of the sign and located directly on the ground or a maximum of twelve (12) inches above grade.</section><section prefix='e.'>Cantilever signs are mounted on those portions of the building that project horizontally.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>Maximum size, location, and number of signs shall be as follows:</section><section prefix='3.'>Illumination/lighting shall comply with the following:<section>Flat attached, cantilever, and projecting signs utilizing flashing, moving, intermittent, chasing, or rotating lights shall be permitted in conjunction with convention halls or meeting halls and auditoriums, theaters, movie theaters, athletic facilities, museums, and other visual and performance arts buildings.</section><section>Where digital technology is allowed, it shall be provided in compliance with the following:</section><section prefix='a.'>No auditory message or mechanical sounds shall be emitted from the sign.</section><section prefix='b.'>The sign shall not display any illumination that moves, appears to move, blinks, fades, rolls, dissolves, flashes, scrolls, shows animated movement, or changes in intensity during the static display period.</section><section prefix='c.'>All digital signs shall be modulated so that, from sunset to sunrise, the brightness shall not be more than 500 Nits. Sunset and sunrise times are those times established by the Miami office of the National Weather Service. At all other times, the maximum brightness levels shall not exceed 5,000 Nits. All digital signs shall have installed ambient light monitors and at all times shall allow such monitors to automatically adjust the brightness level of the sign based on ambient light conditions.</section><section prefix='d.'>The message display shall not change more often than once each eight seconds, with all moving parts or illumination moving or changing simultaneously.</section><section prefix='e.'>Any digital sign that malfunctions, fails, or ceases to operate in its usual or normal programmed manner shall immediately revert to a black screen and shall be restored to its normal operation conforming to the requirements of this section within twenty-four (24) hours.</section></section><section prefix='4.'>Maximum heights shall be as follows:<section prefix='a.'>Six (6) feet above grade to top of sign for monument signs; except, for signs associated with nonconforming structures located on corner parcels fronting major or minor roads identified on the Land Use Plan, one monument sign may be constructed at a maximum height of twelve (12) feet above grade to top of sign in lieu of two six-foot signs;</section><section prefix='b.'>No height limits for flat attached, cantilever, or projecting signs;</section><section prefix='c.'>For signs painted on the facade of a building or on the valance of an awning, the copy shall not exceed one (1) foot.</section></section><section prefix='5.'>No setback is required for any sign. Cantilever, projecting, and awning signs may encroach into any required setback. Awning signs and projecting signs attached to awnings may encroach into the right-of-way. Where a zero (0) foot setback is permitted, cantilever and projecting signs may encroach into the right-of-way up to three (3) feet. Signs encroaching into the right-of-way shall be a minimum of eleven (11) feet above the sidewalk.</section></section><section prefix='D.'>Directional Signs. Directional signs, to direct traffic flow and locate entrances and exits shall be permitted on private property in connection with any permitted use. Detached directional signs shall not exceed three (3) square feet in area; directional signs attached to buildings shall not exceed twelve (12) square feet in area. The maximum height of a detached directional sign shall be ten (10) feet. Directional signs shall be shown and approved on site plans which indicate sign size, location, copy, etc.</section><section prefix='E.'>Flags. Each parcel may display no more than three (3) flags and three (3) flagpoles. Flagpoles shall not exceed seventy (70) feet in height. Flag dimensions shall be proportional to the pole such that the hoist side of the flag is not more than fifty (50) percent of the vertical height of the flagpole. For purposes of this section, "flag" means any fabric or bunting containing colors, patterns, or symbols.</section><section prefix='F.'>Prohibited Signs. The following types of outdoor signs shall be prohibited:<section prefix='1.'>Revolving, rotating, and other moving signs.</section><section prefix='2.'>Backlit signs of any type.</section><section prefix='3.'>Banners.</section><section prefix='4.'>Roof signs.</section><section prefix='5.'>Balloon signs.</section><section prefix='6.'>Class C commercial signs or other outdoor advertising, except those within bus shelters.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-143, ยง 7, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 06-10, ยง 4, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 08-102, ยง 4, 9-2-08; Ord. No. 12-86, ยง 6, 10-2-12)</history></law>