<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='3'>ARTICLE XIX. RU-4A, HOTEL APARTMENT HOUSE DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-220</section_number>
<catch_line>Setback requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004177</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-220. Setback requirements.<section>The setbacks shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Front setback. For structures not exceeding thirty-five (35) feet in height, the minimum setback shall be twenty-five (25) feet; for structures over thirty-five (35) feet in height the setbacks shall be increased by forty (40) percent of the additional height; provided, however, that the required front setback shall not exceed fifty (50) feet.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Rear setback. For structures not exceeding thirty-five (35) feet in height, the minimum setback shall be twenty-five (25) feet; for structures over thirty-five (35) feet in height the setbacks shall be increased by forty (40) percent of the additional height.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Interior side setbacks and side street setbacks. Minimum setbacks for all structures shall be determined by a sixty-three-degree line projected from the interior side property line(s) or side street property line(s) upward towards the center of the site; provided, however, that no structure shall be permitted to be closer than twenty-five (25) feet to the interior side property line(s) or side street property line(s) (see the following sketch) and further provided that the passageway areas to Biscayne Bay or the Atlantic Ocean are adhered to as provided in this article.</section></section><section><section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Minimum setback between buildings shall be twenty (20) feet, except where doors, windows or other openings in the building wall of a living unit face a wall of the same building and/or a wall of another building on the same site. In that case there shall be provided a minimum clear distance of not less than thirty (30) feet, said distance to be measured on a line projected at right angles from the opening to the opposite wall. Cantilevers and open porches may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than six (6) feet and stairways may project from the building wall into the required open space (court only) not more than ten (10) feet. Stairways, when located in the required open space (court), shall be supported by the necessary columns only; support by a wall is strictly prohibited.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Bungalow villas shall be setback as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Twenty-five (25) feet from the front property line.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Twenty (20) feet from a side property line abutting a highway right-of-way, except where the rear of the lot abuts a key lot; in which event, the setback for the key lot shall govern.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Ten (10) feet from an interior side lot line.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Ten (10) feet from the rear property line.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The minimum clear distance between units of a bungalow villa shall be twenty (20) feet. Ingress and egress to all units shall be provided by a common and continuous clear space with a thirty (30) foot minimum width.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 72-92, ยง 1, 12-5-72; Ord. No. 82-6, ยง 1, 2-2-82; Ord. No. 83-20, ยง 2, 4-19-83)</history></law>