<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.85</section_number>
<catch_line>Building Placement Standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004399</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.85. Building Placement Standards.<section prefix='A.'>The diagrams in paragraph (G) of this section establish the Building Placement Standards by land use category. Building frontage and setback areas shall be required as illustrated in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.</section><section prefix='B.'>Where Building Placement Standards Diagrams reference a Frontage Table, such table specific to each Urban Center or Area District shall be provided in the regulations for each individual District. It is provided, however, that colonnades may be placed on the property line regardless of any such frontage requirements. Unless otherwise provided, the colonnade height and width shall be in accordance with Section 33-284.86(B) of this article. When a Frontage Table is not provided in the individual Urban Center or Area District regulations, building setbacks shall be required as set forth in the following table:</section><section></section><section prefix='C.'>In all Sub-districts, mixed-use, non-residential, and multi-family, developments shall comply with the following:<section prefix='1.'>Minimum building frontage requirements may be met by a single building, multiple buildings or multi-phased developments, and such requirements shall apply along the front property line only.</section><section prefix='2.'>Where a minimum number of stories is required, said stories above the second story may be set back further than the requirements set forth in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.</section><section prefix='3.'>To articulate the building facade, fifty (50) percent of the portion of the building required to be located along the build-to line may be recessed up to two (2) feet. Further, once the minimum building frontage requirement is met, the remainder of the building may be set back from the build-to line.</section><section prefix='4.'>A portion of the building may be set back up to twenty-five (25) feet to accommodate a forecourt.</section><section prefix='5.'>Belfries, chimneys, spires/steeples, and other such non-habitable structures shall comply with Section 33-55 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='6.'>Accessory buildings shall follow parking and/or allowable building area setbacks provided in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.</section></section><section prefix='D.'>In all Sub-districts, accessory buildings for rowhouse, courtyard, sideyard, single-family detached, duplex and urban villa shall follow the accessory building/dwelling/parking area setbacks provided in the Building Placement Standards Diagrams.</section><section prefix='E.'>In all Sub-districts, for all land use categories, accessory structures shall be permitted provided that they do not encroach on the front and side street setbacks.</section><section prefix='F.'>The table below identifies the Building Placement Standards that apply to each Land Use Category:</section><section prefix='G.'>Building Placement Standards Diagrams.<section prefix='1.'>Mixed Use, Multi-Family:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>Building Frontage Required: Seventy (70) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.</section><section prefix='b.'>Build-to lines or street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from a service road or the lowest ranking street.</section><section prefix='d.'>The vehicular entry width permitted shall be a maximum of thirty-three (33) feet.</section><section prefix='e.'>The minimum interior side/rear setback for the pedestal, tower, and penthouse shall be zero (0) feet.</section><section prefix='f.'>Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.</section><section prefix='g.'>Colonnades shall be two (2) stories high and a minimum of fifteen (15) feet deep. The colonnade depth shall not exceed the colonnade height. The exterior of the colonnade shall be no closer than two (2) feet from the curb line.</section><section prefix='2.'>Mixed Use, Multi-Family:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>Building Frontage Required: Seventy (70) percent minimum at build-to line in all Sub-districts. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.</section><section prefix='b.'>Build-to lines or street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>The interior side/rear setbacks shall be as shown above.</section><section prefix='d.'>When provided, the front setback shall be hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk. A minimum of five (5) feet clear width within the setback shall be kept unobstructed for pedestrians.</section><section prefix='e.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road or lowest ranking street.</section><section prefix='f.'>Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.</section><section prefix='g.'>Above the fourth story the setback shall be from the property line.</section><section prefix='3.'>Industrial:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>Building Frontage Required: Twenty-five (25) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.</section><section prefix='b.'>Build-to lines or street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>For industrial uses, any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have an eight (8) foot high masonry wall, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.</section><section prefix='d.'>For all other uses permitted in the ID category, walls, fences and hedges shall be provided in accordance with Section 33-284.86(H) of this article, and where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a 5-foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.</section><section prefix='e.'>The interior side/rear setbacks shall be as shown above.</section><section prefix='f.'>When provided, the front setback and side street setback shall be landscaped or hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk.</section><section prefix='g.'>Above the fourth story the setback shall be from the property line.</section><section prefix='h.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from a service road or from the lowest ranking street.</section><section prefix='4.'>Rowhouse, Multi-Family:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>Building Frontage Required: Seventy (70) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road or lowest ranking street.</section><section prefix='d.'>The front setback and, when provided, the side street setback shall be landscaped.</section><section prefix='e.'>Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.</section><section prefix='f.'>Above the fourth story the setback shall be from the property line.</section><section prefix='5.'>Rowhouse:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>Building Frontage Required: One hundred (100) percent at build-to line except at end of building groups. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>For Rowhouses all on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road.</section><section prefix='d.'>The front setback and, when provided, the side street setback shall be landscaped.</section><section prefix='e.'>Common parking facilities shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='6.'>Courtyard, Sideyard:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>For Sideyard and Courtyard Houses, all on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>Any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have a masonry wall with a minimum height of forty-two (42) inches and a maximum height of seventy-two (72) inches, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.</section><section prefix='d.'>The front setback and, when provided, the side street setback shall be landscaped.</section><section prefix='7.'>Single-Family:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road, where provided.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>For lots with frontages between fifty (50) and seventy-five (75) feet, the minimum interior side setback shall be ten (10) percent of the lot frontage; for lots with frontage greater than seventy-five (75) feet, the interior side setback shall be a minimum of seven and a half (7.5) feet.</section><section prefix='d.'>The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.</section><section prefix='8.'>Single-Family:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from the street as shown above.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.</section><section prefix='d.'>Any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have a masonry wall with a minimum height of forty-two (42) inches and a maximum height of seventy-two (72) inches, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.</section><section prefix='e.'>Driveways between the front property line and build-to line shall be a maximum of ten (10) feet wide.</section><section prefix='9.'>Duplex:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.</section><section prefix='10.'>Duplex:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>This building standard shall only be permitted on existing platted lots less than twelve thousand (12,000) square feet in area.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from the street as shown above.</section><section prefix='d.'>Any part of the build-to line not occupied by a building shall have a masonry wall with a minimum height of forty-two (42) inches and a maximum height of seventy-two (72) inches, not pierced except to provide pedestrian and vehicular ingress/egress.</section><section prefix='e.'>Driveways between the front or side street property lines and build-to line shall be a maximum of ten (10) feet wide.</section><section prefix='f.'>The front and side street setback shall be landscaped.</section><section prefix='11.'>Civic:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>All on-site parking shall be accessed from the service road, where provided. For properties without an adjoining service road, parking may be accessed from the street through a driveway as shown above.</section><section prefix='b.'>Build-to lines and street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>When on-site parking is provided, the off-street parking spaces shall be placed to the rear of the building.</section><section prefix='d.'>Civic uses shall not be required to comply with height requirements indicated on the Building Heights Plan.</section><section prefix='e.'>When provided, the front and side street setback areas shall be treated as a green or plaza. When treated as a plaza, the setback area shall not be required to be fronted by mixed-use, retail, or office uses. When treated as a plaza or green, the plaza or green shall be in addition to any designated open space required by the regulating plan.</section><section prefix='f.'>Where a wall or fence is used to screen parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.</section><section prefix='12.'>Urban Villa:</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>Building Frontage Required. Eighty (80) percent minimum at build-to line. Minimum frontage requirement applies along the front property line only. At least fifty (50) percent of Urban Villas along a block face shall provide a walled court or patio between the front property line and the building face; maximum setback shall be fifteen (15) feet only where such court or patio is provided.</section><section prefix='b.'>Front and side street setback requirements shall be measured from the edge of sidewalk.</section><section prefix='c.'>Parking shall be accessed from the street as shown above. Garage entrances accessed from the front property line shall be a maximum of ten (10) feet in width and no further than ten (10) feet from the front property line. Walled courts or patios shall not be used for parking.</section><section prefix='d.'>The minimum height for an Urban Villa shall be two (2) stories.</section><section prefix='e.'>The front setback, and when provided, the side street setback, shall be landscaped.</section></section><section> </section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-143, § 5, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 06-10, § 2, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 07-93, § 3, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 07-169, § 8, 11-6-07; Ord. No. 08-102, § 2, 9-2-08; Ord. No. 12-86, § 4, 10-2-12)</history></law>