<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='3'>ARTICLE XXVII. BU-3 LIBERAL BUSINESS DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-256.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Plan review standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004260</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-256.8. Plan review standards.<section prefix='(A)'>The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The decisions of the Department in relation to the site plan review criteria may be appealed by the party(ies) which filed the application for the project to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board within thirty (30) days of the date the project was denied approval in writing. Appeals will be heard as expeditiously as possible. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination and variety in the design process and thereby insure the congruity of the proposed developments and its compatibility with the surrounding area. All final plans submitted for building permits shall be substantially in compliance with plans approved under the plan review procedure herein established.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Exhibits which the applicant shall submit to the Department shall include, but not be limited to the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Schematic site plan at a scale of not less than one (1) inch equals one hundred (100) feet containing the following information:<section prefix='(a)'>Proposed commercial floor area.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Height, size, shape and location of existing and proposed buildings.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Parking layouts.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Proposed grades if significantly altered.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Existing and proposed fences, walls, signs, architectural accents, street furniture and location of advertising or graphic features.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Schematic building plans including elevation and/or sections of major structures.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Isometrics or perspective and/or model(s) of the proposed development.</section></section><section>The Director shall have the right to waive any of the items required because of the nature or timing of the development or because the information cannot be furnished at the time of this review.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The following checklist of criteria shall be utilized as a guide by the Department and by the appropriate board, upon appeal, in the review process.<section prefix='(1)'>Planning studies. Design or planning studies completed by the Department and submitted to the County Commission that include recommendations for development patterns or site plan criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the site plan review process.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Exterior spatial relationships. The three-dimensional air-space volume created by the arrangement of structures and landscape shall produce spatial relationships that function with the intended use of the project and are compatible with the development or zoning in the adjoining area.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Landscape. Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscape treatment shall be provided to enhance architectural features, strengthen vistas and important axes and provide shade.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Buffers. Buffering elements that provide a logical transition to adjoining, existing or permitted uses shall be provided.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Scale. Scale of proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding existing or permitted uses or shall be made compatible by the use of the buffering element.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Signs and outdoor lighting. All outdoor lighting, signs or permanent outdoor advertising or identification features shall be designed as an integral part of and be harmonious with building design and the surrounding landscape.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Roof installation and facilities. All permitted installations housing mechanical equipment located in the roof shall be screened from ground view and from view at the level in which the installations are located, and shall be designed as an integral part of and be harmonious with the building design.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Circulation. Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as practicable and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the project and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development. When head-in parking is located directly adjacent to a storefront, an anti-ram fixture with a minimum Department of State protection rating of K4 shall be placed along the outer edge of the sidewalk to visually and physically separate the vehicular and pedestrian areas. Installations must include a landscaping/planting component to mitigate the visual impacts of the anti-ram fixture. The anti-ram fixture shall be continuous with reasonable breaks provided to allow for pedestrian access and compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Parking areas. Building wall extensions, plantings, berms or other innovative means shall be used as a means of minimizing the adverse effect of the visual impact of parking areas. This requirement is in addition to the requirements of the landscape regulations of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Service areas. Service areas which may be provided shall be screened and so located as not to be visible from view.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:<section prefix='(a)'>Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:<section prefix='(1)'>Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.</section></section><section prefix='(12)'>Window Height. When head-in parking is located directly adjacent to a storefront, ground floor windowsills shall be placed at a minimum height of 24 inches and a maximum of 48 inches above grade.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-25, § 1, 4-16-74; Ord. No. 95-19, § 12, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 18, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-38, § 13, 4-27-99; Ord. No. 12-47, § 4, 7-3-12)</history></law>