<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00026' order_by='00026' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. RU-3B, BUNGALOW COURT DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-206</section_number>
<catch_line>Number of families per unit; submission of plans before permit issued; minimum size; minimum number of units.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004145</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-206. Number of families per unit; submission of plans before permit issued; minimum size; minimum number of units.<section prefix='(a)'>Not more than one (1) family may occupy a bungalow court single unit nor more than two (2) families in a double (duplex) unit.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The special requirements applying to bungalow courts including minimum sizes of building and lot areas, shall apply only where all other provisions for bungalow courts are complied with. Before a permit shall be granted to place buildings of a lot under the bungalow court provisions plans shall be filed covering the size and spacing of all buildings intended in the court and the total area of lot to be included. In no case shall such first single bungalow be less than the minimum size required for a one (1) family residential building for the neighborhood by deed restrictions or zone regulations as shown on the official zoning maps, nor shall any units within fifty (50) feet of the street fronting the property be less than the minimum cubic content requirement for the area. Not less than three (3) units shall be permitted under the provisions of the bungalow court regulations. All cottages or bungalows in a court shall be of a similar design which meets the approval of the Director and shall be erected within specified time limits. Permit for the immediate erection of less than the total number of intended buildings shall be conditional upon the entire area of lot remaining available for such use.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 11(B), 10-22-57)</history></law>