<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00052' order_by='00052' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIID. PLANNED AREA DEVELOPMENT DISTRICT (PAD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.26</section_number>
<catch_line>Review procedures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004341</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.26. Review procedures.<section>The planned area development review procedures are divided into four (4) steps: (A) Preapplication conference; (B) total development plan review; (C) development tract review; and (D) review criteria.</section><section>(A)</section><section>To obtain information each applicant shall confer with the Department, other affected interested department heads, and where applicable, representatives of adjacent municipalities, in connection with the preparation of the planned area development application. It shall be the responsibility of the Department to coordinate and invite department heads, municipalities or their representatives to a joint meeting. The general outlines of the proposal evidenced schematically by sketch plans and including narrative information sufficient for the understanding of the proposed development shall be provided by the applicant for consideration at said joint meeting, before submission of the zoning application for Planned Area District boundary change. Thereafter and within ten (10) working days after the preapplication conference, the Director shall furnish the applicant with all written comments resulting from such conference including appropriate recommendations to inform and assist the applicant in his preparation of the components of the planned area development application.</section><section>(B)</section><section>Following the preapplication conference the total development plan reviews shall be initiated by the applicant. Required exhibits listed below and a completed development impact statement if required by of the Miami-Dade County Code, together with an application for public hearing as required by of the Miami-Dade County Code, shall be submitted to the Department.<section prefix='(1)'>Required exhibits—Written documents. The following written documents shall be submitted as part of the planned area development zoning application:<section prefix='(a)'>Recordable agreement guaranteeing the development in accordance with promises made in the written and graphic documents listed below as approved by the Community Zoning Appeals Board. Said agreement shall be submitted to the Department after the Development Impact Committee review and prior to the Community Zoning Appeals Board review.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A completed development impact statement, if required in Chapter 33 of the Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A development schedule indicating the approximate date(s) when construction of the planned area development and stages thereof can be expected to be initiated.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Quantitative data for the following: Total number of dwelling units; total number of bedrooms; size of total development proposed land coverage of buildings and structures; acres of common open space; gross and net residential densities; total amount of open space; total amount of nonresidential construction, amount of public and private roads, and population projections.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Tentative agreements with appropriate governmental agencies for the proposed dedication of land for public uses prior to public hearing.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Required exhibits—Graphic documents. Maps, site plans and drawings of the proposed planned area development shall be submitted as part of the total development plan and shall contain the following minimum information:<section prefix='(a)'>The existing site characteristics including any major variations of elevations, water course(s), unique natural features, and natural vegetation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Legal description and size of developmental tracts (see Section 33-284.27(B) for details of developmental tracts).</section><section prefix='(c)'>The location of all major land uses with densities and/or floor area of such uses including structure heights, with drawings indicating basic development concepts of the proposed development.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The location and size in acres or square feet of all areas to be conveyed, dedicated, or reserved as common open spaces, public facility space, common recreational areas, school sites, and similar public and semipublic uses.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The existing and proposed circulation system of arterial and collector streets, and major points of access to public rights-of-way including major points of ingress and egress to the development. Notations of proposed ownership of roadways—public or private—should be included where appropriate.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The existing and proposed pedestrian, equestrian and bicycle circulation systems including interrelationships with the vehicular circulation system, indicating proposed treatment of points of conflicts.</section><section prefix='(g)'>A schematic landscape plan in accordance with Chapter 18 A of this Code, indicating the proposed design of major landscape elements. Plant names and sizes of tree masses shall be provided.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Adequate information on land areas adjacent to the proposed planned area development to indicate the relationships between the proposed development and adjacent areas, including existing land uses, zoning classifications, densities, vehicular, pedestrian and equestrian circulation systems and public facilities, as well as unique natural features of the landscape.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The proposed treatment of the perimeter of the planned area development including materials and techniques to be used such as screens, landscape buffer, fences, walls and berms when appropriate.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Any additional information required by the review authority necessary to evaluate the character and impact of the proposed planned area development.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Review process. The review of the total development plan of a planned area development shall be by the Developmental Impact Committee, and review and action by the Community Zoning Appeals Board shall be in accord with Section 33-304(f) of the Miami-Dade County Code.</section></section><section>(C)</section><section>Following approval of the total development plan by the Community Zoning Appeals Board, review at the development tract level may be initiated.<section prefix='(1)'>Required exhibits. The following exhibits shall be prepared by Florida registered landscape architects, architects and engineers and shall accompany the development tract review application to be filed with the Department:<section prefix='(a)'>A plan indicating existing zoning on site and adjacent areas.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Aerial photograph or map indicating site and development in the immediate area.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Site plan at no less than one (1) inch to fifty (50) feet which shall include the following information:<section prefix='1.'>Location, shape, size and height of existing and proposed buildings, fences and walls.</section><section prefix='2.'>Pedestrian, equestrian and vehicular circulation systems.</section><section prefix='3.'>Parking layouts and drives.</section><section prefix='4.'>Landscaping in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='5.'>Major changes in grades.</section><section prefix='6.'>Building setbacks and spacing.</section><section prefix='7.'>A legend including the following applicable information shall be provided as part of the site plan in accordance with the following format:</section><section prefix='8.'>The following information shall be provided on the site plan or in a separate document:<section>Amount of pervious and impervious surfaces.</section><section>Maximum density of development tract approved at public hearing.</section><section>Density as proposed.</section><section>Total dwelling units.</section><section>Table of dwelling unit mix.</section><section>Total number of bedrooms.</section><section>Total number of building types including accessory buildings.</section><section>Table of buildings by heights, stories, unit types, and square footage.</section><section>Name of water utility.</section><section>Name of sewer utility.</section><section>Required private open space.</section><section>Provided minimum and average private open space.</section><section>Table of parking spaces required and provided.</section><section>Acreage dedicated for public and semipublic facilities.</section><section>Survey of existing trees.</section><section>Total trees required and provided in accordance with of this Code.</section><section>Any supplementary data needed to adequately review the proposed development.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Floor plans, elevations, sections, when appropriate, and either isometrics or perspectives for the different proposed buildings at no less than one (1) inch equals sixteen (16) feet which shall include the following information:<section prefix='1.'>Location, shape, size and heights of enclosed and unenclosed spaces within the proposed buildings.</section><section prefix='2.'>Horizontal and vertical circulation systems of the proposed buildings.</section><section prefix='3.'>Design of the outdoor surfaces of the proposed buildings.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Review process. Prior to the development of a development tract (see Section 33-284.27(B)) or prior to the sale, transfer or lease of any portion of a development tract, a development tract plan shall be prepared, submitted to, and approved by the Department for review and approval in accordance with review criteria, Section 33-284.26(D), and development plan(s) approved by the Community Zoning Appeals Board. Said development tract plan is a detailed refinement of information provided in the approved total development plan. If the planned area development involves only one (1) development tract the same procedure shall be followed.<section>Upon approval of a development tract plan, a copy of said approved plan and statement of approval shall be forwarded to the applicant and to the Department for filing in the planned area development file for the particular project.</section><section>If requested approval is denied, the proposed project may be appealed to the Community Zoning Appeals Board, in accordance with regulations as provided in governing appeals from administrative decisions contained in the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section><section>(D)</section><section>The following criteria shall be utilized as a basis for the review of the total development plan and the development tract plans:<section prefix='(1)'>Purpose and intent. The proposed development shall fulfill the purpose and intent of this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Planning studies. Design, planning or development studies accepted or approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental design criteria which would apply to the development proposal under review shall be utilized in the site plan review process.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Exterior spatial relationships. The three-dimensional airspace volume created by the arrangement of structures and landscape shall produce spatial relationships that function with the intended use and occupancy of the project and are compatible with the development or zoning in the adjoining area. Building height shall reflect a scale compatible with the development or zoning in the adjoining area. Elements that provide a logical transition to adjoining existing or permitted uses shall be provided. Spacing between buildings shall provide ample access for emergency equipment.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Subtropical characteristics. Architecture and site development should incorporate consideration of the subtropical characteristics of the area. The provision of sun-control devices, shaded areas, vegetation, roof terraces and similar features characteristic of subtropical design shall be encouraged.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Energy conservation. Design methods to reduce energy consumption shall be encouraged. Energy conservation methods may include but not be limited to natural ventilation of structures, siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles, insulation of structures, use of landscape material for shade, direction of breezes and transpiration.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Privacy. Due consideration of aural and visual privacy shall be evidenced in the design of the overall development and in the design of individual units.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Open space. A variety of open spaces shall be provided, appropriate to the needs of the particular type of development. Open space shall relate to any natural characteristics in such a way as to preserve and enhance their scenic and functional qualities to the fullest extent possible and shall be so located and developed as to be easily accessible to all residents of the development.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Landscape. The landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing tree removal. Landscaping shall be used to shade and cool, direct wind movements, provide scale, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to the site, visually screen noncompatible uses and block noise generated by the major roadways and intense use areas.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Location of public and semipublic uses. All public uses and semipublic uses such as churches, schools, day care centers, post offices, and other similar facilities shall be so located as to provide easy access by residents of the proposed development.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Circulation. Pedestrian, bicycle trails and equestrian trails shall be separated from auto circulation insofar as is practicable and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional in its relationship to circulation systems outside the development.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Parking areas. Parking areas shall be provided that are screened and so located as not to interfere with the livability of the development, its environs, and adjacent properties. Parking areas shall be conveniently located for occupants of the residential structures.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Service areas. Service areas shall be provided that are screened and so located as not to interfere with the livability of the development or adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Visual screening for decorative walls. In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:<section prefix='(a)'>Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:<section prefix='(1)'>Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 76-106, § 1(3), 12-7-76; Ord. No. 78-2, § 1, 1-3-78; Ord. No. 84-28, § 1, 4-3-84; Ord. No. 95-19, § 19, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 27, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-38, § 20, 4-27-99)</history></law>