<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.81</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004395</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.81. Purpose and applicability.<section prefix='A.'>The Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) contains directives to promote urban centers in places where mass transit, roadways, and highways are highly accessible. The CDMP provides for three types of urban centers: community (CUC), metropolitan (MUC) and regional (RUC).</section><section prefix='B.'>The regulations in this article shall apply to urban centers, as defined in the CDMP. Specifically, these standard regulations apply to the Urban Center Districts provided for in this code that were created after the effective date of this ordinance (July 27, 2005). Each Urban Center District, as adopted by the Board of County Commissioners by separate ordinances, shall contain a set of regulating plans and additional regulations addressing unique circumstances that, in conjunction with this article, shall control development in each particular urban center.</section><section prefix='C.'>The standard regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18-A, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='D.'>The area within the boundaries of an urban center is divided in three Sub-districts: Core, Center and Edge. The highest density and intensity within an urban center shall be allocated to the Core Sub-districts, a mixed-use area adjacent to the transit station(s) or major transit stop(s). The densities and intensities shall then gradually decrease from the Core to the Center Sub-district where mixed-uses are still permitted and then further decrease to the Edge Sub-district which is characterized by single uses, including low density residential.</section><section prefix='E.'>In the case of multiple-phase development, each phase of the development, whether standing independently or in conjunction with existing developed or proposed future contiguous phases, shall meet all the requirements of this article and of the additional requirements and of the regulating plans provided in each Urban Center Districts. In addition, construction of each phase shall be directed first toward the street of higher hierarchy as provided in the Urban Center Districts; and the minimum building frontage length requirements may be disregarded in approving each individual phase, provided that the building frontage length requirements are met at the conclusion of all phases.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-143, ยง 1, 7-7-05)</history></law>