<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00057' order_by='00057' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(I). DOWNTOWN KENDALL URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.63.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Center DRI Sub-District Alternative Development Parameters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004381</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.63.1. Center DRI Sub-District Alternative Development Parameters.<section>Notwithstanding the provisions of sections and, property within the Center DRI Sub-district may be developed in compliance with the following provisions. Development undertaken pursuant to the following provisions shall be subject exclusively to those provisions and not to any of the provision or requirements of sections or. Development in the Center DRI Sub-district pursuant to sections and shall be subject exclusively to the provisions and requirements of those sections and not to the provision contained herein.<section prefix='(A)'>Uses permitted. No land, body of water or structure in the Center DRI Sub-district shall be used or permitted to be used, and no structure shall be hereafter erected, constructed, arranged or intended to be used, occupied or maintained for any purpose, except for one or more of the following uses:<section prefix='(1)'>All uses permitted in the BU-2 District.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Electric Vehicle Retail Showroom.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Setbacks, cubic content, yard area and lot size requirements. There shall be no setback requirements, minimum cubic content requirements, yard area requirements, or minimum lot size requirements.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Building height and number of stories. Building height shall be limited to eight (8) stories. A story shall be measured from floor to ceiling, with a minimum clearance of eight (8) feet and a maximum clearance of fourteen (14) feet. In the event that the clearance in any story is greater than fourteen (14) feet, it shall be counted as more than one story.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Floor area and lot coverage. The floor area ratio and lot coverage are not limited.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Landscaped open space. There shall be no landscaping requirement. However, if landscaping is provided, all plant material shall be in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Parking. No parking spaces are required, but if parking spaces are provided, such spaces shall comply with sections 33-122, 33-122.2, 33-122.3 and 33-131 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(G)'>Enclosed uses. All uses in the Center DRI Sub-district shall be conducted within completely enclosed buildings, unless otherwise specifically provided herein. All materials and products shall be stored within the building or within an area completely enclosed with masonry walls not less than six (6) feet in height. Storage shall not be made above the height of the walls.</section><section prefix='(H)'>Plan review standards for the Center DRI Sub-district.<section prefix='(1)'>The purpose of the plan review is to encourage logic, imagination and variety in the design process and thereby insure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. The Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria contained herein. The decision of the Department in relation to the plan review criteria may be appealed by the applicant to the Board of County Commissioners within thirty (30) days of the date the project was denied approval in writing. Such appeals shall be in accordance with Section 33-309 and shall be heard as expeditiously as possible. All final plans submitted for building permits shall be substantially in compliance with the plans approved under the plan review procedure herein established.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Exhibits which the applicant shall submit to the Department shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Schematic and fully dimensioned site plan including the following information:<section prefix='(i)'>Lot lines and setbacks.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Location, shape, size, height and use of all existing and proposed buildings.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Location of decorative walls, entrance features and signage.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Location of landscaping, if any.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Location of off-street parking, if any, and parking layout.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Location of outdoor lighting.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Location of loading facilities, waste collection areas and other service areas.</section><section prefix='(viii)'>Location of internal drives, including ingress and egress drives to existing or proposed roadway and sidewalk systems.</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Location of pedestrian access points, including connections to existing or proposed bridges, roadways, or sidewalk areas.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including total gross square footage of each floor, the floor area ratio of each building and the total floor area ratio.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Figures indicating the following:<section prefix='(i)'>Gross and net acreage.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Amount of building coverage at ground level in square feet.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Total trees and shrubs, if any, percentage of landscaping and type of plant material.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Location and number of parking spaces, if any, parking layout and total amount of paved areas in square feet.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Such other design data as may be needed to evaluate the project.</section></section></section><section prefix='(3)'>The following checklist of criteria shall be utilized by the Department in the review process:<section prefix='(a)'>Circulation. Pedestrian and auto circulation shall be separated insofar as is practicable, and all circulation systems shall adequately serve the needs of the development and be compatible and functional with circulation systems outside the development.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Signs and outdoor lighting. All signs and outdoor lighting shall be designed as an integral part of and be harmonious with the building design and the surrounding landscape.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Service areas. Service areas shall be screened and so located as not to be visible from view.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Roof installations and facilities. All permitted installations housing mechanical equipment located on the roof shall be screened from ground view at the level at which the installations are located, and shall be designed as an integral part of and be harmonious with the building design.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Outdoor furniture and graphics. All outdoor furniture and graphics shall be designed as an integral part of the overall design of the project.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Art display. Permanent interior and exterior art displays, sculptures and water features should be encouraged in the overall design of the project.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-11, ยง 5, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 13-41, ยง 2, 5-7-13)</history></law>