<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(L). GOULDS COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.91</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose and Intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004407</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.91. Purpose and Intent.<section prefix='A.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Illustrative Master Plan (Figure 1), illustrates the citizens' vision and may be used to interpret this article. Where the Illustrative Master Plan conflicts with the text of this article, the text shall govern.</section><section prefix='C.'>The boundaries shown in Figure 1 shall constitute the Goulds Community Urban Center Boundary Plan and are generally described as follows: from the intersection of the south side of the right-of-way of the Black Creek Canal with the extension of the centerline of SW 114th Avenue, then south along the centerline of SW 114th Avenue to the centerline of SW 214th Street, then east along theoretical SW 214th Street to the centerline of SW 113th Avenue, then south along the centerline of SW 113th Avenue to the centerline of SW 216th Street, then west along the centerline of SW 216th Street to the centerline of SW 115th Avenue, then south along the centerline of SW 115th Avenue to the centerline of SW 220th Street, then west along the centerline of SW 220th Street to a point located approximately 190 feet west of the centerline SW 120th Avenue, then north along an imaginary line at 190 feet to the west of the centerline of SW 120th Avenue to the south side of the right-of-way of the Black Creek Canal, then east along the south side of the right-of-way of the Black Creek Canal to the beginning point.</section><section>A more detailed legal description of the boundaries follows:<section>Beginning in the intersection of south side of the R/W of the Black Creek Canal and the centerline of SW 114th Avenue, then South along the centerline of SW 114th Avenue to the intersection with the centerline of SW 214th Street, then East along the centerline of 214th Street, to the intersection with the centerline of SW 113 Avenue, then South along the centerline of SW 113 Avenue to the intersection with the centerline of SW 216th Street, then Westerly along the centerline of SW 216th Street to the intersection with the centerline of SW 115 Avenue, then South along the centerline of SW 115 Avenue to the intersection with the centerline of SW 220th Street, then West along the centerline of SW 220th Street to a point located approximately 190 feet West of the centerline of SW 120th Avenue, and intersecting with the centerline of the SW 220th Street, then North along an imaginary line at 190 feet parallel and west of the centerline of SW 120th Avenue to the intersection with the south side of the R/W of the Black Creek Canal, then East along the south side of the R/W of the Black Creek Canal to the point of beginning (the intersection with the centerline of SW 114th Avenue).</section></section><section prefix='D.'>Full scale maps of the Illustrative Master Plan presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='E.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the Goulds Community Urban Center District (GCUC) as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the GCUC shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to GCUC has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-144, ยง 1, 7-7-05)</history></law>