<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXV. HOMESTEAD AIR FORCE BASE ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-297</section_number>
<catch_line>Variances and appeals.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004493</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-297. Variances and appeals.<section>Any person desiring to erect any structures, or increase the height of any structure, or permit the growth of any tree, or otherwise use his property in violation of the airport zoning regulations adopted under this chapter, may apply to the Community Zoning Appeals Board for a variance from the zoning regulations in question. Such variances shall be allowed where a literal application or enforcement of regulations would result in practical difficulty or unnecessary hardship and the relief granted would not be contrary to the public interest but do substantial justice and be in accordance with the spirit of these regulations. Provided, that any variance may be allowed subject to any reasonable conditions that the Board may deem necessary to effectuate the purpose of these regulations. All such variances shall be applied for in the same manner as any other variances and shall be granted only after the same notice and hearing as required in the case of other variances. Any person aggrieved, or taxpayer affected, by any decision of the administrative agency made in its administration of these airport zoning regulations or any governing body or Board of a political subdivision, or any airport zoning board, which is of the opinion that a decision of such administrative agency is an improper application of these airport zoning regulations of concern to such governing body, may appeal to the Community Zoning Appeals Board to hear and decide appeals from the decision of such administrative agency.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-33, ยง 1, 5-21-68; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 21, 9-3-98)</history></law>