<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00054' order_by='00054' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIIIF. ZERO LOT LINE DEVELOPMENTS (ZLL)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.43</section_number>
<catch_line>Development parameters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004358</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.43. Development parameters.<section>All applications for a zero lot line development shall comply with the following applicable development parameters:<section prefix='(A)'>Uses permitted. Detached one-family dwellings on individually platted lots, including every customary accessory use not inconsistent therewith, shall be permitted. Fencing, walls, trellises, and other similar uses can be used as connecting elements between one-family dwellings on adjacent lots subject to site plan review. Garages, carports and utility storage structures shall be permitted accessory uses; however, said structures shall not be used as connecting elements.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Minimum lot sizes and widths. Calculation of lot size shall not include any credit for streets, recreation areas, common open space, water bodies, or private roads.<section prefix='(1)'>The minimum net lot size shall be four thousand five hundred (4,500) square feet for sites zoned RU-1Z. For each lot that is less than five thousand (5,000) square feet, there shall be two (2) lots of five thousand (5,000) square feet or greater in size. The minimum lot width shall be forty-five (45) feet.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The minimum net lot size shall be four thousand (4,000) square feet for sites zoned RU-2, RU-TH, RU-3, RU-3M, RU-4, RU-4A, RU-4L, or RU-4M. For each lot that is less than four thousand five hundred (4,500) square feet, there shall be two lots of four thousand five hundred (4,500) square feet or greater in size. The minimum lot width shall be forty (40) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Dwelling unit setback.<section>The dwelling unit or a portion thereof shall be placed on one (1) interior side property line with a zero (0) setback and the dwelling unit setback on the other interior side property line shall be a minimum of ten (10) feet excluding the connecting elements such as fences, walls and trellises. It is provided, however, that units are not required to be placed on the zero lot line property line when said units fall at the end of a sequential row of units and where said units cannot be placed on a separate zero lot line without attaching the unit to an adjacent unit. In that event a minimum spacing of ten (10) feet shall be provided from the residence on the adjacent zero lot line lot. Patios, pools, garden features and other similar elements shall be permitted within the ten-foot setback area; provided, however, no structure, with the exception of fences or walls shall be placed within easements required by Subsection (K).</section><section>All dwelling structures shall be set back a minimum of twenty (20) feet from the front property line for a minimum of fifty (50) percent of the width of the lot and shall be set back a minimum of ten (10) feet along the remaining width of the lot.</section><section>The minimum rear spacing between dwelling units shall be thirty (30) feet between two (2) story units or between a one (1) story and a two (2) story unit. The minimum rear spacing between one (1) story units shall be twenty (20) feet.</section><section>The dwelling setback shall be a minimum of fifteen (15) feet from the side street property line.</section><section>shall comply with the following minimum setback requirements.</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Alleys. Alleys shall be permitted in zero lot line developments. Said alleys shall provide auto access to individual units and provide service access for trash collection and other public and private services. Alleys shall not be used as storage or parking areas.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Street frontage. Each lot shall have a clear, direct frontage on public streets or to accessways complying with private street requirements.</section><section prefix='(F)'>Maximum lot coverage permitted. The total lot coverage permitted for all buildings on the site shall not exceed fifty (50) percent of the lot area.</section><section prefix='(G)'>Platting requirements. Each dwelling shall be located on its own individual platted lot. If areas for common use of occupants of the development are shown on the plat, satisfactory arrangements shall be made for the maintenance of the common open space and facilities as provided in Subsection (N) of this article [section]. The plat shall indicate the zero lot lines and easements appurtenant thereto.</section><section prefix='(H)'>Building heights. The maximum building height shall not exceed two (2) stories and thirty-five (35) feet in height.</section><section prefix='(I)'>Integration of interior/exterior areas through the use of penetrable openings. The amount of penetrable opening shall be determined by multiplying 0.018 times the interior floor area, excluding garages, up to a maximum of one thousand (1,000) square feet on the ground floor of a dwelling unit. Said penetrable openings shall be provided to exterior patio court areas and shall be totally visual and physically passable. The amount of penetrable opening for units between one thousand (1,000) square feet and fifteen hundred (1,500) square feet shall be calculated on a basis of 0.014 times the square feet of interior floor area on the ground floor. No additional penetrable opening shall be required when the ground floor square footage, excluding garage, exceeds fifteen hundred (1,500) square feet. In all cases, the final linear dimension of said openings shall be calculated to the nearest even foot.</section><section prefix='(J)'>Openings prohibited on the zero lot line side. The wall of the dwelling unit located on the lot line shall have no windows, doors, air-conditioning units, or any other type of openings except for the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Atriums or courts shall be permitted on the zero lot line side when the court or atrium is enclosed by three (3) walls of the dwelling unit, and a solid wall of at least eight (8) feet in height is provided on the zero lot line. Said wall shall be constructed of the same material as exterior walls of the unit.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Windows shall be permitted on the zero lot line side provided said windows are placed at a minimum height of six (6) feet above the finished floor level of any floor adjacent to the wall below the window.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Windows shall be permitted on a building wall which is located perpendicular to the zero lot line property line or where said windows are located at least ten (10) feet from the property line.</section></section><section prefix='(K)'>Maintenance and drainage easements. A perpetual four-foot wall-maintenance easement shall be provided on the lot adjacent to the zero lot line property line, which, with the exception of walls and/or fences, shall be kept clear of structures. This easement shall be shown on the plat and incorporated into each deed transferring title to the property. The wall shall be maintained in its original color and treatment unless otherwise agreed to in writing by the two (2) affected lot owners. Roof overhangs may penetrate the easement on the adjacent lot a maximum of twenty-four (24) inches but the roof shall be so designed that water runoff from the dwelling placed on the lot line is limited to the easement area. Building footings may penetrate the easement on the adjacent lot a maximum of eight (8) inches.</section><section prefix='(L)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(M)'>Trees and shrubs. Trees, as defined within Chapter 18A, Landscaping, shall be provided on the basis of four (4) trees for each platted lot. In addition, street shade trees shall be provided along each side of the roadway(s) at a minimum spacing of thirty (30) feet on center for private roads. In case of developments with public roads, the trees may be placed on private lots in lieu of the public right-of-way, provided the thirty-foot spacing and the rowing of trees are maintained. This shall be in addition to the four (4) trees required for each platted lot. Existing trees, excluding those trees exempt from the protection provisions within Chapter 26B, Tree Preservation, shall be preserved to the maximum extent practical and shall count towards meeting the total tree requirements. Removal of any existing trees shall be in accordance with the provisions within Chapter 26B, Tree Preservation. A minimum of twenty (20) shrubs of a minimum height of eighteen (18) inches shall be planted in the front yard of each dwelling unit. Where double frontage lots are proposed, a minimum five-foot landscape buffer is required. Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(N)'>Common open space and maintenance of facilities. Common open space is not required but may be permitted. If common open space is provided, provisions satisfactory to the Community Zoning Appeals Board shall be made to assure that nonpublic areas and facilities for the common use of occupants of zero lot line development shall be maintained in a satisfactory manner, without expense to the general taxpayer of Miami-Dade County. Such may be provided by the incorporation of an automatic membership home association for the purpose of continually holding title to such nonpublic areas and facilities, and levying assessments against each lot, whether improved or not, for the purpose of paying the taxes and maintaining such common open space. Such assessments shall be a lien superior to all other liens save and except tax liens and first mortgage liens, which are amortized in monthly or quarter-annual payments over a period of not less than ten (10) years. Other methods may be acceptable if the same positively provide for the proper and continuous payment of taxes and maintenance without expense to the general taxpayers. The instrument incorporating such provisions shall be approved by the County Attorney, as to form and legal sufficiency, before submission to the Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners, and shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, if satisfactory to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(O)'>Fence/walls requirements. Fences and/or walls, with an overall height of six (6) feet, shall be provided on all side and rear property lines that are located behind the front building line and where said walls and/or fences are needed, as determined by site plan review, to visually screen patio/or deck areas from nearby units, or from public or private roadways. Chain link fencing shall be permitted only when shrubbery is planted with, and along, the fencing; shrubbery shall be provided at a maximum spacing of thirty (30) inches on center with an overall height of twenty-four (24) inches at time of planting. Species selected shall be of a variety that grows to a minimum overall height of six (6) feet. Planting shall be installed and maintained on both sides of a chain link fence where said fence is placed on a property line that divides individual zero lot line lots. Fences and/or walls are not required on property lines which abut a lake, canal, or golf course and other similar areas.</section><section prefix='(P)'>Storage area. Forty (40) square feet of storage area per unit with outdoor access shall be provided when a garage is not provided.</section><section prefix='(Q)'>Minimum number of elevations. Projects with fifty (50) or fewer units shall have a minimum of three (3) different elevations. Projects with more than fifty (50) units shall have a minimum of five (5) different elevations.</section><section prefix='(R)'>Sidewalks. Sidewalks shall be required on both sides of all streets.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-9, § 1, 2-3-81; Ord. No. 83-38, § 1, 6-7-83; Ord. No. 88-9, § 2, 2-16-88; Ord. No. 91-36, § 8, 3-19-91; Ord. No. 93-111, § 1, 10-19-93; Ord. No. 94-163, § 1, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 95-223, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 30, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 99-39, § 1, 4-27-99)</history></law>