<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00065' order_by='00065' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(Q). LEISURE CITY COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT (LCUC)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.34</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004449</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.99.34. Uses.<section>Except as provided herein, all permitted, conditionally permitted, and temporary uses within the LCUC District shall comply with of this code. In addition to the Permitted Uses provided in(A), the following shall be permitted:<section prefix='1.'>In the Mixed-Use Corridor (MC) area:<section prefix='(a)'>Automobile and truck services and facilities including:<section prefix='(1)'>Open lot car and truck sales new or used, including as ancillary uses, automobile repairs, body and top work and painting, provided that no more than fifteen (15) percent of the gross building area is devoted to such ancillary uses, and subject to the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>That attention-attracting devices, such as blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers and all fluttering, spinning advertising devices (either mobile or stationary) are prohibited.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That outdoor lighting shall be designed to avoid spilling beyond the site boundaries.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That no vehicular test drives shall be conducted on residential local traffic streets (fifty-foot right-of-way or less).</section><section prefix='(d)'>That the applicant obtains a certificate of use, which shall be automatically renewable yearly upon compliance with all terms and conditions.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Open lot car rental</section><section prefix='(3)'>Automobile parts, secondhand from store building only.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Automobile body and top work and painting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Engines, gas, gasoline, steam and oil; sales and service.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Garage or mechanical service, including automobile repairs, body and top work and painting. All outdoor paging or speaker systems are expressly prohibited.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Glass installation.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Tire vulcanizing and retreading or sale of used tires.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Truck storage, only within an enclosed building or an area enclosed by a CBS wall.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Automobile washing.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Self-service mini-warehouse storage facility in compliance with Section 33-255(23.1) of this Code.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>In the Industrial District (ID) area:<section prefix='(a)'>In the Core Sub-district, MC uses at a maximum density of 52 units per net acre or at a maximum density of 60 units per net acre with the purchase of the appropriate number of Severable Use Rights pursuant to sections 33B-41 to 33B-47 of this code.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the Center Sub-district, MC uses at a maximum density of 36 units per net acre.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>In the Institutional (I) area:<section prefix='(a)'>On properties located between SW 282 and SW 284 Streets, west of SW 152 Avenue, all uses permitted in the Residential (RM) with the density provided on the Density Plan in Section 33-284.35 of this code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-169, ยง 3, 11-6-07)</history></law>