<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.84</section_number>
<catch_line>Regulating Plans.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004398</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.84. Regulating Plans.<section>A set of Regulating Plans shall be provided with each adopted Urban Center or Area District. The Regulating Plans shall consist of a series of controlling plans that include the following:<section prefix='A.'>The Street Types Plan, which establishes a hierarchy of street types in existing and future locations that shall be provided and shown in all development plans.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Sub-districts Plan, which delineates three (3) sub-districts: Core, Center and Edge. These Sub-districts shall regulate the allowable intensity of development in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and this article.</section><section prefix='C.'>The Land Use Plan, which delineates the areas where specified land uses and development of various types and intensities shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='D.'>The Building Heights Plan, which establishes the minimum and maximum allowable number of stories and permits developments to reach CDMP Urban Center intensity ranges.<section prefix='1.'>Developments in Community Urban Centers shall meet the intensity range by:<section prefix='a.'>Providing the required minimum/maximum number of stories; or</section><section prefix='b.'>Providing a minimum of one (1) story and the following applicable minimum floor-area ratio:<section prefix='i.'>In the Edge Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one-half (0.5);</section><section prefix='ii.'>In the Center Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one (1); and</section><section prefix='iii.'>In the Core Sub-district a minimum of floor area ratio of one and one-half (1.5).</section></section></section><section prefix='2.'>Developments in Metropolitan Urban Centers shall meet the intensity range by:<section prefix='a.'>Providing the required minimum/maximum number of stories; or</section><section prefix='b.'>Providing a minimum of one (1) story and the applicable minimum floor-area ratio:<section prefix='i.'>In the Edge Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one and one-half (1.5);</section><section prefix='ii.'>In the Center Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of one and three-quarters (1.75); and</section><section prefix='iii.'>In the Core Sub-district, a minimum floor area ratio of three (3).</section></section></section></section><section prefix='E.'>The Designated Open Space Plan, which designates open spaces, which shall be shown in all development plans. The designated open spaces shall be controlled by anchor points.</section><section prefix='F.'>The New Streets Plan, which shows the location and the number of new streets needed to create the prescribed network of streets within each Urban Center or Area District. All new A streets shall be required in the same general location as shown on the New Streets Plan. All B streets shall be located as provided in Section 33-284.86(C) of this article.</section><section prefix='G.'>The Bike Route Plan, which depicts the designated bike routes, including the bike facility requirements if any, which shall be shown in all development plans.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-143, ยง 4, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 12-86, ยง 3, 10-2-12)</history></law>