<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXV. HOMESTEAD AIR FORCE BASE ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-292</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004485</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-292. Definitions.<section>As used in this article, unless the context otherwise required:<section prefix='(1)'>Airport is the Homestead Air Force Base Airport.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Airport hazard is any structure or tree or use of land which obstructs the air space required for the safe flight of aircraft in landing or taking-off or maneuvering at or in the vicinity of the airport, or is otherwise hazardous to such landing or taking-off of aircraft.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Airport hazard area is any area of land or water upon which an airport hazard might be established if not prevented as provided in this article.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Nonconforming use is any structure, tree, or use of land which does not conform to this article as of the effective date thereof.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Person is any individual, firm, co-partnership, corporation, company, association, joint stock association or body politic, and includes any trustee, receiver, assignee or other similar representative thereof.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Structure is any object constructed or installed by man, including but without limitation, buildings, towers, smokestacks, utility poles and overhead transmission lines.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Land area is any land or water area outside the governmental reservation and lying within the unincorporated and incorporated area of the County.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Tree is any object of natural growth.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Landing area is that part of the airfield that is used or intended to be used for landing and taking-off of aircraft, and the adjacent clear zone.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Primary surface is that surface which defines the limits of the obstruction clearance requirements in the immediate vicinity of the landing area. This area is entirely within the government reservation.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Clear zone surface is an area entirely within the government reservation and defines the limits of the obstruction clearance requirements in the vicinity contiguous to the ends of the primary surfaces.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Approach-departure clearance surface is an imaginary plane symmetrical about the runway centerline extended, beginning as an inclined plane (known as the glide angle) two hundred (200) feet beyond each end of the ultimate primary surface at the centerline elevation of the runway end (established airfield elevation) and extends for fifty thousand (50,000) feet. The slope of the approach-departure clearance surface is eighty to one (80:1) along the runway centerline extended (glide angle) until it reaches an elevation of five hundred (500) feet above the established airfield elevation. It then continues horizontally at this elevation to a point fifty thousand (50,000) feet from the start of the original inclined plane. The width of this surface at the runway end is two thousand (2,000) feet; it flares uniformly to a width of sixteen thousand (16,000) feet at fifty thousand (50,000) feet.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Inner horizontal surface is a plane; oval shape at a height of one hundred fifty (150) feet above the established airfield elevation. It is constructed by scribing an arc with a radius of seventy-five hundred (7500) feet about the centerline at the ends of the runway and interconnecting these arcs with tangents.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Conical surface is an inclined surface extending outward and upward from the outer periphery of the inner horizontal surface for a horizontal distance of seven thousand (7,000) feet to a height of five hundred (500) feet above the established airfield elevation. The slope of the conical surface is 20:1. It is constructed by scribing an arc with a radius of fourteen thousand five hundred (14,500) feet about the centerline at the ends of the runway and interconnecting these arcs with tangents.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Outer horizontal surface is a plane located five hundred (500) feet above the established airfield elevation. It extends for a horizontal distance of thirty thousand (30,000) feet from the outer periphery of the conical surface.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Transitional surfaces connect the primary surfaces, clear zone surface, and approach-departure clearance surfaces to the inter horizontal surface, conical surface, outer horizontal surface or other transitional surfaces. The slope of the transitional surface is seven to one (7:1) outward and upward at right angles to the runway centerline.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Established airfield elevation is seven (7) feet above MSL.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Airfield reference point is a point or points on the airfield from which certain distances relative to specific criteria referred to in this article are measured. For the purpose of this article, the reference points will be at each end of the runway and on its centerline. These points are described and located in Section 33-293.1</section><section prefix='(19)'>A zone is that area of land falling beneath any surface and each zone will have the same name as the surface describing it.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Administrative agency is the Department, with its Director as the chief executive, is hereby designated the administrative agency charged with the duty of administering and enforcing the regulations herein prescribed, including that of hearing for permits.</section><section prefix='(21)'>MSL—Mean sea level whenever the term MSL or mean sea level is used in the article, the same shall mean one (1) and the same thing.</section><section prefix='(22)'>The County's Community Zoning Appeals Board is hereby appointed the "Board of Adjustment," pursuant to Section 333.10, Florida Statutes.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-33, § 1, 5-21-68; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98)</history></law>