<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.86</section_number>
<catch_line>General Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004400</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-284.86. General Requirements.<section prefix='A.'>Lots and blocks. The following shall be required:</section><section prefix='B.'>Buildings.<section prefix='1.'>Storefronts shall be provided on the first floor of mixed-use buildings, and shall be directly accessible from a street frontage or a designated open space as follows:<section prefix='a.'>For properties with two or more frontages, storefronts shall be located on a minimum of two frontages, with priority given to frontages on a designated open space and the highest ranking street.</section><section prefix='b.'>Storefronts shall have a transparent clear glazed area of not less than seventy (70) percent of the facade area and shall be occupied by habitable uses that generate pedestrian activity and provide surveillance of the street. Security enclosures, if any, shall be of the mesh type that pedestrians can see through, and shall be located behind storefront displays.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>All colonnades shall comply with the following:<section prefix='a.'>Finished floor elevation of the colonnade shall match the adjoining sidewalk.</section><section prefix='b.'>Colonnades shall have a minimum unobstructed clear height of ten (10) feet and a minimum clear width of ten (10) feet. Awnings shall be permitted but shall not count towards the required colonnades. Colonnades shall not cause roof drainage into the street. Colonnades shall be attached to buildings. In no instance shall the depth of a colonnade exceed the colonnade's height.</section><section prefix='c.'>Freestanding colonnades shall not satisfy the build-to line requirement.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>A minimum of thirty (30) percent of all building streetwalls shall be fenestrated with windows. Mirror type glass shall be prohibited. All glazing shall be of a type that permits view of human activities and spaces within the structure. Colonnade column spacing, windows, and doors shall be proportioned such that the height of each opening is greater than its width. At least fifty (50) percent of the area of security screens and gates shall be transparent.</section><section prefix='4.'>The height of an accessory building shall not exceed the height of the principal building.</section><section prefix='5.'>An open, covered, or paved connection between an accessory building and a single-family detached house, urban villa, courtyard house, sideyard house, duplex, or rowhouse may be built within the minimum required ten (10) foot spacing as shown in the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.</section><section prefix='6.'>Weather protection features shall be required when storefronts are provided in the MM, MC, MO, MCS, and MCI categories. In the ID category, weather protection features shall be required when the front setback is hard surfaced.</section><section prefix='7.'>Awnings, balconies, stoops, stairs, open porches, and bay windows shall be permitted to extend into the minimum required setbacks, to a maximum of:<section>Roof eaves, chimneys, signs, and ramps may encroach into all setbacks. Porticoes, canopies, and colonnades shall be guttered, and drainage shall be deposited onsite.</section></section><section prefix='8.'>Where a zero (0) foot setback is permitted, roof eaves, bay windows, and balconies may encroach beyond the property line a maximum of three (3) feet, except when abutting private property. In all Sub-districts, awnings may encroach into the street no more than six (6) inches from the face of the curb. All street encroachments shall be a minimum of eleven (11) feet above the sidewalk.</section><section prefix='9.'>In the Edge Sub-district, accessory buildings shall be permitted to have balconies or bay windows that encroach a maximum of three (3) feet into the rear yard setback.</section><section prefix='10.'>Service areas shall be located out of the view from adjacent properties or from the street and shall be screened by a wall or fence in accordance with Subsection (H) below.</section><section prefix='11.'>The primary entrance of a building shall provide access to a street or a designated open space. The primary entrance to the upper levels of a mixed-use building with colonnades shall be through the colonnaded area along the front property line.</section><section prefix='12.'>Each story shall have a maximum height of sixteen (16) feet, as measured from floor to floor. Any height above sixteen (16) feet shall count as an additional story, except as follows:<section prefix='a.'>Buildings with less than six (6) stories may have a single story with a maximum height of thirty (30) feet, provided that no mezzanine area intended for commercial use exceeds ten (10) percent and no mezzanine area intended for residential use exceeds eighty (80) percent of the floor area of that story. Multiple levels of parking shall be permitted within this single story provided that they are in compliance with Subsection (F)(6) below.</section><section prefix='b.'>Buildings with six (6) or more stories, may have two stories with a maximum height of thirty (30) feet, provided that no mezzanine area intended for commercial use exceeds ten (10) percent and no mezzanine area intended for residential use exceeds eighty (80) percent of the floor area of a story. Multiple levels of parking shall be permitted within these two stories provided that they are in compliance with Subsection (F)(6) below.</section></section><section prefix='13.'>Notwithstanding the building heights regulating plans, rowhouses may have up to three (3) stories.</section><section prefix='14.'>A live-work unit shall have two components: a workshop and a residential unit. The workshop shall be located on the first floor and shall be directly accessible from the primary street frontage or a designated open space. The workshop's facade shall have a transparent clear glazed area of not less than seventy (70) percent of the facade. The residential component of a live-work unit shall connect internally with the work component.</section><section prefix='15.'>Projects with fifty (50) or fewer single-family units shall have a minimum of three (3) substantially different front elevations. Projects with more than fifty (50) and up to one hundred (100) single-family units shall have a minimum of five (5) substantially different front elevations and shall provide, within each block, a minimum of two (2) different single-family building types. Projects with more than one hundred (100) single-family units shall have a minimum of five (5) substantially different front elevations and shall provide, within each block, a minimum of three (3) different single-family building types. Substantially different front elevations shall include variations in fenestration, material, and color.</section><section prefix='16.'>Rowhouses shall provide a minimum of fifteen (15) feet between building groups and the length of a building group shall not exceed two hundred forty (240) feet.</section><section prefix='17.'>Floorplates above eight (8) stories shall not exceed twenty thousand (20,000) square feet. Cantilever balconies shall not count towards floor plate calculation.</section><section prefix='18.'>Civic use designated parcels and lots with less than twenty-five thousand (25,000) square feet shall not be required to comply with the minimum height requirement on the Building Heights Plan.</section></section><section prefix='C.'>Streets, Service Roads and Utilities. All streets and service roads shall comply with the Street Types parameters as set forth in this section.<section prefix='1.'>Typical Minor Street Illustration.</section></section><section><section prefix='*'>Refer to column B in the Street Types Table for required landscape elements.</section><section prefix='**'>Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated.</section><section prefix='2.'>Typical Two-Lane Boulevard Street Illustration.</section></section><section><section prefix='*'>Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.</section><section prefix='**'>Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated.</section><section prefix='3.'>Typical Four-Lane Boulevard Street Illustration.</section></section><section><section prefix='*'>Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements</section><section prefix='**'>Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated</section><section prefix='4.'>Street Types Development Parameters.</section></section><section><section prefix='a.'>Landscape area is exclusive of the minimum sidewalk width.</section><section prefix='b.'>Street trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches at time of planting.</section><section prefix='c.'>Permanent irrigation is required.</section><section prefix='d.'>Tree grates shall have a minimum area of twenty-four (24) square feet; tree planters shall have a minimum area of thirty-two (32) square feet; continuous landscape strips shall have a minimum width of six (6) feet in the Core and Center Sub-districts, eight (8) feet in the Edge Sub-district.</section><section prefix='e.'>In all Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of arterials, boulevards and Main Street; in Core and Center Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of minor streets.</section><section prefix='f.'>On-street parking shall count towards the minimum required parking.</section><section prefix='g.'>Bike lanes shall be four (4) feet in width when adjacent to curb or swale; five (5) feet in width when adjacent to a parking lane.</section><section prefix='h.'>The minimum required width of one-lane/one-way travel lanes shall be determined by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management and Fire Rescue Department on a case-by-case basis during the Administrative Site Plan Review process (ASPR).</section><section prefix='i.'>The use of permeable materials to pave private street sidewalks, on-street parking, and vehicular drives is permitted. Use of permeable materials to pave public street sidewalks, on-street parking and vehicular drives shall require approval from the Director of the Department of Public Works and Waste Management.</section><section prefix='5.'>All streets shall be located according to the New Streets Plan.<section prefix='a.'>All new A streets shall be in the same general location shown on the New Streets Plan and may be modified with respect to alignment, provided that the final realignment does not compromise street connectivity. No new A streets shall be deleted.</section><section prefix='b.'>B streets and service roads shown on the New Streets Plan are encouraged to promote connectivity and to conform with block length requirements. New B streets and service roads may be modified or deleted as provided in paragraph (6) below.</section><section prefix='c.'>All streets shall allow general public access. Privately built streets shall provide an approved plat restriction to allow general public access. No gates that impede through traffic are permitted along A or B streets.</section></section><section prefix='6.'>[Modification approval.] The Director shall approve the modification of A or B streets or service road or the deletion of a B street if the following conditions are satisfied:<section prefix='a.'>The modification/deletion has been approved by the Director of the Public Works and Waste Management Department who shall review the proposed modification for traffic and safety issues.</section><section prefix='b.'>The modification/deletion does not diminish the general size and location of an open space shown in the Designated Open Space Plan.</section><section prefix='c.'>The modification/deletion maintains connectivity to the surrounding area.</section><section prefix='d.'>The modification/deletion enhances pedestrian safety.</section><section prefix='e.'>The modification/deletion is compatible with the surrounding area.</section><section prefix='f.'>The modification/deletion allows for the appropriate use of private property.</section></section><section prefix='7.'>[Design compliance.] The design of new streets and modifications of existing streets shall comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='a.'>Streets shall be in accordance with the Street Types Development Parameters criteria set forth in this section.</section><section prefix='b.'>All streets and service roads shall connect to other streets or service roads. Dead-end streets and T-turnarounds shall only be permitted temporarily for new streets when the adjacent property is not platted, not developed, or both. When the adjacent property is platted or developed, a street shall connect to existing development and the dead-end street or T-turnaround removed.</section><section prefix='c.'>Cul-de-sacs shall be prohibited, except that a close shall be permitted when:<section prefix='i.'>A street is interrupted by a natural barrier such as a river, protected land, or similar natural resource designated by Miami-Dade County or any government agency responsible for the protection of such natural resources; and</section><section prefix='ii.'>Such agency prohibits the street to continue through said natural resource; and</section><section prefix='iii.'>Existing development adjacent to or near the natural resource does not provide a means for the street to connect to the existing or proposed street network.</section><section>The median of such a close shall be landscaped. The landscaped area shall be maintained by a special taxing district, homeowner's association or other mechanism acceptable to the Department of Public Works and Waste Management to positively provide for the proper and continuous payment of maintenance without expense to general taxpayers.</section></section><section prefix='d.'>All sidewalks shall provide the following:<section prefix='i.'>Minimum width of six (6) feet, unless a different width is required by the Street Types Development Parameters set forth in this section;</section><section prefix='ii.'>Minimum unobstructed area of sixty (60) inches;</section><section prefix='iii.'>Where a colonnade is required, free and clear use of a continuous unobstructed area of at least sixty (60) inches within the colonnade; and</section><section prefix='iv.'>No utility poles, fire hydrants or any other temporary or permanent structures within the unobstructed area.</section></section><section prefix='e.'>Where on-street parking is provided, parking lanes shall be no closer than twenty-five (25) feet from the intersection measured from the outermost corner of the nearest corner property line.</section><section prefix='f.'>Maximum curb radii at intersections shall not be larger than required for the safe travel of emergency and service vehicles.</section><section prefix='g.'>Curbs and gutters shall be provided as follows:<section prefix='i.'>All Sub-districts: At all intersections and roadway edges of arterials, boulevards and Main Street.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Core and Center Sub-districts: At all intersections and roadway edges of minor streets.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Edge Sub-district: Not required, except when indicated by the urban center street type development parameters.</section></section><section prefix='h.'>Utilities other than fire hydrants shall run underground.</section><section prefix='i.'>Buildings placed at the end of a Street Vista may provide one additional story above that otherwise permitted by the Building Heights Regulating Plan; such additional story shall occupy up to fifteen (15) percent of the floor area of the story immediately below.</section><section prefix='j.'>Service roads may occur within buildings.</section><section prefix='k.'>Service road access from the front property line shall be limited to one (1) point of access for every two hundred fifty (250) feet of frontage.</section></section></section><section prefix='D.'>Open Spaces and Recreation Areas.<section prefix='1.'>Open spaces under this article shall be classified as (a) designated or (b) private open spaces.<section prefix='a.'>Designated open spaces shall be subject to the following requirements:<section prefix='i.'>The general location, area, and dimensions shall conform with the Designated Open Space Plan. The street area on the side adjoining the designated open space and consisting of the curb, street tree landscape strip and sidewalk shall count towards the square footage of the open space.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Designated open spaces shall include the anchor point depicted on the Regulating Plan, and shall be provided at grade level.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Provided that all other parameters on the Designated Open Space Plan are met and that an individual/developer owns the entire designated open space area and an adjacent area, the final location of the designated open space may be pivoted around its anchor point onto such adjacent area, allowing the area previously designated as open space to be developed as permitted in the land use regulating plan.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Designated open spaces shall be provided in the form of squares, greens, or plazas as provided in the Designated Open Space Plan. Golf courses and parking lot buffers shall not count towards the designated open space requirement. Fifty (50) percent of an area designated as open space may contain a lake.</section><section prefix='v.'>No replatting or other land subdivision shall divide property in such a way that required designated open space is avoided or its location changed.</section><section prefix='vi.'>Designated open spaces shall be shaded, and their ground surface shall be a combination of paving materials, lawn, or groundcover.</section><section prefix='vii.'>If a lot or group of lots is designated entirely as open space in the Designated Open Space Plan, half of the lot or group shall be developable in a contiguous pattern and at a density in compliance with its land use designation for the entire parcel. Two (2) additional stories above the number of stories permitted by the Sub-districts and Building Heights Plans shall be permitted. Under this circumstance, the developable portion shall not be required to comply with the private open space requirement for residential development provided herein.</section><section prefix='viii.'>If a lot or group of lots is designated partially as open space in the Designated Open Space Plan, the portion not designated as open space shall be developable in a contiguous pattern at a density/intensity which will equal the density/intensity permitted by the land use designation for the entire parcel. Up to an additional two (2) stories above the number of stories permitted by the Sub-districts and Building Heights Plans shall be permitted to allow the increased density/intensity only.</section><section prefix='ix.'>Around designated open spaces, the building's frontage, height and placement shall be in accordance with the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.</section></section><section prefix='b.'>Private open spaces shall be subject to the following requirements:<section prefix='i.'>Private open spaces shall be provided in the form of colonnades, courtyards, terraces, lawns, community gardens, and landscaped roof terraces/gardens on buildings or garage structures. Designated open spaces shall count towards the private open space requirement. Lakes, golf courses, and parking lot buffers shall not count towards the open space requirement.</section><section prefix='ii.'>All residential developments, except for multi-family residential and live-work units, shall provide a minimum of four hundred (400) square feet of private open space per lot, in the form of courtyards, terraces, or lawns.</section><section prefix='iii.'>All multi-family residential, nonresidential and mixed-use developments shall reserve a minimum of ten (10) percent of the site for common, private open space.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Private open spaces shall be shaded, and their ground surface shall be a combination of paving materials, lawn, ground cover, flowers, fruits or vegetables. Enclosures of private open spaces shall comply with subsection (H) below.</section></section><section prefix='c.'>Community gardens shall be permitted in all land use categories to satisfy private open space requirements, subject to the following restrictions:<section prefix='i.'>Cultivated and harvested products may only be sold at permitted farmers markets and at grocery stores.</section><section prefix='ii.'>The raising or sale of livestock or poultry is prohibited.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Only handheld tools shall be permitted in the cultivation and harvesting process. Use of heavy agriculture equipment is prohibited.</section><section prefix='iv.'>All tools, equipment and products used to grow and harvest plant material shall be stored in an enclosed structure subject to the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.</section><section prefix='v.'>Gardens shall only be tended between sunrise and sunset.</section></section></section><section prefix='2.'>Recreation Areas. Educational and child care facilities located within an Urban Center District shall be exempt from the outdoor recreation area requirements of Section 33-151.18(a) of this chapter and shall be required to provide indoor and/or outdoor recreation areas subject to the following requirements:</section></section><section prefix='E.'>Landscape. Except as provided herein, landscape shall be provided as required by Chapter 18A of this code. In the Core and Center Sub-districts, landscape shall be provided as follows:<section prefix='1.'>Street trees shall be planted at a maximum of twenty-five (25) feet average on center, with a minimum six (6) inch diameter at breast height. Unless otherwise indicated by the Urban Center District or Area street type parameters, street trees shall be planted in one or more of the following methods of installation as required by Section 33-284.86(C)(4) above;<section prefix='a.'>Tree grates. Trees are planted within openings on the sidewalk. The openings shall be covered by permanently installed grates perforated to permit natural irrigation. The grates shall be installed flush with the surrounding sidewalk.</section><section prefix='b.'>Tree planters. Trees are planted within a raised planter located on the sidewalk. The planter shall be defined on all sides by a permanent masonry structure to consist of a minimum six (6) inch raised curb. The area within the planter, in addition to the required trees, shall be planted with ground cover, shrubs, or other appropriate plant material.</section></section></section><section><section prefix='c.'>Continuous landscape strips. Trees are planted in the area between the curb or roadway edge and the sidewalk. This area, in addition to the required trees, shall be planted with grass.</section><section prefix='2.'>For all land uses except for single-family or duplex, tree requirements for private property shall be based on sixteen (16) trees per net acre of lot area and, in addition to the placement on the lot, may be placed in greens, squares, plazas and medians within the Urban Center District or Area.</section></section><section prefix='F.'>Parking. Except as provided herein, parking shall be provided as required by Section 33-124 of this chapter.<section prefix='1.'>Multi-story parking garages, parking lots, and on-street parking shall count toward all parking requirements except for the parking requirements of detached single-family residences, courtyard and sideyard houses, rowhouses, urban villa, or duplexes.</section><section prefix='2.'>At a minimum, parking shall be provided as follows:<section>Single-Family Residential (off-street):<section>Single-family detached: 2 spaces/unitCourtyard or sideyard house: 2 spaces/unitRowhouse or urban villa: 2 spaces/unitDuplex: 2 spaces/unit</section></section><section>Multi-Family Residential:<section>1 spaces/1 bedroom unit1.5 spaces/2 bedroom unit1.75 spaces/3 or more bedroom units</section></section><section>Housing for the elderly: 0.5 spaces/unit</section><section>Hotel/Motel: 1 space/first 40 guest rooms and 1 additional space/ every 2 guest rooms or suites thereafter</section><section>General Retail/Personal Services and Entertainment Uses: 1 space/250 square feet of gross floor area</section><section>Professional Business Offices and Health Care Services: 1 space/400 square feet of gross floor area</section><section>Food/Beverage Establishments: 1 space/ 50 square feet of patron area</section><section>Industrial: shall comply with of this chapter.</section><section>Live-work units:<section>(1) Residential component: 2 spaces/unit, and(2) Workshop component: 1 space/325 square feet of workshop area</section></section><section>Live-work buildings:<section>(1) Residential component: shall comply with the multi-family residential requirements described in this subsection, and(2) Work space, nonresidential component: shall comply with, of this chapter.</section></section><section>Civic uses: shall comply with of this chapter.</section><section>All other uses shall comply with the parking standards provided in of this chapter. Educational and child care facilities located within a mixed-use building shall be exempt from the auto-stacking requirements of Section(c) of this chapter.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Parking reduction. Development meeting certain criteria shall be permitted to reduce the number of parking spaces required. Specific use, location, and parcel requirements and permitted reductions are provided in the following table:<section>Developments meeting more than one of the use, location, and parcel criteria shall be permitted to combine each permitted reduction; the combined reduction shall be calculated by reducing the first applicable criteria from each group in the order of the table above.</section></section><section prefix='4.'>Mixed-use, multi-family residential, or non-residential developments in all Sub-districts may provide the required parking off-site, where the off-site parking is within seven hundred fifty (750) feet of the development and in a land use designation that is similar to or higher intensity than the land use designation of the development being served. Any certificate of use for mixed-use, multi-family residential, or nonresidential development shall immediately terminate in the event such parking area is not available. An applicant for approval of a mixed-use, multi-family residential or nonresidential development with off-site parking shall execute and record in the public records of this County a declaration of restrictions approved by the Director covenanting that such development shall cease and terminate upon the elimination of such parking area, and that no development requiring such parking shall be made of such property until the required parking area is available and provided.</section><section prefix='5.'>Except for detached single-family homes, courtyard or sideyard houses, and duplexes, all parking may be in the form of parking garage structures or parking lots which shall be located in the rear or on one side of the building, and shall be screened from the street. Parking is not permitted in setback areas required along street frontages.</section><section prefix='6.'>Parking garage structures shall be screened by a liner building containing a minimum depth of twenty (20) feet of habitable space for all stories along the primary frontage, and for parcels with three (3) or more frontages, on at least two (2) frontages. For all other frontages, architectural features of a parking structure shall appear consistent and harmonious with that of habitable space. On parcels having a lot depth at any one point of less than one hundred fifty (150) feet, as measured from the front property line, a liner building shall only be required on the ground floor. No vehicles parked within the structure shall be visible from the street.</section><section prefix='7.'>Mechanized parking shall be allowed for mixed-use, nonresidential, and multi-family developments and, when provided, shall be exempt from the provisions of Section 33-122 of this code. For the purpose of this article, mechanized parking shall be defined as a mechanism with vertical and horizontal transport capability that provides for automobile storage and retrieval. A mechanized parking space shall be counted toward the parking requirements of this section. When provided, mechanized parking shall comply with the following:<section prefix='a.'>A queuing analysis is submitted and approved during the Administrative Site Plan Review process.</section></section><section prefix='8.'>Parking lots shall provide for vehicular connectivity to adjacent parking areas.</section><section prefix='9.'>The use of permeable materials for paving parking lots shall be permitted in the urban center districts.</section><section prefix='10.'>Parking for individuals with disabilities shall comply with the Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='11.'>Parking for persons transporting strollers shall comply with Section 33-122.2 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='12.'>Individual parking garages for single-family homes shall count towards the parking requirement.</section><section prefix='13.'>In the Edge Sub-district, parking for detached single family homes and duplexes on platted lots of 12,000 square feet or less shall be subject to the following:<section prefix='a.'>Where there is no service road, parking shall be in the form of individual garages or carports accessed through a driveway from the street. When provided, attached garages and carports shall be located as provided in the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.</section><section prefix='b.'>Along the front property line the maximum width of the driveways in front of the build-to line shall be ten (10) feet. On any other frontage the maximum width of the driveway shall be twenty (20) feet.</section><section prefix='c.'>The parking area shall be screened at the build-to line through the use of walls, hedges, or fences in accordance with Subsection (H) below and the Building Placement Standards set forth in Section 33-284.85 of this article.</section><section prefix='d.'>The sidewalk shall be continuous and remain at a constant level at all instances where a driveway intersects it.</section></section><section prefix='14.'>Required parking for single-family homes, courtyard or sideyard houses, duplexes, urban villas and rowhouses may be provided in a tandem configuration.</section><section prefix='15.'>Where a wall or fence is used for screening parking areas along streets, a five (5) foot landscape strip with a hedge shall be required in front of the wall or fence.</section><section prefix='16.'>The provisions of Section 33-131 of this chapter shall not apply to the required parking for mixed-use and nonresidential developments.</section></section><section prefix='G.'>Lighting.<section prefix='1.'>Street lighting shall comply with the following:<section prefix='a.'>Street lighting shall be provided in these areas: commercial and live-work unit driveways and parking areas, sidewalks and pedestrian passages, commercial establishment entryways, recreation areas, and multi-family residential common areas and entryways.</section><section prefix='b.'>Outdoor lighting of these areas shall comply with Section 33-4.1 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='c.'>All light fixtures shall be of a pedestrian scale, with a maximum height of eighteen (18) feet and a maximum spacing between fixtures of sixty (60) feet or such other spacing as may be required by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management, whichever is the most restrictive.</section><section prefix='d.'>The type and spacing of light fixtures shall be approved by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management or its successor. Approval shall be based on uniformity of types, location, right-of-way width, and luminosity.</section><section prefix='e.'>Weather and vandalism resistant covers shall protect all light fixtures.</section><section prefix='f.'>Streetlamps shall be installed on both sides of streets.</section><section prefix='g.'>Cobra-head lights shall not be permitted.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>Open parking lot, access road, and service road lighting shall be provided as required in Section 8C-3 of this Code. Lighting fixtures in these areas shall have a maximum height of eighteen (18) feet above grade.</section></section><section></section><section prefix='H.'>Walls, fences, and hedges. The following shall be permitted:</section><section></section><section><section>Hedges and shrubs shall be subject to of this Code.</section><section>Additional requirements for walls, fences and hedges may be included in the Building Placement Standards set forth in of this article, and in the event of a conflict, the Building Placement Standards shall govern.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-143, § 6, 7-7-05; Ord. No. 06-10, § 3, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 07-93, § 4, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 07-169, § 9, 11-6-07; Ord. No. 08-102, § 3, 9-2-08; Ord. No. 12-86, § 5, 10-2-12)</history></law>