<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00046' order_by='00046' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXII. IU-C, INDUSTRIAL DISTRICT, CONDITIONAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-267</section_number>
<catch_line>Intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004284</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-267. Intent.<section>IU-C District shall be applied only to those lands that appropriately may be used and utilized for the development, construction and operation of large industrial projects and industrial park development of the nature, type and character commensurate with the public health, safety, comfort, convenience, and the general welfare of the County. It is intended that this district shall be utilized to provide an adequate reservoir of lands suited for the needs and requirements of large industries, and industrial park developments, to the end that desirable industrial concerns may be attracted to this area. It is intended, however, that this district shall not be used indiscriminately, so as to permit any industrial use which might be offensive or obnoxious by reason of the emanation of odors, gases, dust, noise or vibration, pollution of air or water, or otherwise detrimental to the general welfare of this community; but that it shall be restricted and confined to only those large industrial uses and industrial park type developments which produce a net gain to the community. It is recognized that the rapid development of new and different industrial uses and operations makes it impossible and impractical to accurately enumerate those which would be beneficial or detrimental to the welfare of this community. Therefore, the intent and purpose for the establishment of this district is expressly set forth, and standards set forth for the use of lands embraced within this district.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 58-40, ยง 2(A), 10-7-58; Ord. No. 69-51, ยง 4, 9-3-69)</history></law>