<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-309</section_number>
<catch_line>Community Zoning Appeals Board/Board of County Commissioners Applications for public hearing.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004509</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-309. Community Zoning Appeals Board/Board of County Commissioners Applications for public hearing.<section prefix='(a)'>All hearings before the Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners shall be initiated by the filing with the Department an application on forms prescribed by the Director, executed and sworn to by the owner or owners of at least seventy-five (75) percent of the property described in the application, or by tenant or tenants, with owner's written sworn-to consent or by duly authorized agents, evidenced by a written power of attorney, if not a member of the Florida Bar, or by the Director, or by any person aggrieved by an order, requirement, decision or determination of an administrative official when appealing the same, or by anyone desiring an amendment or repeal to the zoning regulations. All properties described in one (1) application must be contiguous and immediately adjacent to one (1) another, and the Director may require more than one (1) application if the property concerned contains more than forty (40) acres, or the fee paid for one (1) application would not equal the cost of processing the same. Only applications which the Community Zoning Appeals Board or the Board of County Commissioners are authorized to consider and act upon shall be accepted for filing.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Applications which are to be considered by the Community Zoning Appeals Boards in accordance with this chapter shall be assigned by the Director to the Community Zoning Appeals Board which has jurisdiction based upon the location of the property which is encompassed by the application. In the event that the property which is encompassed by the application is located in more than one (1) Community Zoning Appeals Board's district the application shall be heard directly by the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Whenever any hearing is initiated by the Director or the Zoning Official, pursuant to this section, the County Mayor may order that no building permits shall be issued for any construction work on the property involved in the hearing, until the hearing has been finally concluded in accordance with the provisions of this Code. Should the County Mayor issue such an order the administrative personnel shall schedule the application for the first public hearing date after appropriate legal notice.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 69-88, § 1, 12-3-69; Ord. No. 70-39, § 1, 5-13-70; Ord. No. 70-80, § 1, 10-27-70; Ord. No. 72-53, § 1, 9-19-72; Ord. No. 74-20, § 2, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 83-60, § 1, 7-19-83; Ord. No. 91-91, § 1, 9-16-91; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-16, § 3, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 97-106, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 09-76, § 4, 9-1-09; Ord. No. 11-86, § 2, 11-15-11; Ord. No. 13-16, § 5, 2-5-13)</history></law>