<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-304</section_number>
<catch_line>Applications.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004502</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-304. Applications.<section prefix='(a)'>All requests for a district boundary change, changes in the zoning regulations, appeals of administrative decisions, special exceptions or unusual uses, new uses, variances, approvals of or modifications to developments of regional impact ("DRI"), including substantial deviation determinations, and determinations that a DRI is essentially built out, shall be made by filing an application therefor with the Director on application forms prescribed by the Director or by rule and regulation of the Developmental Impact Committee. Forms shall include, but not be limited to, disclosure forms for corporations, trusts, and partnerships, and disclosure of information regarding contract purchasers and their percentage(s) of interest. Disclosure shall not be required of: i) any entity, the equity interests in which are regularly traded on an established securities market in the United States or another country; or ii) pension funds or pension trusts of more than five thousand (5,000) ownership interests; or iii) any entity where ownership interests are held in a partnership, corporation or trust consisting of more than five thousand (5,000) separate interests, including all interests at every level of ownership, and where no one (1) person or entity holds more than a total of five (5) percent of the ownership interest in the partnership, corporation or trust. Entities whose ownership interests are held in a partnership, corporation, or trust consisting of more than five thousand (5,000) separate interests, including all interests at every level of ownership, shall only be required to disclose those ownership interest which exceed five (5) percent of the ownership interest in the partnership, corporation, or trust. Disclosure forms shall be established by administrative order to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Such disclosure forms shall be included in the agendas distributed in connection with the public hearing on the application. Where applicable, requests shall specify whether, and the extent to which, the requested change in land use or proposed development conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section>All requests which authorizes or permits development filed pursuant to this section shall include a boundary survey of the property which is the subject of the application performed in accordance with Chapter 61G17-6.0031, Florida Administrative Code as may be amended from time to time in the event any portion of the property is contiguous to or across the street from a municipal boundary. It is further provided that such survey shall depict the location of any municipal boundary on or across the property being surveyed. The boundary survey submitted shall have been updated within one year proceeding the date of an application filed pursuant to this section.</section><section>Upon the approval of a zoning application in whole or in part, a period of six (6) months must run prior to the filing of any subsequent application on the same property; provided that the appropriate board upon approving the application may provide for a different waiting period upon a showing of good cause. Applications approved for withdrawal without prejudice must wait a period of six (6) months prior to the filing of any subsequent application on the same property; provided that the appropriate board upon approving the withdrawal without prejudice may provide for a different waiting period upon a showing of good cause. Upon the final denial of a zoning application without prejudice, a period of one (1) year must run prior to the filing of a subsequent application on the same property; provided that the appropriate board upon denying the application without prejudice may provide for a different waiting period upon a showing of good cause. Upon the withdrawal or final denial of a zoning application with prejudice in whole or in part, a period of eighteen (18) months must run prior to the filing of a subsequent application. In the event an application in whole or in part has been twice or more denied or withdrawn, a period of two (2) years must run prior to the filing of any subsequent application. Such periods of limitation shall not commence to run until the decision has been rendered by the last Board to consider the application. Further, such periods of limitation shall not apply to applications filed by the Director or the Zoning Official.</section><section>Notwithstanding the provisions in the foregoing paragraph, it is expressly provided that, except for applications that have been twice or more denied or withdrawn, there shall be no period of limitation for either (1) a subsequent application that proposes a lesser total density or a less intense use than the preceding application, as determined by the Director at the time of filing; (2) a subsequent application that proposes five (5) or fewer residential units; or (3) a subsequent application that proposes development in the "urban infill area," as that area is defined in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section>An application may be withdrawn without prejudice by the applicant as a matter of right, provided the request for withdrawal is in writing and executed in the same manner as provided by for the executing of application, and filed with the Department no later than forty (40) days prior to the public hearing; otherwise all such requests for withdrawal shall be with prejudice save and except that the Community Zoning Appeals Boards or the Board of County Commissioners may permit withdrawals without prejudice at the time the matter is considered by such Boards; provided, further, no application may be withdrawn after final action has been taken.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All zoning hearing applications delineated in this chapter shall only be accepted during the established filing periods. which shall consist of three consecutive days beginning on the first and third Monday of each month. It is provided however that no zoning application will be accepted on a day set forth above which occurs on a legal holiday. Administrative variances may be filed at any time.</section><section prefix='(c)'>At the end of each said time period set forth in subpart (b) the Director shall promptly identify and group those applications for district boundary changes, use special exceptions, unusual and new uses and use variances which relate to or affect any particular or immediate neighborhood or area as determined by the Director, and, to the extent possible, shall notice public hearings thereon, in accordance with Section 33-310 of the Code of Miami- Dade County, so as to allow the appropriate board to consider and determine the effect of the said applications on the said neighborhood or area as a whole and their relation to and conformity with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. Upon receipt of an application, the Director shall forward the application to the appropriate Departments, as determined by the Director, for review. To allow for timely processing of applications. Department comments are to be provided to the Director within twenty-one (21) days following transmittal of the request for review, unless a greater review period is allowed by the Director.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All applications for zoning action which would permit, if granted, development activity that meets one (1) of the following criteria are hereby declared "developments of county impact":<section prefix='(1)'>Residential apartment developments involving in excess of eight hundred (800) units;</section><section prefix='(2)'>All planned developments (provided by article XXXIIIB) or cluster developments (provided by article XXXIIIA) involving in excess of eight hundred (800) units;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Business uses involving in excess of thirty (30) acres or one hundred fifty thousand (150,000) square feet of retail floor area, or one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Mobile home parks involving in excess of eight hundred (800) mobile home units;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Townhouse developments involving in excess of one hundred (100) acres or eight hundred (800) units;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Recreational, cultural, or entertainment facilities, exclusive of golf courses, involving in excess of one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity for single performances of fifty (50) acres;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Office buildings or office complexes involving two hundred fifty thousand (250,000) square feet of floor space, or one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Industrial, processing or manufacturing activity involving in excess of one hundred (100) acres, or one thousand (1,000) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Hotel and/or motel developments involving in excess of five hundred (500) units;</section><section prefix='(10)'>Detached single-family development involving in excess of eight hundred (800) units.</section></section><section>If any applicant is in doubt as to whether his proposed development would be a development of County impact, he may request a determination from the Developmental Impact Committee. Within thirty (30) days of the receipt of such request, the Chairman, on behalf of the Developmental Impact Committee, shall issue a letter of interpretation with respect to the proposed development. Where an application seeks only a special exception for site or plot use plan approval, the Developmental Impact Committee may require completion of a site plan application on a form prescribed by rule and regulation.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Amendments to an application shall be permitted; provided that, unless otherwise requested, suggested or concurred in by the Developmental Impact Committee, no substantial amendment shall be accepted by the Director within thirty (30) days prior to the first scheduled hearing on the application by the appropriate board or once the application has been heard and determined by the Community Zoning Appeals Board; provided further that an applicant may petition the appropriate board to permit such amendment at the time of hearing on the application and such amendment shall be accepted if approved by majority vote of those present upon good cause shown and provided it falls within the scope of the legal advertisement. In determining good cause, the appropriate board shall consider, among other factors, the timeliness of the amendment and the degree of inconvenience or surprise to objectors to the application. It is further provided that an amendment to correct a scrivener's error shall be permitted at any time up to and including the time of hearing.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All planned area development applications shall adhere to the following procedures which shall be deemed exclusive notwithstanding any other section herein: The Department shall submit the required exhibits for the total development plan to the Developmental Impact Committee for review in accordance with standards and review procedures of the Developmental Impact Committee. At a public hearing held by the Community Zoning Appeals Board, the developer shall present the proposal. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall have the recommendations of the Developmental Impact Committee. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall consider the information presented by the applicant, the recommendations of the Developmental Impact Committee and viewpoints of the public expressed at the hearing. The Community Zoning Appeals Board shall take formal action either approving the plan as presented, approving it subject to certain specified modifications, or disapproving it. Upon approval, plans, documents and recordable development agreements shall be filed with the Department and recorded in the official records and shall thereby constitute the planned area development district. If the planned area development is approved with specific modifications, as incorporated in the Community Zoning Appeals Board resolution, those modifications shall be made by the applicant prior to filing documents and plans with the Department. Such filing shall be completed within sixty (60) working days from the date the action of the Community Zoning Appeals Board becomes final including all appeals. Failure to do so shall nullify the Community Zoning Appeals Board's action unless waived by the Community Zoning Appeals Board or if appealed, by the County Commission. The Director shall review all modifications in accordance with the Community Zoning Appeals Board's resolution. The approved planned area development shall be indicated on the zoning map as would any other district boundary change. Review at the development tract level may then be initiated pursuant to the provisions of the planned area development districts.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Extensions granted by the Florida Legislature for development orders or development permits shall be approved administratively upon application on a form prescribed by the Director and shall not be subject to the provisions of Sections 33-310 and 33-310.1 of this Chapter. It is provided, however, that an extension shall not be approved administratively where the Director determines: (i) that the permit holder is in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or order, as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action; (ii) that extension of the permit or order would delay or prevent compliance with a court order; or (iii) that extension of the permit or order would create an immediate threat to public safety or health.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 62-48, § 1A, 12-4-62; Ord. No. 63-12, § 1, 4-16-63; Ord. No. 71-35, § 1, 4-22-71; Ord. No. 74-20, § 1, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 74-40, § 1, 6-4-74; Ord. No. 75-47, § 3, 6-18-75; Ord. No. 76-107, § 1, 12-7-76; Ord. No. 78-16, §§ 1, 2, 3-21-78; Ord. No. 78-52, § 2, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 79-20, § 1, 3-6-79; Ord. No. 83-59, § 3, 7-19-83; Ord. No. 88-82, § 1, 9-6-88; Ord. No. 89-24, § 1, 4-4-89; Ord. No. 89-96, § 1, 10-17-89; Ord. No. 91-31, § 1, 3-5-91; Ord. No. 92-67, § 2, 7-7-92; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 95-217, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 34, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 98-172, § 1, 12-1-98; Ord. No. 00-31, § 2, 2-24-00; Ord. No. 02-9, § 1, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 02-150, § 1, 9-12-02; Ord. No. 02-254, § 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 03-131, § 1, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 13-16, § 4, 2-5-13)</history></law>