<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-348</section_number>
<catch_line>Administration and enforcement of airport height zoning.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004553</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-348. Administration and enforcement of airport height zoning.<section>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or Code to the contrary, it shall be the duty of the Director of the Miami-Dade Aviation Department (MDAD), to administer and enforce the regulations prescribed herein relating to height zoning within unincorporated Miami-Dade County and all incorporated municipalities therein.</section><section>In the event of any violation of the regulations contained herein, the Aviation Department shall provide notice of such violation to the appropriate administrative official, with a copy to the owner of the property where such violation occurred. Such notice shall indicate the nature of the violation and the necessary action to correct or abate the violation. A copy of said notice shall be sent to the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning. The Director of the Miami-Dade Aviation Department or the director of the appropriate municipal office or designee shall order discontinuance of use of land or buildings; removal of structures or trees to conform with height limitations set forth herein; removal of buildings, additions, alterations, or structures; discontinuance of any work being done; or shall take any or all other action necessary to correct violations and obtain compliance with all the provisions of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-92, ยง 14, 7-10-07)</history></law>