<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-312</section_number>
<catch_line>Community Zoning Appeals Board—Decisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004514</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-312. Community Zoning Appeals Board—Decisions.<section>All decisions of the Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall be by resolution. The decision, if for denial, shall specify whether it is with or without prejudice. A final finding by the Ethics Commission as provided in(z) of a willful violation of Sections or of the Code by any member of a Community Zoning Appeals Board regarding a particular matter shall constitute malfeasance in office and shall render the action regarding that particular matter voidable by the Board of County Commissioners. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, a decision of the Board of County Commissioners to void a decision as provided in this section shall be by simple majority vote of the members present. Decisions of the Community Zoning Appeals Boards are final and may be appealed to circuit court pursuant to provided however within fourteen (14) days, but not thereafter, decisions of the Community Zoning Appeals Boards as specified in, shall be appealed to the Board of County Commissioners, as provided by. The fourteen-day appeal period provided herein shall commence to run the day after notification that the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board has taken action on the particular matter, such notification to be given by the Department by posting a short, concise statement of the action taken on a conspicuous bulletin board that may be seen by the public at reasonable times and hours in the office of the Department. Where the fourteenth (14th) day falls on a weekend or legal holiday the fourteen-day period shall be deemed to extend through the next business day. No appeal may be withdrawn after a period of ten (10) days from the date of the decision of a Community Zoning Appeals Board; except at the appeal hearing before the Board of County Commissioners and with the permission of such Board. In no event shall an appellant be entitled to a refund of the appeal fee. It is hereby intended that the Community Zoning Appeals Board's decision concerning a requested regulation amendment shall be considered only as a recommendation, which shall be transmitted, together with the Community Zoning Appeals Board's record on each such application, to the Board of County Commissioners for final action by way of approval, disapproval or modification pursuant to hereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 62-48, § 1C, 12-4-62; Ord. No. 71-22, § 1, 1-19-71; Ord. No. 74-20, § 5, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 04-92, § 1, 5-11-04)</history></law>