<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-39.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Consent agreements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003940</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-39.3. Consent agreements.<section>The Director or his designee may, in the discretion of the Director or designee, terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this chapter upon execution of a written consent agreement between the Director or his designee and the persons who are the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance with all the applicable provisions of this chapter by such persons. The consent agreement may in addition provide for the following: Mitigation of injuries accruing on account of the violation investigated or sued upon; compensatory damages; punitive damages; civil penalties; costs and expenses of enforcement; attorneys' fees; and remedial or corrective action. Except as expressly and specifically provided in the executed written consent agreement, an executed written consent agreement shall neither be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter nor shall such agreement be deemed to impose any limitation or action by the Director or the County in enforcing any of the provisions of this chapter, nor shall the agreement constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, State or local law or ordinance. Each violation of any of the terms of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate violation under this chapter by the persons who executed the agreement and by their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees, attorneys, heirs, successors and assigns, and by any persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who have received actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of which each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-118, ยง 5, 11-21-89)</history></law>