<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-343.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Notice of airport proximity (airport land use zoning).</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004548</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-343.1. Notice of airport proximity (airport land use zoning).<section>All approval of uses in the CA-A sub-zone, including, but not limited to, approvals of permits, site plans, exceptions and variances, shall include the following notice prominently displayed:</section><section>NOTIFICATION OF AIRPORT PROXIMITY<section>The property that is the subject of this zoning approval is located in proximity to Miami International Airport and is therefore subject to certain impacts as a result of such proximity. Among the potential impacts are increased noise levels associated with aircraft and airport operations, overhead aircraft flights at reduced altitudes, and frequent overhead aircraft flights throughout the day and night.</section><section>Application for and utilization of any approval under Article XXXVII of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field) Zoning), shall constitute acknowledgment of the above-described conditions, and acknowledgement that the owner of the property and successors in title are not entitled to any present or future relief or compensation from Miami-Dade County or any other party to mitigate or ameliorate such impacts.</section></section><section>Additionally, each approval of a new educational facility, or an expansion or modification of an existing educational facility, in the Critical Approach (CA) Zone shall contain notification that the facility is located within 5 miles of a Miami International Airport runway.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-203, ยง 17, 11-30-04; Ord. No. 07-92, ยง 10, 7-10-07)</history></law>