<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-323</section_number>
<catch_line>Administrative zoning moratoria.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004528</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-323. Administrative zoning moratoria.<section prefix='(a)'>Whenever it shall be made to appear to the County Manager that it is in the public interest to make a comprehensive determination as to whether the existing County master plan as it applies to a portion of the area of Miami-Dade County is outdated and of little or no use in formulating correct zoning patterns in relation thereto, or as to whether existing zoning districts are compatible with existing or proposed growth patterns and land uses, the County Manager shall immediately issue his administrative order delineating the area in question and prohibiting the consideration by any County department, board or agency of any zoning amendment, modification, variance, special exception or other zoning change, in said area. However, applications for special exceptions not involving zoning changes but incorporating requests for site plan approval only may be considered and appropriate action taken thereon.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any administrative order issued pursuant to Subsection (a) shall be complied with by all Miami-Dade County departments, boards and agencies and shall be effective until reversed, modified or superseded by order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Immediately upon issuance of any administrative order pursuant to Subsection (a), the County Manager shall notify the clerk of the Board of County Commissioners whose duty it shall then be to place the matter before the Board of County Commissioners for consideration and review following a public hearing as soon as is reasonably practicable. The aforesaid clerk shall give reasonable notice by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County of the public hearing which he has scheduled before the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(d)'>At the public hearing the Board of County Commissioners shall inquire into the propriety of the zoning moratorium and may reverse, modify or supersede the zoning moratorium order previously issued. The Board's determination shall be predicated upon the need for a detailed and comprehensive analysis of the area in question which would enable the Board to correct any deficiencies in the master plan or to provide any changes necessary or desirable in the master plan.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Should the Board of County Commissioners determine that a zoning moratorium pending the preparation of a detailed and comprehensive analysis of the area in question is necessary or desirable, it shall order the continuance of the County Manager's zoning moratorium order. The Board's order shall fix a time within which the County Manager shall report back to the Board with his recommendations relating to modifying or correcting the County master plan as to the affected area. The said time limitation shall be a reasonable one, predicated upon the time needed for a comprehensive analysis of the area by the County Manager and all planning agencies of the County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Upon the submission of the County Manager's report and recommendations to the Clerk of the Board, the Clerk shall call a public hearing thereon before the Board at the earliest practicable time, after reasonable notice by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. After said public hearing, the Board shall either amend the master plan and terminate the zoning moratorium order or, if it finds no amendment in order or necessary, terminate the zoning moratorium; provided, however, the Board may continue the moratorium or any portion thereof for an additional period of time if the Board finds such continuance to be reasonably necessary.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Should the County Manager be unable to report back to the Board within the time prescribed by its moratorium order, upon timely request, by the County Manager and after public hearing on the need therefor, the Board may reasonably extend the time limitations for the report and the moratorium if the Board finds such extension is reasonably necessary.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 72-89, ยง 1, 12-5-72; Ord. No. 73-19, ยง 1, 3-8-73; Ord. No. 83-83, ยง 3, 9-20-83)</history></law>