<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='3'>ARTICLE XL. KENDALL TAMIAMI EXECUTIVE AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-391</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of airport zoning area for Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004594</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-391. Establishment of airport zoning area for Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport.<section>For the purpose of this article there is hereby created and established the airport zoning area for Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport and it is hereby ordained that such area shall include, and the provisions of this article shall be applicable to and embrace all of the unincorporated and the incorporated land and water area lying, situate and being in those certain portions of Miami-Dade County, Florida, described as follows, to wit:<section prefix='(1)'>In Township 55 South, Range 37 East, all of Sections 1, 12, 13, 24, 25 and 36.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In Township 55 South, Range 38 East, all of Section 1 to 32 inclusive.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In Township 55 South, Range 39 East, all of Sections 1 to 30 inclusive.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In Township 55 South, Range 40 East, all of Sections 1 to 30 inclusive, and the north one-half (½) of Section 36.</section><section prefix='(5)'>In Township 55 South, Range 41 East, all of Sections 6, 7, 18, 19, 30, and the north one-half (½) of Section 31</section><section prefix='(6)'>In Township 54 South, Range 40 East, the south one-half (½) of Sections 35 and 36.</section><section prefix='(7)'>In Township 54 South, Range 41 East, the south one-half (½) of Section 31</section><section prefix='(8)'>All of Lot 1 as the same lies between Township 54 South, Range 37 East and Township 55 South, Range 37 East.</section><section prefix='(9)'>All of Lot 6 as the same lies between Township 54 South, Range 38 East and Township 55 South, Range 38 East.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-40, § 4, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 99-118, § 1, 9-21-99)</history></law>