<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-340</section_number>
<catch_line>Airport land use zoning permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004544</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-340. Airport land use zoning permits.<section>Applications for development permits in incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County that are located within any airport zone or sub-zone established in shall be reviewed by the appropriate municipal board(s) or official(s) for the purpose of assuring compliance with the minimum airport land use zoning standards set forth in this article. Applications for development permits in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County that are located within any airport zone or sub-zone shall be reviewed by the appropriate County board(s) or official(s) for the purpose of assuring compliance with the minimum airport land use zoning standards set forth in this article. In all such instances, whether in the incorporated or unincorporated areas, a copy of the application for development permit shall be provided to the Director of the Miami-Dade Aviation Department and the Director of the Miami-Dade Planning and Zoning Department at the time such application is submitted.</section><section>The directors of MDAD and the Planning and Zoning Department shall submit in writing, to the appropriate board or official, any objections they may have to an application for development permit regulated by this article. All permits for traditional public school facility projects will be issued through the Miami-Dade Public School Building Department. Written notice of such school facility projects shall be submitted to the Directors of MDAD and the Planning and Zoning Department in sufficiently reasonable time to allow them to file written objections prior to the issuance of any permit.</section><section>The Director of MDAD and the Director of the Planning and Zoning Department are authorized to appeal or otherwise legally contest decisions of any municipality or other governmental agency granting a development permit regulated by this article for failure to comply with the airport land use zoning standards of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-39, § 11, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 78-78, § 1, 11-7-78; Ord. No. 86-83, § 1, 10-28-86; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 04-203, § 11, 11-30-04; Ord. No. 07-92, § 7, 7-10-07)</history></law>