<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-313</section_number>
<catch_line>Appeals to Board of County Commissioners.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004515</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-313. Appeals to Board of County Commissioners.<section prefix='(A)'>Any appealable decision of the Community Zoning Appeals Board may be appealed by an applicant, governing body of any municipality, if affected, or any aggrieved party, including neighborhood, community and civic associations, whose name appears in the record of the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board by filing with the Department a petition in a form prescribed by the Director and a written statement specifying in brief, concise language the grounds and reasons for reversal of the ruling made by the Community Zoning Appeals Board, together with a fee for the processing of the appeal, as provided by Administrative Order No. 4-40, as amended from time to time, within the fourteen (14) days provided by Section 33-312 hereof.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Upon the timely filing of an application for appeal, the Director shall transmit to the County Commission the petition for appeal, any associated documents which may be submitted on appeal, the application and Director's recommendation as presented to the Community Zoning Appeals Board, and the decision and record of the Community Zoning Appeals Board. If the ground for reversal is a failure to provide notice as required by Section 33-310, the name of the appellant need not appear in the record.</section><section prefix='(C)'>If the decision of the Community Zoning Appeals Board has not been appealed within the fourteen-day period, the Director may appeal such decision within four (4) additional days in the manner aforestated, except that a fee will not be required.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Upon the taking of an appeal, the County Commission shall conduct a de novo hearing and shall consider why the decision of the Community Zoning Appeals Board should or should not be sustained or modified. By resolution, the Board shall either affirm, modify or reverse the Community Zoning Appeals Board's decision and such action of the County Commission shall be by a majority vote of all members present except that a two-thirds () vote of all members present shall be required to reverse any Community Zoning Appeals Board decision denying a request for zoning action or to approve any Development of Regional Impact or modifications thereof, substantial deviation determination or related request pursuant to Section 33-314 where a Community Zoning Appeals Board's recommendation is for denial.</section><section prefix='(E)'>No appeal shall be heard or considered until notice has been provided in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-310(c), (d), (e) and (f).</section><section prefix='(F)'>With respect to appeals arising from the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District a two-thirds () vote of all members present shall be required to reverse any Community Zoning Appeals Board decision denying a request for zoning action for a development proposed within the Center or Edge Sub-Districts of the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District. For any application for a development proposed within the Core Sub-District of the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District pursuant to Section 33-311 shall be decided by a majority vote of all members then in office.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 62-48, § 1D, 12-4-62; Ord. No. 64-3, § 2, 2-4-64; Ord. No. 64-65, § 5, 12-15-64; Ord. No. 65-11, § 1, 2-16-65; Ord. No. 66-66, § 4, 12-20-66; Ord. No. 74-20, § 6, 4-3-74; Ord. No. 74-40, § 4, 6-4-74; Ord. No. 77-54, § 1, 7-19-77; Ord. No. 78-18, § 1, 3-21-78; Ord. No. 78-52, § 2, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 80-88, § 1, 9-2-80; Ord. No. 87-29, § 1, 5-19-87; Ord. No. 89-129, § 1, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-16, § 3, 2-25-97; Ord. No. 99-166, § 4, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 00-31, § 2, 2-24-00; Ord. No. 00-100, § 1, 7-25-00; Ord. No. 05-32, § 1, 2-1-05; Ord. No. 13-16, § 9, 2-5-13)</history></law>