<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-32</section_number>
<catch_line>Limitations and restrictions on use of metal covering for buildings and additions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003925</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-32. Limitations and restrictions on use of metal covering for buildings and additions.<section>The limitations and restrictions on the use of metal covering for buildings and additions are as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>That such metal buildings, their components and their use shall conform in every respect with all applicable provisions of the South Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That metal sandwich-type panel units, which are approved as conforming to the standards of the South Florida Building Code shall be permitted for construction of all buildings in all zoning districts; provided, the exterior metal walls shall have a noncorrosive surface with a secondary finish, shop or field applied, or integral finish which will not reflect more than sixty (60) percent of the incident light.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That approved architecturally shaped metal structural sheets may be used for exterior wall and roof covering of buildings in BU and IU Districts and for nonresidential use buildings in the AU District and for nonresidential accessory use buildings in the RU and EU Districts, provided the same, and the use thereof are approved as conforming with all requirements of the South Florida Building Code and the proviso portion of Subsection (b) above.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Nonstructural aluminum exterior wall lap siding with baked enamel or other approved finish, which is approved as complying with standards of the South Florida Building Code, shall be permitted as veneer siding in all zoning districts.</section><section prefix='(e)'>This section is not intended to amend, repeal, modify or supersede Article V, Chapter 33 or Section 33-246(23) of this Code or to prevent the use of metal shingles as roofing, if such shingles are approved as complying with the standards of the South Florida Building Code. It is intended, however, that the provisions of this section shall supersede all reference in Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County to requirements for masonry construction, and that type of construction shall be governed by the provisions of this section and the South Florida Building Code.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 28, 10-22-57; Ord. No. 61-14, ยง 1, 4-11-61; Ord. No. 65-22, ยง 2, 4-6-65)</history></law>