<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-302</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004498</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-302. Definitions.<section>In construing the provisions hereof and each and every word, term, phrase or part thereof where the context will permit the definitions provided in Section 1.01, Florida Statutes, and Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and the following additional definitions, shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>Comprehensive Development Master Plan. The words "Comprehensive Development Master Plan" shall mean and refer to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County adopted by Ordinance No. 75-22 on March 31, 1975, or as amended.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan. The words "conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan" shall mean and refer to zoning request or action which is consistent with the goals, objectives, standards and policies of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Development. The word "development" shall mean and refer to the carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning regulations (i.e., Chapter 33 of Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida) or making any material change in the use or character of the land, including, but not limited to, the placement of structure or structures on land. When appropriate to the context, development refers to the act of zoning or rezoning through district boundary changes, site or plot use approvals, or otherwise, which authorizes or permits development of the land.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Developments of County impact. The words "developments of County impact" shall mean and refer to any development which, because of its character, magnitude or location, would have a substantial effect upon the health, safety and welfare of the citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Development activity meeting one (1) of the criteria specified in Section 33-304(d) is declared to be a development of County impact.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Developmental Impact Committee (Committee). The words "Developmental Impact Committee (Committee)" shall mean and refer to the Miami-Dade County Administrative Committee, created by Ord. No. 74-47, adopted on June 18, 1974.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Land. The word "land" shall mean and refer to earth, water and air above, below or on the surface.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Director. The word "Director" shall mean the Director Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Department. The word "Department" shall mean the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(i)'>District. The word "District" shall mean and refer to the various zoning districts provided by Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(j)'>District boundary maps. The words "district boundary maps" shall mean those maps kept on file in the Department showing the boundaries of the various districts, and more particularly described in Section 33-3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Record. The word "record" when pertaining to the record of any board shall mean and include any application, exhibits, appeal papers, written objections, waivers or consents, considered by such board, transcript or stenographic notes taken for the Department at a hearing held before such board, if any, the board's minutes and resolution showing its decision or action, and if the record of a lower board is transmitted to a higher board, the record of the higher board shall include that of the lower board. The word "record" shall also include any and all applicable portions of Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, the report and recommendations of the Director and the Developmental Impact Committee; the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida; and Ordinance No. 75-22, or as amended, or applicable neighborhood or area studies or plans approved by action of the Board of County Commissioners, as well as applicable district boundary maps, aerial photographs and final zoning resolutions. It shall also include the record made as a result of any previous zoning application on the same property. The Clerk of the County Commission shall identify all exhibits used or referred to at the zoning hearing. All exhibits so identified or introduced shall be a part of the record. The record shall not include documents prepared or relied upon by an expert not filed in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-f(D) of the Code, or any oral testimony or written reports or documents which were not filed in accordance with the provisions of Section 2-114.1 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Regulations or zoning regulations. The word "regulations" or the words "zoning regulations" shall mean and refer to the contents of Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as from time to time amended.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Administrative official. The words "administrative official" shall mean the Director and any staff member of the Department authorized by the Director to enforce or interpret the regulations or various zoning resolutions.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Public benefit. The words "public benefit" shall mean and refer to a development which, after consideration of all of its aspects (including, but not limited to, environmental impact on facilities, economic and social) would be consistent with and not detrimental to the welfare of the community.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Unit. The word "unit" shall mean and refer to houses, apartments, group of rooms, or a single room occupied or intended for permanent or transient occupancy as separate living quarters.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Citizen participation. The words "citizen participation" shall refer to the suggestions and comments of responsible and recognized persons and groups to the Developmental Impact Committee during the deliberative processes and prior to final recommendations on appropriate developments. Citizen participation shall not refer to public hearings or adversary proceedings of any nature before the Developmental Impact Committee. The Developmental Impact Committee shall prepare appropriate guidelines involving citizen participation in the process.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Zoning actions. The words "zoning action" shall refer to any action pursuant to Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County taken after a public hearing, including the acceptance of a declaration of restrictive covenants proffered at a public hearing.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Independent development parcel. The words "independent development parcel" shall refer to a development parcel which is buildable in one (1) or more phases, which parcel has parking, an independent circulation system, and sufficient identity to be developed independently of surrounding property. A development parcel may consist of one (1) or more platted tracts, developed as a single independent development parcel.</section><section prefix='(s)'>"Immediate vicinity" means an area in which a parcel of land proposed for alternative development is located that is physically, functionally or geographically identifiable as a distinct realm, place or neighborhood, or an area within a radius of not more than five hundred (500) feet from the parcel proposed for alternative development, whichever is smaller.</section><section prefix='(t)'>"Open space" means that portion of a parcel of land which is not covered with a building and is open to the sky and may include patios, limited roof overhangs, screened enclosures with screened roofs, open trellises, walkways, swimming pools, tennis courts, landscaped areas, decks, and non-covered parking areas.</section><section prefix='(u)'>"Parcel proposed for alternative development" means the site of the structure for which alternative site development option approval is sought.</section><section prefix='(v)'>"Proposed alternative development" means any building activity for which alternative site development approval is sought.</section><section prefix='(w)'>"Underlying district regulations" means the site development regulations of the particular zoning district in which proposed alternative development is located, such as setbacks, lot area, frontage, and depth, lot coverage, and structure height.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, § 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 75-47, § 1, 6-18-75; Ord. No. 77-40, § 2, 6-21-77; Ord. No. 83-59, § 1, 7-19-83; Ord. No. 89-10, § 3, 2-21-89; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 33, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 97-131, § 1, 7-22-97; Ord. No. 98-125, § 21, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 03-91, § 1, 4-22-03; Ord. No. 13-16, § 2, 2-5-13)</history></law>