<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-317</section_number>
<catch_line>Limitation on issuance of permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004522</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-317. Limitation on issuance of permits.<section>The Department shall not issue any type of permit or certificate based upon any action of the Community Zoning Appeals Board which the County Commission has jurisdiction to review until a final decision has been rendered on the application by the County Commission as provided by this chapter; provided, however, a temporary conditional permit or certificate may be issued prior to such final decision if the Director should first determine that the withholding of the same would cause imminent peril to life or property and then only upon such conditions and limitations, including the furnishing of an appropriate bond, as may be deemed proper by the Director.</section><section>Upon application of the Director, any variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use heretofore or hereafter granted that is not utilized within the three-year period following the date of its grant or approval, may be terminated by the Board of County Commissioners after the required noticed public hearing or hearings, if it is determined that there have been sufficient changes in circumstances in the neighborhood and area concerned that to permit the same to be used would be detrimental to the area and incompatible therewith; provided, a variance shall not be terminated if the guidelines for granting the same exist. The foregoing provision shall not apply if the resolution granting the variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use establishes a specific time limitation for utilizing the same. In such instances, the time limitation established by such resolution shall prevail.</section><section>In the event application is made for a change of zoning on property which possesses any variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use not yet utilized, no permits or certificates shall be issued for such variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use until the hearing has been concluded. If the application for change of zoning is approved, the variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use shall terminate, unless continued by the rezoning resolution; otherwise such variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use shall remain in full force and effect, unless terminated by other provisions in this section.</section><section>A variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use shall be deemed to have been utilized if the use pursuant thereto shall have been established, or if a building permit has been issued, acted upon, and the development to which such variance, special exception, new use, special permit or unusual use is an integral part is progressively and continuously carried to conclusion.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, ยง 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 73-104, ยง 1, 12-18-73; Ord. No. 96-127, ยง 38, 9-4-96)</history></law>