<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-304.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Voluntary contribution or dedication of property to Miami-Dade County or Miami-Dade County School Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004503</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-304.1. Voluntary contribution or dedication of property to Miami-Dade County or Miami-Dade County School Board.<section>No applicant for zoning action pursuant to shall seek to induce favorable consideration of such application through contribution, dedication or conveyance of land for use of Miami-Dade County or the Miami-Dade County School Board unless the following requirements have been met:<section prefix='A.'>Property proposed to be conveyed to Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='1.'>The zoning applicant has submitted to the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management an environmental site assessment for the subject property which specifically complies with the requirements set forth in the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) Standards on Environmental Site Assessments for Commercial Real Estate, Second Edition, E1527-94 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments: Phase I Environmental Site Assessment Process and 1528-93 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments Transaction Screen Process.</section><section prefix='2.'>The Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management has provided a recommendation after considering the environmental site assessment.</section></section><section prefix='B.'>Property proposed to be conveyed to the Miami-Dade County School Board.<section prefix='1.'>The zoning applicant has submitted to the Miami-Dade County School Board an environmental site assessment for the subject property which specifically complies with the requirements set forth in the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) Standards on Environmental Site Assessments for Commercial Real Estate, Second Edition, E1527-94 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments: Phase I Environmental Site Assessment Process and 1528-93 Standard Practice for Environmental Site Assessments Transaction Screen Process.</section><section prefix='2.'>The Miami-Dade County School Board has provided a recommendation regarding the School Board's acceptance of the proposed conveyance or dedication after considering the environmental site assessment.</section></section></section><section>This section shall not be the subject of any variance request.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-92, ยง 1, 6-17-97)</history></law>