<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-306</section_number>
<catch_line>Community Zoning Appeals Boards—Establishment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004505</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-306. Community Zoning Appeals Boards—Establishment.<section prefix='(a)'>There are hereby established multiple Community Zoning Appeals Boards whose boundaries shall coincide with the boundaries of Community Councils established pursuant to the Code of Miami-Dade County. The Community Councils shall serve as Community Zoning Appeals Boards and shall have jurisdiction over zoning applications as provided in this chapter. Each member shall be a qualified elector of Miami-Dade County, with an outstanding reputation for civic interest, community welfare, integrity and responsibility; provided, no member shall be employed by Miami-Dade County, or be a member of the County Commission. The seven (7) members of each Community Zoning Appeals Board shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval of the County Commission.</section><section prefix='(b)'>These boards are created and established pursuant to Section 4.08 of the Home Rule Charter, and for the purpose of facilitating the zoning powers granted by the Home Rule Charter to the Board of County Commissioners, and to provide a board to hear, consider and review appeals from the zoning regulations or decisions of an administrative official, and to take appropriate action as in this article provided and limited.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 64-39, § 17, 9-1-64; Ord. No. 64-65, § 1, 12-15-64; Ord. No. 68-51, § 1, 9-19-68; Ord. No. 96-127, § 35, 9-4-96)</history></law>