<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-333</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of airport zoning area for Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field).</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004535</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-333. Establishment of airport zoning area for Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field).<section>For the purpose of this article there is hereby created and established the airport zoning area for Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field), and it is hereby ordained that such area shall include, and that the provisions of this article shall be applicable to and embrace, all of the unincorporated and incorporated land and water area lying, situate and being in those certain portions of Miami-Dade County, Florida, within the following described boundaries:<section prefix='(1)'>Northern boundary. Commencing at the intersection of the Miami-Dade County-Broward County line and the centerline of U.S. Highway 27, proceed easterly along the County line to the range line between Range 42 East and Range 43 East.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Eastern boundary. Commencing at the intersection of the Miami-Dade County-Broward County extended, and the range line between Range 42 East and Range 43 East, proceed southerly along said range line to the intersection of theoretical S.E. 152 Street.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Southern boundary. Commencing at the intersection of theoretical S.E. 152 Street and the range line between Range 42 East and Range 43 East, proceed westerly along theoretical S.E. 152 Street and S.W. 152 Street to the intersection S.W. 152 Street and Krome Avenue.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Western boundary. Commencing at the intersection of Krome Avenue and S.W. 152 Street, proceed northerly along the centerline of Krome Avenue to the intersection of U.S. Highway 27, thence northerly along the centerline of U.S. Highway 27 to the Miami-Dade County-Broward County line.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-39, ยง 4, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 78-78, ยง 1, 11-7-78; Ord. No. 86-83, ยง 1, 10-28-86; Ord. No. 04-203, ยง 4, 11-30-04)</history></law>