<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00073' order_by='00073' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVIII. OPA LOCKA AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-363.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Site plan review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004566</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-363.2. Site plan review.<section prefix='(A)'>For all non-aviation uses, the Department shall review plans for compliance with zoning regulations and for compliance with the site plan review criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, innovation and variety in the design process and encourage the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. All plans submitted to the Department shall be reviewed and approved or denied within fifteen (15) days from the date of submission. Denials shall be in writing and shall specifically set forth the grounds for denial. Receipt of applicant's plans for fifteen (15) days without formal written denial shall constitute approval. Notwithstanding the provisions of 33-314, if the site is located within unincorporated or incorporated Miami-Dade County and if the plan is disapproved, the applicant may appeal to the Board of County Commissioners. Appeals by the applicant shall be filed within thirty (30) days of the date the project was denied.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Required exhibits. The following exhibits shall be prepared by design professionals such as architects and landscape architects and submitted to the Department:<section prefix='(1)'>Dimensioned site plan(s) indicating, as a minimum, the following information:<section prefix='(a)'>Existing zoning on the site and on adjacent properties.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The basic use, height, bulk and location of all buildings and other structures with setbacks.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Vehicular and pedestrian circulation systems including connection(s) to existing or proposed roadway and sidewalk system and the layout of parking, service and loading areas.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Graphics and/or notations indicating the site planning or structure design methods used to minimize the impact of those industrial activities that could have a negative impact on existing or proposed adjacent land uses.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Sketches of design elements to be used for buffering surrounding uses.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Elevation of the proposed buildings and other major design elements.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Landscape plans: Landscaping and trees shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A of this Code.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Figures indicating the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Proposed uses.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Gross floor area:  square feet</section><section prefix='(c)'>Land area:<section>Gross lot area: square feet acres</section><section>Net lot area: square feet acres</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Landscaped open space:<section>Required: square feet % of net land area</section><section>Provided: square feet % of net land area</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Tree Required:<section>Trees Provided:</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Off-street parking spaces:<section>Required:</section><section>Provided:</section></section></section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Criteria. The following shall be considered in the plan review process:<section prefix='(1)'>Planning studies: Planning studies approved by the Board of County Commissioners that include development patterns or environmental and other design criteria shall be considered in the plan review process.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Landscape: Landscape shall be preserved in its natural state insofar as is practicable by minimizing removal of existing vegetation. Landscape shall be used to shade and cool, enhance architectural features, relate structure design to the site, visually screen noncompatible uses, and ameliorate the impact of noise.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Compatibility: The architectural design and scale of the proposed structures shall be compatible with surrounding existing or proposed uses or shall be made compatible by the use of screening elements. Screening elements can include such devices as trees and shrubs, walls and fencing, berming or any combination of these elements. Visual buffering shall be provided between parking and service areas and adjacent non-commercial uses.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Emergency access: Unobstructed on-site access for emergency equipment shall be considered.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Circulation: Internal vehicular and pedestrian circulation systems shall be designed to function with existing and/or approved systems outside the development. Vehicular traffic generated from the industrial activity should be routed in such a manner as to minimize impact on residential development.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Energy conservation: Applicants are advised to consider requirements of Florida Statutes Chapter 553 (Energy Code).</section><section prefix='(7)'>Visual screening for decorative walls: In an effort to prevent graffiti vandalism, the following options shall be utilized for walls abutting zoned or dedicated rights-of-way:<section prefix='(a)'>Wall with landscaping. The wall shall be setback two and one-half (2½) feet from the right-of-way line and the resulting setback area shall contain a continuous extensively landscaped buffer which must be maintained in a good healthy condition by the property owner, or where applicable, by the condominium, homeowners or similar association. The landscape buffer shall contain one (1) or more of the following planting materials:<section prefix='(1)'>Shrubs. Shrubs shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Hedges. Hedges shall be a minimum of three (3) feet in height when measured immediately after planting and shall be planted and maintained to form a continuous, unbroken, solid, visual screen within one (1) year after time of planting.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vines. Climbing vines shall be a minimum of thirty-six (36) inches in height immediately after planting.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Metal picket fence. Where a metal picket fence abutting a zoned or dedicated right-of-way is constructed in lieu of a decorative wall, landscaping shall not be required.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-33, § 2, 5-5-09)</history></law>