<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='3'>ARTICLE XL. KENDALL TAMIAMI EXECUTIVE AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-390</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004593</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-390. Definitions.<section>In construing the provisions hereof and each and every word, term, phrase or part thereof, where the context will permit, the definitions provided in Section 1.01 F.S. and Section 33-1 and Section 33-302 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and the following definitions shall apply:</section><section prefix='(1)'>Airport means Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport.<section prefix='(2)'>Airport elevation means the established elevation of the highest point on the usable landing area. The airport elevation for Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport is ten (10.0) feet mean sea level.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Airport reference point means the point established as the approximate geographic center of the landing area and so designated and identified. The position of the airport reference point for Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport is described as follows:<section>Commence at the northeast corner of, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, and run thence southward along the east line of said at a bearing of South 02° 22′ 40″ East a distance of 2734.47 feet; thence westward at right angles to the said east line of at a bearing of South 87° 37′ 20″ West for a distanced of 334.45 feet to the airport reference point.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Aviation schools shall mean any educational facility that primarily provides education or training in the science and art of flight, including, but not limited to: the operation and construction of aircraft, aircraft power plants and accessories, including the repair, packing and maintenance of parachutes; the design, establishment, construction, extension, operations, improvement, repair or maintenance of airports or other air navigation facilities, and instruction in flying or ground subjects pertaining thereto.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Educational facilities shall mean those facilities as defined by Chapter 235, Florida Statutes, as amended, and the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Hazard to Air Navigation is an obstruction determined by the Federal Aviation Administration to have a substantial adverse effect on the safe and efficient utilization of the navigable airspace.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Height for the purpose of determining the height limits in all districts set forth in this article and shown on the boundary map for zone classification districts, the datum shall be mean sea level (MSL) elevation unless otherwise specified.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Instrument runway means a runway equipped or to be equipped with electronic or visual air navigation aids adequate to permit the landing or take-off of aircraft under restricted visibility conditions. The instrument runways at Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport are designated as Runway 9L/27R and Runway 9R/27L and their centerlines are described as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Runway 9L/27R: Commencing at the northeast corner of Section 15, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence south 03° 53′ 36″ East along the east line of said Section 15 a distance of 945.03 feet; thence south 87° 04′ 03″ West a distance of 2606.21 feet to the east end of the runway and the point of beginning; thence continue south 87° 04′ 03″ West a distance of 5000 feet to the west end of the runway.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Runway 9R/27L: Commencing at the southeast corner of Section 15, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence north 04° 35′ 16″ West along the east line of said Section 15 a distance of 1068.16 feet; thence south 87° 04′ 03″ West a distance of 2684.19 feet to the east end of the runway and the point of beginning; thence continue south 87° 04′ 03″ West a distance of 5000 feet to the west end of the runway.</section></section><section prefix='(8.5)'>Landing area means the area of the airport used or intended to be used for landing, take-off, or taxiing of aircraft.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Nonconforming use means any structure, tree or use of land lawfully in existence on the effective date hereof which does not conform to a regulation prescribed in this article or any amendment thereto, as of the effective date of such regulations.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Non-instrument runway means a runway other than an instrument runway. The non-instrument runway at Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport is designated as Runway 13/31 and its centerline is described as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Runway 13/31: Commencing at the northeast corner of Section 15, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence south 03° 53′ 36″ East along the east line of said Section 15 a distance of 945.03 feet; thence south 87° 04′ 03″ West a distance of 9254.87 feet; thence south 52° 54′ 00″ East a distance of 1148.67 feet to the northwest end of the runway and the point of beginning; thence continue south 52° 54′ 00″ East a distance of 4000 feet to the southeast end of the runway.</section></section><section prefix='(11)'>Person means an individual, firm, co-partnership, corporation, company, association, joint stock association or body politic, and includes any trustee, receiver, assignee, administrator, executor, guardian or other similar representative thereof.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Runway means the defined area on an airport prepared for landing and take-off of aircraft along its length.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Structure means an object constructed or installed by man, including, but without being limited to, buildings, derricks, draglines, cranes and other boom-equipped machinery, towers, signs, smokestacks, utility poles, or overhead transmission lines.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Tree means any object of natural growth.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Obstruction means any structure, growth, or other object, including a mobile object, which exceeds the height limitations as set forth herein.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Airport hazard means any structure or tree or use of land which would exceed the federal obstruction standards as contained in 14 C.F.R. §§ 77.21, 77.23, 77.25, 77.28, and 77.29 and which obstructs the airspace required for the flight of aircraft in taking off, maneuvering, or landing or is otherwise hazardous to such taking off, maneuvering, or landing of aircraft.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-40, § 3, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 99-118, § 1, 9-21-99)</history></law>