<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00074' order_by='00074' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIX. HOMESTEAD GENERAL AVIATION AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-374</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004577</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-374. Definitions.<section>In construing the provisions hereof and each and every word, term, phrase or part thereof, where the context will permit, the definitions provided in Section 1.01 F.S. and Section 33-1 and Section 33-302 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(1)'>Airport means Homestead General Aviation Airport.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Airport elevation means the established elevation of the highest point on the usable landing area. The airport elevation for Homestead General Aviation Airport is eight and five-tenths (8.5) feet mean sea level.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Airport hazard means any structure or tree or use of land which obstructs the airspace required for or is otherwise hazardous to the flight of aircraft in landing or taking off at the airport.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Airport reference point means the point established as the approximate geographic center of the landing area and so designated and identified. The position of the airport reference point for Homestead General Aviation Airport is described as follows:<section>Commence at the southwest corner of Section 5, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, and run thence northward along the west line of said Section 5 at a bearing of North 00° 42′ 33″ West for a distance of two thousand five hundred fifty-five (2,555) feet; thence eastward at right angles to the said west line of Section 5 at a bearing of North 89° 17′ 27″ East for a distance of five hundred seventy-six (576) feet to the airport reference point.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Height for the purpose of determining the height limits in all districts set forth in this article and shown on the boundary map for zone classification districts, the datum shall be mean sea level (MSL) elevation unless otherwise specified.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Instrument runway means a runway equipped or to be equipped with electronic or visual air navigation aids adequate to permit the landing or take-off of aircraft under restricted visibility conditions. The instrument runway at Homestead General Aviation Airport will be designated as Runway 9L/27R, the centerline of which is described as follows:<section>Commencing at the northeast corner of Section 5, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence South 00° 29′ 23″ East along the east line of said Section 5 a distance of 758.10 feet; thence South 89° 29′ 21″ West a distance of 1160 feet to the east end of the runway and the point of beginning; thence South 89° 29′ 21″ West a distance of 6500 feet to the west end of the runway.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Landing area means the area of the airport used or intended to be used for landing, take-off, or taxiing of aircraft.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Nonconforming use means any structure, tree or use of land lawfully in existence on the effective date hereof which does not conform to a regulation prescribed in this article or any amendment thereto, as of the effective date of such regulations.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Non-instrument runway means a runway other than an instrument runway. The non-instrument runways at Homestead General Aviation are designated as Runways 18L/36R, Runway 18R/36L, and Runway 9R/27L and their centerlines are described as follow:<section prefix='(a)'>Runway 18L/36R: Commencing at the northwest corner of Section 5, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence South 00° 42′ 37″ East along the west line of said Section 5 a distance of 1388.10 feet; thence North 89° 29′ 21″ East a distance of 500 feet to the north end of the runway and the point of beginning; thence South 00° 42′ 37″ East a distance of 4000 feet to the south end of the runway.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Runway 18R/36L: Beginning at the northeast corner of Section 6, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, thence South 00° 42′ 37″ East along the east line of said Section 6 a distance of 683.10 feet; thence South 89° 29′ 21″ West a distance of 200 feet to the north end of the runway and the point of beginning; thence South 00° 42′ 37″ East a distance of 5000 feet to the south end of the runway.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Runway 9R/27L: Beginning at the southeast corner of Section 5, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, thence North 00° 09′ 23″ West along the east line of said Section 5 a distance of 500.13 feet; thence South 89° 29′ 21″ West a distance of 2175 feet to the east end of the runway and the point of beginning; thence continue South 89° 29′ 21″ West a distance of 4000 feet to the west end of the runway.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Person means an individual, firm, co-partnership, corporation, company, association, joint stock association or body politic, and includes any trustee, receiver, assignee, administrator, executor, guardian or other similar representative thereof.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Runway means the paved surface of an airport landing strip.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Structure means an object constructed or installed by man, including, but without being limited to, buildings, derricks, draglines, cranes and other boom-equipped machinery towers, signs, smokestacks, utility poles, or overhead transmission lines.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Tree means any object of natural growth.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-38, § 3, 7-9-69)</history></law>