<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-347</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of height limitations for height zoning districts in the airport zoning area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004552</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-347. Establishment of height limitations for height zoning districts in the airport zoning area.<section>Except as otherwise provided elsewhere in this article, no structure or object shall be erected or altered and no tree shall be allowed to grow or be maintained in any height zoning district created and established by this article to a height in excess of the height limits herein established for such district, as depicted by the MIA Height Map. In applying the provisions of this article, such height limitations shall be corrected to elevations referred to the heretofore established mean sea level datum plane, by adding such height limitations to the mean sea level elevation of the point, line or plane to which such height limitation is referenced, or to the airport elevation, as the context of this article requires. An area, structure, or tree located in more than one (1) of the described districts is considered to be only in the district with the more restrictive height limitation.</section><section>The MIA Height Map adopted in of this article shall be the official height zoning map for the Miami International Airport, shall establish the maximum height of structures and trees and shall be applicable to and controlling of such height limitations established herein.</section><section>Height limitations are hereby established for the districts of the MIA Height Map as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Instrument Approach Districts:<section prefix='(a)'>For Runways 8R, 26L, 12 and 30: One (1) foot vertically for each sixty-five (65) feet horizontally beginning at a point two hundred (200) feet from the end of each instrument runway and extending for a distance of ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet from the end of each runway; thence one (1) foot vertically for each forty (40) feet horizontally for a distance of forty thousand (40,000) feet to a point fifty thousand two hundred (50,200) feet from the end of each runway. Within the high structure set-aside district, this imaginary inclined surface shall terminate in its intersection with any of the HSA districts as defined in Section 33-346(6), subsections (a) through (e) hereinbefore described under "high structure set-aside district." The HSA districts shall have precedence when they are in conflict or coincide with any of these surfaces.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For Runways 9 and 27, one (1) foot vertically for each fifty (50) feet horizontally beginning at a point two hundred (200) feet from the end of these instrument runways and extending for a distance of ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet from the end of each runway; thence one (1) foot vertically for each forty (40) feet horizontally for a distance of forty thousand (40,000) feet to a point fifty thousand two hundred (50,200) feet from the end of each runway. Within the high structure set-aside district, this imaginary inclined surface shall terminate in its intersection with any of the HSA districts as defined in Section 33-346(6), subsections (a) through (e) hereinbefore described under "high structure set-aside district." The HSA districts shall have precedence when they are in conflict or coincide with any of these surfaces.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Horizontal district: One hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Conical district: One (1) foot vertically to twenty (20) feet horizontally beginning at the periphery of the hereinbefore described horizontal district for a horizontal distance of four thousand (4,000) feet. Within the high structure set-aside district, the imaginary inclined Conical surface shall terminate in its intersection with any of the HSA districts as defined in Section 33-346(6), subsections (a) through (e) hereinbefore described under "high structure set-aside district." The HSA districts shall have precedence when they are in conflict or coincide with any of the conical surfaces.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Departure zone district: For departure zone surface 1, one (1) foot vertically to forty (40) feet horizontally beginning at the departure end of each runway at an elevation of forty-five (45) feet AMSL and extending outward a distance of two (2) nautical miles (12,152 feet) from the end of the runway. For departure zone surface 2, one (1) foot vertically to forty (40) feet horizontally beginning at the edge of each runway and the edge of the departure zone surface 1, and at an elevation of three hundred forty-nine (349) feet AMSL, which is the elevation at the high end of the departure zone 1 surface, then extending until an elevation of one thousand five hundred ten (1,510) feet AMSL is reached. The one thousand five hundred ten-foot elevation continues outward from the airport as a horizontal plane to the boundaries of the airport zoning area. The height restrictions in the departure zone district do not apply within the high structure set-aside district.</section><section prefix='(5)'>HSA or High structure set-aside district: A "high structure set-aside district" is established which identifies an area where tall buildings and other structures may be permitted with limited impact on the capacity and operation of Miami International Airport. When in conflict with any other imaginary surface specified within this article, the herein defined HSA sub-districts shall be the prevailing height limitation. The high structure set-aside district embraces and includes all of the land and water lying within an area in the City of Miami, Florida bounded by the following five (5) sub-districts as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>This sub-district shall be known as the 1010-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 1010 feet. This sub-district shall be bounded by an imaginary polygon connecting the following six (6) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #10 Latitude: 25° 46′ 47.5296″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 37.7784″Then east to Point #16 Latitude: 25° 46′ 49.646″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 6.9859″Then east to Point #9 Latitude: 25° 46′ 50.2126″ Longitude: 80° 10′ 56.2165″Then southeast to Point #8 Latitude: 25° 46′ 31.6176″ Longitude: 80° 10′ 47.7207″Then southwest to Point #7 Latitude: 25° 45′ 21.8290″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 08.4645″Then northwest to Point #6 Latitude: 25° 45′ 32.3210″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 38.2714″Then northeast to Point #17 Latitude: 25° 45′ 42.3695″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 35.448″Then north back to the first point.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>This sub-district shall be known as 709-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 709 feet. This sub-district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of seven (7) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #12 Latitude: 25° 47′ 10.4625″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 38.7278″Then easterly to Point #18 Latitude: 25° 47′ 09.0115″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 24.5157″Then Northeast to Point #23 Latitude: 25° 47′ 10.2132″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 19.4348″Then northeast to Point #19 Latitude: 25° 47′ 13.4815″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 11.6725″Then east to Point #14 Latitude: 25° 47′ 14.1187″ Longitude: 80° 11 07.1561″Then south to Point #16 Latitude: 25° 46′ 49.646″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 06.9859″Then west to Point #10 Latitude: 25° 46′ 47.5296″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 37.7784″Then north back to the first point.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>This sub-district shall be known as the 649-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 649 feet. This sub-district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of eleven (11) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #11 Latitude: 25° 48′ 41.4522″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 43.1295″Then east to Point #22 Latitude: 25° 48′ 40.8496″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 15.5784″Then northeast to Point #24 Latitude: 25° 48′ 41.4146″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 08.9165″Then northeast to Point #15 Latitude: 25° 48′ 41.0436″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 07.1879″Then south to Point #14 Latitude: 25° 47′ 14.1187″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 07.1561″Then west to Point #19 Latitude: 25° 47′ 13.4815″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 11.6725″Then Northeast to Point #23 Latitude: 25° 47′ 10.2132″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 19.4348″Then southwest to Point #18 Latitude: 25° 47′ 09.0115″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 24.5157″Then west to Point #12 Latitude: 25° 47′ 10.4625″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 38.7278″Then north to Point #20 Latitude: 25° 47′ 17.2495″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 39.0561″Then northwest to Point #21 Latitude: 25° 47′ 18.5731″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 40.7420″Then north back to the first point.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>This sub-district shall be known as the High-Set Aside Transitional District. Boundary end shall vary in its slope depending on the allowable heights that are adjacent to this sub-district as set forth in this article. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 310 feet AMSL along some portions of the western boundary and increase to a maximum allowable height of 1010 feet AMSL along those areas that are adjacent to the 1010-foot boundary. This sub-district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of eleven (11) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #1 Latitude: 25° 47′ 37.6803″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 18.9273″Then east to Point #13 Latitude: 25° 47′ 38.5695″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 41.318″Then south to Point #21 Latitude: 25° 47′ 18.5731″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 40.7420″Then southeast to Point #20 Latitude: 25° 47′ 17.2495″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 39.0561″Then south to Point #12 Latitude: 25° 47′ 10.4625″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 38.7278″Then south to Point #10 Latitude: 25° 46′ 47.5296″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 37.7784″Then south to Point #17 Latitude: 25° 45′ 42.3695″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 35.448″Then southeast to Point #6 Latitude: 25° 45′ 32.3210″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 38.2714″Then northwest to Point #5 Latitude: 25° 45′ 43.2122″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 59.4724″Then north to Point #32 Latitude: 25° 46′ 46.9187″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 01.4771″Then north to Point #2 Latitude: 25° 47′ 02.6758″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 01.9730″Then back to the first point of this district.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>This sub-district shall be known as 310-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 310 feet. This sub-district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of twelve (12) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #3 Latitude: 25° 47′ 41.6854″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 40.3263″Then east to Point #25 Latitude: 25° 47′ 33.8427″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 17.0685″Then south to Point #2 Latitude: 25° 47′ 02.6758″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 01.9730″Then south to Point #32 Latitude: 25° 46′ 46.9187″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 01.4771″Then south to Point #5 Latitude: 25° 45′ 43.2122″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 59.4724″Then northwest to Point #4 Latitude: 25° 46′ 18.54″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 50.8037″Then northwest to Point #26 Latitude: 25° 46′ 31.8645″ Longitude: 80° 14′ 15.3849″Then northeast to Point #27 Latitude: 25° 46′ 29.9925″ Longitude: 80° 14′ 04.5838″Then north to Point #28 Latitude: 25° 46′ 53.1392″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 15.1815″Then northwest to Point #29 Latitude: 25° 46′ 55.9420″ Longitude: 80° 14′ 5.6983″Then northeast to Point #30 Latitude: 25° 46′ 56.6371″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 54.8079″Then north to Point #31 Latitude: 25° 47′ 19.8838″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 55.9731″Then back to the first point of this district.</section></section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Transition district: One (1) foot vertically for each seven (7) feet horizontally from the sides of the primary surfaces and from the sides of the approach surfaces (instrument or non-instrument). Transition surfaces extend from the primary surfaces to the horizontal surface, and from the approach surfaces to the adjacent horizontal surface, conical surface or departure zone surface. Within the high structure set-aside district, the imaginary inclined transition, conical, and approach surfaces shall terminate in its intersection with any of the HSA districts as defined in subsection (6)(a) through (e) of this article hereinbefore described under "high structure set-aside district." The HSA districts shall have precedence when they are in conflict or coincide with any of the approach, conical, or transitional surfaces.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Non-Instrument approach districts: For Runways 8L and 26R, the non-instrument approach surface shall extend outward and upward from its base, the elevation of which shall be the same as that of the runway end adjacent thereto, with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to thirty-four (34) feet horizontally for its entire length.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-92, § 13, 7-10-07)</history></law>