<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-346</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of airport height zoning districts for airport obstruction analysis area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004551</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-346. Establishment of airport height zoning districts for airport obstruction analysis area.<section>The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts, approves and ratifies the map entitled "Airport Height Zoning District Map Miami International Airport", dated September 20, 2006, ("MIA Height Map") reflecting the location and identifying Miami International Airport and other topographic data pertinent thereto depicting the boundaries of the airport height zoning districts. Such map establishes the boundaries of the airport height zoning districts, and the prohibitions, restrictions, and limitations on heights permitted thereon by this article.</section><section>The above defined map, which is on file in the Miami-Dade Aviation Department and the Department of Planning and Zoning, shall be the official height use zoning map for the Miami International Airport and surrounding area, shall evidence the boundaries of the districts depicted thereon, and shall be applicable to and controlling of height zoning for such districts.<section prefix='(A)'>For the purpose of this article all of the airport height classification areas for Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field), as the same is created, established and described hereinbefore, is hereby divided into height zoning districts as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>L or Landing districts (Primary Surfaces). A "landing district" is established for each instrument and non-instrument runway. A landing district for an instrument runway shall have a uniform width of one thousand (1,000) feet. A landing district for a non-instrument runway shall have a uniform width of five hundred (500) feet. All landing districts shall extend for the full length of such runway plus a distance of two hundred (200) feet beyond each end thereof and shall include such runway and be symmetrical about the centerline thereof. Each landing district shall embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath an imaginary surface referred to as the "primary surface" which shall have an elevation equal to the elevation of the nearest point on the runway centerline.</section><section prefix='(2)'>IA or Instrument approach districts. An "instrument approach district" is established for each end of each instrument runway for instrument landings and takeoffs, and it is further established that each instrument approach district shall embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath an imaginary inclined surface which shall hereafter, for the purposes of this article, be referred to and described as the instrument approach surface.<section>The instrument approach surface shall begin on a base one thousand (1,000) feet wide, such base to be at a position two hundred (200) feet beyond the end of the runway and from such base the approach surface shall widen uniformly to sixteen thousand (16,000) feet at a horizontal distance of fifty thousand two hundred (50,200) feet beyond the end of the runway, the centerline of this surface being the extension of the centerline of the runway.</section><section>Within the high structure set-aside district, the imaginary inclined instrument approach surface shall terminate in its intersection with any of the HSA districts as defined in(6), subsections (a) through (e) hereinafter described under "high structure set-aside district." The HSA districts shall have precedence when they are in conflict or coincide with any of the instrument approach surfaces.</section><section>The instrument approach surface shall extend outward and upward from its one thousand-foot-wide base, the elevation of which base is ten (10) feet MSL.</section><section prefix='(a)'>For runways 8R, 26L, 12 and 30, the approach surface shall slope upward one (1) foot vertically to sixty-five (65) feet horizontally for the first ten thousand (10,000) feet of its length, and from thence it shall slope upward one (1) foot vertically to forty (40) feet horizontally for the remaining forty thousand (40,000) feet.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For runways 9 and 27, the approach surface shall slope upward one (1) foot vertically to fifty (50) feet horizontally for the first ten thousand (10,000) feet of its length, and from thence it shall slope upward one (1) foot vertically to forty (40) feet horizontally for the remaining forty thousand (40,000) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>HZ or Horizontal districts. A "horizontal district" is established by swinging arcs of ten thousand (10,000) feet from the center of each end of the primary surface of each runway and connecting the adjacent arcs by lines tangent to those arcs. The horizontal district does not include the landing, instrument approach and transition districts. The surface of the horizontal district is a horizontal plane at an elevation of one hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation.</section><section prefix='(4)'>CN or Conical district. A "conical district" is established commencing at the periphery of the horizontal district and extending outward for a horizontal distance of four thousand (4,000) feet. The surface of the conical district commences at the elevation of the surface of the horizontal district and extends outward and upward at a slope of one (1) foot vertically to twenty (20) feet horizontally. Within the high structure set-aside district, the imaginary inclined Conical surface shall terminate in its intersection with any of the HSA districts as defined in Section 33-246 (6), subsections (a) through (e) hereinafter described under "high structure set-aside district." The HSA districts shall have precedence when they are in conflict or coincide with any of the conical surfaces.</section><section prefix='(5)'>DZ or Departure zone district. A "departure zone district" is hereby established adjacent to each instrument runway, and it is further established that each departure zone district shall embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath imaginary inclined surfaces which shall hereafter, for the purpose of this article, be referred to and described as departure zone surface 1 and departure zone surface 2 as depicted on the Airport Height Zoning Area Map for Miami International Airport as defined herein. The high structure set-aside district, which is hereinafter established and described, shall not be a part of and is hereby specifically excluded from the departure zone district.</section><section prefix='(6)'>HSA or High structure set-aside district. A "high structure set-aside district" is established which identifies an area where tall buildings and other structures may be permitted with limited impact on the capacity and operation of Miami International Airport. When in conflict with any other imaginary surface specified within this article, the herein defined HSA districts shall be the prevailing height limitation. The high structure set-aside district embraces and includes all of the land and water lying within an area in the City of Miami, Florida bounded by the following five (5) sub-districts as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>This district shall be known as the 1010-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 1010 feet AMSL. This district shall be bounded by an imaginary polygon connecting the following six (6) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #10 Latitude: 25° 46' 47.5296" Longitude: 80° 11' 37.7784"Then east to Point #16 Latitude: 25° 46' 49.646" Longitude: 80° 11' 6.9859"Then east to Point #9 Latitude: 25° 46' 50.2126" Longitude: 80° 10' 56.2165"Then southeast to Point #8 Latitude: 25° 46' 31.6176" Longitude: 80° 10' 47.7207"Then southwest to Point #7 Latitude: 25° 45' 21.8290" Longitude: 80° 11' 08.4645"Then northwest to Point #6 Latitude: 25° 45' 32.3210" Longitude: 80° 11' 38.2714"Then northeast to Point #17 Latitude: 25° 45' 42.3695" Longitude: 80° 11' 35.448" Then north back to the first point.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>This district shall be known as 709-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 709 feet AMSL. This district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of seven (7) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #12 Latitude: 25° 47' 10.4625" Longitude: 80° 11'38.7278"Then easterly to Point #18 Latitude: 25° 47' 09.0115" Longitude: 80° 11' 24.5157"Then Northeast to Point #23 Latitude: 25° 47' 10.2132" Longitude: 80° 11' 19.4348"Then northeast to Point #19 Latitude: 25° 47' 13.4815" Longitude: 80° 11' 11.6725"Then east to Point #14 Latitude: 25° 47' 14.1187" Longitude: 80° 11 07.1561"Then south to Point #16 Latitude: 25° 46' 49.646" Longitude: 80° 11' 06.9859"Then west to Point #10 Latitude: 25° 46' 47.5296" Longitude: 80° 11' 37.7784"Then north back to the first point.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>This district shall be known as the 649-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 649 feet AMSL. This district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of eleven (11) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #11 Latitude: 25° 48' 41.4522" Longitude: 80° 11' 43.1295"Then east to Point #22 Latitude: 25° 48' 40.8496" Longitude: 80° 11' 15.5784"Then northeast to Point #24 Latitude: 25° 48' 41.4146" Longitude: 80° 11' 08.9165"Then northeast to Point #15 Latitude: 25° 48' 41.0436" Longitude: 80° 11' 07.1879"Then south to Point #14 Latitude: 25° 47' 14.1187" Longitude: 80° 11' 07.1561"Then west to Point #19 Latitude: 25° 47' 13.4815" Longitude: 80° 11' 11.6725"Then Northeast to Point #23 Latitude: 25° 47' 10.2132" Longitude: 80° 11' 19.4348"Then southwest to Point #18 Latitude: 25° 47' 09.0115" Longitude: 80° 11' 24.5157"Then west to Point #12 Latitude: 25° 47' 10.4625" Longitude: 80° 11' 38.7278"Then north to Point #20 Latitude: 25° 47' 17.2495" Longitude: 80° 11' 39.0561"Then northwest to Point #21 Latitude: 25° 47' 18.5731" Longitude: 80° 11' 40.7420"Then north back to the first point.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>This district shall be known as the High Set-Aside Transitional District. Boundary end shall vary in its slope depending on the allowable heights that are adjacent to this district as set forth in this article. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 310 feet AMSL along some portions of the western boundary and increase to a maximum allowable height of 1010 feet AMSL along those areas that are adjacent to the 1010-foot boundary.<section>This district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of eleven (11) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:</section><section>Northwestern most corner: Point #1 Latitude: 25° 47' 37.6803" Longitude: 80° 12' 18.9273"Then east to Point #13 Latitude: 25° 47' 38.5695" Longitude: 80° 11' 41.318"Then south to Point #21 Latitude: 25° 47' 18.5731" Longitude: 80° 11' 40.7420"Then southeast to Point #20 Latitude: 25° 47' 17.2495" Longitude: 80° 11' 39.0561"Then south to Point #12 Latitude: 25° 47' 10.4625" Longitude: 80° 11' 38.7278"Then south to Point #10 Latitude: 25° 46' 47.5296" Longitude: 80° 11' 37.7784"Then south to Point #17 Latitude: 25° 45' 42.3695" Longitude: 80° 11' 35.448"Then southeast to Point # Latitude: 25° 45' 32.3210" Longitude: 80° 11' 38.2714"Then northwest to Point #5 Latitude: 25° 45' 43.2122" Longitude: 80° 11' 59.4724"Then north to Point #32 Latitude: 25° 46' 46.9187" Longitude: 80° 12' 01.4771"Then north to Point #2 Latitude: 25° 47' 02.6758" Longitude: 80° 12' 01.9730"Then back to the first point of this district.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>This district shall be known as 310-foot AMSL boundary district. It shall have a maximum allowable height of 310 feet AMSL. This district shall be bounded by an imaginary line connecting the following polygon consisting of twelve (12) NAD 83 Latitude and Longitude coordinates starting with the Northwest corner traversing in a clockwise manner and overlies all the land and water area bounded as follows:<section>Northwestern most corner: Point #3 Latitude: 25° 47′ 41.6854″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 40.3263″Then east to Point #25 Latitude: 25° 47′ 33.8427″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 17.0685″Then south to Point #2 Latitude: 25° 47′ 02.6758″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 01.9730″Then south to Point #32 Latitude: 25° 46′ 46.9187″ Longitude: 80° 12′ 01.4771″Then south to Point #5 Latitude: 25° 45′ 43.2122″ Longitude: 80° 11′ 59.4724″Then northwest to Point #4 Latitude: 25° 46′ 18.54″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 50.8037″Then northwest to Point #26 Latitude: 25° 46′ 31.8645″ Longitude: 80° 14′ 15.3849″Then northeast to Point #27 Latitude: 25° 46′ 29.9925″ Longitude: 80° 14′ 04.5838″Then north to Point #28 Latitude: 25° 46′ 53.1392″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 15.1815″Then northwest to Point #29 Latitude: 25° 46′ 55.9420″ Longitude: 80° 14′ 5.6983″Then northeast to Point #30 Latitude: 25° 46′ 56.6371″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 54.8079″Then north to Point #31 Latitude: 25° 47′ 19.8838″ Longitude: 80° 13′ 55.9731″Then back to the first point of this district.</section></section></section><section prefix='(7)'>TR or Transition districts. "Transition districts" are hereby established adjacent to each landing and each instrument approach district.<section>Transition districts adjacent to landing districts embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath an imaginary inclined surface symmetrically located on each side of such landing districts. For instrument runways such imaginary inclined surfaces extend outward and upward at right angles to the runway centerline and the runway centerline extended at a slope of one (1) foot vertically to seven (7) feet horizontally from the sides of the primary surface and from the side of the approach surface.</section><section>Transition districts adjacent to instrument approach districts embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath imaginary inclined surfaces which extend outward and upward from the long sides of the instrument approach surfaces as hereinbefore described, with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to seven (7) feet horizontally.</section><section>Within horizontal districts, this imaginary inclined transition surface shall terminate when it reaches an elevation of one hundred sixty (160) feet AMSL. Within conical districts, the imaginary inclined transition surface shall terminate in its intersection with the conical surface as hereinbefore described under "conical district." Within the departure zone district, the imaginary inclined transition surface shall terminate in its intersection with the departure zone surface hereinbefore described under "departure zone district." Within the high structure set-aside district, the imaginary inclined transition surface shall terminate in its intersection with any of the HSA districts as defined in subsection (6)(a) through (e) of this article hereinbefore described under "high structure set-aside district." The HSA districts shall have precedence when they are in conflict or coincide with any of the transitional surfaces.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>NA or Non-instrument approach districts. A "non-instrument approach district" is established for each end of each non-instrument runway for non-instrument landings and take-offs and it is further established that each such non-instrument approach district shall embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath an imaginary inclined surface which shall hereafter, for the purposes of this article, be referred to and described as the non-instrument approach surface.<section>The non-instrument approach surface shall begin, and shall have a base five hundred (500) feet wide, at a distance of two hundred (200) feet beyond the end of the runway, widening thereafter uniformly to a width of three thousand five hundred (3,500) feet at a horizontal distance of ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet beyond the end of the runway, the centerline of this surface being the continuation of the centerline of the runway.</section><section>The non-instrument approach surface shall extend outward and upward from its five hundred-foot-wide base, the elevation of which is base is ten (10) feet AMSL.</section><section>For Runways 8L and 26R, the approach surface shall slope upward one (1) foot vertically to thirty-four (34) feet horizontally for its entire length.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Criteria included in the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Plan shall be utilized in the review of land use and zoning modifications which are requested in the hereinbefore established airport zoning area.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-92, § 12, 7-10-07)</history></law>