<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='3'>ARTICLE XL. KENDALL TAMIAMI EXECUTIVE AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-395</section_number>
<catch_line>Land use zoning classifications for airports.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004598</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-395. Land use zoning classifications for airports.<section prefix='(A)'>Except as otherwise provided in this article, limitations on development of land, structures, and utilization of land within areas designated herein as being restricted due to non-compatibility with aircraft operations are in effect. In situations where land is beneath more than one land use classification the most restrictive shall apply. Restrictions to insure land use compatibility around Kendall-Tamiami Executive Airport are hereby established as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Inner District (ILZ). New residential construction and educational facilities, excluding aviation, are not permitted within this land use classification.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Outer District (OLZ). New residential construction and educational facilities excluding aviation, within this land use classification are required to incorporate at least a 25 db Noise Level Reduction (NLR) into the design/construction of the structure.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No School Zone (NSZ). New educational facilities, excluding aviation schools, are not permitted within this land use classification.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Inner Safety Zone (ISZ). New residential construction, educational facilities (excluding aviation schools), churches and places of public assembly are not permitted within this land use classification.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Outer Safety Zone (OSZ). Residential units are limited to less than two per acre. Educational facilities (excluding aviation schools) and places of public assembly are not permitted.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Except as otherwise provided in this article, it shall be unlawful to put any land or water located within L, T, and NA Districts and within TR Districts adjoining L and NA Districts and within the inner ten thousand (10,000) feet of IA Districts and the adjoining portions of TR Districts to any of the following prohibited uses:<section><section prefix='(1)'>Establishments or uses that emit smoke, gases, or dust in quantities or densities sufficient to jeopardize the safe use of the airport.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article, no use may be made of land or water within the airport zoning area in such a manner as to create electrical interference with radio communications between the airport and aircraft; make it difficult for aircraft pilots and tower control operators to distinguish between airport lights, aircraft and others; result in glare in the eyes of aircraft pilots using the airport, or tower control operators; impair visibility in the vicinity of the airport; or otherwise endanger the landing, taking off or maneuvering of aircraft.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Neither residential construction nor any educational facility as defined in Chapter 235, Florida Statutes, and the Code of Miami-Dade County, with the exception of aviation school facilities, shall be permitted within an area contiguous to the airport measuring one-half the length of the longest runway on either side of and at the end of each runway centerline.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Nothing contained herein shall be construed to require the removal, alteration, sound conditioning, or other change, or to interfere with the continued use or adjacent expansion of any educational structure or site in existence on July 1, 1993, or be construed to prohibit the construction of any new structure for which a site has been determined as provided in Section 235.19, Florida Statues, as of July 1, 1993.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Land fills and associated uses that emit smoke, gases, dust or attract birds shall not be permitted within 10,000 feet of any runway.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-40, ยง 8, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 99-118, ยง 1, 9-21-99)</history></law>