<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00073' order_by='00073' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVIII. OPA LOCKA AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-359</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of airport zoning area for Opa Locka Airport.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004560</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-359. Establishment of airport zoning area for Opa Locka Airport.<section>For the purpose of this article there is hereby created and established the airport zoning area for Opa Locka Airport and it is hereby ordained that such area shall include, and that the provisions of this article shall be applicable to and embrace all of the unincorporated and the incorporated land and water area lying, situate and being in those certain portions of Miami-Dade County, Florida, described as follows, to wit:<section prefix='(1)'>In Township 52 South, Range 39 East, all of Sections 10 to 15, inclusive; 22 to 27, inclusive; 34 to 36, inclusive, and the east one-half (½) of Sections 9, 16, 21, 28 and 33.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In Township 53 South, Range 39 East, all of Sections 1 to 3, inclusive, and the east one-half (½) of Section 4.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In Township 52 South, Range 40 East, all of Sections 1 to 3, inclusive, and all of Sections 7 to 36 inclusive.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In Township 53 South, Range 40 East, all of Sections 1 to 6, inclusive, and the north one-half (½) of the north one-half (½) of Section 12</section><section prefix='(5)'>In Township 51 South, Range 41 East, all of Sections 31 to 33, inclusive.</section><section prefix='(6)'>All of Township 52 South, Range 41 East.</section><section prefix='(7)'>In Township 53 South, Range 41 East, all of Sections 3 to 6, inclusive, and the north one-half (½) of the north one-half (½) of Sections 7 and 8.</section><section prefix='(8)'>All of Township 52 South, Range 42 East.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-37, § 4, 7-9-69)</history></law>