<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00073' order_by='00073' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVIII. OPA LOCKA AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-364</section_number>
<catch_line>Nonconforming uses, regulations not retroactive.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004567</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-364. Nonconforming uses, regulations not retroactive.<section>The regulations prescribed by this article or any amendment thereto shall not be construed to require the removal, lowering, or other change or alteration of any structure or tree or use of land lawfully in existence not conforming to the regulations as of the effective date hereof, or otherwise interfere with the continuance of any nonconforming use. After effective date hereof, property owners shall not be permitted to grow or maintain trees to heights in excess of those provided herein. Nothing herein contained shall require any change in the construction, alteration, or intended use of any structure, the construction or alteration of which was lawfully begun prior to the effective date of this article, and is diligently prosecuted and completed within the time limit as prescribed by the South Florida Building Code. Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this article, the owner of any such nonconforming structure or tree is hereby required to permit the installation, operation and maintenance thereon of such marking, or marking and lighting, as shall be deemed necessary by the Director of the Miami-Dade County Port Authority, to indicate to the operators of aircraft in the vicinity of the airport the presence of such airport hazard. Such marking, or marking and lighting, and the installation, operation and maintenance thereof, or such disposition of the hazard as may be agreed upon by and between the owner and the Director of the Miami-Dade County Port Authority in lieu of such marking, or marking and lighting, shall be at the expense of the Miami-Dade County Port Authority.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-37, ยง 9, 7-9-69)</history></law>