<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-337.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted on Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field) lands in the GP Governmental Property zoning district.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004540</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-337.1. Uses permitted on Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field) lands in the GP Governmental Property zoning district.<section>The Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) provides for aviation, aviation-related and non-aviation uses at Miami International Airport-Wilcox Field (MIA). The purpose of this section of the Code is to provide for non-aviation uses on those lands at MIA that are in the GP Governmental Property zoning district, provided that such uses comply with the requirements of the CDMP's Aviation Subelement, are compatible with and not disruptive of airport operations occurring on such lands, and comply with all applicable regulations of the Federal Aviation Administration and other applicable law.</section><section>The portion of the airport designated in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for non-aviation uses may be developed at a maximum FAR of 2.0 (excluding parking structures). All non-aviation uses shall be subject to the site plan review standards of of this Code.<section prefix='(1)'>Subject to the restrictions contained herein, the following non-aviation uses may be approved in the non-aviation areas of the airport:<section prefix='(a)'>Lodgings such as hotels and motels (except in terminal concourses), subject to the standards of the BU-2 district.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Office buildings (except in terminal concourses), subject to the standards of the BU-2 district.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Industrial uses such as distribution, storage, manufacturing, research and development, and machine shops, subject to the site development standards of the IU-1 zoning district.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Agricultural uses, subject to the standards of the AU district.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Retail, restaurants, and personal service establishments, subject to the standards of the BU-2 district.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>MIA area requirements for non-aviation use lands designated GP in this subsection of the Code. The minimum and maximum of land area devoted to particular non-aviation uses for those parcels designated as "non-aviation use" in Figure 1 shall be as follows:</section></section><section>NON-AVIATION AREA (±56.7 ACRES)</section><section></section><section></section><section><section prefix='(3)'>The Director of the Miami-Dade Aviation Department shall monitor the allocation of non-aviation uses in all areas of MIA lands zoned GP in order to maintain compliance with the Aviation Subelement of the CDMP.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-56, § 1, 7-3-12)</history></law>