<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-335</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of height limitations for zone classification districts in the airport zoning area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004537</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-335. Establishment of height limitations for zone classification districts in the airport zoning area.<section>Except as otherwise provided elsewhere in this article, no structure shall be erected or altered and no tree shall be allowed to grow or be maintained in any district created and established by this article to a height in excess of the height limits herein established for such district, as established by the Airport Height Zoning Area Map for Miami International Airport defined in this section. Such height limitations will, in applying the provisions of this article, be corrected to elevations referred to the heretofore established mean sea level datum plane, by adding such height limitations to the mean sea level elevation of the point, line or plane to which such height limitation is referenced, or to the airport elevation, as the context of this article requires. An area, a structure or a tree located in more than one (1) of the described districts is considered to be only in the district with the more restrictive height limitation.</section><section>The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts, approves and ratifies the map entitled "Airport Height Zoning Area Map for Miami International Airport" as prepared by the Miami-Dade Aviation Department, dated August 26, 2003, reflecting the above-defined height limitations, which is on file in the Office of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning. Such map shall be the official height zoning map for the Miami International Airport, shall establish the maximum height of the structures and shall be applicable to and controlling of such height limitations established herein.</section><section>Such limitations are hereby established for the districts as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For Runways 8R, 26L, 12 and 30: One (1) foot vertically for each sixty-five (65) feet horizontally beginning at a point two hundred (200) feet from the end of each instrument runway and extending for a distance of ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet from the end of each runway; thence one (1) foot vertically for each forty (40) feet horizontally for a distance of forty thousand (40,000) feet to a point fifty thousand two hundred (50,200) feet from the end of each runway.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For Runways 9 and 27, one (1) foot vertically for each fifty (50) feet horizontally beginning at a point two hundred (200) feet from the end of these instrument runways and extending for a distance of ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet from the end of each runway; thence one (1) foot vertically for each forty (40) feet horizontally for a distance of forty thousand (40,000) feet to a point fifty thousand two hundred (50,200) feet from the end of each runway.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Horizontal district: One hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Conical district: One (1) foot vertically to twenty (20) feet horizontally beginning at the periphery of the hereinbefore described horizontal surface for a horizontal distance of four thousand (4,000) feet.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Departure zone district: For departure zone surface 1, one (1) foot vertically to forty (40) feet horizontally beginning at the departure end of each runway at an elevation of forty-five (45) feet MSL and extending outward a distance of two (2) nautical miles (12,152 feet) from the end of the runway. For departure zone surface 2, one (1) foot vertically to forty (40) feet horizontally beginning at the edge of each runway and the edge of the departure zone surface 1, and at an elevation of three hundred forty-nine (349) feet MSL, which is the elevation at the high end of the departure zone 1 surface, then extending until an elevation of one thousand five hundred ten (1,510) feet MSL is reached. The one thousand five hundred ten-foot elevation continues outward from the airport as a horizontal plane to the boundaries of the airport zoning area. The height restrictions in the departure zone district do not apply within the high structure set-aside district.</section><section prefix='(6)'>High structure set-aside district: For the 949-foot level surface, nine hundred forty-nine (949) feet MSL; for the 660-foot shelf, six hundred sixty (660) feet MSL; for the 710 foot shelf, seven hundred ten (710) feet MSL; for the west climb gradient surface, one (1) foot vertically to thirty and eight hundredths (30.08) feet horizontally beginning at the westerly edge of the 949-foot level surface down to the hereinbefore described westerly boundary of the high structure set-aside district; for southeast climb gradient surface, one (1) foot vertically to twenty-four and three-tenths (24.3) feet horizontally beginning at an elevation of eight hundred forty (840) feet MSL at the easterly boundary of the 710-foot shelf up to the easterly boundary of the high structure set-aside district; and for the transition surfaces, one (1) foot vertically to seven (7) feet horizontally as a continuation of the transition surfaces described hereinbefore under transition district, beginning at the northerly boundaries of the 660 shelf, the 710 shelf and the southeast climb gradient, and the northerly boundary of the high structure set-aside district and extending up to the 949-foot level surface or the west climb gradient surface.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Transition district: One (1) foot vertically for each seven (7) feet horizontally from the sides of the primary surfaces and from the sides of the approach surfaces. Transition surfaces from the primary surfaces to the horizontal surface, and from the approach surfaces to the adjacent horizontal surface, conical surface or departure zone surface. Within the high structure set-aside district, the transitional surfaces extend from the adjacent departure zone surface on the north to the 949-foot level surface and to the west climb gradient surface; and from the northerly boundaries of the 660-foot shelf, the 710-foot shelf and the southeast climb gradient to the 949-foot level surface and to the west climb gradient surface.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Non-Instrument approach districts:<section prefix='(a)'>For Runways 8L and 26R, the non-instrument approach surface shall extend outward and upward from its base, the elevation of which shall be the same as that of the runway end adjacent thereto, with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to thirty-four (34) feet horizontally for its entire length.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-39, § 6, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 78-78, § 1, 11-7-78; Ord. No. 86-83, § 1, 10-28-86; Ord. No. 99-65, § 1, 6-8-99; Ord. No. 04-203, § 6, 11-30-04)</history></law>