<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-30</section_number>
<catch_line>Telephone booths, public.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003923</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-30. Telephone booths, public.<section prefix='(a)'>Residential and agricultural districts. In all residential, agricultural and GU Interim Districts, temporary permits may be issued for the installation of public telephone booths for a one-year period of time subject to an extension of time for justifiable reason. Such permits shall be subject to cancellation when, in the opinion of the Director, sufficient telephone service has been brought into the area, or when the use creates a traffic hazard or a nuisance.</section><section>Certificates of use and occupancy must be secured for each public telephone booth erected. The application for said certificate must be accompanied by a location sketch, and with written approval of property owners in the form of a waiver of objection from the abutting property owners within one hundred fifty (150) feet on each side of the location site, and from the corresponding, abutting property owner on the opposite side of the street from the site location in question. A fee, as provided by Administrative Order No. 4-40, as amended from time to time, shall be paid for each certificate issued.</section><section>Location of the booth must be approved by the Director, and if a right-of-way is concerned, must be approved by the Director of Public Works.</section><section>Each booth shall be properly fastened to the ground so that it shall not become a wind hazard.</section><section>All booths shall be properly maintained and painted so that they shall not become unsightly or an eyesore.</section><section>The conventional type of strip telephone signs will be permitted providing they are placed on the booth in the usual and conventional manner. Signs shall not be erected independent of the booth structure.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Business and industrial districts. In all commercial and industrial districts, the booths shall be permitted on a permanent basis so long as they do not constitute a traffic hazard or a nuisance.</section><section>Certificates of use and occupancy must be secured for each booth erected; the application for said certificate must be accompanied by a local sketch. A fee, as provided by Administrative Order No. 4-40, as amended from time to time, shall be paid for each certificate issued.</section><section>The booth must be erected on private property, conform to regular setback requirements and the location must be approved by the Director.</section><section>Construction and maintenance requirements shall be the same as for the residential areas.</section><section>In addition to the usual booth signs, the standard public telephone plaque signs shall be permitted. The location of signs shall meet the approval of the Director.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 5(AA), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 78-52, ยง 2, 7-18-78)</history></law>