<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00073' order_by='00073' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVIII. OPA LOCKA AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-366</section_number>
<catch_line>Permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004569</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-366. Permits.<section>Applications for permits under this article shall be obtained from the appropriate Building and Zoning Department or agency.</section><section>Applications for permits for all construction, for adding height to any existing structures, and for all alterations, repairs, or additions that will change the use of the structure from the existing use to any commercial or industrial use in any airport zone classification district lying within unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, shall be obtained from the Director and from the Building Department.</section><section>All applications for permits made to appropriate municipal Building and Zoning Departments or agencies for all construction or for adding height to any existing structure, and for all alterations, repairs, or additions that will change the use of structure from the existing use to any commercial or industrial use in any airport zone classification district lying within a municipality for which airport zone classification district boundaries have been established herein, shall be approved by the Director and the Building Official or by their duly authorized representatives prior to issuance of the permit by any municipal Building and Zoning Department or agency for the purpose of assuring compliance with the minimum standards governing zoning as set forth in this article; provided however, no approval by the Director and Building Official will be required for building and use permits from municipalities which have adopted by ordinance effective airport zoning regulations, the minimum standards of which are at least as restrictive as the minimum standards prescribed herein as such apply to the areas covered by this article; no approval by the Director and Building Official will be required for building and use permits from municipalities which have adopted by ordinance effective general zoning regulations, the minimum standards of which are at least as restrictive as the minimum standards prescribed herein as such apply to the areas covered by this ordinance; provided, however, that no municipality may grant any variance to said general zoning regulations which would make said minimum standards less restrictive than the minimum standards prescribed herein.</section><section>Permits will be approved by the Director and Building Official or their duly authorized representatives unless the proposal fails to meet the requirements of all applicable zoning regulations and building codes including the provisions of this article.</section><section>Permits, when issued to applicants intending to use derricks, draglines, cranes and other boom-equipped machinery for such construction, reconstruction or alteration as is consistent with the provisions hereof, shall when the boom operating height exceeds the height limitations imposed by this article, require applicant to mark, or mark and light, the highest point on the boom to reflect conformity with the Federal Aviation Administration's standards for marking and lighting obstructions, and in such cases the applicant shall notify the Director of the Miami-Dade County Port Authority at least twenty-four (24) hours prior to the time that such use is to begin.</section><section>Any decision of the Director may be appealed as provided and prescribed under Article XXXVI, of, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-37, ยง 11, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 21, 9-3-98)</history></law>