<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='3'>ARTICLE XL. KENDALL TAMIAMI EXECUTIVE AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-394</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of land use zoning criteria for airports.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004597</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-394. Establishment of land use zoning criteria for airports.<section>For the purpose of this article all of the land use zoning criteria for Kendall-Tamiami Executive Airport and the surrounding area, as the same is created, established and described hereinbefore, is hereby divided into classifications as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Inner District (ILZ). An ILZ covers an area measured as one-half the length of the longest runway at the airport on either side and at the end of each runway centerline at the airport.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Outer District (OLZ). The OLZ at an airport is based on VFR traffic pattern criteria and predominant type of aircraft utilizing the airport. For Kendall-Tamiami Executive Airport "Category A" is used due to the predominant type of aircraft having an approach speed less than 91 knots and aircraft weighing less than 30,001 pounds. The mathematical formula for determining the limits of the OLZ are found in Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) Advisory Circular 7400.2C.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No School Zone (NSZ). An NSZ for each runway covers an area that extends five statute miles from the end of a runway in a direct line along the centerline of the runway, and has a width measuring one-half the length of the longest runway at the airport.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Inner Safety Zone (ISZ). Also referred to as the Runway Protection Zone (RPZ). For Kendall-Tamiami Executive Airport the ISZ is defined as an area which is centered about the extended runway centerline and begins 200 feet beyond the end of the area usable for take-off or landing. The ISZ dimension for Runway 13/31 begins at a width of 500 feet and extends 1,000 feet to a width of 700 feet. The ISZ dimension for Runway 9R/27L and Runway 9L/27R begin at a width of 1,000 feet and extends 2,500 feet to a width of 1,750 feet.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Outer Safety Zone (OSZ). The OSZ is described as an area that extends outward from the ISZ to a point 5,000 feet from a runway end. The OSZ dimension for Runway 13/31 begins at a width of 700 feet and extends 3,800 feet to a width of 1,460 feet. The OSZ dimensions for Runway 9R/27L and Runway 9L/27R begin at a width of 1,750 feet and extend 2,300 feet to a width of 2,440 feet.</section></section><section>The drawing entitled "Airport Land Use Zoning Map for Kendall-Tamiami Executive Airport and Surrounding Area," as prepared by the Miami-Dade Aviation Department, dated September 13, 2001, reflecting the above defined classifications, which is on file in the Office of the Miami-Dade County Planning and Zoning Department, shall be the official land use zoning map for the Kendall-Tamiami Executive Airport, shall be prima facie evidence of the boundaries of the zones and districts dipicted thereon, and shall be applicable to and controlling of zoning for such zones and districts.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-118, ยง 1, 9-21-99; Ord. No. 02-169, ยง 1, 9-24-02)</history></law>