<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-330.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative intent, findings and purposes.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004532</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-330.1. Legislative intent, findings and purposes.<section>The Board of County Commissioners for Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares and finds that the uncoordinated use of lands within the County threatens the orderly development and the health, safety, order, convenience, prosperity and welfare of the present and future citizens of this County. Pursuant to Ordinance No. 75-22, the Board adopted and accepted the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) for Miami-Dade County whereby it specifically declared that it was the continuing policy of Miami-Dade County, in cooperation with federal, state, regional and local governments, and other concerned public and private organizations, to use all reasonable means and measures to:<section prefix='(a)'>foster and promote the general welfare;</section><section prefix='(b)'>to create and maintain conditions under which man and nature can exist in productive harmony; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>to fill the social, economic and other requirements of the present and future generations of citizens of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>The Board further finds that the CDMP was enacted to assure for all people of Miami-Dade County an attempt to create safe, healthful, productive and aesthetically and culturally pleasing surroundings; to attain the widest range of beneficial uses of the environment without unreasonable degradation, risk to the health or safety, or other undesirable and unintended consequences, to preserve important historic, cultural and natural aspects of our national heritage; to maintain, wherever possible, an environment which supports diversity and variety of individual choice; to achieve a balance between population and resources which will permit the high standards of living and a wide sharing of life's amenities, and to enhance the quality of renewal resources and approach the maximum attainable recycling of depletable resources.</section><section>Among the CDMP provisions designed to achieve these ends are goals, objectives and policies to ensure the provision of an economic, integrated environment and community sensitive and balanced system of air transportation, facilities and services; to maximize compatibility between airports and the surrounding communities; and to maximize aviation's support of local and regional economic growth. In furtherance of these goals, objectives and policies, the Board finds that the coordinated review and analysis of its airport facilities and surrounding communities is necessary to carry on a central metropolitan government in Miami-Dade County, Florida. Coordinated review and analysis of airport facilities and the surrounding communities' present and future land uses is susceptible to, and would be most effectively carried on, under a uniform plan of regulation applicable to the County as a whole. The planning of the efficient land use around the airport, combined with other plan implementation tools, can be effectively used in meeting social, economic and environmental needs and in creating a major influence on metropolitan development patterns and life styles. The capability of an efficient, safe airport system and associated industry and businesses, acting in conjunction with other urban services, including public and private educational facilities, to establish general development trends, is well recognized.</section><section>A maximum coordination of the airport system requirements and land use policy decisions is therefore essential to optimize the role of the airport system as a potent tool for implementing the desired patterns of metropolitan development in Miami-Dade County. To this end, height limitations for the high structure set-aside (HSA) height zoning district were developed in coordination with the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and the City of Miami. The height limitations for the HSA are at the maximums tolerable under the current state of aviation technology and should not be raised unless and until technological advances make greater height limits in the HSA both safe and feasible.</section><section>This Board further finds that the Legislature of the State of Florida has mandated the adoption of land use regulations by Miami-Dade County, as a political subdivision authorized to establish and operate airports within its territorial limits, to assure compatible land uses in the areas surrounding such airports. This Board acknowledges and adopts as its own those legislative findings in Chapter 333, Florida Statutes, that call for coordinated planning airports and coordinated land uses in proximity thereto.</section><section>Among the matters specifically required by Chapter 333, Florida Statutes, to be regulated are the siting and construction of public and private educational facilities in certain defined areas in proximity to airports. This Board hereby finds that public and private educational facilities for all of Miami-Dade's communities are an indispensable urban service, essential to achieving a high standard of living for Miami-Dade County's residents and to meeting critical social and economic needs. This Board further finds that meeting the escalating demand for such educational facilities in already developed or rapidly developing urban areas is expensive and difficult, due in part to dwindling supplies of available developable land. This Board further finds that where certain conditions and requirements are met, as prescribed by the zoning regulations contained herein, educational facilities can safely, effectively and economically be sited and constructed within defined areas in proximity to all of Miami-Dade County's airports, including Miami International Airport. This Board's adoption of the regulations contained herein reflect its balancing of the escalating need and demand for educational facilities to serve its residents, the health and safety concerns pertinent to allowing development in proximity to Miami International Airport, and the interest in maintaining and fostering business and industry associated with aviation in general and specifically with Miami International Airport.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-203, ยง 1, 11-30-04; Ord. No. 07-92, ยง 1, 7-10-07)</history></law>