<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-320</section_number>
<catch_line>Other building moratoria.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004525</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-320. Other building moratoria.<section prefix='(a)'>Should any person make written application to the County Manager for the issuance of an administrative order provided by Section 33-319(a), Miami-Dade County Code, and the County Manager refuses to issue such order, or fails to take action thereon within thirty (30) days, such person may make written application to the Board of County Commissioners for the issuance of a building moratorium by that Board. Such application to the Board shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, whose duty it shall be to placed the matter before the Board of County Commissioners as soon as is reasonably practicable for the Board's determination as to whether a public hearing shall be called thereon. The County Manager shall be notified by the Clerk of the date that the matter is to be considered by the Board. The word "person" as used in this subsection includes, but is not limited to, any individual, firm, corporation, and governmental entity, including the Planning Advisory Board, and the Community Zoning Appeals Board.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Should the Board determine that a public hearing should be held as to whether a building moratorium is appropriate, it shall call the same for the earliest practicable date and give reasonable notice thereof by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County. Pending the public hearing the Board may issue an order prohibiting the issuance of building permits in the affected area.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The procedure to be followed for this section, after the completion of the steps provided in Subsections (a) and (b) above, is that set forth in Section 33-319(e) through (i), Miami-Dade County Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 72-18, ยง 1, 3-14-72; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 21, 9-3-98)</history></law>