<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-35</section_number>
<catch_line>Nonconforming uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003928</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-35. Nonconforming uses.<section prefix='(a)'>A nonconforming use shall not be extended in any direction nor shall such use be replaced by another use not specifically permitted in the district concerned.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No building or premises wherein or whereon a nonconforming use is discontinued for a period of at least six (6) months, or is superseded by a use permitted under the provisions of this chapter in the district in which said building or premises are situated, shall again be devoted to any use prohibited by this chapter in the district.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any building which does not conform in use, occupancy or construction, or in some other way, with the provisions of this chapter (said structure, use of occupancy having existed prior to the adoption of these regulations) which becomes damaged as to roof and/or structure to an extent of fifty (50) percent or more of its reasonable market value at the time, by fire, flood, explosion, wind, war, riot or any other act of God or man, shall not be reconstructed or used or occupied as before said damage, but, if damage to an extent of less than fifty (50) percent of the reasonable market value at the time of the damage, the building may be reconstructed or used as before, provided such reconstruction is completed or such use is started within six (6) months of the date of such damage.</section><section prefix='(d)'>When a nonconforming building is vacated, the Director may attach, or have attached, a notice to the effect that new occupancy shall require conformance to this chapter, but the absence of such notice shall not relieve the owner of full compliance with this chapter.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Where any premises, whereon a building containing a nonconforming use is located, is partially acquired by an official public body for a public purpose, the use shall be permitted to continue on remaining portion of the premises under the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>Where part of the structure is taken, an amount equal to that portion required may be added to the remaining structure.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the entire structure is acquired, a new structure may be erected on the remaining portion of the premises, if such premises conform to the requirements of this chapter, providing said new structure does not exceed in size the original structure that was taken.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If such existing structure does not warrant remodeling or relocating, then a new structure may be erected on the remaining portion of the premises, providing the same does not exceed in size the original structure and providing that the new structure can be erected on the site in accordance with applicable zoning regulations.</section><section prefix='(4)'>If the existing structure is such that it can be relocated on the portion of premises remaining, then the same can be relocated providing it complies with applicable zoning and building regulations.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Where a new structure is erected for several uses and it is desired to reestablish a nonconforming use, the same shall be permitted providing the area to be devoted to the nonconforming use shall not exceed the original area devoted to the nonconforming use.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>In the event a nonconforming use is created by resolution pursuant to an application filed by the Director, an application requesting a nonuse variance or special exception pursuant to Section 33-304 of the Code which furthers the original purpose and intent of the nonconforming use may be filed at no fee to the applicant. The application filed under this subsection must be filed within twelve (12) months of the date the zoning resolution is transmitted to the Clerk of the Commission and shall only apply to those nonuse variances and special exceptions which are necessitated by a change of zoning and that would not have been required under the prior zoning district.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 35, 10-22-57; Ord. No. 79-54, ยง 1, 7-3-79; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>