<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00074' order_by='00074' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIX. HOMESTEAD GENERAL AVIATION AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-377</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of height limitations for zone classification districts in the airport zoning area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004580</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-377. Establishment of height limitations for zone classification districts in the airport zoning area.<section>Except as otherwise provided elsewhere in this article, no structure shall be erected or altered and no tree shall be allowed to grow or be maintained in any district created and established by this article to a height in excess of the height limits herein established for such district. Such height limitations will, in applying the provisions of this article, be corrected to elevations referred to the heretofore established mean sea level datum plane, by adding such height limitations to the mean sea level elevation of the point, line or plane to which such height limitation is referenced, or to the airport elevation, as the context of this article requires. Such limitations are hereby established for the districts as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Landing districts: Structures and trees will not be permitted in landing districts except as required, necessary and pertinent to the operation and maintenance of Homestead General Aviation Airport and then only to the extent permitted or authorized by applicable rule or regulation promulgated by the Federal Aviation Administration, or its successor counterpart.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Instrument approach districts: One (1) foot in height for each fifty (50) feet in horizontal distance beginning at a point two hundred (200) feet from the end of the instrument runway and extending to a distance of ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet from the end of the runway; thence one (1) foot in height for each forty (40) feet in horizontal distance to a point fifty thousand two hundred (50,200) feet from the end of the runway.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Non-instrument approach districts: One (1) foot in height for each forty (40) feet in horizontal distance beginning at a point two hundred (200) feet from the end of the non-instrument runway and extending to a point ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet from the end of the runway.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Transition districts: One (1) foot in height for each seven (7) feet in horizontal distance beginning at a point two hundred fifty (250) feet from the centerline of non-instrument runways and five hundred (500) feet from the centerline of instrument runways, measured at right angles to the longitudinal centerline of the runway and extending upward to a maximum height of one hundred fifty (150) feet above the airport elevation as established elsewhere herein.<section>In addition to the foregoing, there are established height limits of one (1) foot vertical height for each seven (7) feet horizontal distance measured from the edges of all instrument approach surfaces and non-instrument approach surfaces upward and outward to an intersection with the hereinbefore described horizontal and conical surfaces. Further, where the instrument approach surface projects beyond, or through and beyond the conical surface, the height limit of one (1) foot for each seven (7) feet of horizontal distance shall be maintained, beginning at the edge of the instrument approach surface and extending a distance of five thousand (5,000) feet from the edge of the instrument approach surface, such five thousand (5,000) feet being measured horizontally and at right angles to the continuation of the centerline of the runway.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Horizontal district: One hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Conical district: One (1) foot in height for each twenty (20) feet of horizontal distance beginning at the periphery of the hereinbefore described horizontal surface and measured in a vertical plane passing through the airport reference point.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Non-zoned districts: The height limitations as well as land use requirement in non-zoned districts, shall, for the purposes of this article, be identical with requirements as set forth in Chapter 33 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or, as the same may be set forth in the general zoning ordinances of the various municipalities where the property is located within a municipality.</section></section><section>Where the hereinbefore described imaginary inclined or horizontal surfaces for one (1) district overlap, merge, or intersect with those of any other district, the imaginary inclined or horizontal surface that prescribes the most restrictive height limitation shall obtain and shall govern.</section><section>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article to the contrary, the height limits prescribed by this article shall not establish for any particular parcel of privately owned land at any particular point within such a parcel, a height limit of less than thirty-eight and five-tenths (38.5) feet above the mean sea level at that point.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-38, ยง 6, 7-9-69)</history></law>