<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='3'>ARTICLE XL. KENDALL TAMIAMI EXECUTIVE AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-396.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Uses permitted on Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport lands in the GP Governmental Property zoning district.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004600</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-396.1 Uses permitted on Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport lands in the GP Governmental Property zoning district.<section>The following public airport uses shall be permitted on those lands at Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport zoning area that are in the GP Governmental Property zoning district, provided that such uses comply with the requirements of the Future Aviation Facilities Section of the Aviation Subelement, are compatible with and not disruptive of airport operations occurring on such lands, and comply with all applicable regulations of the Federal Aviation Administration and other applicable law.<section prefix='(A)'>Aviation Uses: The portion of the airport designated in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) for aviation uses, shall be deemed to consist of all portions of the airport where general public access is restricted (but not including terminal concourses).<section prefix='(1)'>Areas designated for aviation uses shall be limited to aviation uses, including, but not limited to:<section prefix='a)'>Airfield uses such as runways, taxiways, aprons, runway protection zones, safety areas, landing areas, and support and maintenance facilities such as control towers, flight service stations, access roads, fire stations, storage and aircraft maintenance and repair facilities and hangars,</section><section prefix='b)'>Aircraft and aircraft parts manufacturing and storage,</section><section prefix='c)'>Fixed base operators,</section><section prefix='d)'>Air cargo operations,</section><section prefix='e)'>Specialized aircraft service operations,</section><section prefix='f)'>Fuel farms,</section><section prefix='g)'>Where not otherwise prohibited by law, open space and interim or existing agricultural uses and zoning may also be permitted in the portions of the airport designated for aviation use, subject to such conditions and requirements as may be imposed to ensure public health and safety.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Aviation-Related and Non-Aviation Uses: The portion of the airport designated in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for aviation-related and non-aviation uses, shall be deemed to consist of all portions of the airport where general public access is not restricted, and may be developed with aviation uses (aviation facilities), aviation-related uses and non-aviation uses that are compatible with airport operations and consistent with applicable law.<section prefix='(1)'>Aviation-related uses:<section prefix='a)'>Facilities where general public access is allowed may include existing uses and the following or substantially similar uses:<section prefix='(1)'>Fixed Base Operator's lounge areas for aviation passenger traffic, including private or corporate aircraft passenger traffic, which may include non-aviation uses designated to serve the traveling public and on-site employees, such as offices, personal services, retail activities, restaurants, auto rental businesses, and lodging establishments,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Parking garages and lots serving the airport,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Access roadways serving the airport,</section><section prefix='(4)'>Offices of aviation industry companies and the Miami-Dade Aviation Department,</section><section prefix='(5)'>Hangar rentals and tie-downs,</section><section prefix='(6)'>Ground transportation services,</section><section prefix='(7)'>General aviation aircraft, such as private and corporate jets or other aircraft, and automobile rental establishments,</section><section prefix='(8)'>Aviation-related educational uses such as flight schools, simulator training facilities, helicopter and aerobatics training and other educational facilities providing aviation courses,</section><section prefix='(9)'>Aviation-related governmental agency facilities,</section><section prefix='(10)'>Flying club facilities,</section><section prefix='(11)'>Aviation-related entertainment uses such as museums and sightseeing services,</section><section prefix='(12)'>Aviation-related retail uses such as general aviation aircraft sales, electronic and instrument sales and pilot stores,</section><section prefix='(13)'>Storage and aircraft maintenance and repair facilities and hangars,</section><section prefix='(14)'>Aircraft and aircraft parts manufacturing and storage,</section><section prefix='(15)'>Air cargo operations, and</section><section prefix='(16)'>Specialized aircraft service operations.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Non-aviation uses:<section prefix='a)'>Subject to the restrictions contained herein, the following non-aviation uses may be approved in the aviation-related and non-aviation areas of the airport:<section prefix='(1)'>Lodgings such as hotels and motels,</section><section prefix='(2)'>Office buildings,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Industrial uses such as distribution, storage, manufacturing research and development and machine shops,</section><section prefix='(4)'>Agricultural uses, and</section><section prefix='(5)'>Retail, restaurants, and personal service establishments.</section></section><section prefix='b)'>Such non-aviation uses shall be limited as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>The distribution, range, intensity and types of such non-aviation uses shall vary by location as a function of the availability of public services, height restrictions, Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) intensity ceiling for the Urbanizing Area (FAR of 1.25 not counting parking structures), impact on roadways, access and compatibility with neighboring development.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Freestanding retail uses and shopping centers shall front on major access roads preferably near major intersections, where practical, and have limited access to major roadways.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Each non-aviation use shall comply with applicable law, including, but not limited to, FAA regulations and the current airport layout plan on file with the Miami-Dade County Aviation Department governing permissible uses on the entire airport property.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Warehouses, storage showrooms, printing shops and any other industrial use shall be subject to the site development standards of the IU-1 zoning district. Office buildings, retail sales, hotels and motels, restaurants, personal service establishments, and any other similar uses shall be subject to the standards of the BU-2 district.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All development shall comply with the off-street parking regulations of Chapter 33 and with Chapter 18A (Landscaping) of this code. All non-aviation uses shall be subject to the site plan review standards of Section 33-396.2 of this code.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The development of the 8.2 acre (973.52 ft × 363 ft) parcel for non-aviation uses at the southwest corner of SW 137 Avenue and theoretical SW 124 Street shall be limited to access roads, open space, parking and drainage facilities.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The minimum and maximum land area devoted to non-aviation uses shall be limited as follows:</section></section></section></section></section><section>Non-Aviation Uses Area(±43 Acres)<section prefix='(C)'>Airport Area Map: The following map depicts the airport's areas where aviation, aviation-related and non-aviation uses are permitted in accordance with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section></section><section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-66, § 1, 8-2-11)</history></law>