<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='3'>ARTICLE XL. KENDALL TAMIAMI EXECUTIVE AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-392</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of zone classification districts for airport zoning area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004595</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-392. Establishment of zone classification districts for airport zoning area.<section>For the purpose of this article all of the Airport Zoning Area for Kendall Tamiami Executive Airport, as the same is created, established and described hereinbefore, is hereby divided into zone classification districts as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>L or Landing districts (Primary Surfaces). A "landing district" is established for each instrument runway for instrument landings and take-offs and for each non-instrument runway for non-instrument landings and take-offs.<section>A landing district for an instrument runway shall have a uniform width of one thousand (1,000) feet, shall extend for the full length of such instrument runway plus a distance of two hundred (200) feet beyond each end thereof and shall include such runway and be symmetrical about the centerline thereof.</section><section>A landing district for non-instrument runway shall have a uniform width of five hundred (500) feet, shall extend for the full length of such non-instrument runway plus a distance of two hundred (200) feet beyond each end thereof and shall include such runway and be symmetrical about the centerline thereof.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>IA or Instrument approach districts. An "instrument approach district" is established for each end of each instrument runway for instrument landings and take-offs and it is further established that each such instrument approach district shall embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath an imaginary inclined surface which shall hereafter, for the purposes of this article, be referred to and described as the instrument approach surface.<section>The instrument approach surface shall begin, and shall have a base one thousand (1,000) feet wide, at a distance of two hundred (200) feet beyond the end of the runway, widening thereafter uniformly to a width of sixteen thousand (16,000) feet at a horizontal distance of fifty thousand two hundred (50,200) feet beyond the end of the runway, the centerline of this surface being the continuation of the centerline of the runway. The instrument approach surface shall extend outward and upward from its base, the elevation of which shall be the same as that of the runway end adjacent thereto, with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to fifty (50) feet horizontally for the first ten thousand (10,000) feet of its length and thence with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to forty (40) feet horizontally for the remainder.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>NA or Non-instrument approach districts. A "non-instrument approach district" is established for each end of each non-instrument runway for non-instrument landings and take-offs and it is further established that each such non-instrument approach district shall embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath an imaginary inclined surface which shall hereafter, for the purposes of this article be referred to and described as the non-instrument approach surface.<section>The non-instrument approach surface shall begin, and shall have a base five hundred (500) feet wide, at a distance of two hundred (200) feet beyond the end of the runway, widening thereafter uniformly to a width of three thousand five hundred (3,500) feet at a horizontal distance of ten thousand two hundred (10,200) feet beyond the end of the runway, the centerline of this surface being the continuation of the centerline of the runway. The non-instrument approach surface shall extend outward and upward from its base, the elevation of which shall be the same as that of the runway end adjacent thereto, with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to thirty-four (34) feet horizontally for its entire length.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>TR or Transitional districts. "Transitional districts" are hereby established adjacent to each landing, instrument approach and non-instrument approach district.<section>Transitional districts adjacent to runways embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath an imaginary inclined surface symmetrically located on each side of each runway. For instrument runways such imaginary inclined surfaces extend outward from lines parallel to and five hundred (500) feet on either side of the centerline of the runway, upward with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to seven (7) feet horizontally and terminating at an elevation one hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation. For non-instrument runways such imaginary inclined surfaces extend outward from lines parallel to and two hundred fifty (250) feet on either side of the centerline of the runway, upward with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to seven (7) feet horizontally and terminating at an elevation one hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation.</section><section>Transitional districts adjacent to non-instrument approach districts embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath imaginary inclined surfaces which extend outward and upward from the long sides of the non-instrument approach surfaces, as hereinbefore described, at right angles to the centerline of the runway, with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to seven (7) feet horizontally terminating at an elevation one hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation.</section><section>Transitional districts adjacent to instrument approach districts embrace and include all of the land and water area lying vertically beneath imaginary inclined surfaces which extend outward and upward from the long sides of the instrument approach surfaces as hereinbefore described, at right angles to the centerline of the runway with a slope of one (1) foot vertically to seven (7) feet horizontally.</section><section>Within horizontal districts, which are hereafter established and described, this imaginary inclined plane shall terminate when it reaches an elevation one hundred fifty (150) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation. Within conical districts, which are also hereafter established and described, this imaginary inclined surface shall terminate in its intersection with the conical surface which, for the purposes of this article, is described hereinbelow. Outward from the limits of such conical surface, this imaginary inclined surface shall terminate five thousand (5,000) feet from the long sides of the hereinbefore described instrument approach surfaces, such five thousand (5,000) feet being measured horizontally and at right angles to the continuation of the centerline of the runway.</section><section>For the purposes of this subsection, the horizontal surface is established one hundred fifty (150) feet above the heretofore established airport elevation by swinging arcs of 10,000 feet radii for all runways from the center of each end of the primary surface of each runway and connecting the adjacent arcs by lines tangent to those arcs.</section><section>For the purposes of this article, the conical surface is established at the outer edge of the horizontal surface base which has a radius of thirteen thousand two hundred and fifty (13,250) feet centered vertically above the airport reference point at an elevation one hundred fifty (150) feet above the heretofore established airport elevation and the horizontal circular top of which has a radius of seventeen thousand two hundred and fifty (17,250) feet at an elevation three hundred and fifty (350) feet above the hereinbefore established airport elevation by extending outward and upward from the periphery of the horizontal surface at a slope of 20 to 1 for a horizontal distance of 4,000 feet.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>T or Horizontal districts. A "horizontal district" is established as the area within the oblique circle having its center at the airport reference point and thirteen thousand two hundred and fifty (13,250) feet as its radius is created by swinging arcs of 10,000 feet for all runways from the center of each end of the primary surface of each runway and connecting the adjacent arcs by drawing lines tangent to those arcs. The horizontal district does not include the landing, instrument approach, non-instrument approach, transitional or conical districts.</section><section prefix='(6)'>TI or Conical districts. A "conical district" is established commencing at the periphery of the horizontal district and extending to a periphery seventeen thousand two hundred and fifty (17,250) feet from the airport reference point therefrom a horizontal distance of 4,000 feet. The conical district does not include the landing instrument approach, non-instrument approach and transitional or horizontal districts.</section><section prefix='(7)'>NZ or Non-zoned districts. Those portions of the airport zoning area not embraced and included in landing, instrument approach, non-instrument approach, transitional, horizontal and conical districts, as the same are established and described elsewhere herein, are hereby designated as non-zoned districts.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-40, ยง 5, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 99-118, ยง 1, 9-21-99)</history></law>