<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00074' order_by='00074' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIX. HOMESTEAD GENERAL AVIATION AIRPORT ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-375</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of airport zoning area for Homestead General Aviation Airport.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004578</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-375. Establishment of airport zoning area for Homestead General Aviation Airport.<section>For the purpose of this article there is hereby created and established the airport zoning area for Homestead General Aviation Airport and it is hereby ordained that such area shall include, and that the provisions of this article shall be applicable to and embrace all of the unincorporated and the incorporated land and water area lying situate and being in those certain portions of Miami-Dade County, Florida, described as follows, to wit:<section prefix='(1)'>In Township 57 South, Range 36 East, all of Sections 1, 2, 11 to 14 inclusive, 23 to 26 inclusive, the east one-half (½) of Sections 3, 10, 15, 22 and 27, the northeast one-quarter (¼) of Section 34, and the north one-half (½) of Sections 35 and 36.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All of that portion of Range 36½ East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, which lies north of the prolongation west of the south line of Section 18, Township 57 South, Range 37 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, and south of the prolongation west of the north line of the south half of Section 19, Township 56 South, Range 37 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In Township 56 South, Range 37 East, the south one-half (½) of Sections 19 to 23 inclusive, the northeast one-quarter (¼) of Section 23 and all of Sections 24 to 36 inclusive.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In Township 57 South, Range 37 East, all of Sections 1 to 18 inclusive, the east one-half (½) of Section 23, and all of Section 24</section><section prefix='(5)'>In Township 56 South, Range 38 East, all of Sections 19 to 21 inclusive, 25 to 36 inclusive, and the south one-half (½) of Sections 22 to 24 inclusive.</section><section prefix='(6)'>In Township 57 South, Range 38 East, all of Sections 1 to 22 inclusive.</section><section prefix='(7)'>In Township 56 South, Range 39 East, the south one-half (½) of Sections 19 to 23 inclusive, the southwest one-quarter (¼) of Section 24, the west one-half (½) of Sections 25 and 36, and all of Sections 26 to 35 inclusive.</section><section prefix='(8)'>In Township 57 South, Range 39 East, all of Sections 2 to 11 inclusive, all of Sections 14 to 18 inclusive, and the west one-half (½) of Sections 1, 12 and 13.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-38, § 4, 7-9-69)</history></law>