<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-303.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Airport Developmental Impact Committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004501</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-303.2. Airport Developmental Impact Committee.<section>There is hereby established an Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council. When a zoning application under Article XXXVII of this code (Miami International Airport (Wilcox Field) Zoning) or under Article XXXVIII of this code (Opa Locka Airport Zoning) is for property located entirely in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, the Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall be composed of the County's Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council established by of this code, and the Director of Miami-Dade County Aviation Department, or designee, as a non-voting member. When a zoning application under Article XXXVII or Article XXXVIII of the code is for property located in whole or in part in the incorporated area of any municipality, the Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall be composed of the persons described above and the Mayor of the municipality, if not a voting member of the municipal governing body, or if the Mayor is a voting member, then the City Manager of said municipality serving as the representative from the municipality where the application property is located. The Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall, in accordance with the procedures in of this code, review and make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners on all applications for exceptions, variances and appeals of decisions on applications for site plan approval under Article XXXVII and Article XXXVIII of this code.</section><section>Mailed notice of meetings of the Airport Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall be provided in the manner prescribed for notice of applications for special exceptions under(d)(2) of this code. Mailed notice of meetings shall also be provided simultaneously to any municipality in which an application site is located. Applications shall comply with the procedural requirements of of this code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-203, ยง 15, 11-30-04; Ord. No. 08-73, ยง 1, 6-3-08)</history></law>