<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-303</section_number>
<catch_line>Exclusive procedure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004499</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-303. Exclusive procedure.<section prefix='(a)'>The procedure provided herein shall be exclusive in the unincorporated area of the County; provided, however, that unless a governmental facility is authorized as a designated permitted use in a zoning district, Miami-Dade County and its agencies and authorities shall not be bound by the procedures herein contained in constructing, erecting or operating any governmental facility listed below in the unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, and the Board of County Commissioners may establish any governmental facility listed as follows where the Board may direct without regard to the zoning or use classification of any particular site or location: public parks, playgrounds and buildings, and structures supplementary and incidental to such uses; domestic violence centers; fire stations; police stations; public auto inspection stations; public water and sewer treatment and distribution facilities; public libraries; public buildings and centers; public hospitals, nursing homes and health facilities; public auditoriums, arenas, museums, art galleries and convention halls; maximum and minimum detention facilities; solid-waste collection and disposal facilities; public maintenance and equipment yards; public bus stations and Rapid-Transit stations and facilities; and uses determined by the Board of County Commissioners to be similar to those listed above.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Board of County Commissioners may only authorize the erection, construction and operation of the governmental facilities enumerated in Subsection (a) above by resolution following public hearing. The said public hearing shall be held upon at least fifteen (15) days' notice of the time and place of such hearing published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, which publication shall include the time and place of hearing before the Board of County Commissioners. A courtesy notice containing general information as to the date, time, and place of the hearing, the property location and general nature of the application may be mailed to the property owners of record, within a radius of three hundred (300) feet of the property described in the application, or such greater distance as the Director may prescribe; provided, however, that failure to mail or receive such courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken hereunder. To provide additional notice to the public, the property shall be posted by a sign or signs indicating the action desired and the time and place of the public hearing thereon. Failure to post such property shall not affect any action taken hereunder. At the public hearing the Board of County Commissioners shall consider, among other factors, the type of function involved, the public need therefor, the existing land use pattern in the area, alternative locations for the facility and the nature of the impact of the facility on the surrounding property. After considering these said factors, the Board of County Commissioners shall take such action as is necessary to provide for and protect the public health, safety and welfare of the citizens and residents of Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='(1)'>In the event the Board of County Commissioners authorizes the construction, erection, use or operation of a governmental facility in accordance with the procedures delineated above, or in the event the Board otherwise determines that County-owned property should be utilized by the County for a particular public purpose, the property shall be posted by a sign or signs conspicuously located thereon indicating the governmental facility or use authorized for the property. Such sign or signs may be removed upon the commencement of construction. The County Manager or designee shall periodically check the property to ensure that the signs provided for in this subsection remain in existence and accurately depict the proposed use of the subject property. This subsection shall be construed as directory only and failure to comply with the provisions hereof shall not affect the validity of the County Commission's action authorizing the use of the property for the designated purposes.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Any facility which is designated as or intended to be operated as a domestic violence center at the time of consideration, planning, erection, construction or acquisition, shall be exempt from the notice and public hearing provisions set forth in Subsection (b) above.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The procedure established by this chapter shall be the exclusive procedure when applicable to any airport zoning regulations in both the unincorporated and incorporated areas of the County, and no application for a district boundary change, change in zoning regulations, appeals of administrative decisions, special exceptions or unusual and new uses or variances shall be considered or granted by any County Board or Commission unless the same is provided for by this chapter and only by the procedure and method so provided; provided, however, the Board of County Commissioners may change the zoning regulations without following the procedure provided therefor in this article; provided, however, that no such change will be made unless the written recommendation of the Director and Zoning Official are first considered by the Board. No special permit shall be considered or granted by any County Board or Commission.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A commissioner may request a deferral of consideration of any item relating to the construction, erection, use or operation of a governmental facility for up to thirty (30) days the first time the item appears on a commission agenda or the first time the item is raised at a commission meeting if the proposed construction, erection, use or operation of the governmental facility affects that commissioner's district exclusively or primarily. Upon the commissioner's invoking this right, discussion upon that item shall cease and the commission shall move to another item of business. The provisions of this Subsection (d) shall be deemed waived unless asserted by a commissioner before the board takes action on the resolution in question.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 66-66, § 1, 12-20-66; Ord. No. 74-68, § 1, 9-3-74; Ord. No. 75-94, § 1, 11-4-75; Ord. No. 79-30, § 1, 4-17-79; Ord. No. 81-113, § 1, 10-6-81; Ord. No. 87-29, § 1, 5-19-87; Ord. No. 93-11, § 1, 2-16-93; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 97-12, § 2, 2-25-97)</history></law>