<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVII. MIAMI INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT (WILCOX FIELD) ZONING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-334</section_number>
<catch_line>Establishment of airspace review criteria.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004536</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-334. Establishment of airspace review criteria.<section>The Board of County Commissioners hereby adopts, approves and ratifies the map entitled "Airspace Review Criteria MIA" as prepared by the Miami-Dade Aviation Department (MDAD), dated January 2, 2007. This map depicts the regions within the Airport Zoning Area in which structures and trees of varying height levels are subject to review by MDAD. The map is on file in the Miami-Dade Aviation Department and the Department of Planning and Zoning. Such map shall be the official height review criteria map for Miami International Airport, and shall establish the locations and heights of structures and trees that shall be reviewed by MDAD for the issuance of a letter of determination by MDAD pursuant to of this article prior to the issuance of any development permit.</section><section>If a property, parcel, or project (as defined by its folio number(s)) is bifurcated by any of the review boundaries defined in this section and depicted in the Airspace Review Criteria MIA Map, then the more restrictive review criteria shall apply to the entire property, parcel, or project.</section><section>For the purposes of this article, the following shall establish the criteria, based upon a structure or tree's height and location, that determines if such structure or tree is subject to MDAD's review pursuant to.</section><section>Within the All Objects Review Boundary, MDAD shall review all applications for development permits.</section><section>Between the All Objects Review Boundary and the 35 foot AMSL Review Boundary, all development permit applications for structures or trees greater than or equal to 35 feet AMSL shall be reviewed by MDAD.</section><section>Outside of the 35 foot AMSL Review Boundary but within or partially within the MIA Airport Zoning Area, all development permit applications for structures or trees greater than or equal to 200 feet in height shall be reviewed by MDAD.</section><section>Any crane use within the airport zoning area shall be coordinated with MDAD and the Federal Aviation Agency (FAA) for a "Determination of No Hazard" by the FAA.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-39, § 5, 7-9-69; Ord. No. 78-78, § 1, 11-7-78; Ord. No. 86-83, § 1, 10-28-86; Ord. No. 99-65, § 1, 6-8-99; Ord. No. 04-203, § 5, 11-30-04; Ord. No. 07-92, § 3, 7-10-07)</history></law>