<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXVI. ZONING PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-316</section_number>
<catch_line>Exhaustion of remedies; court review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004521</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-316. Exhaustion of remedies; court review.<section>No person aggrieved by any zoning resolution order, requirement, decision or determination of an administrative official or by any decision of the Community Zoning Appeals Board may apply to the Court for relief unless such person has first exhausted the remedies provided for herein and taken all available steps provided in this article. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners that all steps as provided by this article shall be taken before any application is made to the Court for relief; and no application shall be made to the Court for relief except from a resolution adopted by the Board of County Commissioners, or where applicable from a resolution adopted by a Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to this article. Zoning resolutions of the Board of County Commissioners, or where applicable, zoning resolutions of Community Zoning Appeals Boards shall be reviewed in accordance with the procedure and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for the review of the quasi-judicial rulings of any commission or board; and such time shall commence to run from the date the zoning resolution sought to be reviewed is transmitted to the Clerk of the Commission. The Director, or his duly authorized representative, shall affix to each zoning resolution the date said zoning resolution is transmitted to the Clerk of the Commission. The Clerk of the Board shall comply with all requirements of the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. For the purposes of appeal the Director shall make available, for public inspection and copying, the record upon which each final decision of the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board is based; provided, the Director may make a reasonable charge commensurate with the cost in the event the Department is able to and does furnish copies of all or any portion of the record. Prior to certifying a copy of any record or portion thereof, the Director or his designee shall make all necessary corrections in order that the copy is a true and correct copy of the record, or those portions requested, and shall make a charge as provided by administrative order as amended from time to time for preparation of the record, instrument maps, picture or other exhibit; provided, the charges here authorized are not intended to repeal or amend any fee or schedule of fees otherwise established. The Chair, Vice-chair or Acting Chair of the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board at any zoning hearing before the Commission or Community Zoning Appeals Board may swear witnesses and, upon timely request in writing, compel the attendance of witnesses in the same manner prescribed in the Circuit Court. The Director shall employ a qualified court reporter to report the proceedings before the Board of County Commissioners and Community Zoning Appeals Board, who shall transcribe the notes only at the request of the County or other interested party, at the expense of the one (1) making the request. Such transcript, as well as the transcript of the proceedings before the Community Zoning Appeals Board, when certified by the reporter, may be used in a court review of a matter in issue.</section><section>It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners that no decision under this chapter shall constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights (taking or vested rights deprivation). In the event that any court shall determine that a decision of the Board of County Commissioners or Community Zoning Appeals Board under this chapter constitutes a taking or vested rights abrogation, such decision of the board is declared to be non-final and the court is hereby requested to remand the matter to the Board of County Commissioners, which shall reconsider the matter after notice of the County Commission hearing is given pursuant to(c) through (f). In the event that a court fails to remand a matter to the Board of County Commissioners after finding that a taking or vested rights abrogation has occurred, the director is instructed to forthwith file an application to remedy such taking or vested rights abrogation, which application shall be heard directly by the Board of County Commissioners after notice is given pursuant to(c) through (f). The Board of County Commissioners may elect to request that any remand or director's application be deferred until a later point in the litigation, including the completion of any judicial appeals. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained in this chapter, the Board of County Commissioners shall have original administrative jurisdiction over any remand or director's application pursuant to this paragraph.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-14, 4-19-60; Ord. No. 61-30, § 1, 6-27-61; Ord. No. 62-48, § 1F, 12-4-62; Ord. No. 64-65, § 6, 12-15-64; Ord. No. 65-11, § 2, 2-16-65; Ord. No. 66-66, § 5, 12-20-66; Ord. No. 76-74, § 1, 7-20-76; Ord. No. 78-52, § 2, 7-18-78; Ord. No. 79-91, § 1, 10-16-79; Ord. No. 94-37, § 4, 3-3-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-127, § 38, 9-4-96; Ord. No. 13-16, § 11, 2-5-13)</history></law>