<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00076' order_by='00076' level='3'>ARTICLE XLI. ROCKMINING OVERLAY ZONING AREA (ROZA)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-421</section_number>
<catch_line>Districts and Locations Where Rockmining Uses Are Permitted.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004613</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-421. Districts and Locations Where Rockmining Uses Are Permitted.<section prefix='(1)'>The boundaries of the ROZA are defined in Section 33-420</section><section prefix='(2)'>Rockmining uses are permitted in all zoning districts within the ROZA without a public hearing, upon approval of plans by the Department that are in compliance with the specified criteria of this Article, particularly the lake excavation plan criteria enumerated in Section 33-423(5) and Chapter 24 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All of the regulations of the underlying zoning districts apply within the ROZA except:<section prefix='(a)'>Height restrictions. Notwithstanding the existing height restrictions within the underlying zoning districts imposed by this Chapter, and due to the nature of the uses permitted by this Article and the requirements imposed thereby, none of the height restrictions of the underlying zoning districts apply.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Setback regulations. Within the ROZA, all buildings, structures and equipment shall be setback a minimum of 25 feet from all property lines under different ownership, except that no setback regulation is imposed upon conveyor belts and/or other systems or equipment used for the transportation of raw materials permitted below by Section 33-422(1)(b)(i), provided; however, that such conveyor belt and/or systems or equipment for transportation of raw materials shall not extend across property boundaries without the consent of the adjacent property owner(s).</section><section prefix='(c)'>Off-street parking regulations. Notwithstanding the existing parking regulations within the underlying zoning districts imposed by this chapter and due to the nature of the uses permitted by this Article, the off-street parking area requirements of Section 33-126 of this Code do not apply.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Rockmining uses shall not be permitted in any other area of unincorporated Miami-Dade County, Florida, other than as described in Section 33-421(1) and (2) of this Article, unless approved after public hearing pursuant to Section 33-13 of this Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-163, ยง 2, 9-9-04)</history></law>