<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00076' order_by='00076' level='3'>ARTICLE XLI. ROCKMINING OVERLAY ZONING AREA (ROZA)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-420</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004612</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-420. Definitions.<section>The following words and phrases when used in this Article shall have the meaning ascribed to them in this Section:</section><section>shall mean a facility used for the manufacture of asphalt paving products by combining crushed limestone, sand or screening with a heated petroleum binder in a kiln. An asphalt plant includes parking spaces needed for trucks, materials handling equipment, and administrative, control and office buildings. The asphalt manufactured at an asphalt plant consists of more than 80% limestone quarry products, which asphalt is primarily used in highway and parking area paving.</section><section>shall mean a facility used for the manufacture of cement and mortar products. The products are manufactured by grinding limestone to a fine consistency and mixing it with certain additives such as silicates, aluminates, and iron oxides and then heating it in kilns to temperatures in excess of 2000° Fahrenheit. This process produces clinker, which is ground by mills with other ingredients such as gypsum to make specific types of cement and mortar products used in concrete manufacturing and masonry/brick construction. A cement plant includes parking spaces needed for trucks, materials handling equipment, and administrative, control and office buildings. The cement manufactured at a cement plant consists of more than 90% limestone quarry products.</section><section>shall mean a facility used for the delivery of limestone aggregate, sand or screenings, cement and water into mixer trucks as part of the concrete manufacturing process. This facility may contain a system of conveyor belts, chutes, storage silos, stockpile areas, water and air systems, and weight scales and meters for the accurate dispensing of the raw materials to produce the desired strength and type of concrete. A concrete batching plant or ready mixed concrete plant facility includes parking spaces needed for trucks, materials handling equipment, and administrative, control and office buildings. The concrete manufactured at a concrete batching plant or ready mixed concrete plant consists of more than 90% limestone quarry products.</section><section>shall mean a facility used for the manufacture of concrete block and contains sufficient ground and/or covered storage for curing the blocks once removed from their molds, as well as materials batching equipment with automated systems for placing the concrete into block molds and transporting the blocks to curing racks and stockpile areas. A concrete block plant includes parking spaces needed for trucks, materials handling equipment, and administrative, control or office buildings. The concrete blocks manufactured at a concrete block plant consist of more than 90% limestone quarry products.</section><section>shall mean the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section>shall mean the Director of DERM or the Director's designee.</section><section>shall mean a facility used for the manufacture of various concrete products and includes the equipment necessary to deliver concrete into molds and the materials needed to add strength to the final product such as steel reinforcement bars, strands or mesh, or, in the case of prestressed concrete, wire strands in tension. A prestressed and precast concrete production plant manufactures such things as concrete pipe, vaults, and bridge and highway components, requires a large outside storage area for finished product inventory, and includes parking spaces needed for trucks, materials handling equipment, and administrative, control and office buildings. The products produced at a prestressed and precast concrete production plant consist of more than 95% limestone quarry products, excluding the steel reinforcement material.</section><section>shall mean that area described as follows: All of Section 6; that part of Section 4, lying northwesterly of the Florida Turnpike and west of Interstate 75, and those parts of Sections 5, 7, 8, 18 and 19 lying northwesterly of the Florida Turnpike, all lying in Township 52 South, Range 40 East; and all of Sections 1 and 2, the east ½ of Section 3, Section 10 less northwest ¼ thereof, and all of Sections 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 33, 34, 35 and 36, all lying in Township 52 South, Range 39 East; all of Sections 1, 2, 3, 4, 9, 10, the west ½ of, all of Sections 15, 16, 21, 22, 23, the west ½ of, the west ½ of, all of Sections 26, 27, 28, 33, 34, 35 and the west ½ of Section 36, less the Northwest Wellfield area consisting of all lands within a 2,500 ft. distance from each of the wells, all lying in Township 53 South, Range 39 East; and Government Lots 3 and 4 lying between Township 53 South and Township 54 South; and that part of Section 3 and that part of Section 4 lying north of the Tamiami Trail, SR. 90 (U.S. 41) lying in Township 54 South, Range 39 East; and the East ½ of, all of and the North ½ of of Township 54 South, Range 38 East.</section><section>shall mean a facility comprised of systems used for the automated conveying, crushing, segregation and blending of crushed rock in order to manufacture the basic materials used in construction such as concrete, concrete block, cement, asphalt, road base and many other rock products. A rock crushing and screening plant facility includes portable crushing facilities used primarily for the processing of road base material and parking spaces for trucks, materials handling equipment, and administrative, control and office buildings.</section><section>shall mean the dredging or excavation of an area for the purpose of extracting subsurface materials. Rockmining shall also include ancillary property uses necessary for the extracting and processing of subsurface materials.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-163, § 2, 9-9-04)</history></law>