<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-4.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Outdoor lighting.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003885</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-4.1. Outdoor lighting.<section>Lights for area lighting of outdoor areas, such as, but not limited to, tennis courts, golf courses, sporting areas or grounds, parking lots or areas, amusement or entertainment areas, and outside lighting for security purposes, shall not be permitted except under the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>Detailed plans shall be submitted to the Department showing the location, height, type of lights, shades, deflectors and beam directions.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department may issue a permit for such lighting if, after a review of the detailed plans therefor and after consideration of the adjacent area and neighborhood and its use and future development, the proposed lighting will be so located, oriented, adjusted and shielded that the lighting will be deflected, shaded and focused away from such adjacent property and will not be or become a nuisance to such adjacent property, and will not create a traffic hazard on adjacent streets by reason of glare or the like.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Upon a determination by the Department that the proposed lighting will not conform to the provisions of this subsection or as to the negative effect such lighting may have on the adjacent area and neighborhood or traffic, after considering the detailed plan and such area and neighborhood, the Department shall not issue a permit for the same, and no such lighting shall be permitted until approved after public hearing.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In addition, outdoor lighting for recreational and offstreet area parking purposes, or for any other purpose in the RU, EU, AU and GU Zones shall be designed so that any overspill of lighting onto adjacent properties shall not exceed one-half (½) footcandle (vertical) and shall not exceed one-half (½) footcandle (horizontal) illumination on adjacent properties or structures. An outdoor lighting installation shall not be placed in permanent use until a letter of compliance from a registered engineer or architect or the duly authorized representative of such engineer or architect is provided stating that the installation has been field checked and meets the requirements as set forth above. The requirements of this subparagraph shall apply to any night lighting in BU and IU Zones abutting an RU, EU, AU, or GU Zone.</section><section prefix='(e)'>It is not intended here to regulate permitted sign lights and it is not the intent to modify, amend or repeal any portion of the South Florida Building Code.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-47, § 1, 11-5-63; Ord. No. 75-73, § 1, 9-17-75; Ord. No. 79-114, § 2, 12-4-79; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>