<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING CONTENT, SETBACKS AND AREA OF SITES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-49</section_number>
<catch_line>Table of minimum widths, area of lots; maximum lot coverage, and minimum building sizes.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003950</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-49. Table of minimum widths, area of lots; maximum lot coverage, and minimum building sizes.<section>The minimum width and area of lots, the maximum lot coverage, and minimum building sizes shall be in effect for the districts enumerated in the following table:</section><section></section><section></section><section>NOTE 1. Percentage of lot coverage allowed applied to principal structure. Lot coverage for accessory buildings such as guest houses, secondary residences, etc., shall be as provided in other applicable Sections.</section><section>Lot coverage requirements shall in no way affect existing setback or spacing requirements, or the requirements that residential uses must conform to residential setbacks when established in business or industrial districts.</section><section>NOTE 2. Unless otherwise stated, figures in this column are for single-family residential use. Duplex structure shall be one and one-half (1½) times minimum cubic content. Three (3) or four (4) units shall be twice the minimum cubic content.</section><section>NOTE 3. Where a lot is to be used exclusively for commercial purposes, the number of store units shall not be dependent on any square foot area requirements; however, where it is desired to combine a residential use of any type with a commercial use, necessary lot area shall first be provided for the residential use and, if there is any surplus area, the commercial use will be permitted, providing all setback, spacing, parking, and other requirements are met.</section><section>NOTE 4. Unless otherwise stated herein or shown on the district maps, the cubic content specified shall refer to a one (1) story, single-family dwelling. Proportional increases in size or value shall be required for two (2) story or more than one (1) family use.</section><section>NOTE 5. Minimum width of lots in new subdivisions in the RU-1Z, RU-1, RU-1M(a), RU-1M(b), EU-M, EU-S and EU-1 Districts may be decreased from the amount required under the following conditions:<section prefix='(a)'>The decrease shall be applicable to lots containing a portion of their frontage along the curvilinear streets and cul-de-sacs.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The minimum lot frontage as defined elsewhere for the various zoning districts must be provided at the minimum building setback line of curvilinear lots.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That the minimum frontage requirement at street right-of-way line and radius requirements of exterior street right-of-way line along curvilinear streets and cul-de-sacs shall meet the following requirements:</section><section prefix='(d)'>Lot area must comply with all other minimum zoning requirements.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The design of the streets where the lot frontage occurs must conform to standards of the Public Works Department.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 29(C), (D), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 59-43, § 2, 11-24-59; Ord. No. 61-2, 1-17-61; Ord. No. 63-28, § 1, 7-9-63; Ord. No. 64-19, § 1, 5-5-64; Ord. No. 68-22, § 1, 4-16-68; Ord. No. 72-59, § 1, 9-19-72; Ord. No. 82-30, § 1, 4-20-82; Ord. No. 94-201, § 1, 11-1-94; Ord. No. 95-135, § 5, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 02-32, § 1, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 03-132, § 2, 6-3-03; Ord. No. 05-189, § 1, 11-3-05)</history></law>