<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING CONTENT, SETBACKS AND AREA OF SITES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-51</section_number>
<catch_line>Setbacks in business and industrial districts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003952</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-51. Setbacks in business and industrial districts.<section>The minimum setback distances and spacing requirements in all business districts and in IU-1, IU-2 and IU-3 Industrial Districts (see for IU-C setback requirements) shall be as follows:</section><section>—Twenty (20) feet.</section><section>—Fifteen (15) feet, except where an RU, EU or GU lot abuts a business or industrial lot, then the side street setback shall be twenty-five (25) feet on any part of the commercial structure located within twenty-five (25) feet of the residential district boundary provided, however, if an abutting GU lot is depicted as "Industrial &amp; Office" on the adopted Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and no building permit has been issued for a residence at the time of the approval of the building permit for the business or industrial use, the setback shall be fifteen (15) feet from the side street property line.</section><section>—Zero (0) feet where the adjacent property is BU or IU Districts and where the use of the building is limited exclusively to business or industrial use. The wall along the side property line shall be constructed in accordance with the Florida Building Code.<section>Five (5) feet where any openings are provided in the wall of the proposed structure, adjacent to the interior side property lot line.</section><section>Ten (10) feet for such portions of the business structure as are devoted to residential use.</section><section>Fifteen (15) feet where the adjacent property is zoned RU or EU or GU. It is provided, however, that where an abutting GU lot is depicted as "Industrial &amp; Office" on the adopted Land Use Plan map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and no building permit has been issued for a residence at the time of the approval of the building permit for the business or industrial use, in such instances the setback shall be:<section>Zero (0) feet where the wall along the interior side property line is unpierced and constructed in accordance with the Florida Building Code; or</section><section>Five (5) feet where any openings are provided in the wall of the proposed structure, adjacent to the interior side property lot line.</section></section></section><section>—Twenty (20) feet from residential district boundary, except that credit shall be given for full width of dedicated alleys in computing this setback.<section>Five (5) feet from business or industrial district boundary, where any openings are provided in wall of proposed structure, adjacent to rear lot line.</section><section>Zero (0) feet from business or industrial district boundary where no openings are proposed in wall of proposed structure, adjacent to rear lot line.</section><section>Same setbacks shall apply for accessory buildings as apply to principal structures.</section></section><section>—Twenty (20) feet.<section>Structures containing residential uses or mixed residential-business uses shall comply with residential setbacks (for the entire building) as may be required for the residential use in the residential district.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 3, 10-22-57; Ord. No. 58-4, § 1, 2-13-58; Ord. No. 64-19, § 4, 5-5-64; Ord. No. 80-89, § 1, 9-2-80; Ord. No. 83-39, § 1, 6-7-83; Ord. No. 02-255, § 3, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 03-41, § 1, 3-11-03)</history></law>