<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. HEIGHT OF BUILDINGS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-55</section_number>
<catch_line>Certain structures exempt.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003956</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-55. Certain structures exempt.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this article regarding building height shall not apply to: airplane beacons, belfries, chimneys, church spires/steeples, conveyors, cooling towers, cupolas, domes, elevator bulkheads and shafts and enclosures for mechanical equipment shall not be considered a part of a building for height calculations, fire towers, flag poles, monuments, parapet wall extending not more than five (5) feet above the limited height of the building on which it rests, radio and television towers, roof structures used only for ornamental purposes providing they do not exceed ten (10) percent of the roof area on which they stand, smokestacks, stage towers or scenery lofts, tanks, bins and silos used for purpose of storing grain or feed products such as silage in connection with agricultural production, water towers, and structures used in connection with screening of Antennas.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The provisions of this article III regarding building height shall not apply to active and passive recreational facilities which may be provided on the roof of a building, provided that the enclosed portion of such facilities shall not exceed sixty (60) percent of the total area of such roof, and provided that the same does not exceed one (1) story or twenty (20) feet in height.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 29(D), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 69-28, § 1, 4-15-69; Ord. No. 73-5, § 1, 1-9-73; Ord. No. 87-8, § 3, 3-3-87; Ord. No. 01-02, § 4, 1-23-01)</history></law>