<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. TOWERS, POLES AND MASTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-63.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Satellite dish antennas.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003966</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-63.1. Satellite dish antennas.<section>The standards of this section pertain to privately owned satellite dish antennas and are intended to enable clear television reception for the private use and enjoyment of the dish owner. The standards for commercial telecommunications facilities and antennas associated therewith are enumerated in.</section><section prefix='(a)'>Definition. A Satellite dish antenna (SDA) shall be defined as a device incorporating a reflective surface that is solid, open mesh, or bar configured and is in the shape of a shallow parabolic dish, cone, horn, or cornucopia. Such device is used to transmit and/or receive radio or electromagnetic waves between terrestrially and/or orbitally based uses. This definition is meant to include but not be limited to what are commonly referred to as satellite earth stations and satellite microwave antennas.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Measuring an SDA. The diameter of an SDA shall be measured to the outermost part of the SDA. The height of an SDA shall be measured from natural grade to the top of the SDA fastened in a vertical position. The setback of an SDA shall be measured from the property line to the nearest portion of the SDA fastened in a horizontal position.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Permits and exceptions. Unless preempted by Federal Law, no SDA shall be erected unless a building permit is first obtained from the Building Department. Under current Federal Law no permit is necessary for SDA's measuring less than one (1) meter (39.37 inches) in diameter when placed as an accessory use to any single-family residence, duplex or townhouse unit, or less than two (2) meters (78.74 inches) in diameter when placed as an accessory use to any permitted business, industrial, office or multi-family use.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The trend determination regulations specified in Section 33-196 for the GU (Interim) District shall govern the standards to be utilized in the placement of SDA's within the GU District.</section><section prefix='(e)'>As an accessory use to any single-family residence, duplex or townhouse, one (1) ground-mounted SDA is permitted per dwelling unit subject to all the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>No installation shall exceed fifteen (15) feet in height.</section><section prefix='(2)'>SDA's must be located behind the front and side street building line of the principal building and a minimum of seventy-five (75) feet from the front property line. SDA's are to be setback from the interior side property lines a minimum of seven and one-half (7½) feet in RU Districts and twenty (20) feet in the EU, AU and GU Districts. The minimum rear setback is seven and one-half (7½) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>As an accessory use to any single-family residence, duplex or townhouse, one (1) roof-mounted or wall-mounted SDA is permitted per dwelling unit in lieu of a ground mounted SDA, subject to all the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>A certified engineer's report reflects that clear reception of all satellite transmissions is not possible with a ground mounted SDA under paragraph (e) above;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The SDA shall be mounted on the rear or interior side wall of the principal building or on the roof to the rear of the actual front building line;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The SDA shall not exceed ten (10) feet in diameter;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The height of the proposed installation shall not exceed the maximum height restriction imposed upon principal uses within the underlying zoning district.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>As an accessory use to any business, office or multi-family use, ground-mounted SDA's are permitted subject to all the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>The ground mounted SDA shall not exceed sixteen (16) feet in diameter;</section><section prefix='(2)'>All installations shall comply with the principal building setback requirements specified within the underlying zoning district. The ground mounted SDA shall be located behind the actual front and side street building line;</section><section prefix='(3)'>No ground mounted SDA shall project beyond the height of the tallest principal building on the lot on which it is erected.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>As an accessory use to any business, office or multi-family use, roof or wall-mounted SDA's are permitted, in lieu of ground-mounted antennas, subject to all the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>The SDA shall not exceed sixteen (16) feet in diameter;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each SDA must be mounted on the roof to the rear of the front building line or on the rear or non-street side wall of the principal building;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The height of the SDA shall not exceed seventeen (17) feet above the height of the principal building on which it is placed.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>SDA's are permitted as an accessory use in any Industrial District (IU) subject to compliance with the principal building setback requirements within the underlying zoning district. In Industrial Districts (IU) abutting or across the street from a residential district, SDA's must also comply with all conditions of paragraphs (g) and (h) above.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Signage of any type is prohibited on SDA's.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Nothwithstanding the provisions contained in this section to the contrary, the Director shall have the discretion to administratively modify setback requirements when it can be demonstrated through a certified engineer's report that compliance with such setback requirements would hinder clear reception of signals. In such instances, the Director:<section prefix='(1)'>May require that the SDA be buffered with landscaping or screened from view, providing such buffering or screening does not interfere with clear reception;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Shall ensure that the modification is within the spirit and intent of this section; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>To the extent possible shall ensure that the SDA installation is compatible with the appearance and character of the neighborhood.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-8, § 2, 3-3-87; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 02-10, § 1, 1-29-02)</history></law>