<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. TOWERS, POLES AND MASTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-63</section_number>
<catch_line>Antennas for amateur radio stations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003965</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-63. Antennas for amateur radio stations.<section>Poles, masts and towers for supporting antenna used in the operation of amateur radio stations licensed by the Federal Communications Commission shall be excepted from the above regulations and shall be governed by the following requirements:<section prefix='(a)'>Location on property. All such poles, masts and towers shall be placed no closer than five (5) feet to an official right-of-way line or to property under different ownership, or closer than one (1) foot to an easement. If beam (array) type of antenna installed, no element or part of such beam type array antenna shall extend closer than five (5) feet to an official right-of-way line and/or the property under different ownership or closer than one (1) foot to an easement.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Compliance with electrical codes and federal regulations. All such installations shall conform to the requirements of the National Electrical Code and the F.C.C. regulations, Part 12, Section 12.60 governing amateur radio services. National Electrical Code installation must maintain a minimum of eight (8) feet clearance from power lines over two hundred fifty (250) volts and all high voltage primary lines, and this includes the beam elements or any part thereof.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Permits. Permits shall be required for installation of any poles, masts or towers over twenty (20) feet above the roof of any structure to which they may be attached, and for any installation over thirty-five (35) feet in height when erected on natural ground. Where permits are required, they shall be obtained from the Department; and applications for permits shall be accompanied by plans and specifications, three (3) copies, showing all dimensions, size and kind of members, footings and guy wires, if any; locations, depth and type of guy anchors and footings, if any, and showing the type and weight of antenna, apparatus or structure to be attached to or supported by the structure.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Poles, type. Poles shall be of the approved creosoted type or treated or painted with a chemical preservative and an outer coat of oil base paint before installation (Color to match surrounding development).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Holes. Recommended sizes and depths of holes for various type poles subject to good engineering standards:<section>If the earth is damp or soggy, the depth of hole is to be increased by one (1) foot.</section><section>If the pole is guyed in accordance with American Standards Association standards, the depth of hole as listed in Code can be decreased by one (1) foot. If carrying a beam, poles must be properly guyed, as is the case where pulling effect of wire antenna or weight of other installations will require guying.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Masts. Masts constructed of wood (2″ x 2″ or 4″ x 4″ for either the "A" frame type construction or straight masts) shall be properly chemically treated, painted with an outside coat of oil base paint and be properly guyed both at the top and middle in at least three (3) different directions, approximately one hundred twenty (120) degrees apart, or otherwise suitably guyed. Masts to support a beam, whether of wood or metal pipe, must comply with all the regulations applicable in regard to location, guying, etc., and the maximum allowable weight of antenna, rotator and components shall not exceed one hundred fifty (150) pounds.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Towers. Towers of steel, iron or aluminum, whether of the rigid nondemountable type or the rigid, demountable type with the crank-up, crank-down and either the hinged base or swivel crank-over features shall carry no more weight on the top than specified by the manufacturers' specifications.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Waiver of objection for certain structures; servicing; removal. All poles, masts or towers, and other structures used for antennas under this section, which exceed thirty-five (35) feet in height above grade elevation, or which exceed twenty (20) feet in height above the roof of any structure shall be subject to the following requirements:<section>If the top of such poles, masts or towers are higher above their foundation, or the foundation of the structure on which they are erected, than ninety (90) percent of the horizontal distance from its base or projected base to the nearest point on adjacent property under different ownership or to the nearest edge of an official right-of-way, then no permit shall be issued for such installation unless a waiver is obtained from each and every owner of adjacent property that the structure could fall upon.</section><section>In calculating the height of demountable type towers, the top of the lower rigid section shall be considered the top for the purpose of this subsection.</section><section>Beam array antenna shall be so mounted so as to provide easy servicing and easy access for removal at approach of hurricanes, or provide for the lowering of such beam.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, § 28(B)(3), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>