<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. TOWERS, POLES AND MASTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-63.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Wireless supported service facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003967</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-63.2 Wireless supported service facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>Permitted Districts and Criteria for Antennas.<section prefix='(1)'>Permitted Districts. Antennas used as part of a Wireless Supported Service Facility which are mounted on existing Structures shall be permitted in the following zoning districts subject to the criteria outlined below.<section prefix='(A)'>In hotels, motels, and apartment hotels in an RU-4A district; in all RU-5, RU-5A, OPD, in all business and industrial districts.</section><section prefix='(B)'>On multi-family residential buildings in an RU-4L, RU-4M, RU-4 and RU-4A district.</section><section prefix='(C)'>In any district on any structure lawfully being used for any of the following purposes, where the site is located at the intersection of section-line roads, a transition area, or abutting a major roadway as depicted on the Land Use Plan Map of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, or section center: public or private/nonpublic educational facilities on a site of 10 or more gross acres, hospitals, race tracks, stadiums, or public or private utilities.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Criteria. Antennas may be located on existing Structures with a height of thirty (30) feet or greater, so long as the Antennas do not extend (i) more than thirteen (13) feet above the highest point of the roof of a building as measured in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-1(17) or (ii) the highest point on the Structure as measured from the average elevation of the finished building site to the top of the structure.<section prefix='(A)'>Except for Cylinder Type Antennas, Antennas shall be screened from view or wall mounted and shall not exceed nine (9) Sectors.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Where wall mounted, Antennas shall not extend above the wall where located and shall be painted to match the supporting Structure. Wall mounted Antennas shall be limited to one (1) Sector per building elevation.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Wall mounted Antennas not exceeding the height of the wall where located and painted to match the supporting Structure will be allowed on rooftop elevator bulkheads, rooftop enclosures for mechanical equipment, and rooftop Accessory Wireless Equipment Buildings in addition to (b)(2)(i), above, but shall be limited to one (1) Sector per elevation on the particular rooftop structure where they are placed.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Where roof mounted:<section prefix='1.'>Requests to install roof mounted Antennas shall be accompanied by a line of sight analysis for each building elevation. The line of sight analysis shall be as provided for in the sketches shown below as Figures 33-63.2(b)(2)iii and iv. In conducting such analysis, the width of the right-of-way shall be equal to the width of the right-of-way fronting the particular elevation.</section></section></section></section><section><section></section></section><section><section></section><section prefix='2.'>Any Antennas or portion thereof above the line of sight will require screening. All required screening used in conjunction with such rooftop installations shall be architecturally compatible and harmonious in color and materials with the supporting structures and any existing or approved screening on the structure. Screening materials at corners shall be the same length and height on all corners.<section prefix='(i)'>An initial antenna installation within 13 feet of the corner of a structure shall require screening along the rooflines of both sides of the corner to a distance of 13 feet.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>An initial antenna installation more than 13 feet from the corner of a structure, or the installation of any antenna subsequent to a prior antenna installation, shall provide screening along the entire rooflines from which the line of sight analysis shows that the antenna can be seen.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Cylinder Type Antennas shall be limited to three (3) per Structure and shall be painted to match the Structure.</section><section prefix='4.'>No sign shall be allowed on an Antenna.</section><section prefix='5.'>No signals, lights, or illumination shall be permitted on an Antenna, unless required by any applicable federal, state or local rule, regulation or law.</section><section prefix='6.'>Accessory Wireless Equipment Buildings used in conjunction with Antennas, if located on the ground, shall comply with the minimum principal building setback requirements of the zoning district in which they are located. Self-standing, non sheltered equipment cabinet(s) used in conjunction with Antennas, if located on the ground shall be deemed mechanical equipment similar to air conditioning units and shall be limited to a height not to exceed eight (8) feet and an area not to exceed eighty (80) square feet. There shall be no minimum spacing between Accessory Wireless Equipment Buildings and the building located on the property.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Permitted Districts and Criteria for Antenna Support Structures.<section prefix='(1)'>Permitted Districts. Wireless Supported Service Facilities including Antenna Support Structures of one hundred (100) feet or less in height used in connection with a Wireless Supported Service Facility shall be permitted in the BU-3 and in all Industrial Districts. For Antenna Support Structures greater than one hundred (100) feet in height in the BU-3 and in the Industrial Districts, and for all Antenna Support Structures, except Antenna Support Structures for broadcast radio and television, in the RU-3M, RU-4L, RU-4M, RU-4, RU4A, RU-5, RU5-A, AU, GU with an agricultural trend determination, BU-1, BU-1A, BU-2, OPD, TND and PAD zoning districts, a public hearing is required pursuant to Section 33-311(A)(18) and this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Criteria.<section prefix='(A)'>Signage.<section prefix='(1.)'>No advertising signs, including commercial advertising, logo, political signs, flyers, flags or banners, whether or not posted temporarily, shall be permitted on any part of the antenna support structures or antenna with the exception of the following:<section prefix='a.'>Warning, danger or other sign designed to maintain public safety;</section><section prefix='b.'>Any federal, state or municipal flags located on such facilities designed to look like a flagpole; or</section><section prefix='c.'>Permitted signage associated with the principle use on the property where the principle use incorporates a camouflaged antenna support structure.</section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Zoning District. Antenna Support Structures considered for approval under section 33-311(A)(18) of this code shall meet each of the following requirements, as applicable, except as alternative development options may be approved pursuant to section 33-311(A)(18)(b).<section prefix='1.'>In the BU-1, BU-1A, RU-5, and RU-5A zoning districts:<section prefix='a)'>A stealth or camouflaged Antenna Support Structure shall be designed to resemble a natural object or a man-made structure (i.e. tree, bell tower, clock tower, church steeple, flag pole, etc.), shall be located on a minimum one (1) gross acre parent tract and<section prefix='1)'>shall be a camouflaged artificial tree or flagpole not exceeding 150 feet in height; or</section><section prefix='2)'>shall be designed to serve a purpose other than supporting antennas (i.e., lighting of sports facilities, transmission of electrical and/or telephone lines, flag poles); or</section><section prefix='3)'>shall be designed to be harmonious with the architectural elements of the surrounding structures, such as bulk, massing and scale of surrounding properties; or be designed to blend and be harmonious with the principal structure on the property on which the Antenna Support Structure is proposed to be constructed and installed.</section></section><section prefix='b)'>A non-camouflaged Antenna Support Structure shall not exceed 125 feet in height and shall be located on a minimum one (1) gross acre parent tract.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>In the AU zoning district and the GU zoning district with an agricultural trend determination:<section prefix='a.'>non-camouflaged Antenna Support Structures shall be located on a minimum five (5) gross acre parent tract, and</section><section prefix='b.'>no Antenna Support Structures shall exceed 200 feet in height.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>In all RU-3M, RU-4L, RU-4M, RU-4, and RU-4A zoning districts non-camouflaged Antenna Support Structures shall not exceed 150 feet in height, and shall not exceed 125 feet in height if located on a parcel where the immediate vicinity contains any existing single-family or duplex residential dwelling or is zoned for single-family or duplex dwellings.</section><section prefix='4.'>In all BU-3, IU-1, IU-2, IU-3, and IU-C zoning districts, a non-camouflaged Antenna Support Structure shall not exceed 200 feet in height.</section><section prefix='5.'>In all OPD and BU-2 zoning districts, a non-camouflaged Antenna Support Structure shall not exceed 200 feet in height.</section><section prefix='6.'>On properties zoned PAD or TND, location and design criteria for Antenna Support Structures and related equipment buildings shall be controlled as part of the conditions of approval of the PAD or TND agreement and any amendments thereto, in accordance with the applicable requirements of section 33-284.24 or section 33-284.46 and section 33-246.47 of this code.</section></section></section><section prefix='[3]'>No signals, lights, or illumination shall be permitted on the Antenna Support Structure or the Antennas, unless required by any applicable federal, state or local rule, regulation or law.</section><section prefix='[4]'>Accessory Wireless Equipment Buildings used in conjunction with Antenna Support Structures and Antennas, if located on the ground, shall comply with the minimum principal building setback requirements of the zoning district in which they are located. Self-standing, non sheltered equipment cabinet(s) used in conjunction with Antenna Support Structures or Antennas, if located on the ground shall be deemed mechanical equipment similar to air conditioning units and shall be limited to a height not to exceed eight (8) feet and an area not to exceed eighty (80) square feet. There shall be no minimum spacing between Accessory Wireless Equipment Buildings and the building located on the property.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-02, ยง 2, 1-23-01; Ord. No. 01-157, ยง 1, 9-25-01; Ord. No. 02-153, ยง 2, 9-12-02; Ord. No. 03-163, ยง 1, 7-8-03)</history></law>