<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. TOWERS, POLES AND MASTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-60</section_number>
<catch_line>Compliance with article.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003961</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-60. Compliance with article.<section prefix='(a)'>Before erection of a water tower, standpipe, windmill, tower or mast for any purpose, over ten (10) feet in height above the roof of a structure or over twenty (20) feet in height if erected on natural ground, the requirements of this article and the construction requirements of the South Florida Building Code shall be observed. All towers, poles, and masts requiring notice to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) as prescribed in Federal Aviation Regulations (FAR) Part 77, shall be lighted as specifically recommended by the FAA in the determination rendered to the proponent's notice of proposed construction. In addition, for all towers, poles, and masts not requiring notice to the FAA which are one hundred fifty (150) feet or higher above grade in height, one (1) flashing red beacon safety light will be required for each one hundred fifty (150) feet in height. The peak effective intensity of said lights should not be less than one thousand five hundred (1,500) candles (in red) when measured at any horizontal angle. The flashing mechanism should not permit more than forty (40) nor less than twenty (20) flashes per minute. The beacons shall conform to Federal Aviation Administration type L-866 (red) or Military Specification L-6273. All existing towers, poles, and masts, which are one hundred fifty (150) feet or higher above grade shall be made to conform with those requirements by May 1, 1989. This section shall be applicable and enforceable in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Until December 31, 2008, telecommunications antennas owned and operated by a telecommunications company providing services to the public for hire attached to any pole or H-frame or lattice structure owned by a utility which is used in and is part of the utility's network for the provision of electric services, shall be permitted in any zoning district, provided that (a) equipment appurtenant to the antenna is maintained on the utility pole or structure, (b) the utility pole or structure does not exceed one hundred twenty-five (125) feet in height above ground unless the utility pole or structure is located in an easement or right-of-way which is greater than fifty (50) feet in width or, if less than fifty (50) feet in width, such easement or right-of-way is adjacent to and parallel with road right-of-way which is one hundred (100) feet or greater in width, and (c) the antenna was attached to the utility pole or structure prior to January 1, 1997.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 28(B), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 88-2, ยง 1, 1-19-88; Ord. No. 88-125, ยง 1, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 98-173, ยง 2, 12-1-98)</history></law>