<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. AWNINGS, CANOPIES AND TENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-71</section_number>
<catch_line>Use of cloth, canvas canopies in residential districts, excepting canopy carports.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003976</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-71. Use of cloth, canvas canopies in residential districts, excepting canopy carports.<section prefix='(a)'>Canopies comprised of a covering made of cloth, canvas, or other similar material shall be permitted within the side and rear yards in all residential districts subject to the regulations of this section. Canopies shall have a maximum height of ten feet as measured from grade to the lowest horizontal element of the frame structure with the total height of the structure not exceeding 15 feet. Canopies may encroach into the rear and side setback but shall not be located closer than ten feet to the rear property line and five feet to the interior side property line. On a side street, the canopy shall meet the principal building setback. In no event shall the area protected by the canopy be enclosed or screened in any manner. See section 33-75 for regulations related to canopy carports.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In addition to the requirements of section 33-71(a), an attached canopy comprised of cloth, canvas or other similar material shall project a maximum of 15 feet from the primary structure.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to the requirements of Section 33-71(a), freestanding canopies comprised of cloth, canvas or other similar material shall not exceed 12 feet by 24 feet in size. Freestanding canopies exceeding the maximum size requirement may be permitted for authorized special events but shall not remain on the site for a period exceeding 30 days.</section><section prefix='(d)'>If the canopy has aluminum, shingle, or other solid roof, it shall be considered to be part of the principal structure and subject to all setbacks and height restrictions for principal structures.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The canopy shall be erected in such manner that it shall be removed during hurricanes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 5(FF)(B)(7), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 70-35, ยง 1, 4-29-70; Ord. No. 70-67, ยง 1, 9-15-70; Ord. No. 10-38, ยง 5, 6-3-10)</history></law>