<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-8.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Zoning Improvement Permit (ZIP).</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003891</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-8.1. Zoning Improvement Permit (ZIP).<section>Certain buildings, structures, improvements and installations are exempted by the Florida Building Code from building permit issuance, but must otherwise comply with the minimum requirements of this chapter. Therefore, such buildings, structures, improvements and installations shall be subject to review under the Zoning Improvement Permit (ZIP) standards contained in this section, as well as the regulations of the underlying zoning district.</section><section>The following buildings, structures, improvements and installations shall require a ZIP from the Department of Planning and Zoning:<section>Above ground pools that contain water over 24 inches deep;</section><section>Agricultural/farm buildings and non-habitable structures on bona fide farms;</section><section>Canopy carports, canopy and other fabric covered framework installed on residential properties;</section><section>Chickee huts constructed by Miccosukee or Seminole Indians;</section><section>Chain link fences, picket fences, ornamental iron fences and other fences installed on residential property that are deemed non-wind resistant; provided, however, any pool safety barrier fence and any fence with concrete columns shall require a building permit; Decorative reflective pools and fishponds that contain water less than 24 inches deep, that contain less than 250 square feet in area, and contain less than 2,250 gallons in volume;</section><section>Decorative garden-type water fountains;</section><section>Parking lot refurbishing - resurfacing, re-striping or seal coating, and paving and drainage of existing parking lots;</section><section>Portable mini-storage unit, subject to the conditions and limitations of(i);</section><section>Signs - balloon type;</section><section>Signs - painted wall type;</section><section>Signs - stick on letter type.</section></section><section>The director of the Department shall have the authority to require ZIP review for other buildings, structures, improvements and installations that are newly created or come about by changes in the state or local building codes.</section><section>In the event any portion of the subject property is contiguous to or across the street from a municipal boundary, applicant shall submit a boundary survey performed in accordance with Chapter 61G17-6.0031, Florida Administration Code.</section><section>The submittal of plans shall be necessary to fully advise and acquaint the issuing Department with the location and use of the buildings, structures, improvements and installations, and such plans must accompany the application for a ZIP. The respective Directors of the Department of Public Works, Department of Environmental Resources Management, Miami-Dade County Fire Rescue Department and Department of Planning &amp; Zoning shall review the submitted plans only to the extent of their respective jurisdiction under the Code of Miami-Dade County In the event there is a question as to the legality of a use, the Director may require affidavits and such other information as may be deemed appropriate or necessary to establish the legality of the use, before a ZIP permit is issued.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-186, ยง 1, 9-9-03; Ord. No. 05-191, ยง 1, 11-1-05)</history></law>