<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Certificate of use.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003890</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-8. Certificate of use.<section prefix='(a)'>No structure, other than a single-family residence or duplex, shall be used or any existing use enlarged, or any new use made of any land, body of water, or structure, without first obtaining a certificate of use (C.U.) therefor from the Department. Said certificate of use shall be required for each individual business and each multi-family building located within unincorporated Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event there is a question as to the legality of a use, the Director may require inspections, affidavits and such other information he may deem appropriate or necessary to establish the legality of the use, before a certificate of use will be issued. Additionally, the Department shall have the right to periodically inspect premises at any reasonable time to ensure the existence of a current and valid C.U., and to ensure compliance with the terms and conditions under which a C.U. was issued.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The person or entity listed upon a Certificate of Title issued pursuant to Chapter 45, Florida Statutes as the purchaser of a single-family residence, condominium unit, townhouse or duplex shall obtain a C.U. from the Department prior to offering said residence for sale, transfer or other alienation. The C.U. required by this subsection (c) shall be for the purpose of determining whether or not the residence in question complies with all building codes and zoning codes applicable to the residence and to provide a disclosure of those findings. The Director shall require disclosure by requiring an inspection of the property by personnel authorized to conduct such inspections by the Director and to subsequently record in the public records of Miami-Dade County the inspection report. Said report shall include a good faith estimate of the cost to repair or remedy all code violations disclosed by the inspection. The Director shall prescribe the form of the inspection report and disclosure to ensure compliance with the intent of this section. Upon the recording of the inspection report and estimate in the public records of Miami-Dade County, the Director is authorized to issue the C.U. required by this subsection (c). The Director shall refer any County Code violations disclosed in the report to the proper County Department for enforcement action. County Departments are authorized to collect fees for inspections and other administrative costs and/or for the issuance of the C.U., as maybe applicable, and as established in the Departments' approved schedule of fees.</section><section>Except for C.U.s required by code or zoning resolution to be renewed annually, and except for C.U.s issued on a temporary basis, certificates of use shall remain valid for an unlimited time unless revoked for cause. The C.U. is only valid for the specific address, business name, corporate name and type of business for which it was issued. A new C.U. shall be required for any changes in; use, name, ownership, expansion of square footage occupied, the inclusion of additional uses, or when changes to the structure have been approved by final building inspection.</section><section>No certificate of use shall be utilized in a manner contrary to the regulations contained in this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 57-19, ยง 5(E), 10-22-57; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 02-114, ยง 1, 6-18-02; Ord. No. 08-133, ยง 1, 12-2-08)</history></law>