<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00068' order_by='00068' level='2'>Chapter 33A DEVELOPMENTS IN INCORPORATED AREAS CREATING COUNTY IMPACT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33A-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004622</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33A-5. Definitions.<section>It is expressly declared that the words, terms and phrases used in this chapter shall have the same meaning as provided in, Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, including:<section prefix='(a)'>Comprehensive Development Master Plan: The words "Comprehensive Development Master Plan" shall mean and refer to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Metropolitan Miami-Dade County adopted by the Board of County Commissioners by Ordinance No. 75-22 on March 31, 1975, or as amended.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan: The words "conforms to the Comprehensive Development Master Plan" shall mean and refer to zoning request or action which is in furtherance of and consistent with the goals, objectives, standards and policies of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Development: The word "development" shall mean and refer to the carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning regulations (i.e., Chapter 33 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida) or making any material change in the use or character of the land, including, but not limited to, the placement of a structure or structures on land. When appropriate to the context, development refers to the act of zoning or rezoning through district boundary changes, or otherwise, which authorizes or permits development of the land.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Developments of County impact: The words "developments of County impact" shall mean and refer to any development which, because of its character, magnitude or location, would have a substantial effect upon the health, safety and welfare of the citizens of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida. Development activity that meets one (1) of the following criteria shall be deemed "developments of County impact," and shall be accompanied by a developmental impact statement:<section prefix='(1)'>Residential apartment developments involving in excess of eight hundred (800) units or one hundred (100) acres;</section><section prefix='(2)'>All types of cluster or planned unit developments in excess of eight hundred (800) units;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Business uses involving in excess of thirty (30) acres or one hundred fifty thousand (150,000) square feet of retail floor area, or one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Mobile home parks involving in excess of one hundred (100) acres or eight hundred (800) mobile home units;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Townhouse developments involving in excess of one hundred (100) acres or eight hundred (800) units.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Recreational, cultural or entertainment facilities (exclusive of golf courses) involving in excess of one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity for single performances or fifty (50) acres;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Office buildings or office complexes involving in excess of twenty (20) acres or two hundred fifty thousand (250,000) square feet of floor space, or one thousand five hundred (1,500) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Industrial, processing or manufacturing activity involving in excess of one hundred (100) acres, or one thousand (1,000) vehicle off-street parking space capacity;</section><section prefix='(9)'>All developments in lands designated as the Rapid Transit Development Impact Zone as defined in Section 33C-3 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Developmental Impact Committee (Committee): The words "Developmental Impact Committee (Committee)" shall mean and refer to the Miami-Dade County Administrative Committee, created by Ordinance No. 74-47 of the Board of County Commissioners, adopted on June 18, 1974 [Section 33-36.1].</section><section prefix='(f)'>Developmental impact statement: The words "developmental impact statement" shall mean and refer to the information required to be completed by rule and regulations of the Developmental Impact Committee as approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners for Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Unit: The word "unit" shall mean or refer to a house, apartment, group of rooms or a single room occupied or intended for permanent or transient occupancy as separate living quarters.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Zoning action: First municipal action approving request(s) for district boundary change, special exception, variance, or the like, or any combination thereof, which would permit a development of County impact within a municipality in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-52, ยง 5, 7-2-75; Ord. No. 78-74, ยง 2, 10-17-78)</history></law>