<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative intent, findings and purposes.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004623</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-1. Legislative intent, findings and purposes.<section prefix='(a)'>The health, safety, welfare, comfort and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County are dependent upon the orderly development and minimal degradation of the natural ecosystems of certain lands in Miami-Dade County; and the health, safety, welfare, comfort and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County require that the natural ecosystems in certain lands in Miami-Dade County remain functionally intact; and the maintenance of the present hydrology (both surface and subsurface) within certain lands in Miami-Dade County is vital to the health, safety and welfare of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County; and the protection of the ecological form and functions of the Everglades National Park and its estuarine areas and adjacent wetlands is vital to the health, safety, welfare, comfort and convenience of the present and future residents of Miami-Dade County and is inextricably related to certain lands in Miami-Dade County; and land use regulations and performance standards, which are part of a land and water management system, are necessary in certain areas of Miami-Dade County to insure the orderly, well-planned development of those lands and to protect the public interests specified; and the Home Rule Charter for Metropolitan Miami-Dade County specifically authorizes the Board of County Commissioners to prepare and enforce comprehensive plans for the development of Miami-Dade County; to provide and regulate water supply and conservation programs; to establish, coordinate and enforce comprehensive plans for the development of Miami-Dade County; to provide and regulate water supply and conservation programs; to establish, coordinate and enforce zoning as is necessary for the protection of the public, and to exercise all powers and privileges granted to municipalities, counties and county offices by the Constitution and laws of the State, and all powers not prohibited by the Constitution or by the Charter, and to perform any other acts consistent with law which are required by the Charter or which are in the common interest of the people of the County; and this chapter is declared to be a proper and necessary exercise of the aforesaid powers.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The statements aforesaid made are declared to be the legislative intent, findings and purposes of the Board of County Commissioners and are hereby adopted and made a part hereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-49, ยง 1, 6-19-75)</history></law>