<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='2'>Chapter 33C FIXED-GUIDEWAY RAPID TRANSIT SYSTEM—DEVELOPMENT ZONE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33C-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Rapid Transit Zone.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004630</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33C-2. Rapid Transit Zone.<section prefix='(A)'>Definition. The "Rapid Transit Zone" consists of all land area, including surface, subsurface, and appurtenant airspace, heretofore or hereafter designated by the Board of County Commissioners as necessary for the construction of the fixed-guideway portion of the Stage I Rapid Transit System, including all station sites, parking areas and yard and maintenance shop facilities.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Designation of lands included. The Board of County Commissioners hereby designates all land areas (including surface, subsurface, and appurtenant airspace) shown on Exhibits 1 through 16, bearing the following effective dates: Exhibit 1, July 31, 1998, Exhibits 2 through 9 and Exhibits 11 through 16, July 13, 1979 and Exhibit 10, May 26, 1983, certified by the Clerk of the Board as a portion of this chapter, incorporated hereby by reference, and transmitted to the custody of the Department of Planning and Zoning, as the Rapid Transit Zone for the Stage I Fixed-Guideway Rapid Transit System. The Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning shall submit to each affected municipality an official map or maps designating the Rapid Transit Zone which may from time to time be altered, enlarged, added to, amended or deleted by ordinance, after a public hearing within each municipality affected.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Jurisdiction of County. Jurisdiction for purposes of building and zoning approvals (including, but not limited to, site plan approvals, issuance of building permits, building inspections, compliance with the South Florida Building Code, issuance of certificates of occupancy, zoning applications, special exceptions, variances, district boundary changes, building and/or zoning moratoria, and all other types of functions typically performed by Building and/or Zoning Departments), water and sewer installations, compliance with environmental regulations, street maintenance (including sidewalks where applicable) and utility regulation, all of which relate to the uses specifically delineated in subsection (D) below, shall be and are hereby vested in Miami-Dade County regardless of any municipal code, charter, or ordinance provisions to the contrary.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Permitted land uses. The following land uses are permitted within the Rapid Transit Zone and no others:<section prefix='(1)'>Fixed guideways for the Rapid Transit System.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Stations for the Rapid Transit System, including such uses as passenger platforms and waiting areas, ticket and information booths, restrooms, utility rooms, in-station advertising displays, stairs, elevators, walkways, concessions, vending machines, and other service-related businesses offering goods and services for sale to passengers, and other similar uses as are necessary for or ancillary to the proper functioning of a rapid transit station.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Parking lots and parking structures.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Bus stops and shelters.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Streets and sidewalks.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Maintenance facilities for the Rapid Transit System, including yard and shops, and associated tracks and facilities.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Landscaping.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Bikeways, parks, community gardening, playgrounds, power substations and other uses necessary for the construction, operation and maintenance of the Rapid Transit System.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Such other uses, including commercial, office and residential uses, as may be appropriate to and compatible with the operation of the Rapid Transit System and the convenience of the ridership thereof.<section prefix='(b)'>Subzones; development regulations, standards and criteria. In the unincorporated areas of the Rapid Transit Zone, subzones shall be created by separate ordinances which shall become part of this chapter. Said ordinances shall identify the boundaries of the individual subzones and shall establish development regulations and site plan review standards and criteria for those land uses permitted pursuant to subsection (9)(a) herein and approved pursuant to subsection (9)(c) herein.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Requests for approval of development of those land uses permitted pursuant to subsection (9)(a) herein within a subzone created pursuant to subsection (9)(b) herein shall be made by filing an application in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-304. Said application shall be considered a special exception for site plan approval to be considered and acted upon directly by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to the criteria established in Section 33-311(d) and the provisions of the applicable subzone.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Whenever uses authorized by subparagraph (a) above are proposed within portions of the Rapid Transit Zone passing through municipalities, the Station Area Design and Development Program process, a joint municipal-County program administered through the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee, shall prepare proposed master plan development standards for such proposed uses. Such proposed master plan development standards shall be submitted to the appropriate municipality for review and adoption as the Master Land Use Plan for such uses. Once adopted, said land use plans shall control all public actions involving or affecting land use or development, including action on applications for zoning relief. Amendments to said Master Land Use Plans shall be subject to the procedures specified in this subparagraph. Applications for a site plan approval and other related zoning actions under a Master Land Use Plan that was approved by a municipality on or before September 30, 2003, shall be considered by the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee under the standards and requirements established by such plan, upon receipt of the recommendations of the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Miami-Dade Transit Agency. Decisions of the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee upon such applications shall be subject to appeal to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with the requirements of Section 33-314, Miami-Dade County Code. It shall be the duty of the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners to immediately transmit to the relevant municipality a certified copy of the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee's and the County Commission's actions in regard to the uses provided for in this subsection. An aggrieved party may seek judicial review of the County Commission's action in accordance with Section 33-316, Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section prefix='(e)'>After March 15, 2008, (the effective date of this ordinance), whenever uses authorized by subparagraph (a) above are proposed within portions of the Rapid Transit Zone located within the City of Miami not yet subject to an approved set of development standards, the master plan development standards set forth in Section 33C-8 herein shall control such proposed uses. Said land use plans shall control all public actions involving or affecting land use or development, including action on applications for zoning relief. Amendments to said Master Land Use Plans shall be subject to the procedures specified in this subparagraph. Applications for site plan approval and other related zoning actions under a Master Land Use Plan shall be considered by the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee under the standards and requirements established by such plan, upon receipt of the recommendations of the Department of Planning and Zoning and the Miami-Dade Transit Agency. Decisions of the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee upon such applications shall be subject to appeal to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with the requirements of Section 33-314, Miami-Dade County Code. It shall be the duty of the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners to immediately transmit to the City of Miami a certified copy of the decision of the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee and the actions of the Board of County Commissioners in regard to the uses provided for in this subsection. An aggrieved party may seek judicial review of the County Commission's action in accordance with Section 33-316, Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The uses provided in this subsection shall, where applicable, be subject to municipal ordinances relating to occupational license taxes, and such taxes be and they are hereby expressly reserved to such municipalities.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>County government office development in the Rapid Transit Zone within municipalities. Whenever County office development is proposed for that portion of the Rapid Transit Zone surrounding the Douglas Road Metrorail Station, the directors of the Departments of Planning and Zoning, the Miami-Dade Transit Agency and the department proposing the development shall develop proposed master plan development standards for such proposed uses. The standards shall contain, at a minimum: (a) maximum height of the building; (b) maximum floor area ratio; (c) maximum parking provided; (d) minimum open space; (e) minimum setbacks from property lines; (f) gross and net land area; (g) criteria for pedestrian and vehicular circulation systems; (h) signage criteria; (i) criteria for parking layouts and drives; and (j) features demonstrating conformity with the guidelines for development of urban centers contained in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, conformity with the Miami-Dade County Urban Design Manual, and consistency with the Metrorail Compendium of Design Criteria. Upon the consent of the county manager, the proposed standards shall be submitted to the affected municipality's governing board for review and approval.<section>In reviewing the standards, the municipality shall consider the type of function involved, the public need therefor, the existing land use pattern in the area and the nature of the impact of the facility on the surrounding property. The municipal governing board shall have the power to approve or reject the standards, but shall not modify the standards as submitted. Unless extended by agreement with the County Manager, failure of the municipal governing board to reach a final decision on the proposed development standards within 60 days after receipt of the standards may be deemed by the County to be a lack of objection to the standards as proposed. If the municipal governing board rejects the proposed development standards, the proposed County office development shall not be permitted at the site unless the Board of County Commissioners determines after duly noticed public hearing that the proposed development is of County-wide necessity and significance, and upon such determination approves the development standards in accordance with the criteria applicable to the municipal governing board.</section><section>After approval of the development standards, a site plan consistent with the approved development standards shall be submitted to the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning. After review by the Directors of the Departments of Planning and Zoning, the Miami-Dade Transit Agency and the department seeking development approval, the County Manager may submit the site plan to the Board of County Commissioners with a recommendation for approval.</section><section>The Board of County Commissioners may authorize the development and approve the site plan by resolution following public hearing. The public hearing shall be held upon 15 days' notice of the time and place of the hearing published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, which publication shall include the time and place of hearing before the Board of County Commissioners. A courtesy notice containing general information as to the date, time and place of the hearing, the property location and general nature of the proposed development may be mailed to the property owners of record within a radius of three hundred (300) feet of the property described in the application, or such greater distance as the County Manager may provide; provided, however, that failure to mail or receive such courtesy notice shall not affect any action or proceeding taken hereunder. To provide additional notice to the public, the property may be posted by a sign or signs indicating the action desired and the time and place of public hearing thereon. Failure to post the property shall not affect any action taken hereunder. At the public hearing, the Board shall consider, among other factors, the type of function involved, the public need therefor, the existing land use pattern in the area, alternative locations for the facility and the nature of the impact of the development on the surrounding property.</section><section>This process shall apply only to that portion of the Rapid Transit Zone surrounding the Douglas Road Metrorail Station.</section></section></section><section prefix='(E)'>Effect on existing land uses. All land areas included by this section within the Rapid Transit Zone upon which uses other than those specified in subsection (D) of this section were authorized or permitted prior to October 27, 1978 may be used as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Existing structures. All existing buildings or structures and all uses for which building permits have already been issued prior to the effective date of this article and which have complied with the applicable provisions of the South Florida Building Code, may be continued or constructed in accordance with the approved plans and specifications therefor. Alterations, improvements, or expansions of existing structures shall be subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) hereof.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All other lands. No applications for site or plan approvals and/or building permits shall be issued for new facilities within the Rapid Transit Zone except in the following circumstances:<section prefix='(a)'>The estimated construction cost does not exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) in any consecutive two-year period; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Miami-Dade Transit Agency certifies that approval of the application will not have an adverse impact upon a material element of the Stage I System. The Miami-Dade Transit Agency shall, with respect to any application for which certification is refused, provide a detailed written explanation supporting the refusal to certify and specifying the corrective actions, if any, which would lead to certification. The decision of the Agency may be appealed to the Board of County Commissioners within thirty (30) days from the date of the written explanation by filing a notice of appeal with the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners, after giving public notice as required by Chapter 33 of the Code, shall hear the appeal and either affirm, deny or modify the decision of the Agency. Appeals from the Board of County Commissioners' action shall be in accordance with Section 33-316 of this Code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-74, § 1, 10-17-78; Ord. No. 79-59, § 1, 7-3-79; Ord. No. 82-80, § 1, 9-7-82; Ord. No. 83-27, § 1, 5-17-83; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; 98-114, § 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 98-125, § 24, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-38, § 1, 2-21-00; Ord. No. 02-171, § 1, 9-24-02; Ord. No. 03-113, § 2, 5-6-03; Ord. No. 08-28, § 1, 3-4-08)</history></law>