<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='2'>Chapter 33C FIXED-GUIDEWAY RAPID TRANSIT SYSTEM—DEVELOPMENT ZONE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33C-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Rapid transit zone district regulations for non-Metrorail development within the City of Miami.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004636</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33C-8. Rapid transit zone district regulations for non-Metrorail development within the City of Miami.<section prefix='(A)'>Purpose and intent. The purpose of these development standards is to provide guidelines governing the use, site design, building mass, parking, and circulation for all non-Metrorail development in the Rapid Transit Zone within the City of Miami with the intent of fulfilling the goals, objectives and policies of the County's Comprehensive Development Master Plan urban center text. Unless specified to the contrary, the Rapid Transit Zone District Regulations supersede all conflicting requirements in Chapter 33 and Chapter 18A of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Definitions. Terms used in this section shall take their commonly accepted meaning unless otherwise defined in Chapter 33 or Chapter 28 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, or already defined herein. Terms requiring interpretation specific to this section are as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Arcade/colonnade: A roofed structure, extending over the sidewalk, open to the street except for supporting columns and piers. An arcade/colonnade's depth shall be measured from face of column to face of building. In Metropolitan Urban Centers colonnade depth shall be a minimum of 15 feet and in Community Urban Centers colonnade depth shall be a minimum of 10 feet.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Block: A combination of contiguous building lots, the perimeter of which abuts rights-of-way, drives, or an open space.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Build-to-line: A line parallel to the block face, along which a building shall be built.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Building height: A limit to the vertical extent of a building measured in stories above grade, not including chimneys, antennas, elevator shafts, mechanical rooms or other non-habitable areas.</section><section prefix='(5)'>F.A.R.: The floor area of the building or buildings, excluding parking structures, on any lot divided by the area of the site.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Habitable space: Building space whose use involves human presence. Habitable space shall not include areas devoted to the parking of vehicles in parking garage structures, self-service storage facilities, or warehouses.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Live-work unit: A mixed-use building type with one single-family residential dwelling located above one work space.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Open space: An outdoor, at grade space which is accessible to the public all or most of the time, including parks, plazas, squares, colonnades, greens, promenades, pedestrian paths and/or associated ornamental or shaded landscaped areas.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Penthouse: In a Community Urban Center, the 2 top stories (top 5 stories with Gold LEED Certification; top 3 stories with Silver LEED Certification) of a building with a floorplate area less than that of the tower below. In a Metropolitan Community Urban Center, the 5 top stories (7 top stories for Gold LEED Certification; 6 top stories for Silver LEED Certification) stories of a building with a floorplate area less that that of the tower below.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Pedestal: In a Community Urban Center, the bottom 5 stories (7 stories with Gold LEED Certification; 6 stories with Silver LEED Certification) portion of a building that creates the street frontage. In a Metropolitan Urban Center, the bottom 7 stories (11 stories with Gold LEED Certification; 8 stories with Silver LEED Certification) portion of a building that creates the street frontage.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Plaza: An open space fronted by retail and office uses. A minimum of 50% and a maximum of 75% of the plaza's area, exclusive of dedicated rights-of-way and drives, shall be hard-surfaced. Landscaping shall consist primarily of hard-surfaced areas, permanent architecture or water-oriented features, and trees that are placed in an orderly fashion and that are regularly spaced.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Square: An outdoor open space that shall be flanked by streets or drives on at least 3 sides and shall not be hard-surfaced for more than 50% of the area exclusive of dedicated rights-of-way. Landscaping shall consist primarily of hard-surfaced walks, lawns, and trees that are placed in an orderly fashion and that are regularly spaced.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Story: An enclosed floor level within a building containing habitable space.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Tower: In a Community Urban Center, the middle 8 stories (13 stories with Gold LEED Certification; 11 stories with Silver LEED Certification) portion of a building above the pedestal and below the penthouse. In a Metropolitan Urban Center, the middle 13 stories (22 stories with Gold LEED Certification; 16 stories with Silver LEED Certification) portion of a building above the pedestal and below the penthouse.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Workforce housing unit or WHU: A dwelling unit, the sale, rental or pricing of which, in accordance with this article, is restricted to households whose income is within the workforce housing target income range.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Workforce housing target income range: Households whose income range is established at 65% up to 140% of the most recent median family income for the County reported by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development as maintained by the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Development Parameters. The following parameters shall apply to Rapid Transit Zone Station development provided such uses are compatible with transit uses and operations as determined by the Miami-Dade Transit Agency:<section prefix='(1)'>Permitted Uses. A minimum of two of the following uses shall be included in all Rapid Transit Zone Station development:<section prefix='(a)'>Business and civic uses allowed in the BU-1, BU-1A and BU-2 zoning districts. Drive-thru services are permitted and shall be concealed from the adjoining street network.<section prefix='(i)'>Outside food sales and services including but not limited to outdoor dining, cart vendors, and merchandise displays.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The provisions of Section 33-150(A) and (B) of the Zoning Code regarding alcoholic beverage uses shall not apply.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Residential uses. All residential or mixed-use developments, including those which obtained LEED or similar organization certification, located within any of the Rapid Transit Zones, with more than 4 residential units, shall provide a minimum of 12.5% of their units as work force housing units.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Housing for the elderly.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Setbacks. The setbacks for Rapid Transit Zone station development shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Pedestal build-to-line from streets and drives: 0 feet when colonnade is provided in all urban centers; 15 feet in Metropolitan Urban Centers when colonnade is not provided. 10 feet in Community Urban Centers when colonnade is not provided. The build-to-line setback shall be hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk when a colonnade is not provided.<section>Minimum 10 feet when colonnade is provided in all urban centers; minimum 25 feet in Metropolitan Urban Centers when colonnade is not provided, minimum 20 feet in Community Urban Centers when colonnade is not provided. The build-to-line setback shall be hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk when a colonnade is not provided.</section><section>For up to a minimum of 50% of the building frontage, minimum 20 feet when colonnade is provided in all urban centers; minimum 35 feet in Metropolitan Urban Centers when colonnade is not provided, minimum 30 feet in Community Urban Centers when colonnade is not provided. The build-to-line setback shall be hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk when a colonnade is not provided.</section><section>When nonresidential uses are located across the street from single-family zoned property, the build-to-line shall be 30 feet for the pedestal, except 20 feet if colonnade is provided, a minimum of 40 feet for the tower and a minimum of 50 feet for the penthouse.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Interior side: 0 feet in all urban centers, except 30 feet minimum for all portions of the building including parking structures when adjacent to single-family residential zoned districts.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Rear side: 0 feet minimum in all urban centers including the metrorail station guideway, except 30 feet minimum for all portions of the building including parking structures when adjacent to single-family residential zoned districts</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Floor Area Ratio (F.A.R.). The floor area ratio for Rapid Transit Zone station development shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Community Urban Centers (Civic Center Station; Coconut Grove Station; Culmer Station; the undeveloped portion of Douglas Road Station) shall have a minimum F.A.R. of 1.5.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Density. The maximum densities for Rapid Transit Zone station development shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Metropolitan Urban Centers: 250 units per net acre.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Community Urban Centers: 125 units per net acre.</section><section>A 25% density bonus above the listed maximum urban center densities is permitted for residential rapid transit developments being designed for and having registered for certification for a Gold certification rating from LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) or a similar organization accredited by the U.S. Green Building Council (USGBC). Residential developments being designed and having registered for certification for a Silver Certification rating from LEED or a similar organization accredited by the U.S. Green Building Council (USGBC) are permitted a density bonus of 12.5% above the listed maximum urban center densities.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Building Heights. The maximum building heights for all Rapid Transit Zone station development shall be as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Metropolitan Urban Centers: 25 stories (maximum — 7 stories pedestal, 13 stories tower, 5 stories penthouse)</section><section prefix='(b)'>Community Urban Centers: 15 stories (maximum — 5 stories pedestal, 8 stories tower, 2 stories penthouse)</section><section prefix='(c)'>The maximum building height for the Coconut Grove station shall be 250 feet provided the development is designed and has registered for certification for a Silver Certification rating from LEED or a similar organization accredited by the U.S. Green Building Council (USGBC).</section><section>All rapid transit development having been designed and having registered for a certification rating from LEED or a similar organization accredited by the USGBC is permitted an increase in the number of allowable stories as follows:</section><section prefix='(a)'>Metropolitan Urban Centers: a total of 30 stories (maximum — 8 stories pedestal, 16 stories tower, 6 stories penthouse) with Silver Certification; 40 stories (maximum — 11 stories pedestal, 22 stories tower, 7 stories penthouse) with Gold Certification</section><section prefix='(b)'>Community Urban Centers: a total of 20 stories (maximum — 6 stories pedestal, 11 stories tower, 3 stories penthouse) with Silver Certification; 25 stories (maximum — 7 stories pedestal, 13 stories tower, 5 stories penthouse) with Gold Certification</section><section>Each story shall have a maximum height of 16 feet, as measured from floor to floor, except that a single story may have a maximum height of 30 feet, provided no mezzanine area exceeds 10% of the floor area of that story. Any height above 16 feet shall count as an additional story.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Building Frontage. 80% minimum at build-to-line for all Rapid Transit Zone station developments. Habitable space is required along the entire ground floor portion of all buildings including parking garages.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Parking. The minimum parking requirements for all Rapid Transit Zone station development shall be provided as specified in Section 33-124 of the Zoning Code, except as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Residential: 1 parking space for 1-bedroom units; 1.5 parking spaces for 2-bedroom units; 1.75 parking spaces for 3 or more bedroom units; and 0.5 parking spaces for housing for the elderly.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Workforce housing units: Workforce housing units may reduce the parking requirements of this section by 0.25 spaces/unit.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Retail: 1 parking space for each 250 square feet of gross floor area.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Restaurants: 1 parking space for each 50 square feet of patron area.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Office: 1 parking space for each 400 square feet of gross floor area.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Hotel: 1 parking space for first 40 guest rooms and one additional space for every 2 guest rooms or suites thereafter.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Live-work units: residential component: 2 spaces per unit; workshop component: 1 space for 325 square feet of workshop area.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The minimum combined parking requirement for mixed-use development shall be as follows:</section><section>Multi-story parking garage structures shall be screened along all frontages (streets and common open spaces), except along a service road or a pedestrian passage, by a liner building containing a minimum depth of 20 feet of habitable space. Parking garages shall have all architectural expression facing public open space consistent and harmonious with that of habitable space.</section><section>Surface parking shall be located a minimum of 20 feet from property lines. Streetwalls and/or habitable space shall be built at the frontage line or at the build-to-line to screen parking from view.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>Encroachments. Awnings, balconies, roof eaves, signs, porches, stoops and ramps may encroach into setbacks. Awnings, balconies, roof eaves and signs may encroach into rights-of-way; however, they shall not extend a distance closer than 6 inches from the curb face. All right-of-way encroachments shall be a minimum of 132 inches above the sidewalk. Encroachments shall not be taller than the building or pedestal, whichever is lower. Cantilevers and mouldings shall not exceed 3 feet in extension beyond the vertical wall surface, unless visibly supported by brackets or other supports.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Building Facades.<section prefix='(a)'>Building streetwall surfaces shall be a minimum 30% glazed. Mirror-type glass shall not be allowed. All glazing shall be of a type that permits view of human activities and spaces within. The first floor streetwall shall be a minimum 30% glazed. Glazing shall be clear or very lightly tinted for the first 5 stories, except where used for screening garages where it may be translucent.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Security screens and gates shall be a minimum 50% transparent.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Colonnade column spacing, windows, and doors shall have a vertical proportion.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Open Space. A minimum of 15% of the lot area shall be reserved for open space in the form of greens, squares, plazas, parks, promenades and pedestrian paths. It shall be at grade level and it shall be accessible to the public. Arcades/colonnades shall count toward meeting the minimum open space requirements. Parking lot buffers shall not count toward the open space requirement.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Landscape. Landscape shall be provided in accordance with Chapter 18A (Landscape Code) of Miami-Dade County with the following exceptions:<section prefix='(a)'>Street trees shall be placed along all streets at an average spacing of 25 feet on center with a minimum 4-inch diameter at breast height.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Street trees shall not be required when colonnades are being provided along the street.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Tree requirements for private property shall be based on 16 trees per net acre of lot area.</section></section><section prefix='(12)'>Pedestrian Passage. A pedestrian passage shall be required every 400 linear feet of street frontage to allow public access through the site. The passage shall be minimum unobstructed 8 feet wide.</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Site Plan Review Standards and Criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination, and variety in the design process in an attempt to ensure congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. The following site plan review standards shall be utilized as a guide by the Miami-Dade Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee, the Miami-Dade Department of Planning and Zoning, and by the Board of County Commissioners in the consideration for site plan approval for all Rapid Transit Zone stations: All development in the Rapid Transit Zone shall be designed to contribute to the creation of a high-quality pedestrian environment within the zone and along its perimeter and provide direct logistical connections between the transit station and the adjacent neighborhood.<section prefix='(1)'>Design considerations shall include: the placement, orientation and scale of buildings and building elements particularly at street level, sidewalks and connections, and provisions of weather protection, landscape, and lighting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The architectural design and scale of any proposed structure shall be compatible with surrounding existing or proposed uses or shall be made compatible by the use of screening elements. Screening elements can include such devices as trees and shrubs, walls and fencing, berming or any combination of these elements. Visual buffering shall be provided between parking and service areas and adjacent uses.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All buildings shall have their main entrance opening to a street or meaningful open space from such as squares, parks, greens, plazas and promenades. In addition, there shall be pedestrian entrances at maximum intervals of 75' along the street.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Building placement shall architecturally define transit station entrance plazas, fare collection areas, and platforms. Habitable space shall front entrance plazas, fare collection areas, and platforms to promote pedestrian activity between the development and the transit station.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Colonnade column spacing and fenestration (doors, windows, openings) shall have a vertical proportion.</section><section prefix='(6)'>All developments shall have sidewalks or pedestrian paths a minimum 8' wide providing pedestrian linkages between the transit station and anticipated destinations in the Rapid Transit Zone and the adjacent neighborhoods.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Buildings and their pedestrian accommodations, landscapes and parking facilities shall be oriented and arranged toward the street, contribute to spatial enclosure of street space in and around the Subzone, blocks and pedestrian pathways in the Rapid Transit Zone, and shall produce coherent, direct connections within the site and to the adjacent streets, sidewalks and paths.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Building architecture, exterior finish materials and textures, architectural elements and ornamentation shall be selected to produce human scale at street level.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Open spaces and landscaping should be incorporated into the design of all development projects to allow sufficient light and air to penetrate the project, to direct wind movements, to shade and cool, to visually enhance architectural features and relate the structure design to the site, and to functionally enhance the projects. Outdoor graphics and exterior art displays and water features should be encouraged to be designed as an integral part of the open space and landscaped areas.</section><section prefix='(10)'>All development projects should be designed so as to reduce energy consumption. Energy conservation methods may include, without limitation, the natural ventilation of structures, the siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles, and the provision of landscaping for shade and transpiration.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Public open spaces in the form of squares, plazas, greens, etc., shall be connected to the station and proposed development, so as to provide easy access thereto. A sprinkler system shall be installed in all of the proposed landscaped areas to maintain said areas in good, healthy condition.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Service areas shall be located and screened to minimize negative visual impacts from the street.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Mechanical equipment installed on roofs shall be screened from view by parapets or other architectural elements.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Trees shall be used as a design element to provide visual identity to the property and reinforce the street edge. Tree grates or other approved devices shall be provided around all trees in hard surface areas to ensure adequate water and air penetration.</section><section prefix='(15)'>All utilities on site shall be buried underground.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Adequate circulation throughout the development project shall be provided to accommodate emergency vehicles.</section><section prefix='(17)'>The development shall be designed with a coordinated outdoor pedestrian-scaled lighting system that is adequate, integrated into the project and compatible and harmonious with the surrounding areas.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Street furniture such as trash containers and benches shall be permanently secured to the sidewalk. Street furniture shall not obstruct sight visibility triangles at street intersections.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Dumpsters shall not be visible from the public street.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Architectural elements at street level shall have human scale, abundant windows, doors and design variations to create interest for the pedestrian. Blank walls at street level and above the ground floor of buildings are not permitted.</section><section prefix='(21)'>All parking garages shall have all architectural expressions facing public open spaces consistent and harmonious with that of habitable spaces.</section></section><section prefix='(E)'>Site Review Procedure and Exhibits. Development proposal shall be submitted and reviewed as provided in Section 33-304, Code of Miami-Dade County, and herein:<section prefix='(1)'>Preapplication Conference. Prior to the filing of an application for site plan approval, the prospective applicant shall schedule a preapplication conference with the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning for preliminary review of a conceptual development plan. The Department of Planning and Zoning shall notify the Miami-Dade Transit Agency, Miami-Dade County and affected municipal Departments of Public Works, as well as other Miami-Dade County and municipal agencies, as appropriate. Said agencies and departments shall be requested to provide current information about any government-planned street improvements, and any street section standards that would be applicable, on streets adjoining the proposed development site. The applicant shall bring to the conference a schematic development plan illustrating fundamentals of the proposed site design and architecture, addressing locations of existing and planned property lines, property ownership, public right-of-way, streets, transit platform, buildings and open spaces, and other essential elements of the proposed development with sufficient information to demonstrate an understanding of the intent, standards and criteria established in this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Application Exhibits. The exhibits listed below shall be submitted with the formal application for site plan review. The Department of Planning and Zoning shall review the application, including these exhibits, for completeness as required to determine compliance with all requirements of this Section. The Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning is authorized to waive any of the items required because of the nature or timing of the development or because the information cannot be furnished at the time of this review, provided the Director determines that the information is not necessary to a determination of conformance with the requirements of the Section. The exhibits shall include the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Site plan(s) at a scale of not less than 1 inch equals 60 feet containing the following information:<section prefix='(i)'>Location of existing and planned streets and curb lines.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Location of lot lines and setbacks.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Location, shape, size, and height, as applicable, of existing and proposed buildings, open spaces, fencing, walls, projections, signage, and landscaping.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Location of on-street and off-street parking, loading facilities, and waste collection areas.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Phase lines, if applicable.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Landscape plans, including specification of plant material, location, and size.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including total gross square foot area of each floor and all dimensions relating to the requirements of this Section.</section><section prefix='(viii)'>Figures indicating gross and net acreage, and area to be dedicated for public right-of-way.</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Square footage of each land use and total for the development.</section><section prefix='(x)'>Total number of dwelling units and hotel guest rooms if applicable.</section><section prefix='(xi)'>Amount of building coverage at ground level in square feet and percentage of net lot area.</section><section prefix='(xii)'>Amount of open space required and provided, in square feet and percentage of net lot area.</section><section prefix='(xiii)'>Number of parking spaces required and provided.</section></section></section></section><section prefix='(F)'>Conflicts with Other Chapters and Regulations. This article shall govern in the event of conflicts with other zoning, subdivision, or landscape regulations of the Zoning Code, or with the Miami-Dade Public Works Department Manual.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-28, § 3, 3-4-08)</history></law>