<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='2'>Chapter 33C FIXED-GUIDEWAY RAPID TRANSIT SYSTEM—DEVELOPMENT ZONE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33C-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Corridor Subzone.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004635</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33C-7. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Corridor Subzone.<section prefix='(1)'>Boundaries. Pursuant to the provisions of Section 33C-2(D)9(b), the Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Corridor Subzone (MLK Corridor Subzone) of the Rapid Transit Zone is hereby established; the boundaries of the Subzone include all portions of the Rapid Transit Zone located north of NW 51st Street and east of NW 32nd Avenue, as described in and incorporated into Section 33C-2(B) hereof; said boundaries shall be certified by the Clerk of the Board as a part of this section, and transmitted to the Department of Planning and Zoning for custody.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Development regulations. The following development regulations shall apply within the MLK Corridor Subzone, except for the Brownsville and Martin Luther King Jr. Stations, which development shall comply with the Model City Urban Center District regulations set forth in Chapter 33, Article XXXIII(R) of this Code, and except for the Northside Station, which development shall comply with the North Central Urban Area District regulations set forth in Chapter 33, Article XXXIII(S) of this Code:<section prefix='(a)'>Mixed uses, as provided by Section 33C-2(D)(9)(a) shall be permitted, said uses including, but not limited to, residential, office, hotel, clubs, restaurants, theatres, retail, etc.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Parking for single use projects shall be provided at no less than ninety (90) percent or no greater than one hundred ten (110) percent of the following standards:<section prefix='i.'>Residential—One (1) parking space for each dwelling unit.</section><section prefix='ii.'>Office—One (1) parking space for each four hundred (400) square feet of gross floor area.</section><section prefix='iii.'>Hotel—One (1) parking space for every two (2) guestrooms.</section><section prefix='iv.'>Other uses—Ninety (90) percent of the required parking per Section 33-124</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Parking for mixed-use projects (two (2) or more land uses) shall be calculated by applying the ULI Shared Parking Methodology (Library of Congress Card Number 83 51648) to the parking requirements as specified above. Parking shall fulfill between ninety (90) percent and one hundred ten (110) percent of the ULI calculation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Setbacks. See site plan review standards and criteria herein.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The maximum floor area ratio shall not exceed 3.0.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The maximum building height shall not exceed one hundred fifty (150) feet.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The minimum open space shall be twenty-five (25) percent; said open space may be provided at grade or on abovegrade surfaces, provided that at least fifteen (15) percent is outdoor at grade, and shall include landscape areas improved and maintained with grass, shrubbery, and trees, water fountains and features, art displays, and other landscape elements and features.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Sign(s), to direct traffic flow and locate entrances and exits to developments and/or to identify developments within the subzone area and on abutting properties shall be permitted in connection with any permitted use. Said signs shall be reviewed by the Department of Planning and Zoning and Miami-Dade Transit Agency for compliance with the standards and criteria set forth in Section 33C-7(3) below.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Site plan review standards and criteria. The purpose of the site plan review is to encourage logic, imagination and variety in the design process in an attempt to insure the congruity of the proposed development and its compatibility with the surrounding area. The following site plan review standards and criteria shall be utilized as a guide by the Developmental Impact Committee or the Department of Planning and Zoning and by the Board of County Commissioners in the consideration of requests for special exception for site plan approvals within the MLK Corridor Subzone, except for the Brownsville and Martin Luther King Jr. Stations, which development shall comply with the Model City Urban Center District regulations set forth in Chapter 33, Article XXXIII(R) of this Code, and except for the Northside Station, which development shall comply with the North Central Urban Area District regulations set forth in Chapter 33, Article XXXIII(S) of this Code:<section prefix='(a)'>All development shall conform foremost with the guidelines for development of Urban Centers contained in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan, and shall be reviewed for its compatibility with the Miami-Dade County Urban Design Manual, the Metrorail compendium of design criteria, and the applicable station area design and development plan.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Mixed, twenty-four-hour activity uses should be encouraged to be incorporated into the design of development projects.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Setbacks may not be required due to the unique locational characteristics associated with the MLK Corridor Subzone site; however, building locations shall be reviewed to assure compatibility with surrounding existing, proposed, and anticipated development and uses and to assure that no visual or other safety hazards are created in connection with existing, proposed, and anticipated pedestrian and vehicular circulation systems.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Pedestrian open space, in the form of plazas, arcades, courtyards, landscaped areas, etc., particularly at the level of the station, with convenient connections between the station and restaurants, theatres, retail uses, etc., so as to provide easy access thereto, should be encouraged to be incorporated into the design of all development projects.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The scale of all development projects should be designed to be compatible with surrounding existing, proposed, and anticipated development and uses, and, therein, step-down buildings may be encouraged to be incorporated into the design of the project, and all development should be architecturally and aesthetically compatible with the station and enhance the surrounding area.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Open space and landscaping should be incorporated into the design of all development projects to allow sufficient light and air to penetrate the project, to direct wind movements, to shade and cool, to visually enhance architectural features and relate the structure design to the site, and to functionally enhance the projects; outdoor graphics and exterior art displays and water features should be encouraged to be designed as an integral part of the open space and landscaped areas.</section><section prefix='(g)'>All development projects should be designed so as to reduce energy consumption. Energy conservation methods may include, but not be limited to, the natural ventilation of structures, the siting of structures in relation to prevailing breezes and sun angles, and the provision of landscaping for shade and transpiration.</section><section prefix='(h)'>All development projects should be designed so that the pedestrian and vehicular circulation systems adequately serve the needs of the project and are compatible and functional with the circulation systems exterior to the site.</section><section prefix='(i)'>All development projects should be designed with a coordinated outdoor lighting and signage system that is adequate for and an integral part of the project and that is compatible and harmonious with the project and the surrounding area.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-161, § 1, 11-16-99; Ord. No. 10-13, § 8, 2-2-10; Ord. No. 11-65, § 8, 8-2-11)</history></law>