<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='2'>Chapter 33D BISCAYNE BAY MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SHORELINE DEVELOPMENT REVIEW</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33D-33</section_number>
<catch_line>Shoreline Development Review Committee established; organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004645</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33D-33. Shoreline Development Review Committee established; organization.<section prefix='(a)'>There is hereby established a Biscayne Bay Shoreline Development Review Committee composed of thirteen (13) members, nine (9) of whom shall be recognized professionals in one or more of the following fields: architecture, landscape architecture and urban design, and four (4) of whom shall be laypersons with a demonstrated interest in the preservation of the shoreline environment and its natural, aesthetic and recreational values, and in the design, construction and protection of facilities and amenities in the vicinity of the shoreline. The Board of County Commissioners shall invite the cities of Bay Harbor Islands, Miami, Miami Beach, Coral Gables, Miami Shores, Bal Harbour, North Miami, North Miami Beach, North Bay Village, Key Biscayne, and Surfside to submit one (1) recommended candidate for membership on this Committee. The Biscayne Bay Shoreline Development Review Committee may be expanded to fifteen (15) members solely for purposes of considering development actions and plans which involve real property lying within the boundaries of any individual shoreline municipality. In such instances two (2) additional members who are recognized professionals in one or more of the following fields—architecture, landscape architecture and urban design—may be appointed by the local governing body of the municipality and may participate as full members. The method of appointment and term of office of said additional members shall be determined at the discretion of the local governing body of the municipality. Said appointments may be made for a specified term or may be limited to a single development action or plan.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Seven (7) members shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners to serve for two (2) years and six (6) shall be appointed to serve three (3) years. At the end of the initial two-year period, successors to the initial two-year appointments shall be appointed for three (3) years. The process of appointment and other requirements of Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be followed. At its first meeting in each calendar year, the Committee shall elect a Chairman and a Vice-Chairman. A simple majority of the Committee members shall constitute a quorum and a simple majority of Committee members present shall be required for the passage of any motion. Where the membership of the Biscayne Bay Shoreline Development Review Committee has been expanded to include municipal appointees as provided in subsection (a), above, a simple majority of the Committee members shall constitute a quorum and a simple majority of Committee members present shall be required for the passage of any motion.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County Manager shall designate a person to serve as the County Staff Coordinator for the Committee. Administrative and secretarial staff shall be provided by the County. For all proposed development actions and plans located within unincorporated Miami-Dade County, the following Miami-Dade County departments shall provide the staff reviews: Environmental Resources Management, Park and Recreation, Planning and Zoning and Public Works. These departments shall also provide similar professional staff support for any municipality which has not submitted an agreement to the County in accordance with the provisions of Section 33D-36 hereinbelow.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-14, § 3, 3-5-85; Ord. No. 86-46, § 1, 6-17-86; Ord. No. 91-132, § 1, 11-5-91; Ord. No. 94-3, § 1, 1-18-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 25, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-77, § 1, 6-6-00)</history></law>