<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='2'>Chapter 33D BISCAYNE BAY MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33D-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Boundaries of Management Area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004638</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33D-2. Boundaries of Management Area.<section>The Biscayne Bay Management Area includes all of the land, water and submerged lands within the boundary legally described as: Begin at the point of intersection of the north Miami-Dade County line with the centerline of Biscayne Boulevard (State Road No. 5); thence run easterly along the north Miami-Dade County line to the centerline of Ocean Boulevard (State Road A1A); thence run southerly along the centerline of Ocean Boulevard and Collins Avenue to the centerline of 63rd Street (Miami Beach); thence run westerly along the centerline of 63rd Street to the centerline of Alton Road; thence run southerly along the centerline of Alton Road and its southerly extension along Jefferson Avenue to the centerline of Biscayne Street; thence run easterly along the centerline of Biscayne Street and its easterly extension to the easterly mean high water line of Miami Beach; thence run southerly along the easterly mean high water line of Miami Beach to Government Cut; thence run southerly across Government Cut to the easterly mean high water line of Fisher Island; thence run southerly along the easterly mean high water line of Fisher Island to Norris Cut; thence run southwesterly across Norris Cut to the easterly mean high water line of Virginia Key; thence run southerly and southwesterly along the easterly mean high water line of Virginia Key to the south line of, Township 54 South, Range 42 East; thence southerly across Bear Cut to the south line of, Township 54 South, Range 42 East; thence southerly for a distance of 2,250 feet to a point 2,325 feet east of the centerline of Crandon Boulevard; thence westerly to the centerline of Crandon Boulevard; thence run southerly along the centerline of Crandon Boulevard to the northerly boundary of Cape Florida State Park; thence run easterly along said northerly boundary to the easterly mean high water line of Key Biscayne; thence run southerly along said easterly mean high water line of Key Biscayne to a point east of Cape Florida Lighthouse near the southerly tip of Key Biscayne; thence run southerly along straight lines connecting the most easterly points of the easterly mean high water lines of Soldier Key, the Ragged Keys, and Sands Key to the easterly mean high water line of Elliott Key; thence run southerly and southwesterly along the easterly mean highwater line of Elliott Key; thence run southwesterly to the easterly mean high water line of Old Rhodes Key; thence run southwesterly along the easterly mean high water line of Old Rhodes Key to the southerly tip of Old Rhodes Key; thence run due southwest to the centerline of Broad Creek; thence run northwesterly along the centerline of Broad Creek and along the southerly boundary line of Biscayne National Park and its westerly extension to the mean high water line on the western shore of Biscayne Bay in, Township 58 South, Range 40 East; thence run southwesterly along said mean high water line to its intersection with the west line of said; thence run north along the west line of said to the southeast corner of the north one-half of, Township 58 South, Range 40 East; thence run west along the south line of the north one-half of said to the west line of said; thence run northerly along the west line of Sections 22, 15, 10, and 3, Township 58 South, Range 40 East to the southwest corner of Section 34, Township 57 South, Range 40 East; thence run easterly along the south line of said Section 34 for 1,670.00 feet to a point; thence run northerly parallel with the west line of said Section 34 for 1,720.00 feet; thence deflect left 35 degrees, and run northwesterly 1,500.00 feet to a point; thence run northerly parallel with the west line of said Section 34 for 820.00 feet to a point; thence deflect right 45 degrees, 00 minutes and run approximately 1,450 feet to a point located 1,800.00 feet east of the west line and 650.00 feet south of the north line of said Section 34; thence run northerly parallel with the west line of said Section 34 to the north line of said Section 34; thence continue northerly parallel with the west line of, Township 57 South, Range 40 East to a point located 1,550.00 feet north of the south line of said and 1,800.00 feet east of the west line of said; thence deflect left approximately 43 degrees, 00 minutes and run northwesterly to a point located 2,300.00 feet north of the south lines of said and 1,150.00 feet east of the west line of said; thence run westerly 2,300.00 feet north of and parallel to the south lines of Sections 27 and 28, Township 57 South, Range 40 East to a point located northeast of 100.00 feet as measured 90 degrees, 00 minutes from the centerline of the extension of the Palm Drive access road to the FPL Turkey Point Power Plant; thence run northwesterly parallel with and 100.00 feet northeasterly of the centerline of said Palm Drive access road to the north line of said; thence run westerly along the north lines of; thence run westerly along the north lines of Sections 28 and 29, Township 57 South, Range 40 East to the eastern boundary of Levee 31E; thence run northerly along Levee 31E to the centerline of Old Cutler Road; thence run northeasterly and northerly along the centerline of Old Cutler Road to the centerline of LeJeune Road; thence run northerly along the centerline of LeJeune Road to the centerline of West Ingraham Terrace; thence run easterly along the centerline of West Ingraham Terrace to the centerline of Ingraham Highway; thence run northeasterly along the centerline of Ingraham Highway to the centerline of Douglas Road; thence run northerly along the centerline of Douglas Road to the centerline of Main Highway; thence run northeasterly along the centerline of Main Highway to the centerline of McFarlane Road; thence run southeasterly along the centerline of McFarlane Road to the centerline of South Bayshore Drive; thence run northeasterly along the centerline of South Bayshore Drive and South Miami Avenue to the centerline of State Road No. 5; thence run northeasterly and northerly along the centerline of State Road No. 5 to the point of beginning.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-19, ยง 2, 3-3-81; Ord. No. 00-77, ยง 1, 6-6-00)</history></law>