<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00071' order_by='00071' level='2'>Chapter 33D BISCAYNE BAY MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SHORELINE DEVELOPMENT REVIEW</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33D-32</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004644</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33D-32. Definitions.<section>[As used in this article, the following terms shall have the meanings herein ascribed to them unless the context requires otherwise:]</section><section>Any structure other than the principal building on a lot or parcel which is subordinate to or not a part of the principal building.</section><section>A water area in Biscayne Bay defined by the mainland on the west, the barrier islands on the east, and causeways or natural banks on the north and south.</section><section>Biscayne Bay and the northern embayments of Dumfoundling Bay, Maule Lake and Little Maule Lake and the Intracoastal Waterway from NE 163 Street to the Broward County line.</section><section>The carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning regulations (i.e., of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or municipal codes), or making any material change in the use or character of the upland or submerged land, including but not limited to the placement of structures on the upland, or on or over submerged lands.</section><section>Any standard form coastal construction permit as defined in of the Miami-Dade County Code or any plat approval; building permit; zoning permit or approval, rezoning or district boundary change; variance; special exception; conditional permit; unusual use; special use permit or any other zoning action that would alter the outside configuration of any building, structure or ancillary structure or change the existing grade elevation or use of any parcel within the shoreline development review boundary.</section><section>The established grade of the premises, whether vacant or improved, is the highest elevation of the centerline of the existing (or proposed) roadway adjacent to the property.</section><section>A document, area study or map prepared by a private or public entity for or at the request of, a unit of government. Such plans may include goals and objectives, policy statements, guidelines and recommended implementation methods. Such plans shall include the land use master plan amendments as described in the Florida Local Government Comprehensive Planning Act (Florida Statutes, Chapter 163, Part II) or may be related to specific functions and uses such as, but not limited to, resource use, resources management, transportation, commercial or economic development and park plans. For purposes of this article, this shall not include site or building plans which are submitted as part of an application for development action.</section><section>Any cleared, plowed, bulldozed, filled, graded, excavated, or artificially created paved or unpaved path or way on public property intended or used for the passage of vehicles.</section><section>Defined by the nearest public roadway, or extension of such roadway alignment, paralleling the shoreline of Biscayne Bay and the northern embayments of Dumfoundling Bay, Maule Lake and Little Maule Lake and the Intracoastal Waterway from NE 163 Street to the Broward County line. Where it is not feasible to follow existing road configurations or extensions of those alignments, zoning district boundaries shall be used to define the boundary. The boundary line shall extend southward from the Broward County line to the northern boundary of Biscayne National Park. The Board of County Commissioners hereby designates all land areas shown on Exhibit 1, certified by the Clerk of the Board as a part of the ordinance from which this article derives and incorporated hereby by reference [but not reproduced herein], as the land areas lying within the shoreline development review boundary. The official map shall be transmitted to the custody of the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning, and copies of the official map shall be filed with the Clerk of the Board. The Clerk of the Board shall submit to each affected municipality a copy of the official map which may from time to time be altered, enlarged, added to, amended or deleted by ordinance.</section><section>The horizontal distance between the mean high line, or cap of the bulkhead or top of the riprap and a side of the principal building or accessory structures.</section><section>A document including the following information: location of lot lines and setbacks; location, shape, size and height of structures, decorative walls and entrance features; location of on-site and off-street parking, loading facilities, service areas, and waste collection areas; location of all streets, alleys, driveways, pedestrian ways, and sidewalks.</section><section>An unobstructed area extending from a public right-of-way to the shoreline which is retained at grade and landscaped in such a manner as to permit and encourage views of the water.</section><section>Uses which are not directly dependent upon access to a water body, but which are designed to encourage views, public use and enjoyment of the water's edge, such as restaurants, outdoor cafes and boat rental facilities.</section><section>A use or activity which can be carried out only on, in, or adjacent to water areas because the use requires access to a water body for waterborne transportation, energy production or source of water.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-14, ยง 2, 3-5-85; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 25, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-77, ยง 1, 6-6-00)</history></law>