<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Exemptions and credits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004669</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-14. Exemptions and credits.<section prefix='(a)'>Governmental or public facilities are exempt from the requirement that impact fees be paid. Such facilities are those parcels, grounds, buildings or structures owned by municipal, County, State and federal governments, the Miami-Dade County School Board and the South Florida Water Management District and related to the operation of those entities and used for governmental purposes including, but not limited to, governmental offices, police and fire stations, airports, seaports, parking facilities, equipment yards, sanitation facilities, water control structures, schools, parks and similar facilities in or through which general government operations are conducted. It is provided, however, the following shall not be considered governmental or public facilities and shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter: (1) privately owned properties or facilities leased for governmental operations or activities; and (2) public properties or facilities used for private residential, commercial or industrial activities. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the application of the road impact fee to facilities at a County owned airport used for private commercial or industrial activities shall be limited to the extent permitted by federal law or existing contractual commitments with the Federal Aviation Administration.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Unless provided for to the contrary in the current effective development order, all development activity which is subject to an existing Development of Regional Impact Development Order adopted pursuant to Chapter 380, Florida Statutes prior to June 4, 1989 shall be exempt from this chapter with regard to development approved by such development order. This exemption provision does not apply to those development orders which may have been revoked or determined to be null and void or to any development not authorized in such development order by Miami-Dade County or another unit of local government in Miami-Dade County issuing such development order. This exemption shall not apply to any additional development regardless of whether or not such additional development constitutes a substantial deviation pursuant to Chapter 380, Florida Statutes. Any Development of Regional Impact development order amended after January 1, 2009, which generates additional vehicular trips above the previously approved development order shall be not be exempt for said additional trips.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Credit for up to the full amount of the net road cost portion of the impact fee shall be given by the County Public Works Director for off-site roadway contributions, or payments that were voluntarily proffered or required under a county or municipal development order issued for a development of regional impact or development of county impact or under other legislative or ministerial action approved prior to June 4, 1989. Credit shall be given to the extent the contribution, payment or construction meets the definition of off-site roadway improvement contained in Section 33E-5(n) of this chapter. Any claim for credit pursuant to this section must be filed with the County Public Works Director by May 23, 1990, and shall be in accord with the standards and procedures for issuance of credits provided therein. Credits shall not be applied to the two (2) percent county administrative cost portion of the impact fee which remains the responsibility of the feepayer and must be paid at the time of the building permit issuance. A credit shall only be considered against the fee due for improvement to those properties encompassed by the previous development order or action contemplating the off-site roadway improvements. Any feepayer claiming such credit shall present documentation of land valuation at time of roadway improvement and/or construction costs, adjusted to current United States dollar values as defined in the impact fee manual. The same shall be considered by the County Public Works Director in determining the amount of credit to be given toward the impact fee. The County Public Works Director shall be guided by the criteria set forth in the impact fee manual. No refunds shall be made under this provision of this section. Any appeal from such a determination by the County Public Works Director shall be reviewed by the Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council pursuant to the procedures set forth in the adopted impact fee manual.</section><section>Where a feepayer seeks to apply a credit against payment of the road impact fee, the administrative fee portion of the impact fee shall be the sum of: (a) two (2) percent of the credit or one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) whichever is less and (b) two (2) percent of the remaining net road cost not satisfied by the credit.</section><section>Previously approved off-site road impact fee credits which are: (1) unused and (2) based on a net road cost which has been subsequently adjusted, shall be entitled to an adjustment equal to the percentage increase or decrease of the net road cost in the road impact fee formula. Any such adjustment shall only be utilized to offset road impact fees and shall not be refundable.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, development activity shall be exempt from the requirement of payment of road impact fees upon a determination by the County Planning and Zoning Director that such activity conforms to the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>The development activity is consistent with the Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP); and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any portion of a residential development activity, which provides affordable housing as defined in Section 33E-5 provided that:<section prefix='a.'>There shall be no affordable housing exemption for a housing unit priced at more than seventy-five thousand dollars ($75,000.00) unless approved by a governmental assistance program for a higher amount; and</section><section prefix='b.'>There shall be no affordable housing exemption for a housing unit occupied by persons, families or households having total household assets (excluding pensions, annuities and the like) exceeding fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) unless a governmental assistance program has approved a different amount; and</section><section prefix='c.'>Applicant must obtain such third party approvals as may be required by the County Planning and Zoning Director or as provided in the road impact fee manual; and</section><section prefix='d.'>Applicant must covenant with the county that the housing unit will remain affordable as defined in Section 33E-5 for a period of fifteen (15) years. Other such covenants and agreements may be required as provided in the road impact fee manual or by the County Planning and Zoning Department Director to insure that affordable housing purpose of the exemption is maintained. Housing units that lose their affordable housing status prior to the expiration of five (5) years from the date the exemption was granted shall be subject to payment of the road impact fee in effect at the time said affordable status was lost and the County Planning and Zoning Director shall be authorized to lien the property if necessary to secure payment of the fee; or</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Any commercial or industrial development activity located within an existing designated enterprise zone as defined in Section 290.0065, Florida Statutes, as the same may be amended from time to time, provided that: (a) the proposed development activity has been granted a property tax exemption under Sections 29-81 through 29-89 of the Code of Miami-Dade County; (b) if such development activity is located within a municipality the municipality has also granted a property tax exemption under the aforesaid Sections 29-81 through 29-89; and (c) the feepayer has furnished all the documentation required by the County Planning and Zoning Director, in accordance with the provisions of the road impact fee manual and has executed a covenant running with the land, in a form approved by the County Planning and Zoning Director, obligating the feepayer, its successors and assigns to comply with the employee residency requirements of Sections 29-83(a) and 29-84(b) of the Code of Miami-Dade County for a minimum of five (5) years; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Any commercial or industrial development activity located within an area approved for tax increment financing in accordance with Chapter 30-A of the Code of Miami-Dade County as the same may be amended, in which the development activity has made specific expenditures from tax increment dollars for improvements to the collector or arterial roadway systems as identified in Section 33E-12 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as the same may be amended. The total amount of exemption shall not exceed the total expenditure from tax increment dollars for capacity improvements to the collector or arterial roadway system; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Any development activity for which the computed road impact fee amount is less than fifty dollars ($50.00); or</section><section prefix='(6)'>Any house move originating within Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any tie-down permit for a mobile home that was legally in place at the permit location on June 4, 1989, or any tie-down permit for which documentation is provided that a road impact fee has been previously paid for a mobile home at the same permit location; or</section><section prefix='(8)'>Any alteration, replacement or expansion of an existing structure or the addition of an accessory building shall be exempted provided that the land use has not changed and no additional units are created and no additional vehicle trips are generated pursuant to tables 100 or 100-A in Section 33E-8</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>If an exemption is sought pursuant to Section 33E-14(d)(1), (2), (3), and (4), road impact fees shall be paid prior to the issuance of the building permit. However, the feepayer shall be entitled to a refund pursuant to this chapter upon submitting a formal application for a refund to and receiving approval from the County Planning and Zoning Director, in accordance with the provisions of the manual. Application for a refund under this section shall be made within one (1) year of the issuance of a certificate of completion or certificate of occupancy for the building. Failure to apply for a refund by the feepayer, within the above-referred one-year period shall invalidate the right for a refund under this section. Notwithstanding the aforesaid, if an exemption is sought pursuant to Section 33E-14(d)(2), community development corporations as defined in Section 290.033(2), Florida Statutes (1991), and community-based organizations as defined in Section 420.602(4), Florida Statutes, that have received assistance from Miami-Dade County or the State of Florida in funding predevelopment costs to provide affordable housing to low and very low income families shall have the option of executing a covenant running with the land, in a form approved by the County Planning and Zoning Director, in lieu of payment of road impact fees prior to the issuance of the building permit. Joint ventures of either a community development corporation or a community based organization with a for-profit developer for the purpose of affordable housing development shall also have the right to execute the aforementioned covenant provided that the proposed affordable housing development for which an exemption is being sought has been approved by the Miami-Dade County Office of Community Development.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The applicant shall submit a complete application for any exemption from Road impact fees prior to or concurrently with the building permit application. The applicant shall supply all documentation necessary to validate the requested exemption as outlined in the road impact fee manual along with any additional documentation that may be required by the County Planning and Zoning Director.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-112, § 1(14), 12-6-88; Ord. No. 89-130, § 1, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 92-149, § 1, 12-1-92; Ord. No. 92-153, § 1, 12-15-92; Ord. No. 94-134, § 1, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 94-185, § 1, 9-22-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 96-116, § 1, 7-17-96; Ord. No. 98-125, § 26, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-92, § 1, 7-27-99; Ord. No. 09-08, § 11, 1-22-09)</history></law>