<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-17</section_number>
<catch_line>Miami-Dade County Road Impact Fee Manual.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004672</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-17. Miami-Dade County Road Impact Fee Manual.<section prefix='(a)'>In not less than sixty (60) days prior to the effective date of this chapter, a Miami-Dade County Road Impact Fee Manual (the impact fee manual) shall be proposed to the Board of County Commissioners for adoption by resolution. The impact fee manual shall be used for the administration of this chapter and shall contain the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The independent fee calculation methodology relating to Section 33E-9</section><section prefix='(2)'>The independent study administrative cost provided for in Section 33E-9(b);</section><section prefix='(3)'>The standards and procedures for issuance of fee credits set forth in Section 33E-14(c); and</section><section prefix='(4)'>The standards, procedures and other matters required to administer Sections 33E-7 through 33E-15</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Mayor or designee shall periodically review the contents of the adopted road impact fee ordinance and the impact fee manual and, if appropriate, make recommendations for revisions to the adopted road impact fee ordinance and impact fee manual to the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners shall consider the recommended revision(s) to the Miami-Dade County Road Impact Fee Ordinance and the road impact fee manual at least once every twelve (12) months. The recommendations and the Commission's action shall ensure that the benefits to a fee-paying development are equitable in that the fee charged to the paying development shall not exceed a proportionate share of the costs of mitigating road impacts, and the procedures for administering the impact fee process remain efficient.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-08, ยง 13, 1-22-09)</history></law>