<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Fee computation by adopted schedule.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004662</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-8. Fee computation by adopted schedule.<section>The feepayer may elect to allow the County Public Works Director to use the impact fee schedule set forth below developed pursuant to the formula set forth in(a). The Impact Fee Per Unit of Development shall be multiplied by the Present Day Cost (PDC) Multiplier for the calendar year in which the fee is paid in accordance with the table in subsection(d).</section><section prefix='(a)'>The following impact fee schedule shall be used by the County Public Works Director in computing the road impact fee:</section><section>TABLE 100</section><section>ROAD IMPACT FEE SCHEDULEOUTSIDE URBAN INFILL AREA</section><section><section prefix='1.'>Rates are derived from Trip Generation, An Informational Report, 7th Edition by the Institute of Transportation Engineers (ITE), 2003.</section><section prefix='2.'>ADT = Average Daily Traffic.</section><section prefix='3.'>Percentage of New Trips from ITE Generation Handbook, 2nd Edition (retail assumes 10% diverted-link trips in addition to pass-by trips from the formula) and Dade County existing Road Impact Fee Schedule.</section><section prefix='4.'>GSF = Gross Square Feet.</section><section prefix='5.'>The trip generation rates of services and sales areas for Car Sales were obtained from a survey study of Miami-Dade County car dealerships.</section><section prefix='6.'>Base year for Impact Fee Per Unit of Development is 2006.</section></section><section>TABLE 100A</section><section>ROAD IMPACT FEE SCHEDULEWITHIN URBAN INFILL AREA</section><section><section prefix='1.'>Rates are derived from Trip Generation, An Informational Report, 7th Edition by the Institute of Transportation Engineers (ITE), 2003.</section><section prefix='2.'>ADT = Average Daily Traffic.</section><section prefix='3.'>Percentage of New Trips from ITE Generation Handbook, 2nd Edition (retail assumes 10% diverted-link trips in addition to pass-by trips from the formula) and Dade County existing Road Impact Fee Schedule.</section><section prefix='4.'>GSF = Gross Square Feet.</section><section prefix='5.'>The trip generation rates of services and sales areas for Car Sales were obtained from a survey study of Miami-Dade County car dealerships.</section><section prefix='6.'>Base year for Impact Fee Per Unit of Development is 2006.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the type of activity within a proposed or current development is not specified in the above impact fee schedule, the County Public Works Director shall use the activity most nearly comparable in computing the fee. In making this determination the County Public Works Director shall be guided by the current edition of "Trip Generation, an Informational Study" published by the Institute of Transportation Engineers, and based on the same or similar method of trip generation rate and trip length determination.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In determining existing development activity, as defined in Section 33E-5(h) of this chapter, and the units of proposed or existing development, the County Planning and Zoning Director shall use the building permit and certificate of use information contained in the records of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning and municipal building code and zoning regulation administering agencies.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Table of Present Day Cost (PDC) Mutipliers by Calendar Year.<section>This table is based on the table of Construction Cost Inflation Factors published August 3, 2006 by Florida Department of Transportation (FDOT) Office of Policy Planning for FDOT Fiscal Year 2007 (July 1, 2006 to June 30, 2007). PDC Multiplier values have been interpolated onto a calendar year interval.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-112, § 1(8), 12-6-88; Ord. No. 94-134, § 1, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 26, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 09-08, § 5, 1-22-09)</history></law>