<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Fee computation by independent study.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004663</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-9. Fee computation by independent study.<section>The feepayer may elect, either prior to or subsequent to paying the scheduled impact fee (Section), to utilize an independent fee computation study pursuant to the formula set forth in(a). The feepayer shall provide the County Public Works Director notice of intent to utilize an independent fee computation study prior to, but no later than, the time of application for a building permit. All such studies initiated after the issuance of a building permit shall be completed and submitted to the Public Works Director within six (6) months of issuance of building permit. Nothing within this section shall allow a building permit for development activity to be issued without the payment of a roadway impact fee as provided for in herein.<section prefix='(a)'>If the feepayer elects to utilize an independent fee computation study, the feepayer shall, at his own expense, prepare and present to the County Public Works Director such a study that shall document the basis upon which the value of each of the components of the fee formula set forth in Section 33E-7(a) was determined. The feepayer shall follow the impact fee study methodology contained in the impact fee manual. Subjects of the study shall include the following unless determined otherwise by the Public Works Director:<section prefix='(1)'>Trip generation rates;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Average vehicle trip length;</section><section prefix='(3)'>New vehicle trip rates;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Non-transit trip percentages.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The feepayer shall, at the time the independent fee computation study is submitted to the County Public Works Director, pay to the County Planning and Zoning Director a nonrefundable independent study administrative cost in the amount set forth in the impact fee manual to be used solely by the County for the processing and review of the independent fee calculation study. This amount shall not be credited against the road impact fee payment.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County Public Works Director shall determine if an independent fee computation study:<section prefix='(1)'>Adheres to the impact fee formula set forth in Section 33E-7(a);</section><section prefix='(2)'>Provides complete, thorough, and accurate information; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Is prepared by an individual or entity qualified to perform Traffic Engineering and Operations Studies in accordance with the standards set forth in Rule 14-75.003 of the Florida Administrative Code.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Upon approval of the independent fee calculation study by the County Public Works Director, based on his determination that the conditions described in Section 33E-9(c) are fully met, the feepayer shall pay the amount of the fee so computed.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Should the County Public Works Director determine that the conditions described in Section 33E-9(c) are not fully met by the independent fee study he shall issue a letter to the applicant stating the deficiencies and his intent to reject the independent fee calculation study unless the deficiencies are corrected. If the County Public Works Director determines that the deficiencies in the independent fee study have not been corrected within sixty (60) working days from the date of the letter of intent, he shall issue a letter rejecting the independent fee study.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any appeals from a decision of the County Public Works Director to reject an independent fee study because of deficiencies shall be reviewed and decided by the County Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council, pursuant to the procedures set forth in the adopted impact fee manual.</section><section prefix='(g)'>In his annual review of the impact fee ordinance the County Manager may recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that the type of use and fee rates approved pursuant to an independent study prepared under this section be added to or substituted in the impact fee schedule contained in Section 33E-8</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-112, ยง 1(9), 12-6-88; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 26, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 09-08, ยง 6, 1-22-09)</history></law>