<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Impact fee expenditures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004667</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-12. Impact fee expenditures.<section prefix='(a)'>Funds from the roadway impact fee trust funds, including any accrued interest, shall be used only in accordance with Section 33E-11 for the purpose of financing roadway capacity improvements incorporated into the Miami-Dade County Metropolitan Planning Organization's adopted long range transportation plan or short range transportation improvement program, except that an amount not to exceed three (3) percent of the gross receipts shall be used by Miami-Dade County to offset the cost of administering the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Highest priority for impact fee trust account expenditures shall be for roadway capacity improvements deemed by the Miami-Dade County Metropolitan Planning Organization (MPO) as most needed to serve new development. Such determination by the MPO shall consider recommendation from a joint County/municipal committee as provided for in the Metro-Miami-Dade road impact fee manual. This recommendation is not limited to only County or State designated roadways, but may include municipal roads and select transit capital improvements pursuant to subsection 33E-12 (d). Before funds can be allocated or expended for any capacity enhancement projects on local roads within any one Road Impact Fee District, funding for all programmed capacity needs for County arterial and collector roadways, and municipal collector roadways, within said District must have been identified and encumbered, as determined by the Miami-Dade County Public Works Director. Trust account funds shall be deemed expended in the order in which they are collected. Policies to be used in scheduling the expenditure of impact fee trust funds through the long range transportation plan and short range transportation improvement program shall be set forth in the impact fee manual.</section><section>The County may construct or provide any of the roadway improvement elements listed above or alternatively may contract with a municipality to construct or provide such elements with road impact fees.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Roadway trust funds may be expended on roadway improvements to the State road network within the benefit district. Except in the case of roadway improvements to a State road which has vehicular access within the benefit district, no roadway trust fund moneys shall be expended on the State roads network unless such expenditures are reimbursable. Where reimbursable by the State, payments shall be made pursuant to an interlocal agreement between the State and County entered into pursuant to Section 163.01 Florida Statutes. Reimbursements shall be deposited into the appropriate benefit district trust account.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Roadway trust funds may be expended on select transit capital improvements provided that the Board of County Commissioners, after recommendation from the Mayor in consultation with the Public Works Director and after public hearing, determines that any such transit use of roadway trust funds would be effective as part of the county's strategy for providing roadway capacity within the Urban Infill Area. Roadway trust funds may only be used for select transit capital improvements within the Urban Infill Area. Only impact fees generated from within the Urban Infill Area may be used for select transit capital projects. Transit projects are to be selected for road impact fee funding on the basis of their expected effectiveness as roadway capacity improvements.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Each year the County Public Works Director shall present to the Metropolitan Planning Organization pursuant to the Organization's procedures for their review and approval, the annual program for expenditure of roadway capacity improvements projects utilizing road impact fee trust fund monies, to be included within the transportation improvements program. The Public Works Director shall also present the recommended priorities as determined by the joint County/municipal committee for the expenditure of road impact fee trust fund monies. Trust fund monies, including any accrued interest not assigned in any fiscal year, shall be retained in the trust fund until the next fiscal year, except as provided by the refund provisions of this chapter pursuant to Section 33E-13</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-112, § 1(12), 12-6-88; Ord. No. 89-47, § 1, 5-23-89; Ord. No. 89-53, § 1, 6-6-89; Ord. No. 89-130, § 1, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 00-76, § 1, 6-6-00; Ord. No. 08-135, § 3, 12-2-08)</history></law>