<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Road impact fee formula.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004661</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-7. Road impact fee formula.<section prefix='(a)'>The feepayer shall pay a road impact fee amount based on the formula set forth below. Such fee will be based on the capital cost of roadway improvements required to serve any increase in transportation requirements resulting from proposed development activities together with impact fee administrative costs. The formula to be used to calculate the road impact fee shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Total Trips = Proposed Units of Development × Trip Generation Rate × 97% Trips Non-transit × 1/2 × Percent New Trips</section><section prefix='(2)'>(Outside UIA) New Lane Miles = Total Trips × Trip Length ÷ 8,100 Average Daily Vehicles Capacity per Lane Mile<section>(Within UIA) New Lane Miles = Total Trips × Trip Length ÷ 8,500 Average Daily Vehicles Capacity per Lane Mile</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Road Cost = New Lane Miles × $1,951,500 per Lane Mile (Including $151,500 per lane mile for Right-of-Way Costs)</section><section prefix='(4)'>(Outside UIA) Net Road Cost = Road Cost - $265,680 per New Lane Mile credited from Motor Fuels Tax and Vehicle License Fees<section>(Within UIA) Net Road Cost = Road Cost - $278,800 per New Lane Mile credited from Motor Fuels Tax and Vehicle License Fees)</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Inflation Factor = PDC Multiplier from Table of Present Day Cost (PDC) Multipliers by Calendar Year in subsection 33E-8(d).</section><section prefix='(6)'>Road Impact Fee = Net Road Costs × Inflation Factor + 2% Administrative Costs</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>In the case of development activity involving a change of use and/or magnitude of use in which a building permit is required, the proposed development shall be required to pay an impact fee only for any increase in the development activity. The impact fee shall be the difference between the computed impact fee for the proposed development activity and the computed impact fee for the existing development activity as defined in Section 33E-5. Any building permit which expires or is revoked after the effective date of this chapter and for which a fee has not previously been paid under this chapter shall be required to comply with the provisions herein. No refunds will be given for proposed development activity resulting in a negative fee calculation.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No impact fee payment shall be required for any applicants seeking development activity for which the computed fee amount under the terms of this chapter is less than fifty dollars ($50.00).</section><section>The above formula shall be used to compute the amount of the fee to be paid using either of the approaches set forth in or, at the election of the feepayer.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any change of use, redevelopment or modification of an existing use which requires the issuance of a building permit and which generates additional vehicular trips shall pay a road impact fee based on the net increase in the impact fee above that which would have been required for the previous use.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-112, § 1(7), 12-6-88; Ord. No. 89-53, § 1, 6-6-89; Ord. No. 94-134, § 1, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 09-08, § 4, 1-22-09)</history></law>