<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Impact fee benefit districts and trust accounts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004665</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-11. Impact fee benefit districts and trust accounts.<section prefix='(a)'>To insure that fee-funded roadway improvements will benefit impact fee paying development, all collected impact fees shall be spent only for off-site roadway improvements or for principal and interest payments (including sinking fund payments) on bonds or other borrowed revenues used to fund such improvements, within the road impact fee benefit district described in Section 33E-11.1 in which the fee paying development is located, or within three (3) miles of the border of the benefit district upon prior determination by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, that the project benefits the Impact Fee District where the funds were collected. The full width of the right-of-way of the roadways that form a border of a benefit district shall be considered to be within the district.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A separate interest bearing roadway trust account shall be established for each benefit district and all impact fees collected by the County Planning and Zoning Director shall be promptly deposited into the proper trust account, except for general administrative costs paid pursuant to Sections 33E-9 and 33E-12, which shall be directed to County operating fund accounts. Impact fees collected by municipalities pursuant to this chapter shall be transmitted to the County Planning and Zoning Director at the end of each fiscal quarter except for the portion of the general administrative cost designated for retention by the municipality.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A financial and management report on the impact fee trust funds shall be prepared annually by the County Public Works Department and submitted to the County Manager within one hundred twenty (120) days of the end of the County's fiscal year.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 88-112, § 1(11), 12-6-88; Ord. No. 89-130, § 1, 12-19-89; Ord. No. 94-134, § 1, 6-21-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 26, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 99-98, § 1, 9-9-99; Ord. No. 02-257, § 1, 12-3-02; Ord. No. 09-08, § 8, 1-22-09)</history></law>