<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-11.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Boundaries of road impact fee districts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004666</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-11.1. Boundaries of road impact fee districts.<section>Nine (9) road impact fee districts are hereby established. The boundaries of said road impact districts fee are depicted in Figure 1 and described as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>DISTRICT 1: Begin at the intersection of the Miami Canal and Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike (H.E.F.T., S.R. 821); thence Southerly along the H.E.F.T. to Sunset Drive (S.W. 72 Street); thence Easterly along Sunset Drive to the Palmetto Expressway (S.R. 826); thence Southerly along the Palmetto Expressway to Kendall Drive (S.W. 88 Street); thence Easterly along Kendall Drive to Red Road (S.W. 57 Avenue); thence Northerly along Red Road to Tamiami Trail (S.W. 8 Street); thence Westerly along Tamiami Trail to S.W. 77 Avenue; thence Northerly along S.W. 77 Avenue to the boundary of the City of Miami; thence Northeasterly, Northerly, Southerly and Easterly meandering the boundary of the City of Miami, to LeJeune Road (N.W. 42 Avenue); thence Northerly along LeJeune Road to N.W. 28 Street; thence Easterly along N.W. 28 Street and its Easterly extension to the East right-of-way line of the CSX Railroad; thence Northerly along the East right-of-way line of the CSX Railroad to the Miami Canal; thence Northwesterly along the Miami Canal to the Point of Beginning.</section><section prefix='(b)'>DISTRICT 2: Begin one-half mile due East of the most Southerly point of Key Biscayne; thence due West to the Easterly boundary of Coral Gables; thence Northeasterly along the East boundary of Coral Gables to the South boundary of the City of Miami; thence Westerly along the South boundary of the City of Miami to LeJeune Road (S.W. 42 Avenue); thence Northerly, Easterly and Westerly meandering the boundary of the City of Miami to the Northeast corner of the City of Coral Gables; thence Westerly and Southerly along the boundary of Coral Gables to the Tamiami Trail (S.W. 8 Street) at Ponce de Leon Boulevard; thence Westerly along the Tamiami Trail and along the boundary of the City of Miami to S.W. 77 Avenue; thence Northerly along S.W. 77 Avenue to the boundary of the City of Miami; thence Northeasterly, Northerly, Southerly and Easterly meandering the boundary of the City of Miami to LeJeune Road (N.W. 42 Avenue); thence Northerly along LeJeune Road to N.W. 28 Street; thence Easterly along N.W. 28 Street and its Easterly extension to the East line of the CSX Railroad; thence Northerly along the East line of the CSX Railroad to the Airport Expressway (S.R. 112); thence Northeasterly and Easterly along the Airport Expressway to N.W. 27 Avenue; thence Northerly along N.W. 27 Avenue to N.W. 119 Street; thence Easterly along N.W./N.E. 119 Street to N.E. 2 Avenue; thence Northerly along N.E. 2 Avenue to N.E. 121 Street; thence Easterly along N.E. 121 Street and along the North boundary of the Village of Biscayne Park to N.E. 18 Avenue; thence Southerly, Westerly, Southerly and Westerly along the boundary of the Village of Biscayne Park to the intersection of N.E. 119 Street and State Road 5 (S.R. 5); thence Southwesterly along S.R. 5 to the North boundary of the Village of Miami Shores; thence Easterly along said North boundary to the Easterly boundary of the Village of Miami Shores; thence Southwesterly along the Easterly boundary of the Village of Miami Shores and along the Westerly boundary of the City of Miami Beach to the Miami Municipal Channel (Government Cut); thence Southeasterly along the Miami Municipal Channel and along the boundary of the City of Miami Beach to the North line of the F.E.C. Channel (Fisherman's Channel); thence Westerly, Southeasterly, Westerly and Southerly along the boundary of the City of Miami Beach to Norris Cut; thence Southeasterly along Norris Cut and along the boundary of the City of Miami Beach for 6,000 feet; thence Southwesterly to the Point of Beginning.</section><section prefix='(c)'>DISTRICT 3: That portion of Miami-Dade County lying Northerly of the following described line: Begin at the North County Line and Okeechobee Road (U.S. 27); thence Southeasterly along Okeechobee Road to the North line of Section 30-52-40 thence Easterly along the North line of Sections 25 through 30-52-40 (N.W. 138 Street) to Red Road (N.W. 57 Avenue); thence Easterly along N.W. 138/135 Street to N.W. 47 Avenue; thence Southerly along N.W. 47 Avenue to N.W. 119 Street; thence Easterly along N.W./N.E. 119 Street to N.E. 2 Avenue; thence Northerly along N.E. 2 Avenue to N.E. 121 Street; thence Easterly along N.E. 121 Street and along the North boundary of the Village of Biscayne Park to N.E. 18 Avenue; thence Southerly, Westerly, Southerly and Westerly along the boundary of the Village of Biscayne Park to the intersection of N.E. 119 Street and State Road 5 (S.R. 5); thence Southwesterly along S.R. 5 to the North boundary of the Village of Miami Shores; thence Easterly along said North boundary to the Easterly boundary of the Village of Miami Shores; thence Southwesterly along the Easterly boundary of the Village of Miami Shores to the North line of the City of Miami Beach; thence Easterly along the North line of the City of Miami Beach to the Atlantic Ocean and the END of the herein described line.</section><section prefix='(d)'>DISTRICT 4: That portion of Miami-Dade County lying Westerly of Okeechobee Road (U.S. 27) and the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike (S.R. 821) and lying Northerly of Bird Drive Extension.</section><section prefix='(e)'>DISTRICT 5: That portion of Miami-Dade County lying West of Red Road (S.W. 57 Avenue), lying Northerly of the following described line: Begin at the intersection of the West line of Biscayne Bay and Eureka Drive (S.W. 184 Street) extended East; thence Westerly along Eureka Drive to Krome Avenue (S.W. 177 Avenue); thence Northerly along Krome Avenue to S.W. 168 Street; thence Westerly along S.W. 168 Street to the West line of Miami-Dade County and the END of the herein described line, and lying Southerly of the following described line: Begin at Red Road (S.W. 57 Avenue) and Kendall Drive (S.W. 88 Street); thence Westerly along Kendall Drive to the Palmetto Expressway (S.R. 826); thence Northerly along the Palmetto Expressway to Sunset Drive (S.W. 72 Street); thence Westerly along Sunset Drive to the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike (H.E.F.T.) (S.R. 821); thence Northerly along the H.E.F.T. to Bird Drive Extension (S.W. 42 Street); thence Westerly along Bird Drive Extension to Krome Avenue (S.W. 177 Avenue); thence Northerly along Krome Avenue to Bird Drive Extension (S.W. 36 Street); thence Westerly along Bird Drive Extension to the Westerly line of Miami-Dade County and the END of the herein described line; LESS that portion lying within the corporate boundaries of the City of Coral Gables.</section><section prefix='(f)'>DISTRICT 6: That portion of Miami-Dade County lying Southerly of the following described line: Begin at the intersection of the West line of Biscayne Bay and Eureka Drive (S.W. 184 Street) extended East; thence Westerly along Eureka Drive to Krome Avenue (S.W. 177 Avenue); thence Northerly along Krome Avenue to S.W. 168 Street; thence Westerly along S.W. 168 Street to the West line of Miami-Dade County and the END of the herein described line.</section><section prefix='(g)'>DISTRICT 7: That portion of Miami-Dade County lying within the corporate boundaries of the City of Coral Gables; AND that portion of unincorporated Miami-Dade County lying Easterly of Red Road (S.W. 57 Avenue), lying Southerly of Tamiami Trail (S.W. 8 Street), lying Westerly of S.W. 37 Avenue and lying Northerly of Eureka Drive (S.W. 184 Street).</section><section prefix='(h)'>DISTRICT 8: That portion of Miami-Dade County lying Easterly of the following described line: Begin at the Atlantic Ocean and the North boundary of the City of Miami Beach; thence Westerly along the North boundary of Miami Beach to the Westerly boundary of Miami Beach; thence Southwesterly, Southeasterly and Westerly along the Westerly boundary of the City of Miami Beach to the Miami Municipal Channel (Government Cut); thence Southeasterly along the Miami Municipal Channel and along the boundary of the City of Miami Beach to the North line of the F.E.C. Channel (Fisherman's Channel); thence Westerly, Southeasterly, Westerly and Southerly along the boundary of the City of Miami Beach to Norris Cut; thence Southeasterly along Norris Cut and along the boundary of the City of Miami Beach for 6,000 feet and the END of the herein described line.</section><section prefix='(i)'>DISTRICT 9: Begin at the intersection of the Miami River and the North line of Section 30-52-40; thence Easterly along the North line of Sections 25 through 30-52-40 (N.W. 138 Street) to Red Road (N.W. 57 Avenue); thence run Easterly along N.W. 138/135 Street to N.W. 47 Avenue; thence Southerly along N.W. 47 Avenue to N.W. 119 Street; thence Easterly along N.W. 119 Street to N.W. 27 Avenue; thence Southerly along N.W. 27 Avenue to the Airport Expressway (S R. 112); thence Westerly along the Airport Expressway to the East right-of-way line of the CSX Railroad; thence Southerly along the East line of the CSX Railroad to the Miami Canal; thence Northwesterly along the Miami Canal to the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-08, ยง 9, 1-22-09)</history></law>