<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-6.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Payment of road impact fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004660</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33E-6.1. Payment of road impact fees.<section prefix='(a)'>The feepayer shall pay a road impact fee amount based on the formula set forth in Section 33E-7</section><section prefix='(b)'>Payment shall be made in cash, personal check, cashier's check, or money order payable to Miami-Dade County; however, when a municipality is the permitting authority, payment shall not be made by personal check.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No building permit shall be issued by the county or any municipality therein until payment for the road impact fee has been received or a bond accepted pursuant to subsection 33E-6.1(g). The total road impact fee shall be paid prior to issuance of a certificate of completion, temporary certificate of use and occupancy or certificate of use and occupancy for any part of construction authorized by the building permit.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Upon receiving notice that a payment proffered for an impact fee is invalid due to insufficient funds, improper execution or for any other reason, the appropriate county or city building department shall have the authority to stop all construction authorized by the permit until payment in full is received. Payment in full shall include the amount owed for the road impact fee plus any penalty amount charged by a bank against the county as a result said invalid payment, plus, pursuant to Section 68.065 Florida Statutes, a service fee of ten dollars ($10.00) or five (5) percent of the face amount of the invalid payment, which ever is greater.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the amount of the impact fee paid is found to have been insufficient for any reason, the appropriate County or city building department shall have the authority [to] stop all construction authorized by the permit until payment in full is received.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The County shall have the authority to lien real property for which a Final Certificate of Use and Occupancy (C.O.) has been issued but for which the correct required road impact fee has not been paid in full. Such lien must be filed within three years from the date of issuance of the C.O.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Road impact fees exceeding twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) may be deferred provided that the feepayer submits either a surety performance bond (the bond) or an automatically renewable, irrevocable letter of credit (the bond), for the total amount of the impact fee. Upon acceptance of the bond by the County Planning and Zoning Department the building permit may be issued.</section><section prefix='(h)'>All developments subject to road impact fees paid on or after April 22, 2009, but prior to April 22, 2010, shall be obligated to pay thirty (30) percent of the fee as computed herein. All developments subject to road impact fees paid on or after April 22, 2010, but prior to April 22, 2013, shall be obligated to pay fifty (50) percent of the fee as computed herein. All developments subject to road impact fees paid on or after April 22, 2013, but prior to April 22, 2014, shall be obligated to pay sixty-five (65) percent of the fee as computed herein. All developments subject to road impact fees paid on or after April 22, 2014, but prior to April 22, 2015, shall be obligated to pay eighty (80) percent of the fee as computed herein. All developments subject to road impact fees paid on or after April 22, 2015, but prior to January 1, 2016 shall be obligated to pay ninety (90) percent of the fee as computed herein. All developments subject to road impact fees paid on or after January 1, 2016, shall be obligated to pay one hundred (100) percent of the fee as computed herein. This subsection shall expire on January 1, 2016.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Any development subject to road impact fees for which a plat has been filed in the public records prior to January 1, 2009, and for which road impact fees are paid prior to January 1, 2011, shall be charged for road impact fees in accordance with the Fee Schedule in effect for the year 2008. A copy of the 2008 Table 100 and 2008 Table 100A Fee Schedules shall be included in the road impact fee manual until the date of expiration of this provision. This subsection shall expire on January 1, 2011.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 09-08, ยง 3, 1-22-09; Ord. No. 11-31, ยง 1, 5-17-11; Ord. No. 12-19, ยง 1, 3-20-12)</history></law>