<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00074' order_by='00074' level='2'>Chapter 33G SERVICE CONCURRENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33G-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Concurrency information center.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004681</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33G-7. Concurrency information center.<section prefix='(1)'>A concurrency information center shall be established by Miami-Dade County. The concurrency information center shall be the Miami-Dade County agency officially responsible for issuing concurrency information. This information may include concurrency analyses conducted as required by the concurrency review agencies as specified in Section 33G-4. The concurrency information center shall provide the public, upon request, information on existing and anticipated capacities and levels of services of all services addressed by this chapter. This information will reflect existing facility and service capacities, planned and committed facility and service capacity increases or extensions, and existing and committed service demands. The center shall compile and analyze information on service and facility capacities and improvement plans and commitments provided by all concurrency review agencies, and information on active initial, intermediate, and final development orders as provided by County permitting agencies, the Department of Property Appraisal, and municipal permitting agencies as necessary.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The concurrency information center shall, to the maximum extent feasible, develop and maintain computations of development authorized by active intermediate and final development orders. This information will be categorized and formatted in a form useful for CDMP updates, formulation of concurrency statements, projection of facility capacities, and private sector needs. County boards, departments and agencies which issue development orders and certificates of use and occupancy shall periodically furnish the concurrency information center with records of such approved orders and certificates in electronic or written form suitable for the purposes of the concurrency information center.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The concurrency information center shall assist the concurrency review agencies by (a) establishing procedures that equitably and uniformly implement the provisions of this chapter; (b) formulating updated methods and criteria for analyzing applications for development orders and level of service impacts; and (c) updating concurrency analysis fees. Said methods shall be adopted by administrative order of the County Manager and shall become effective upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners. Reasonable fees for conducting concurrency analyses, providing written information, and for providing services to support the concurrency management program may be charged and collected upon establishment of a schedule of reasonable fees by administrative order of the County Manager which shall become effective upon approval by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-66, ยง 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 91-24, ยง 1, 2-19-91)</history></law>