<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00074' order_by='00074' level='2'>Chapter 33G SERVICE CONCURRENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33G-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Extension of capacity reservation and application for equitable tolling of traffic concurrency reservation period.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004680</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33G-6. Extension of capacity reservation and application for equitable tolling of traffic concurrency reservation period.<section prefix='(A)'>Extension of capacity reservation.<section prefix='(1)'>Where a final plat, waiver of plat, or site plan has been approved in accordance with Sections 33G-5(6)(c), which provides for a reservation of adequate capacity for two (2) years from the date of such a final development order, an extension of the two-year reservation period may be granted when the applicant demonstrates that development has commenced on a timely basis and is continuing in good faith. However, no such extended period shall exceed five (5) years from the date of the final plat, waiver of plat, or site plan approval. In determining whether a development has commenced on a timely basis, the Executive Council's consideration shall include but not be limited to: (1) the density, intensity, and size of the development, (2) staging, phasing, or timing of development, and (3) economic conditions prevailing during the two-year period immediately following final plat approval.</section></section><section>For the purposes of this subsection "continuing in good faith" is defined pursuant to of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.<section prefix='(2)'>Any application for an extension of capacity reservation period pursuant to this section shall be filed with the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning no later than one hundred twenty (120) days prior to the expiration of the capacity reservation period or within sixty (60) days after the effective date of this ordinance for those applications whose expiration date has expired or will expire within one hundred eighty (180) days after such effective date.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All applications for an extension of capacity reservation shall be filed with the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning on a form prescribed by the Director to accomplish the purpose of this section. The form shall require information relevant and material to the extension of time requested including but not limited to:<section prefix='(a)'>A letter of intent explaining the basis for the requested extension together with a detailed description of the particular approved development in question including location, and quantity of development or intensity of development.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A complete itemization of all development permits issued including but not limited to building permits and certificates of use and occupancy.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A complete itemization of all development permits needed to complete development. The itemization shall include but are not limited to building permits and certificates of occupancy as well as a schedule including the period of time for which the applicant claims is needed to complete development.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Any application for an extension of capacity reservation filed pursuant to this section shall be reviewed by the Developmental Impact Committee (DIC) Executive Council at a meeting of the Council.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Within fifteen (15) days after receipt of an application for an extension of the capacity reservation, the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall determine and notify the applicant whether the application information is sufficient to enable the DIC Executive Council to issue a determination, and the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall request any additional information needed. If the Department of Planning and Zoning Director determines that the information in the application is not sufficient, the applicant shall either provide additional information as requested, or shall notify the DIC Coordinator in writing that the information will not be supplied and the reasons therefor. If the applicant declines to provide the requested information, the DIC Executive Council shall act on the application as filed. If the applicant does not respond to the request for additional information within ninety (90) days, then the application shall be deemed to be withdrawn. If the applicant provides requested additional information, the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall, within fifteen (15) days from receipt of the additional information, determine whether the additional information furnished is sufficient to comply with this request. If the additional information is not sufficient, the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall notify the applicant of the respects in which the information does not comply with the original request. When all requested information is received, the application will be considered sufficient and the applicant will be so notified.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The DIC Executive Council shall review the completed application and any additional information provided. It shall consider all written documents, written statements, and information submitted by the applicant or gathered and made part of the record by the Department of Planning and Zoning Director during the investigation and evaluation of the application. The Department of Planning and Zoning Director may solicit and shall accept submission of relevant information from any other appropriate departments or agencies of Miami-Dade County. The Department of Planning and Zoning Director may solicit and shall accept information from any third persons who may possess factual information relevant to the investigation of an application. Copies of such information obtained by the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall be furnished to the applicant, and the applicant shall be given an opportunity to respond to the information. The applicant shall be given an opportunity to address the DIC Executive Council and present evidence and argument in favor of its application, and respond to any questions or concerns raised by members of the DIC Executive Council.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Within sixty (60) days after acknowledging receipt of a sufficient application, or receiving notification that additional information requested pursuant to subsection (4) will not be supplied, the DIC Executive Council shall review the application in accordance with the procedures contained herein and shall issue its determination. The time for issuance of the determination by the DIC Executive Council may be extended by agreement between the applicant and the DIC Executive Council. A determination shall contain findings of fact and conclusions supporting the said extension of capacity reservation determination.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Equitable tolling of traffic capacity reservation.<section prefix='(1)'>The Executive Council of the Developmental Impact Committee ("DIC") shall have the authority and duty, after application and hearing, to approve applications for equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period for property adversely affected by an administrative zoning decision issued under Chapter 33, Code of Miami-Dade County, that is subsequently reversed on appeal, and the appellate decision has become final. Executive Council decisions acting on an equitable tolling application may be appealed to the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to section 33-314(C), Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>An application for equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period shall be filed with the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning or successor agency, with notice to the Director of the Public Works Department, no later than ten (10) business days after the later of (1) the date upon which the reversal of the adverse administrative zoning decision by an appellate decision becomes final, or, (2) if applicable, transmittal of the zoning resolution to the Clerk. It is provided, however, that an application for equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period relating to a zoning decision rendered prior to the effective date of this ordinance may be filed within sixty (60) days after the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Standards.<section prefix='(a)'>For the purposes of this section:<section prefix='(i)'>Equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period shall mean extension of traffic capacity reservation beyond the maximum time permitted under section 33G-6(A) for an amount of time no longer than the period starting from the time the applicant for equitable tolling first exercises the right to appeal the prior adverse administrative zoning decision until the conclusion of the appellate process, as provided under the Code of Miami-Dade County. The Executive Council shall have the discretion to approve an for equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period for an amount of time less than or equal to the time consumed in procuring the final appellate determination reversing the adverse administrative decision. An applicant for equitable tolling of traffic capacity reservation must exhaust all administrative remedies, including the maximum extension of capacity reservation permitted under section 33G-6(A), prior to filing an application of equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period under this subsection:</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Administrative zoning decision shall mean any order, requirement, decision or determination made by an administrative official in the interpretation of any portion of the zoning regulations, or of any final decision adopted by resolution that is subject to review pursuant to section 33-311(A)(2) of the Code of Miami-Dade Country;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Appellate decision shall mean any subsequent review of an administrative zoning decision, whether by a community zoning appeals board, the Board of County Commissioners or an appellate court with jurisdiction of the matter.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>An application for equitable tolling traffic capacity reservation period may be granted upon a finding that:<section prefix='(i)'>The applicant has been aggrieved by an adverse administrative zoning decision and that decision has been reversed by an appellate decision that has become final;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>There was no intent to mislead the public or the zoning authority on the part of the applicant for equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period at any time;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Failure to approve the application for equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period would lead to an unjust result and would be contrary to the principles and considerations of fundamental fairness; and</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Either:<section prefix='(a)'>The prior adverse administrative zoning decision prevented the applicant from obtaining a building permit; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Executive Council determines that because of the prior adverse administrative decision, development of the subject property would have been impracticable. The applicant may demonstrate impracticability by producing evidence, included, but not limited to, showing that in the absence of approval of the equitable tolling application, the property can not be developed or is otherwise unmarketable.</section></section></section></section><section prefix='(4)'>All applications for equitable tolling of traffic capacity reservation period shall be filed with the Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning on a form prescribed by the Director to accomplish the purpose of this section, and shall comply with the requirements of section 33G-6 of this Article. In addition to the information sought through section 33G-6, the form shall require information relevant and material to the request for equitable tolling including but not limited to:<section prefix='(a)'>A copy of the underlying original adverse administrative zoning decision, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>A copy of the resolution or order reversing the underlying adverse administrative zoning decision.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Within fifteen (15) days after receipt of an application for equitable tolling, the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall determine and notify the applicant whether the application information is sufficient to enable the DIC Executive Council to issue a determination, and the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall request any additional information needed. If the Department of Planning and Zoning Director determines that the information in the application is not sufficient, the applicant shall either provide additional information as requested, or shall notify the DIC Coordinator in writing that the information will not be supplied and the reasons therefor. If the applicant declines to provide the requested information, the DIC Executive Council shall act on the application as filed. If the applicant does not respond to the request for additional information within ninety (90) days, then the application shall be deemed to have been withdrawn. If the applicant provides requested additional information, the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall, within fifteen (15) days from receipt of the additional information, determine whether the additional information furnished is sufficient to comply with this request. If the additional information is not sufficient, the Department of Planning and Zoning Director shall notify the applicant of the respects in which the information does not comply with the original request. When all requested information is received, the application will be considered sufficient and the applicant will be so notified.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The DIC Executive Council shall review the completed application and any additional information provided. It shall consider all written administrative decisions and judicial rulings made part of the record by the Department of Planning and Zoning Director during the investigation and evaluation of the application. The Department of Planning and Zoning Director may solicit and shall accept submission of relevant information from any other appropriate departments or agencies of Miami-Dade County. The applicant shall be given an opportunity to address the DIC Executive Council and present argument in favor of its application, and respond to any questions or concerns raised by members of the DIC Executive Council. Review shall be limited to the issue of equitable tolling and the appropriate appellate determinations.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Within sixty (60) days after acknowledging receipt of a sufficient application, or receiving notification that additional information requested pursuant to subsection (5) will not be supplied, the DIC Executive Council shall review the application in accordance with the procedures contained herein and shall issue its determination. The time for issuance of the determination by the DIC Executive Council may be extended by agreement between the applicant and the DIC Executive Council. A determination to grant an application for equitable tolling of the traffic capacity reservation period shall contain findings of fact and conclusions supporting the determination.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-84, ยง 1, 7-21-92; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 27, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 00-78, ยง 1, 6-6-00)</history></law>