<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00074' order_by='00074' level='2'>Chapter 33G SERVICE CONCURRENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33G-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Section 163 Development Agreements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004682</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33G-8. Section 163 Development Agreements.<section prefix='(1)'>Pursuant to the Florida Local Government Development Agreement Act (Sections 163.3220—163.3243, Florida Statutes) the Board of County Commissioners has the authority by resolution to enter into a development agreement with any person having a legal or equitable interest in real property located within its jurisdiction for the sole purpose of providing and reserving public facility capacity. Said development agreements shall authorize issuance of building permits for a period not to exceed ten (10) years after issuance of affirmative concurrency findings pursuant to Section 33G-5(6)(c) if:<section prefix='(a)'>The proposed development meets or exceeds the Developmental Impact Committee (DIC) thresholds established in Section 33-303.1(D)(6)(a)1. through 8., Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County as said thresholds may be amended from time to time; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Board of County Commissioners finds, after recommendation of the Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council, that: (1) the time periods specified in Section 33G-5(6)(b)3. and (c)4. for obtaining development orders and progressing with construction would result in an unreasonable hardship due to the size or complexity of the proposed development; or (2) the development will provide necessary public facilities in an amount which, in addition to satisfying the needs of the development, also remedy an existing deficiency; or (3) the proposed improvements provide significant enhancement to the quality or utility of the affected public facilities; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>The proposed development and development agreement shall conform with all applicable requirements of the CDMP and Section 33G-5 except as provided for in subsection (b)(1) above; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>The development agreement is limited to the specific land uses and institutes of use for which affirmative concurrency findings have been issued pursuant to Sections 33G-5(6)(b) and (c); and</section><section prefix='(e)'>The development agreement shall provide for the application of all subsequent laws and policies governing land development except that said laws and policies shall not preclude the development of the land uses, intensities, or densities as provided for in the development agreement; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>The development agreement shall include a schedule of required construction progress, the violation of which shall result in the invalidation of the development agreement.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The Department of Planning and Zoning shall review and make recommendations on all proposed development agreements and shall place the same before the Board of County Commissioners for consideration.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Procedures to administrate this section and a review fee shall be established by administrative order.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-24, § 1, 2-19-91; Ord. No. 91-60, § 1, 5-21-91; Ord. No. 92-47, § 1, 6-2-92; Ord. No. 94-80, § 1, 5-5-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 27, 9-3-98)</history></law>