<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00074' order_by='00074' level='2'>Chapter 33G SERVICE CONCURRENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33G-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004676</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33G-2. Legislative intent.<section prefix='(1)'>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to be inconsistent or in conflict with the legislative intent of the adopted Comprehensive Development Master Plan as specified in Section 2-114(c), Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida; and that legislative intent is hereby incorporated by reference and made a part of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Nothing in this chapter shall limit or modify the rights of any person to complete any development that has been authorized as a development of regional impact pursuant to Chapter 380, Florida Statutes, or who has been issued a final development order, as defined in this chapter, prior to the adoption of this chapter, and where development has commenced and is continuing in good faith. Subdivision plats or waivers of plat approved prior to July 1, 1989, and for which development has commenced and is continuing in good faith are hereby determined to be final development orders for purposes of this section. It is further determined that, for purposes of this section, development has commenced and is continuing in good faith if one of the following has occurred:<section prefix='(a)'>The applicant has received prior tentative plat approval and received final plat approval within one hundred eighty (180) days subsequent thereto, and has applied for a building permit within a period of one hundred twenty (120) days following final plat approval; or</section><section prefix='(b)'>The applicant has received a waiver of plat approval and has applied for a building permit within one hundred twenty (120) days of approval.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Nothing in this chapter shall modify or limit the vested rights of a property as to the specific development and time periods authorized or affirmed through the process specified in Sections 2-114.1, 2-114.2, 2-114.3, and 2-114.4 of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-66, ยง 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 91-24, ยง 1, 2-19-91)</history></law>