<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='2'>Chapter 33H PARK IMPACT FEE ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33H-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Fee computation by adopted schedule.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004692</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33H-8. Fee computation by adopted schedule.<section prefix='(a)'>The feepayer shall pay a park impact fee amount based upon the impact fee schedule per dwelling unit set forth below developed pursuant to the formula set forth in Sections 33H-6 and 33H-7, together with impact fee administrative costs.</section><section>The following impact fee schedule shall be used by the Director in computing the park impact fee:</section><section>IMPACT FEE SCHEDULE</section><section prefix='(b)'>The cost per dwelling unit shall be the open space fee plus the improvement fee multiplied by 1.05 to accommodate the general administrative charge of five (5) percent.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In the case of development activity involving a change of use and/or magnitude of use in which a residential building permit is required, the applicant shall be required to pay the computed impact fee for any proposed residential development activity for which the impact fee has not previously been paid. When any building permit expires or is revoked after the effective date of this chapter and a fee has not previously been paid under this chapter, the applicant shall be required to comply with the provisions herein. No refunds will be given for proposed development activity resulting in a negative fee calculation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No impact fee payment shall be required for any development activity when the total calculated fee is less than fifty dollars ($50.00).</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the type of dwelling unit within a proposed or current development is not specified in the above impact fee schedule, the Director shall use the dwelling unit most nearly comparable in computing the fee in accordance with the expanded list of land use categories which is appended as Exhibit B and incorporated herein by reference.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In determining existing residential development activity and the units of proposed or existing development, the Director shall use the building permit and certificate of use information contained in the building or zoning records of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-59, ยง 2, 6-19-90; Ord. No. 94-184, ยง 1, 9-22-94; Ord. No. 06-13, ยง 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>