<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='2'>Chapter 33H PARK IMPACT FEE ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33H-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Impact fee expenditures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004696</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33H-12. Impact fee expenditures.<section prefix='(a)'>Except as otherwise provided herein, funds from the local park trust funds, including any accrued interest, shall be limited to the financing of park acquisition, park expansion, park improvements to real property, capital facilities (including start-up equipement and technology), or for principal and interest payments (including sinking fund payments) on bonds or other borrowed revenues. Such funds shall only be used to mitigate the impact of and benefit new development within the respective park benefit districts from which the fees are collected or for projects in other park benefit districts which benefit the park benefit district from which the funds were collected. Trust account funds may be used to purchase additional land from a feepayer where such purchase is consistent with the purpose of this chapter or for excess improvement costs approved in accordance with Section 33H-7(c)(8).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Trust account funds shall be deemed expended in the order in which they are collected. Policies to be used in scheduling the expenditure of local park trust funds shall be set forth in the manual.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the Miami-Dade County standards for local parks have been met within the park benefit district, the Board of County Commissioners following a public hearing, may authorize the County Manager or his designee, to expend the funds for land acquisition or improvements in an adjacent benefit district or within the prescribed park service zone. Said authorization shall only be permitted upon a finding that the expenditure will mitigate the impacts of and will benefit the residential development paying the fees in question.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The County Manager shall periodically review this chapter and the park impact fee manual and, if appropriate, make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners for revisions to this chapter and the park impact fee manual. The purpose of this review is to ensure that the benefits to a fee paying development are equitable in that the fee charged to the paying development shall not exceed a proportionate fair share of the costs of mitigating park impacts of new developments, and that the procedures for administering the impact fee shall remain efficient. Additionally, within one hundred twenty (120) days from the date of the end of the fiscal year, the Office of Capital Improvements shall submit to the County Manager a financial and management report on the impact fee trust funds. No later than thirty (30) days after submission of the report, the County Manager shall conduct a public meeting, for the purpose of presenting the report and receiving public comment on the report as well as the impact fee program. This meeting shall be advertised at least seven (7) days in advance in a newspaper of general circulation. No later than thirty (30) days after the public meeting, the County Manager shall schedule the report, which shall serve as the County's Annual Impact Fee Report, for the Board of County Commissioner's consideration. The County Manager shall provide a companion report to the Board advising of any County Manager recommended impact fee program changes and detailing comments received from the annual impact fee public meeting.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-59, ยง 2, 6-19-90; Ord. No. 94-184, ยง 1, 9-22-94; Ord. No. 06-13, ยง 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>