<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='2'>Chapter 33H PARK IMPACT FEE ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33H-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Fee computation by independent study.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004693</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33H-9. Fee computation by independent study.<section prefix='(a)'>Notwithstanding other provisions of this chapter, the feepayer may elect, to use an independent fee computation study. Such study shall calculate the fee pursuant to the formula in Sections 33H-6 and 33H-7. The feepayer shall provide the Director notice of intent to use an independent fee computation study prior to or within thirty (30) days of the issuance of any building permit on the property for which a park impact fee is due. Independent fee computation studies initiated after the notice of intent is filed shall be completed and submitted to the Director within three (3) months after the notice is filed. No building permits will be issued before the payment of the park impact fee.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the feepayer elects to use an independent fee computation study, the feepayer shall, at his own expense, prepare and present to the Director a study that documents the basis upon which the value of the following components were determined:<section prefix='(1)'>Open space valuation for which a fee is to be paid.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Number of dwelling units ascribed to the property.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Number of persons ascribed to each dwelling unit.</section></section><section>The burden shall be upon the feepayer to provide the data, analysis and reports necessary for the Director to make a determination. The analysis and report must be based on the formula set forth in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The feepayer shall, at the time the independent fee computation study is submitted to the Director, pay a nonrefundable independent study review administrative charge to the Department of Planning and Zoning in the amount set forth in the Manual. The administrative charge shall be used by the Department to process and review the independent fee calculation study. The administrative charge shall not be credited against the impact fee.</section><section prefix='(d)'>If the feepayer elects to use an independent fee computation study, and the subject of the study relates in whole or in part to the property valuation, the feepayer shall, at his own expense and in accordance with the provisions of the Manual, retain a real estate appraiser certified in accordance with Section 475.501, Florida Statutes to prepare the valuation element of such a study. The documentation shall be in accordance with procedures in the Manual. The appraiser shall use the land valuation assumptions contained in this section. The valuation shall be predicated on the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Land valuation assumptions:<section prefix='a.'>Definition of value. The most probable price in cash, terms equivalent to cash, or in other precisely revealed terms, for which the appraised property will sell in a competitive market with the buyer and seller each acting prudently, knowledgeably, and for self-interest, and assuming that neither is under undue duress. Fundamental assumptions and conditions presumed in this definition are:<section prefix='1.'>Buyer and seller are motivated by self-interest.</section><section prefix='2.'>Buyer and seller are well-informed and are acting prudently.</section><section prefix='3.'>The property is exposed for a reasonable time on the open market.</section><section prefix='4.'>Payment is made in cash, its equivalent, or in specified financing terms.</section><section prefix='5.'>The price represents the normal consideration for the property sold unaffected by special or creative financing or sales concessions granted by anyone associated with the sale.</section></section><section prefix='b.'>Assumptions. For the purposes of this appraisal, the following shall be assumed:<section prefix='1.'>The property is ready to be developed with building improvements and no funds would have to be expended for site development work regulatory permitting or materials.</section><section prefix='2.'>All utilities are in place and are at the perimeter of the site including roads, walks, curbs, water lines, sewer lines, electric service lines, and telephone service lines.</section><section prefix='3.'>The property is filled and compacted to comply with applicable building and zoning codes and flood insurance laws and regulations. The fill and compaction are of sufficient quality to accept the building improvements contemplated.</section></section><section prefix='c.'>Items considered. In the appraisal process, items to be considered include sales of finished lots (ready to build); sales of completed homes and lots; sales of raw land; entrepreneur's remuneration; and cost of land development work.</section></section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Where the results of an independent fee computation study are at variance with: (1) The County's determination of the park land value; (2) the Director's initial determination of the number of dwelling units ascribed to this property; or (3) the Director's initial determination of the number of persons ascribed to each dwelling unit, the Director shall determine whether to accept all or part of the independent fee study. The Director's decision shall be based upon:<section prefix='(1)'>Whether it adheres to the impact fee formula set forth in Sections 33H-6 and 33H-7</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whether the study was prepared by a qualified individual or entity as defined in the Manual.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Whether the independent fee computation study provides complete, thorough and accurate information.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In the case of a land value appraisal, whether the appraisal is in accordance with Section 33H-9(d).</section><section prefix='(5)'>Whether the independent fee calculation study, in its entirety, is logical and reasonable.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>If the Director after considering the factors described in Section 33H-9 (e)(1) through (5) intends to reject either in whole or in part the independent fee computation study, he shall issue a letter to the feepayer. The Director shall state the deficiencies and his intent to reject the study unless the deficiencies are corrected. If the Director has not received an adequately corrected study, within sixty (60) days from the date the letter of intent was received, he shall issue a letter rejecting the study.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Any appeal from the Director's decision to reject a study shall be filed in accordance with Section 33H-16</section><section prefix='(h)'>When the feepayer's study has been accepted in whole or in part the feepayer shall pay the amount of the fee so computed and be entitled to a refund of any amount previously paid in excess thereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-59, § 2, 6-19-90; Ord. No. 94-184, § 1, 9-22-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 28, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 06-13, § 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>