<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00075' order_by='00075' level='2'>Chapter 33H PARK IMPACT FEE ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33H-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Impact fee benefit districts and trust accounts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004695</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33H-11. Impact fee benefit districts and trust accounts.<section prefix='(a)'>To insure that fees collected will benefit feepaying developments, all local park open space fees and local park improvement fees paid in accordance with the provisions of this chapter shall be deposited in the "Local Park Trust Fund," a combination of interest bearing trust accounts for each park benefit district for local park open space and local park improvements. The fund shall be established and maintained by the County Finance Department with fees accountable by the Finance Division, Park and Recreation Department.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Park benefit districts shall correspond to the Miami-Dade County Park Benefit District map indicating three (3) districts. These benefit districts are delineated in Exhibit A and described in detail in Exhibit A.1 which attachments are incorporated herein by reference and made a part hereof.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All park impact fees collected by the Department of Planning and Zoning shall be promptly deposited into the proper account in the local park trust fund. General administrative charges collected by the Department of Planning and Zoning shall be directed to the park impact fee administrative fund account for the purpose of paying the cost of administering determinations of credits, contributions, suitability and this chapter.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Architectural and engineering, design and inspection charges for public park improvements shall be deposited into the Improvement Fee Account within the respective Park Benefit District.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-59, ยง 2, 6-19-90; Ord. No. 94-184, ยง 1, 9-22-94; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 28, 9-3-98)</history></law>