<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00076' order_by='00076' level='2'>Chapter 33I POLICE SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33I-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004705</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33I-4. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>The definitions contained in Chapters 28 and 33, Code of Miami-Dade County, shall apply to this chapter except as otherwise provided in the following definitions:<section prefix='(1)'>Applicant means the person who applies for a building permit or submits a plat or waiver of plat.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building means any structure having a roof entirely separated from any other structure by space or by walls in which there are no communicating doors or windows or any similar opening and erected for the purpose of providing support or shelter for persons, animals, things or property of any kind.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Building permit means an official document or certificate issued by the Miami-Dade County Building Official, authorizing the construction siting, or change of use of any building. For purposes of this chapter, the term "building permit" shall also include tie-down permits for those structures or buildings, such as mobile homes, that do not require a building permit in order to be occupied.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Comprehensive Development Master Plan (CDMP) means the comprehensive plan of Miami-Dade County adopted and amended pursuant to the Local Government Comprehensive Planning and Land Development Regulation Act, Section 163.3161 et seq., Florida Statutes (1987).</section><section prefix='(5)'>Credit means the present value of past provisions made by new developments for the cost of existing or future capital improvements.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Development activity, development or activity means any activity for which a building permit is required pursuant to the South Florida Building Code or any applicable County ordinance.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Development of regional impact means any development which because of its character, magnitude or location would have a substantial impact on the health, safety or welfare of the citizens of more than one (1) county.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department means the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department or his designee.</section><section prefix='(8.1)'>Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning means the director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning or his designee.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Encumbered means monies committed by contract or purchase order in a manner that obligates Miami-Dade County to expend the funded amount upon delivery of goods, the rendering of services or the conveyance of real property provided by a vendor, supplier, contractor or owner.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Existing development means the lawful land use physically existing as of the effective date of the ordinance from which this chapter derives and any development or additional development for which the landowner holds a valid building permit as of the effective date of this chapter. Existing development shall also include that maximum level of development activity for which a previous impact fee was paid under the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Feepayer means a person intending to commence a proposed development for which an impact fee computation is required under this chapter, or a person who has paid an impact fee, or provided a letter of credit pursuant to this chapter.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Impact means the effect of the new development, including additional residential and nonresidential development, on the police services of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Improvement means any physical improvement related to property, construction costs of a police district station or other facility, or acquisition of capital equipment that increases the capacity of public services.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Nonresidential development means development not providing for any residential units.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Person, for the purpose of this chapter, means individuals, partnerships, trusts, corporations, and all other legal entities authorized by the law of Florida to own and develop real property.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Police services impact fee, fee, or impact fee means the proportionate fair share charge required to be paid in accordance with this chapter.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Residential development means any building or buildings designed to be used as dwelling units.</section><section prefix='(18)'>Unincorporated areas means any land in Miami-Dade County not lying within the boundaries of a municipality.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Unit or unit of development means a residential structure which is a quantifiable increment of development activity; e.g., a single-family home, or a residential module; e.g., each condominium or apartment unit within a condominium complex or building.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-31, ยง 2, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 29, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 06-14, ยง 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>