<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00076' order_by='00076' level='2'>Chapter 33I POLICE SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33I-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Periodic Update of Fee Schedule.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004717</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33I-16. Periodic Update of Fee Schedule.<section prefix='(1)'>The County Manager shall annually adjust the police impact fee schedule provided in Sec. 33I-6 above by indexing the schedule to inflation as defined by the Consumer Price Index (CPI) - All Urban Consumers for the United States, published by the United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics. The first indexing calculation adjustment shall occur during the 2006-2007 County budget year using the difference in Consumer Price Index figures for calendar years 2005 and 2006. The adjusted Impact Fee Schedule shall be on file with the Department of Planning and Zoning, Impact Fee Administration Office.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Unless otherwise directed by the County Commission, any adjustments to the police impact fee, made pursuant to this section, shall be effective the first of October each calendar year.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If the index is changed by the United States Department of Labor so that the base year is different, the index shall be converted in accordance with the conversion factor published by the United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics.</section><section prefix='(4)'>If the index is discontinued or revised, such other government index or computation with which it is replaced shall be used in order to obtain substantially the same result as would be obtained if the index had not been discontinued or revised.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The County Manager shall periodically adjust the police impact fee schedule provided in Sec. 33I-6 above by providing credit in the police impact fee formula for any outstanding debt from General Obligation Bonds issued to finance capital projects for police purposes which meet needs generated by population growth and development.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-14, ยง 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>