<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00076' order_by='00076' level='2'>Chapter 33I POLICE SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33I-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Imposition of police services impact fee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004706</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33I-5. Imposition of police services impact fee.<section prefix='(a)'>Any application for building permit for development activity within unincorporated Miami-Dade County shall be subject to the assessment of a police services impact fee in the manner and amount set forth in this chapter. However, any application for a building permit where the required police services impact fee payment is made prior to October 1, 1994 shall not be subject to the provisions of this ordinance amending Chapter 33I of the Code of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County provided said building permits are issued prior to January 29, 1995.</section><section>For building permits which expire or are revoked after the effective date of this chapter, the feepayer shall be entitled to a refund of previously paid impact fees in accordance with, provided that, in the case of reapplication shall be paid.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No building permit shall be issued by the County until the applicant has paid the assessed impact fees as calculated pursuant to Sections 33I-6 and 33I-14. Payment of the police services impact fee pursuant to this chapter shall not prohibit a feepayer from initiating an independent fee computation study in accordance with Section 33I-9</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding the payment of a police services impact fee, other State or County developmental regulations may limit the issuance of building permits for development activity.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit the County from paying the required impact fee on behalf of any applicant or feepayer. In such an instance, the impact fee payment shall be from allowable fundable sources other than prior impact fee revenues.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The police services impact fee manual (the manual) shall be used for the administration of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-31, ยง 2, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 94-167, ยง 1, 9-13-94)</history></law>