<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00076' order_by='00076' level='2'>Chapter 33I POLICE SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33I-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Police services impact fee computation formula.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004707</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33I-6. Police services impact fee computation formula.<section prefix='(a)'>The feepayer shall pay a police services impact fee amount based on the formula set forth below. Such fee will be based on the capital costs required to serve the increased demand for police services resulting from proposed new development activities, together with impact fee administrative costs. The formula to be used to calculate the police services impact fee shall be established as follows for each property type:</section><section>The Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department shall employ the following schedule to compute the amount of fee to be paid.</section><section>The cost per unit for residential land use/occupancy types and cost per square foot for nonresidential land use/occupancy types shall be adjusted annually based on Consumer Price Index and periodically adjusted based on bond indebtedness as outlined in.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The fee per residential unit or fee per nonresidential square foot shall be multiplied by the feepayer's total number of units for residential property or total number of square feet for nonresidential property. The total will then be multiplied by 1.05 to accommodate the general administrative charge of five (5) percent. The resulting total is the police services impact fee and administrative charge which shall be paid by the feepayer.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In the case of development activity involving a change of use or magnitude of use in which a building permit is required, the proposed development shall be required to pay an impact fee only for the increase in the development activity. The impact fee shall be the difference between the computed impact fee for the proposed development activity and the computed impact fee for the existing development activity as defined in Section 33I-4. Any building permit which expires or is revoked after the effective date of this chapter and for which a fee has not previously been paid under this chapter shall be required to comply with the provisions herein. No refunds will be given for proposed development activity resulting in a negative fee calculation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No impact fee payment shall be required for any development activity when the calculated fee is less than fifty dollars ($50.00).</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the type of activity within a proposed or current development is not specified, the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department shall use the activity most nearly comparable in computing the fee.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In determining existing development activity, as defined in Section 33I-4, and the units or number of square feet for the proposed or existing development, the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department shall use the building permit and certificate of use information contained in the building or zoning records of Miami-Dade County or other governmental agencies.</section><section prefix='(g)'>All building permits subject to Police Services Impact Fee issued within one year after the effective date of this ordinance shall be obligated to pay sixty percent (60%) of the computed fee as determined herein. All building permits subject to the Police Services Impact Fee and issued more than one year after but less than two years after the effective date of this Ordinance shall be obligated to pay eighty percent (80%) of the computed fee as determined herein. Beginning the third year after the effective date of this ordinance, all building permits subject to the Police Services Impact Fee shall be obligated to pay one hundred percent (100%) of the computed fee as determined herein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-31, § 2, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 94-167, § 1, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 29, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 06-14, § 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>