<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00076' order_by='00076' level='2'>Chapter 33I POLICE SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33I-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Credits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004709</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33I-8. Credits.<section prefix='(a)'>Credit for up to the full amount of the impact feet shall be given by the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department for monetary contributions toward capital equipment and facilities that were voluntarily proffered or required under County development order issued for a development of regional impact or development of County impact or under other final legislative or administrative action approved prior to the effective date of this chapter. Credit shall be limited to the extent of monies paid. No refunds shall be made under this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any claim for credit pursuant to this section must be filed with the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department within one (1) year from the effective date of this chapter and shall be in accord with the standards and procedures for issuance of credits provided in the Police Services Impact Fee Manual. A credit shall be considered only for those properties encompassed by the previous development order or action. Any feepayer claiming such credit shall present documentation and any other evidence of a monetary contribution for capital equipment or facilities. Any appeal from the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department's determination of the amount of credit shall be to the Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council pursuant to the procedures set forth in this chapter and in the police services impact fee manual.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The feepayer shall, at the time the application for credit is submitted to the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department, pay the charge for applications for credit set forth in the Police Services Impact Fee Manual. That administrative charge shall be used by the County solely for the processing and review of the application for credit. The amount of the administrative charge shall not be credited against the impact fee.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-31, ยง 2, 4-3-90; Ord. No. 06-14, ยง 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>