<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00077' order_by='00077' level='2'>Chapter 33J FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33J-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Impact fee expenditures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004729</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33J-12. Impact fee expenditures.<section prefix='(a)'>Expenditures from the impact fee shall include but not be limited to:<section prefix='(1)'>Planning, design and construction plan preparation;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Permitting and fees;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Land and materials acquisition, including any costs of acquisition or condemnation;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Relocation of utilities required by the construction of improvements and additions to fire rescue facilities;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Design and construction of new drainage facilities required by the construction of improvements and additions to fire rescue facilities;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Landscaping and site preparation, including demucking, filling to flood criteria and compaction;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Construction management and inspection;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Surveying, soils and materials testing and removal of hazardous and solid waste materials;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Acquisition of capital equipment for fire rescue services including the acquisition of systems, tools and machines related to new development that allow fire rescue service tasks to be performed in a more efficient manner.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Repayment of any monies transferred or borrowed from any budgetary fund of the County subsequent to the effective date of this chapter, which were used to fund any of the growth-necessitated improvements as herein provided. Any funds that are borrowed shall be spent only to mitigate the impact of new development;</section><section prefix='(11)'>Compliance with the provision of "Art in Public Places" if such compliance is necessitated by facility development;</section><section prefix='(12)'>Purchase of land for additional fire rescue stations and support facilities needed to accommodate new growth;</section><section prefix='(13)'>Design and construction of additional fire rescue stations and other facilities or design and improvement of existing fire rescue stations and other facilities needed to accommodate new growth;</section><section prefix='(14)'>Purchase of fire rescue apparatus and other capital equipment for stations affected by new growth.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The four (4) percent general administrative cost portion of the impact fee shall be deposited into the operating account of the Department of Planning and Zoning and shall be used solely to pay the costs of administering the impact fee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A collecting municipal governmental unit shall be entitled to thirty (30) percent of the four (4) percent general administrative cost portion of the impact fee collected within the municipality to compensate it for the administrative expense of collecting and administering its responsibilities under this ordinance and under agreements with the County detailing such responsibilities. The remainder of the four (4) percent general administrative cost portion of the impact fee shall be used by the Department of Planning and Zoning for the further administration of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Trust account funds shall be deemed expended in the order in which they are collected. Procedures to be used in scheduling the expenditure of impact fee trust funds shall be set forth in the impact fee manual.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Monies, including any accrued interest, not encumbered in any fiscal period shall be retained in the trust funds until the next fiscal period except as provided by the refund provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(f)'>To the extent that new development impacts adjacent zones due to fire and rescue alarms and dispatches made pursuant to Miami-Dade Fire Rescue Department policy and mutual response patterns, and receives benefit from growth-necessitated capital acquisitions, expansions or improvements occurring in adjacent zones, funds collected in one (1) benefit zone can be expended on growth-necessitated capital expansion in adjacent zones up to a distance of six (6) miles to mitigate new development impact between zones.</section><section prefix='(g)'>To the extent that new development impacts central response and support services and receives benefit from growth-necessitated acquisition, expansion or improvement of capital facilities and equipment, funds can be expended from each benefit zone to mitigate the impact of new development on central response and support services in proportion to the impact made and funds collected.</section><section prefix='(h)'>If a refund is required under this chapter, it shall be paid out of revenues collected hereunder.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-26, ยง 2, 3-20-90; Ord. No. 94-168, ยง 1, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 07-58, ยง 1, 4-24-07)</history></law>