<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00077' order_by='00077' level='2'>Chapter 33J FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33J-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Rules of construction.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004720</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33J-3. Rules of construction.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this chapter shall be liberally construed so as to effectively carry out its purpose in the interest of the public health, safety and welfare.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For the purposes of administration and enforcement of this chapter, unless otherwise stated in this chapter, the following rules of construction shall apply to the text of this chapter:<section prefix='(1)'>If there is any conflict between the text of this chapter and any table, summary table or illustration, the text shall control.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The word "shall" is always mandatory and not discretionary; the word "may" is permissive.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Words used in the present tense shall include the future; and words used in the singular number shall include the plural, and the plural the singular, unless the context clearly indicates the contrary.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The phrase "used for" includes "arranged for," "designed for," "maintained for," or "occupied for."</section><section prefix='(5)'>The word "person" includes an individual, a corporation, a partnership, an incorporated association, or any other similar entity.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Unless the context clearly indicates the contrary, where a regulation involves two (2) or more items, conditions, provisions, or events connected by the conjunction "and," "or," or "either…or," the conjunction shall be interpreted as follows:<section prefix='a.'>"And" indicates that all the connected terms, conditions, provisions, or events shall apply.</section><section prefix='b.'>"Or" indicates that the connected items, conditions, provisions, or events may apply singly or in any combination.</section><section prefix='c.'>"Either…or" indicates that the connected items, conditional provisions, or events shall apply singly but not in combination.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>The word "includes" shall not limit a term to the specific example but is intended to extend its meaning to all other instances or circumstances of like kind or character.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The word "he" means "he or she" "his" means "his" or "her."</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-26, § 2, 3-20-90)</history></law>