<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00077' order_by='00077' level='2'>Chapter 33J FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33J-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Imposition of fire and emergency medical services impact fee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004722</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33J-5. Imposition of fire and emergency medical services impact fee.<section prefix='(a)'>All development is deemed to create an impact and therefore create a demand for increase fire and rescue service capacity. As such, the cost of new facilities should be borne by new users to the extent new uses require new facilities. Therefore, building permits subject to Fire Rescue Impact Fee issued within one year after the effective date of this ordinance shall be obligated to pay seventy-six (76) percent for residential, ninety (90) percent for retail, ninety-four (94) percent for office, fifty-eight (58) percent for industrial, and fifty (50) percent for hospital of the computed fee as determined herein. All building permits subject to the Fire Rescue Impact Fee and issued more than one year after the effective date of this Ordinance shall be obligated to pay one hundred (100) percent of the computed fee as determined herein.</section><section>For building permits which expire or are revoked after the effective date of this chapter the feepayer shall be entitled to a refund of previously paid impact fees (see) provided that in the case of reapplication for permit, the impact fee in effect at the time of reapplication shall be paid.</section><section>No such building permit shall be issued by the County or any Miami-Dade County municipality within the District unless and until the feepayer has paid such impact fee, or presented adequate security for such impact fee, in a form permitted by this chapter and acceptable to the Department of Planning and Zoning Director, for a contribution in-lieu-of fee as provided in. Payment of the fire impact fee or provision therefor pursuant to this chapter shall not prohibit a feepayer from initiating an independent fee computation study as provided for in herein.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding the payment of a fire impact fee or provision of a contribution in-lieu-of fee in conjunction with land development activity, other State, Miami-Dade County and municipal development regulations may limit the issuance of building permits for development activity.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Nothing herein shall prohibit any municipality or Miami-Dade County from paying the required impact fee on behalf of any applicant or feepayer. In such an instance, said impact fee payment shall be from allowable funding sources other than prior impact fee revenues.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-26, § 2, 3-20-90; Ord. No. 94-168, § 1, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 30, 9-3-98; Ord. No. 07-58, § 1, 4-24-07)</history></law>