<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00077' order_by='00077' level='2'>Chapter 33J FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33J-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Appeal of administrative decisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004731</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33J-14. Appeal of administrative decisions.<section prefix='(a)'>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, decisions of the Fire Director or of the Planning and Zoning Director under this chapter may be appealed by the feepayer to the developmental impact committee executive council. Appeals of the decisions of the Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall be to the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with procedures specified in Section 33-314. The written decision of the Council shall be mailed certified mail, return receipt requested. Any appeal shall be filed within thirty (30) days from the date of receipt of the Council's written decision.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If a feepayer wishes to appeal an administrative decision of the Fire Director or of the Planning and Zoning Director, the feepayer shall first file a notice of administrative appeal on a form specified in the impact fee manual with the Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator. All appeals shall be filed within thirty (30) days of the issuance of a written decision of the Fire Director or of the Planning and Zoning Director and shall be accompanied by a letter which provides a full explanation of the request, the reason for the appeal, and any supporting documentation. The Developmental Impact Committee Coordinator shall schedule the appeal before the Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council as soon as practically possible. The Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council shall vote to affirm, reject or revise the decision of the Fire Director or of the Planning and Zoning Director.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-26, ยง 2, 3-20-90; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 30, 9-3-98)</history></law>