<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00077' order_by='00077' level='2'>Chapter 33J FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33J-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Fire impact fee and periodic review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004732</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33J-15. Fire impact fee and periodic review.<section prefix='(a)'>The impact fee manual shall be used for the administration of this chapter. The impact fee manual shall contain the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The procedure for the designation by the County of municipal staff to administer any part of the impact fee process or procedure pertaining to municipalities participating in the District. Such designation procedure shall be implemented through memoranda of agreement between the County and these municipalities. The impact fee manual shall further detail the specific procedure for entering into such memoranda of agreement.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The methodology for independent fee calculation provided by Section 33J-10</section><section prefix='(3)'>The independent study administrative fee provided for in Section 33J-10(c).</section><section prefix='(4)'>The standards and procedures for issuance of credits as set forth in Section 33J-9</section><section prefix='(5)'>The standards, procedures and other matters required to administer Sections 33J-4 through 33J-16</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The County Manager shall review the contents of this chapter and impact fee manual annually and, if appropriate, make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners for revisions to the chapter and impact fee manual. The purpose of this review is to ensure that the benefits to a fee-paying development are equitable in that the fee charged to the paying development shall not exceed a proportionate fair share of the costs of mitigating fire and emergency medical service impacts of new developments, and that the procedures for administering the impact fee remain efficient. Additionally, within one hundred twenty (120) days from the date of the end of the fiscal year, the Office of Capital Improvements shall submit to the County Manager a financial and management report on the impact fee trust funds. No later than thirty (30) days after submission of the report, the County Manager shall conduct a public meeting, for the purpose of presenting the report and receiving public comment on the report as well as the impact fee program. This meeting shall be advertised at least seven (7) days in advance in a newspaper of general circulation. No later than thirty (30) days after the public meeting, the County Manager shall schedule the report, which shall serve as the County's Annual Impact Fee Report, for the Board of County Commissioner's consideration. The County Manager shall provide a companion report to the Board advising of any County Manager recommended impact fee program changes and detailing comments received from the annual impact fee public meeting.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-26, ยง 2, 3-20-90; Ord. No. 07-58, ยง 1, 4-24-07)</history></law>