<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00077' order_by='00077' level='2'>Chapter 33J FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33J-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Fee computation formula.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004723</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33J-6. Fee computation formula.<section prefix='(a)'>The feepayer shall pay a fire impact fee amount based on the formula set forth below. Such fee will be based on the capital costs of fire and rescue improvements required to serve the increased demand for fire and emergency medical service resulting from proposed new development activities, together with impact fee administrative costs. The formula to be used to calculate the fire impact fee shall be established as follows for each land use/occupancy type:<section prefix='(1)'>NET CAPITAL COSTS (Total Capital Inventory of All Assets1, including land, less Outstanding Debt)</section></section><section>°<section>NUMBER OF FIRE AND RESCUE DISPATCHES PER YEAR</section></section><section>=<section>NET FIRE AND RESCUE CAPITAL COST PER DISPATCH</section><section prefix='(2)'>FIRE RESCUE DISPATCHES BY LAND USE TYPE PER YEAR3</section></section><section>°<section>TOTAL UNITS OF LAND USE BY TYPE OF USE</section></section><section>=<section>FIRE/RESCUE DISPATCH PER YEAR BY LAND USE TYPE</section><section prefix='(3)'>FIRE/RESCUE DISPATCH PER YEAR BY LAND USE TYPE</section></section><section>×<section>NET FIRE AND RESCUE CAPITAL COST PER DISPATCH</section></section><section>=<section>NET FIRE/RESCUE CAPITAL COST PER UNIT OF LAND USE BY TYPE OF LAND USE</section></section><section>+<section>4% GENERAL ADMINISTRATIVE CHARGE</section></section><section>=<section>FIRE AND RESCUE IMPACT FEE</section></section><section>The Fire Director shall employ the following schedule to compute the amount of the fee to be paid. The four (4) percent general administrative charge portion of the fee is nonrefundable.<section prefix='1'>Total Capital Asset Inventory, 2004, Miami-Dade County Fire Rescue Department.</section><section prefix='2'>Fire and Rescue Dispatches 2004, Miami-Dade County Fire Rescue Department</section><section prefix='3'>"Fire and Rescue Alarms by Property Class 2004," Miami-Dade County Fire Rescue Department. "Building Size by Property Class and Fire District, 2004," Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser. Statistical information supporting the calculation for the Fire and Rescue Impact Fee is contained in the Technical Memorandum on the Methods of Calculating an Updated Fire and Impact Fee prepared for Miami-Dade County by James C. Nicholas, P.H.D. dated August 13, 2005 which memorandum shall be on file with the Impact Fee Section of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='4'>The cost per unit for residential land use/occupancy types and the cost per square foot for nonresidential land use/occupancy types shall be adjusted annually based on the Consumer Price Index and periodically adjusted based on bond indebtedness as outlined in Section 33J-17</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The cost per unit or per square foot shall be multiplied by 1.04 to accommodate the general administrative charge of four (4) percent.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In the case of development activity involving a change of use or magnitude of use in which a building permit is required, the proposed development shall be required to pay an impact fee only for any increase in the development activity. The impact fee shall be the difference between the computed impact fee for the proposed development activity and the computed impact fee for the existing development activity as defined in Section 33J-4. Any building permit which expires or is revoked after the effective date of this chapter and for which a fee has not previously been paid under this chapter shall be required to comply with the provisions herein. No refunds will be given for proposed development activity resulting in a negative fee calculation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No impact fee payment shall be required for any development activity when the calculated fee is less than fifty dollars ($50.00).</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the type of activity within a proposed or current development is not specified in the above impact fee schedule, the Fire Director shall use the activity most nearly comparable in computing the fee.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In determining existing development activity, as defined in Section 33J-4, and the units or square feet of proposed or existing development, the Fire Director shall use the building permit and certificate of use information contained in the building or zoning records of Miami-Dade County or of district municipalities or other governmental agencies.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-26, § 2, 3-20-90; Ord. No. 94-168, 9-13-94; Ord. No. 07-58, § 1, 4-24-07)</history></law>