<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00078' order_by='00078' level='2'>Chapter 33K EDUCATIONAL FACILITIES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33K-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Impact fee expenditures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004746</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33K-12. Impact fee expenditures.<section prefix='(a)'>Expenditures from the educational facilities impact fee accounts are authorized for the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Capital educational facilities, including facilities acquired through public educational facilities acquisitions agreement;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Planning, design, and construction plan preparation for capital educational facilities;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Permitting and fees for capital educational facilities;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Land and materials acquisition for capital educational facilities, including any costs of acquisition or condemnation;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Site preparation for land;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Relocation of utilities required by the construction of capital educational facilities;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Costs for utility extension or improvements, or other capital facilities like roads that are necessary to accommodate capital educational facility buildings;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Design and construction of new drainage facilities required by the construction of capital educational facilities and additions to capital educational facilities;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Landscaping and site preparation for capital educational facilities, including demucking, filling to flood criteria and compaction;</section><section prefix='(10)'>Construction management and inspection for capital educational facilities;</section><section prefix='(11)'>Surveying, soils and materials testing and removal of hazardous and solid waste materials related to the construction of capital educational facilities; and</section><section prefix='(12)'>Acquisition of furniture, fixtures and equipment (FF & E) for educational services.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Monies collected shall be deemed to be spent or encumbered for expenditures on the assumption that the first money placed in the appropriate trust fund shall be the first money taken out of the trust fund when monies are spent or encumbered.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The two (2) percent administrative fee portion of the impact fee shall be deposited into a separate operating account of the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning and shall be used solely to pay the costs of administering the impact fee.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-79, ยง 2(12), 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 31, 9-3-98)</history></law>