<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00078' order_by='00078' level='2'>Chapter 33K EDUCATIONAL FACILITIES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33K-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Benefit districts and trust funds.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004744</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33K-10. Benefit districts and trust funds.<section prefix='(a)'>For the purpose of ensuring feepayers receive sufficient benefit for fees paid, there are hereby created and established three (3) educational facilities impact fee benefit districts. The geographic locations of these benefit districts are reflected on Attachment "B", which exhibit is incorporated into and made a part of this chapter by reference.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A separate interest bearing trust account shall be established for each benefit district for the purpose of insuring that the fees collected under this chapter are designated for the accommodation of impacts reasonably attributable to the new residential development paying the impact fee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All impact fees collected by the County Planning and Zoning Director shall be promptly deposited into the trust account designated for the benefit district where the residential development is located, except that general administrative costs not exceeding two (2) percent of the impact fee amount may be kept by the County and deposited into the administrative fund accounts of the County for the purpose of paying for the administrative costs. Miami-Dade County and the School Board shall enter into an Interlocal Agreement which provides for the periodic transfer of a portion of these administrative costs to the School Board to defray the School Board costs in assisting the County in the administration of this chapter. The Interlocal Agreement shall be adopted concurrent with this chapter. The County Planning and Zoning Director shall conduct a study every two (2) years to determine whether the two (2) percent charge continues to reasonably cover the cost of administering this chapter. The County shall adjust the administrative costs according to the findings of those studies and shall amend this provision of the chapter if the administrative costs need to be modified.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-79, ยง 2(10), 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 31, 9-3-98)</history></law>