<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00078' order_by='00078' level='2'>Chapter 33K EDUCATIONAL FACILITIES IMPACT FEE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33K-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Imposition of educational facilities impact fee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004739</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33K-5. Imposition of educational facilities impact fee.<section prefix='(a)'>Any application for a building permit for new residential development within Miami-Dade County shall be subject to the imposition of an educational impact fee in the manner and amount set forth in this chapter. All building permits issued after the effective date of this chapter shall be subject to the imposition of the computed impact fee as determined herein.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No such building permit shall be issued by the County or any Miami-Dade County municipality unless and until the applicant has paid such impact fee, or presented a letter of credit for such impact fee in a form acceptable to the Miami-Dade County Planning and Zoning Director.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding the payment of an educational facilities impact fee, other state, County, or municipal developmental regulations may limit the issuance of building permits for development activity.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit any municipality, School Board, or Miami-Dade County from paying the required impact fee on behalf of any applicant or feepayer. In such an instance, the impact fee payment shall be from allowable fundable sources other than prior impact fee revenues.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The educational facilities impact fee manual (the manual) shall be used for the administration of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-79, ยง 2(5), 5-2-95; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 31, 9-3-98)</history></law>