<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Probation, revocation, or suspension—Grounds.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001291</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-10. Probation, revocation, or suspension—Grounds.<section>Every certificate issued under this article shall be subject to probation, revocation or suspension by the county manager where it shall appear that:<section prefix='(a)'>The certificate holder has failed or neglected to render the full service authorized by the certificate.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The certificate holder has been convicted of a felony or any criminal offense involving moral turpitude after being issued a certificate.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The certificate was obtained by an application in which any material fact was omitted or stated falsely.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The certificate holder has repeatedly operated a vehicle or aircraft in violation of any law.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The certificate holder has failed to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter or has willfully or knowingly violated any of the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The public interest will best be served by probation, revocation or suspension of any certificate provided, however, that good cause be shown.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The certificate holder has demanded money or compensation other than that established in accordance with this chapter.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The certificate holder has failed to load and promptly transport patients with a medical emergency regardless of ability to pay.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The certificate holder has given or allowed a rebate, commission, kickback or any reduced rate discount not provided for in the rates established and prescribed in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The certificate holder or employee has induced or sought to induce a change of destination to or from a hospital or another facility other than the destination specified by the patient unless specifically warranted by protocol or the patient's medical condition.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-93, § 2, 5-17-94; Ord. No. 01-38, § 1, 3-8-01)</history></law>