<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Violations, enforcement and penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001294</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-13. Violations, enforcement and penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to any other remedies provided by law, including those provided in this article, the County Manager may enforce provisions of this article by administrative fines listed in Section 8CC-10 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Failure of a person to pay a civil penalty within three (3) months of the due date for paying such fine as specified on the civil violation notice or within three (3) months of the date of the final outcome of any timely filed appeal of such violation notice, whichever is later, shall result in automatic suspension of such person's certificate and all ambulance operations shall cease until such fine is paid in full. Violation of the provisions of this article using vehicles operating pursuant to the for-hire regulatory provisions contained in Chapter 4, Article III and Chapter 31 of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall subject such operating authority to suspension and revocation proceeding of the applicable chapter or article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Violation of any of the provisions contained in this chapter shall be punishable by a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00), and/or imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Anyone who engages an ambulance or air ambulance with intent to defraud the certificate holder shall be in violation of this article and subject to a fine of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) and/or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-93, ยง 2, 5-17-94; Ord. No. 01-38, ยง 1, 3-8-01)</history></law>