<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-42</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative findings and intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001301</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-42. Legislative findings and intent.<section prefix='(a)'>During the 1979 State legislative session, authority for regulation of nonemergency medical transportation was transferred from the Public Service Commission to the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services (Chapter 401, Florida Statutes). It mandated the elimination of economic regulations at the State level and required each County to establish local control of the industry. A prior condition for obtaining a State license and permit is a County certificate of public convenience and necessity.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The purpose of this article is to ensure the health and safety of those citizens who must use nonemergency transportation. Regulation of the nonemergency medical transportation industry is susceptible to and can most effectively be carried out under a uniform plan of regulation to [of] the County as a whole.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Artificial restrictions upon the nonemergency medical transportation industry based solely upon economic regulations, that limit competition and impose unreasonable standards on the industry, are not in the best interest of the health, welfare, safety and convenience of the handicapped and disabled residents of the County who rely on this form of transportation. The riding public should not be required to bear the effects of governmentally imposed restrictions upon the industry which are artificial or unnecessary.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, ยง 2, 12-18-80)</history></law>