<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-46</section_number>
<catch_line>Maintaining a certificate—Operating rules.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001305</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-46. Maintaining a certificate—Operating rules.<section prefix='(a)'>Display of certificate. The certificate shall be kept at the operator's business office and an CSD-issued certificate emblem shall at all times be displayed within the vehicle and shall be available for inspection by any police officer or authorized agent of CSD.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Color scheme. Each operator shall adopt and use, after approval by CSD, a distinctive, uniform and decorative color scheme for all nonemergency vehicles certified pursuant to this article. No operator shall use the State-required ambulance colors and markings.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Disposal of personal property. Personal property left by a passenger in any nonemergency vehicle shall, upon its discovery by or delivery to the chauffeur of said vehicle, be reported immediately to and deposited at the operator's office, where a record of same shall be maintained and the property held for the owner for a period of six (6) months. At the end of such time, the property shall become the property of the finder. The operator shall be responsible for chauffeur compliance with this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Compliance with other legislation. Every operator shall fully comply with all ordinances, rules and regulations of the County and all statutes of the State of Florida applicable to the operation of nonemergency vehicles.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Accessibility of service to the public; accessibility of records for regulatory purposes. Each operator shall maintain a central place of business in Miami-Dade County, with a properly listed telephone number for receiving all calls for nonemergency service, and where business records and daily manifests shall be kept. Each operator shall provide CSD with a current business telephone number and address.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Records required. Each operator shall maintain accurate records of all financial and operating information as may be required by CSD. CSD shall be granted access to these records for the purpose of inspection and/or copying same, upon five (5) days' prior notice. All such records and information shall be confidential except that they will become public records for the purpose of revocation or suspension hearings, or, if required by the Board of County Commissioners, for the purpose of approving or disapproving applications for new certificates or transfers of certificates.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Anti-discrimination. No operator or chauffeur shall refuse or neglect to transport to and from any place in the County any orderly person requesting service regardless of race, sex, religion, national origin, age, marital status or handicap who is willing and able to pay the prescribed fare.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Vehicle numbering system. Each operator shall adopt a vehicle numbering system approved by CSD, which does not conflict with those in use by other operators.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Manifest or trip sheet required. Every operator shall maintain a manifest or trip sheet which shall include, but not be limited to, the following information on each trip: Name of chauffeur, vehicle number, date, time, origin, destination, number of passengers and fare. The trip sheet form shall be approved by the CSD. Operators shall not destroy, mutilate, alter or otherwise deface any daily manifests without CSD approval. All manifests shall be available for inspection and/or copying by the CSD or any police agency during regular business hours and shall be retained by the operator for three (3) years.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Telephone access. Each operator shall provide twenty-four-hour continuous telephone access to the public.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Advertising. All advertising or other solicitation for business by a nonemergency medical transportation service shall emphasize in a conspicuous manner that the service does not provide medical attention, and the service provided is designed for those persons whose physical impairment(s) render it impractical to use regular common carrier or taxi services.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Stretcher service. Operators providing nonemergency stretcher service shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Determine from information supplied by persons or agencies requesting said service that nonemergency stretcher service can safely accommodate passengers and maintain records of such requests on forms provided by CSD.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Require persons or agencies to pre-arrange service at least one (1) hour in advance of pickup time.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Provide and maintain ten (10) consecutive hours of continuous service to the public for each day of operation.</section></section><section prefix='(m)'>Mobile communication. Each operator must provide and maintain the capability for two-way communications, excluding citizen band (CB) radio, between the service's location and each of its vehicles.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, § 6, 12-18-80; Ord. No. 87-10, § 2, 3-17-87)</history></law>