<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-47</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Fares and rates.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001306</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-47. Same—Fares and rates.<section prefix='(a)'>Legislative basis for establishing rates. The provisions of this section shall be the exclusive method for the establishment of nonemergency vehicle rates throughout Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Rates to be charged. It shall be unlawful for any operator to charge, demand, request or accept any fare other than the rates established pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Methods of establishing rates. Each operator may establish rates under one (1) or both of the following categories:<section prefix='(1)'>Public rates:<section prefix='a.'>The operator's initial rate will be that rate proposed in the application for certificate and will become effective upon issuance of the certificate.</section><section prefix='b.'>An operator may change the rate by filing with CSD a proposed rate thirty (30) days prior to its effective date. The proposed rate shall be posted within the passenger compartment section of each vehicle at least fifteen (15) days before it becomes effective.</section><section prefix='c.'>The public rate(s) fare structure shall be clearly set forth as a schedule of charges based on service elements understandable by the public, posted within the passenger compartment of each vehicle, and upon request explained to each person requesting service.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Contract rates. Each operator may establish, through written contract, rates other than the public rate. Such rates shall become effective after the executed contract containing such rates has been filed with CSD. Contract rates shall not be modified except in accordance with the requirements of this section.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, § 7, 12-18-80; Ord. No. 87-10, § 2, 3-17-87)</history></law>