<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-48</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Insurance requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001307</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-48. Same—Insurance requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Insurance required. No nonemergency vehicle shall be permitted to operate without the operator having first obtained and filed with CSD a certificate of insurance for each nonemergency vehicle on forms provided by CSD.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Type of insurance. Bodily injury and property damage insurance with limits of liability no less than those established on a Statewide basis by the Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services for the operation of nonemergency vehicles is required. This insurance shall be written by an insurance company authorized to do business in the State of Florida. No policy shall be accepted for a period shorter than six (6) months.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Implications of noncompliance. Failure to provide current certificates of insurance or to maintain appropriate insurance coverage for each nonemergency vehicle shall be grounds for automatic suspension of that vehicle's certificate.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notice of change, cancellation, expiration. Each automobile liability insurance policy shall be endorsed to provide for thirty (30) days' notice by registered mail to CSD of any material change, cancellation or expiration.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Self-insurance. An operator may comply with these insurance requirements if found to be a qualified self-insurer by the State of Florida. An operator's failure to maintain the requirements of a qualified self-insurer shall be grounds for CSD to take the actions described in subsection (c) above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, § 8, 12-18-80; Ord. No. 87-10, § 2, 3-17-87)</history></law>