<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-49</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Vehicle standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001308</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-49. Same—Vehicle standards.<section prefix='(a)'>Enumeration. The following vehicle standards apply to all nonemergency vehicles. It is the operator's responsibility to ensure that each nonemergency vehicle operated under the provisions of this article meets the following standards at all times:<section prefix='(1)'>Comply with the safety and mechanical standards of the current edition of Florida's Vehicle Inspection Manual, Florida Highway Patrol.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Display a current, valid State of Florida vehicle inspection sticker.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Have a functioning speedometer indicating speed in miles per hour and a functioning odometer indicating distance in miles.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Have a functioning mechanism which ensures that doors remain securely closed during travel.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The vehicle exterior must be free of grime, oil or other substances and free from cracks, breaks, dents and damaged paint that detract from the overall appearance of the vehicle and that could harm, injure, soil or impair the passenger or the passenger's personal belongings.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The passenger compartment must be clean, free from torn upholstery or floor coverings, damaged or broken seats, and protruding sharp edges.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The operator's name or business name, operator's business telephone number and nonemergency vehicle number shall be permanently affixed to the exterior of the vehicle in accordance with instructions issued by CSD.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Comply with the current sanitation and maintenance and vehicle design standards of the Florida Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services for permitting as a nonemergency vehicle.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Be equipped with a functioning two-and-one-half-pound ABC fire extinguisher.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Each nonemergency stretcher vehicle shall have a minimum of forty-eight (48) inches from the finished floor to the finished ceiling in the passenger compartment.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Each vehicle utilized to transport passengers confined to wheelchairs shall have a lift operated electrically or hydraulically or a manually operated ramp with sufficient capacity to safely and smoothly lift or load passengers into the vehicle.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Each vehicle shall have a mobile two-way radio, excluding CB radios, with all normal accessories, and shall meet all standards and requirements as specified by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC).</section><section prefix='(13)'>No motor vehicle older than fifteen (15) model years shall be operated as a non-emergency vehicle.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Inspection for compliance. CSD shall provide for annual inspection of each vehicle between and including one (1) and two (2) model years old; CSD shall provide for semi-annual inspection of each vehicle between and including three (3) and four (4) model years old; CSD shall provide for quarterly inspection of each vehicle between and including five (5) and fifteen (15) model years old for compliance with the foregoing standards. The CSD shall charge a fee for such inspection. In addition to regular inspection, CSD may also inspect any nonemergency vehicle at any time. The results of each inspection shall be recorded and a copy provided the operator. Any vehicle failing to meet required safety standards shall not be operated as a nonemergency vehicle until such time as the vehicle satisfactorily passes a reinspection. The CSD shall charge a fee for such reinspection. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the quarterly inspection of each vehicle between and including five (5) and fifteen (15) model years old to determine compliance with the vehicle condition standards required by Section 4-49(a)(4), (5), (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11) and (12) shall commence on May 1, 1995 and the quarterly inspection of such vehicle to determine compliance with the vehicle safety and mechanical standards required by Section 4-49(a)(1), (2) and (3) shall be reduced to semi-annual inspection until July 1, 1998.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, § 9, 12-18-80; Ord. No. 87-10, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 88-118, § 1, 12-6-88; Ord. No. 88-124, § 2, 12-20-88; Ord. No. 92-66, § 1, 7-7-92; Ord. No. 93-85, § 1, 9-7-93; Ord. No. 94-190, § 1, 10-7-94; Ord. No. 95-99, § 1, 6-6-95; Ord. No. 96-186, § 1, 12-17-96)</history></law>