<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Administrative renewal of certificates.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001286</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-5. Administrative renewal of certificates.<section>All private ambulance certificates shall be administratively renewed at the expiration of every three-year cycle as provided herein. The first three-year cycle shall end no late than December 31st of the third calendar year following the date of enactment of this ordinance. Subsequent three-year cycles shall end three (3) years after the expiration of the prior cycle. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to governmental entities. A private ambulance certificate issued during the third year of any renewal cycle shall be renewed in the following renewal cycle. Notice of certificate renewal to each private certificate holder shall be given by the County Manager no earlier than one hundred fifty (150) days and no later than one hundred twenty (120) days prior to certificate expiration. Certificate holders shall submit a renewal application to the County Manager on a form provided by the County no earlier than one hundred twenty (120) days and no later than ninety (90) days prior to the certificate expiration date. The Manager shall deny any renewal application that is not timely, is not properly filed, is incomplete, is untrue in whole or in part, or results in a determination by the Manager that the applicant has failed to satisfy the requirements of Sections(a)(6), and of this article. Each application shall be accompanied by an investigative and processing fee, which shall be nonrefundable, as specified by administrative order, and shall not relieve the operator from the necessity of obtaining a state, county or municipal occupational license as prescribed by law. Appeals from the denial of a renewal application shall be in accordance with(c).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-93, ยง 2, 5-17-94; Ord. No. 01-38, ยง 1, 3-8-01)</history></law>