<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-50</section_number>
<catch_line>Maintaining the chauffeur's registration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001309</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-50. Maintaining the chauffeur's registration.<section prefix='(a)'>Requirements enumerated. A chauffeur shall comply with the following regulations:<section prefix='(1)'>Every chauffeur shall operate his vehicle in accordance with principles of defensive driving.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each chauffeur shall display at all times while driving a nonemergency vehicle a current chauffeur's registration and shall not drive a nonemergency vehicle if said chauffeur's registration has been revoked or suspended.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Each chauffeur at all times shall maintain a neat appearance.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Chauffeur shall select routes to trip destinations that are most economical to the passenger unless otherwise directed or agreed to by the passenger.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No chauffeur shall collect fares or compensation for the transportation services other than the established rates or charges for the type of service being provided, nor may any driver collect any additional payment for transporting any baggage which accompanies the passenger; provided, however, that this provision shall not apply to gratuities, nor shall the words "fares" or "compensation" be construed to include gratuities. Upon request the passenger will be given a receipt for the fare collected.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Each chauffeur shall at all times operate all vehicle special equipment with due regard for the safety and convenience of the passenger.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Each chauffeur shall successfully complete bi-annually a training and orientation session conducted by an operator authorized to do so by CSD. Such session will include, but not be limited to, instruction on subjects as defensive driving, safety and convenience of passengers, courtesy, operation of specialized equipment in the vehicle, and requirements of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Grounds for automatic suspension. Any chauffeur's registration shall be automatically suspended by CSD subject to any administrative hearing to revoke the chauffeur's registration, should the chauffeur become addicted to the use of controlled substances or intoxicating liquors, plead nolo contendere, plead guilty, or be convicted of a felony or of any criminal offense involving moral turpitude or of a crime involving the use of deadly weapons or trafficking in narcotics, or should the State of Florida revoke or suspend the chauffeur's license.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, ยง 10, 12-18-80; Ord. No. 87-10, ยง 2, 3-17-87)</history></law>