<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-51</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties of the Consumer Services Department.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001310</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-51. Duties of the Consumer Services Department.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to the duties and responsibilities specified in this article, CSD shall be charged with the following duties and responsibilities:<section prefix='(1)'>Process, investigate and prepare all reports required by this article.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Investigate and prepare reports on alleged violations of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Enforce the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Attempt to resolve complaints received from any source concerning the industry.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Develop and implement, in cooperation with the industry, service expansion and improvements.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Provide technical assistance to the industry.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Create and render technical assistance to a nonemergency vehicle advisory group comprised of representatives from consumers, the industry, transportation-related interests and public interest organizations. The role of the advisory group shall be to monitor the effectiveness of the ordinance [from which this article derives,] improve communication between the County and parties interested in nonemergency transportation, and help develop improved transportation services.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Perform any other functions assigned by the County Manager.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director may propose and the County Manager may promulgate further rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Whenever in this article a fee is charged or is required to be paid, the amount of such fee shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager approved by the Commission. Such fees shall be deposited in a separate Miami-Dade County fund and shall be used exclusively to accomplish the regulatory purposes of this article. The amount of each fee established hereunder shall be reasonably related to the cost of the services and regulation provided therefor.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, ยง 11, 12-18-80; Ord. No. 87-10, ยง 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 88-118, ยง 1, 12-6-88)</history></law>