<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. NONEMERGENCY MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-53</section_number>
<catch_line>Special provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001312</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-53. Special provisions.<section prefix='(a)'>Exclusive Countywide regulations. The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive uniform regulations applicable to the provision and operation of nonemergency transportation services throughout Miami-Dade County in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Exemption from fees. Federal, State, County and municipal governments and their employees shall be exempted from all fees required in this article for nonemergency vehicles owned, operated and driven by such governments.</section><section prefix='(c)'>[Effect on vehicles currently operating.] Any person who on the effective date of this article is operating a nonemergency vehicle within Miami-Dade County and who has continuously operated said vehicle since being authorized to do so by a Florida Public Service Commission certificate of public convenience and necessity authorizing nonemergency service in Miami-Dade County shall be entitled to a certificate for each nonemergency vehicle that operated at least six (6) months during the twelve-month period immediately preceding the effective date of this article; proof of such operation is required. A timely application for each certificate must be submitted on forms provided by CSD and shall include thereon identification of a separate and distinct vehicle meeting the requirements of this article. The application shall be accompanied by proof of insurance as required by Section 4-48, proof of possession of the required Florida Public Safety Commission certificate of public convenience and necessity and operating authority for said vehicle, and the fee required by Section 4-44</section><section>No certificate shall be issued in accordance with this section unless same has been applied for on later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 80-145, ยง 13, 12-18-80; Ord. No. 87-10, ยง 2, 3-17-87)</history></law>