<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='2'>Chapter 4 AMBULANCES AND MEDICAL TRANSPORTATION VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>4-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Insurance requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001287</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 4-6. Insurance requirements.<section>Each certificate holder shall carry insurance as set forth in this section to secure payment for any loss or damage resulting from any occurrence arising out of or caused by the operation or use of any of the operator's vehicles or aircraft. Every insurance policy shall provide for the payment of and satisfaction of any financial judgment entered against the operator or any person operating an ambulance or air ambulance on behalf of the operator.</section><section>The operator shall furnish to Miami-Dade County Certificate(s) of Insurance, or at the request of the county, full certified copies of required insurance policies, which indicate that insurance coverage has been obtained which meets the requirements set forth in this section. An operating certificate will not be issued until such requirements are met.<section prefix='(a)'>Private operators—Ambulances and Air Ambulances.<section prefix='(1)'>Each vehicle or aircraft shall be insured [in an amount not less than] one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) per occurrence combined single limit for bodily injury and property damage.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each certificate holder shall maintain medical malpractice insurance in an amount not less than one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) per occurrence.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Governmental operators.<section prefix='(1)'>Each entity of local government holding a certificate shall be insured for the limits specified in Florida Statutes, Section 768.28, or such successor statute as may be amended from time to time. An entity of local government may comply with this requirement by providing a self-insurance plan acceptable to the county manager.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Insurance certificates shall be endorsed to provide for no modification or material change, cancellation, or expiration without thirty (30) days written advance notice by registered mail to the County. No policy will be accepted for a shorter period than six (6) months.<section>All insurance policies required in this section shall be issued by companies authorized to do business under the laws of the State of Florida, with the following qualifications:<section>The company must be rated no less than "B" as to management, and no less than Class "V" as to financial strength, by the latest edition of Best's Insurance Guide, published by A. M. Best Company, Oldwick, New Jersey, or its equivalent subject to the approval of the County Manager.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-93, § 2, 5-17-94; Ord. No. 01-38, § 1, 3-8-01)</history></law>