<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Requirements for sales of dogs and cats.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001322</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-10. Requirements for sales of dogs and cats.<section prefix='(a)'>Before a dog is offered for sale it shall receive from a veterinarian vaccines and anthelmintics against the following diseases and internal parasites:<section prefix='(1)'>Canine distemper.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Leptospirosis.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Bordetella (which shall be administered in the State of Florida once before sale by intranasal inoculation or by an alternative method of administration if deemed necessary by the attending veterinarian and noted on the official certificate of veterinary inspection).</section><section prefix='(4)'>Parainfluenza.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Hepatitis.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Canine parvo.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Rabies, if the dog is four (4) months of age or older and the inoculation is administered by a veterinarian.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Roundworm.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Hookworm.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Whipworm.</section></section><section>Each dog over six (6) months of age shall be tested for heartworm before being offered for sale.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Before a cat is offered for sale it shall receive from a veterinarian vaccines and anthelmintics against the following diseases and internal parasites:<section prefix='(1)'>Panleukopenia.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Feline viral rhinotracheitis.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Calici virus.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Rabies, if the cat is four (4) months of age or older and the inoculation is administered by a veterinarian.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Hookworm.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Roundworm.</section></section><section>Each cat shall also be tested for feline leukemia virus and feline immunodeficiency virus (FIV) before being offered for sale.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The tests, vaccines, and anthelmintics shall be administered prior to the dog or cat being offered for sale, unless a veterinarian certifies on the official certification of veterinary inspection that to vaccinate or deworm the dog or cat is not in the best medical interest of the dog or cat, in which case the vaccine or anthelmintic may not be administered to that particular dog or cat.</section><section prefix='(d)'>If the dog or cat is under four (4) months of age, the tests, vaccines, and anthelmintics required by this section shall be administered no more than twenty-one (21) days before sale within the County. If the dog or cat is four (4) months of age or older, the tests, vaccines, and anthelmintics required by this section shall be administered at or after three (3) months of age, but no more than one (1) year before the sale.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All dogs and cats sold in the County shall have a microchip implanted prior to sale. The seller shall register the microchip with the national registry associated with the microchip and shall provide the microchip number and other identifying information to the Department. The seller shall also notify the Department and the applicable national registry within 48 hours of the sale of the dog or cat and shall provide the name, address, and telephone number of the new owner of the dog or cat.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Each dog and cat shall be accompanied by an original current official certificate of veterinary inspection at all times while being offered for sale within the County. The buyer shall receive the original certificate. Copies of these certificates shall be held by the seller and the veterinarian for a period of three (3) years.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The examination of each dog and cat by a veterinarian shall take place no more than thirty (30) days before the sale within the County.</section><section prefix='(h)'>No person may offer to sell or transfer any dog or cat that is less than eight (8) weeks of age.</section><section prefix='(i)'>County-operated or City-operated animal control agencies and animal rescue organizations shall be exempt from the requirements of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08)</history></law>