<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Report and sale of license tags.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001323</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-11. Report and sale of license tags.<section prefix='(a)'>Legislative intent. This section utilizes the authority and powers of Miami-Dade County in order to secure for the citizens of this County the protection of their health, safety and welfare. It is applicable to all practicing licensed veterinarians and pet dealers. This section is designed to regulate veterinarians by requiring that license tags be available for purchase at the time and place of vaccination of a dog against rabies, and that a report be forwarded to the Department containing the names of persons refusing to purchase these license tags. This section further requires that license tags be available for purchase by the dog owner at the time and place of sale or transfer of a dog, and that puppy tags be sold with every pupply sold or transferred. These measures are intended to ensure that the County has the necessary information and capital resources to enforce the County's already existing licensing ordinance. The unique history and lack of success with other measures attempted at controlling stray dogs and enforcing the licensing ordinance have been determined to require the special regulations and provisions contained within this section which the County Commission hereby finds reasonable and necessary.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Postmarked no later than the tenth day of each month, all veterinarians administering rabies vaccinations shall, as to each dog vaccinated, deliver to the Department one (1) copy of the certificate prescribed under Section 5-6 as evidence of each vaccination administered the previous month.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It shall be the duty of all veterinarians, upon vaccinating a dog against rabies, to have Miami-Dade County license tags required by Section 5-7 available for purchase at the time and place of vaccination. All veterinarians shall also have Miami-Dade County license tags available for purchase, at the time and place of presentation, by a responsible party who presents evidence to the veterinarian that the party's dog has a current rabies vaccination.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All pet dealers who sell dogs shall have Miami-Dade County license tags required by Section 5-7 available for purchase at the time and place a dog is sold. Pet dealers who sell dogs that are less than 4 months old shall provide puppy tags free of charge.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Veterinarians and pet dealers who sell Miami-Dade County license tags may collect as payment for each tag no more than the value of the tag as established by Miami-Dade County, and a maximum premium of twenty (20) percent of the value of the tag, except that puppy tags shall be provided free of charge. Veterinarians and pet dealers shall be responsible for the value of all tags held by them for sale to dog owners.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Postmarked no later than the tenth day of each month, each veterinarian and pet dealer shall deliver to the Department one (1) payment containing the value of any and all license tags sold or lost, destroyed, or stolen the previous month. Along with each month's remittance, each veterinarian and pet dealer shall submit to the Department documentation to be provided by Miami-Dade County covering all tags sold, lost, destroyed, or stolen, and shall submit all registration information for all puppy tags provided the previous month. The Department shall have the authority to assess interest for any payments received after the deadline established in this section.</section><section prefix='(g)'>All veterinarians and pet dealers shall provide all persons who obtain a dog from them or who bring a dog to them for vaccination against rabies with literature, prepared by Miami-Dade County for this purpose, stating that Miami-Dade County law requires that every dog be vaccinated against rabies and that every dog wear a license tag that must be renewed annually.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Violations of the requirements of this section shall subject the veterinarian or pet dealer to civil penalties, except when such requirement would violate a confidential doctor-client relationship.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The Director may authorize animal rescue organizations approved by the Department to sell license tags, but an animal rescue organization that chooses to sell license tags shall comply with this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08; Ord. No. 09-16, ยง 1, 3-3-09)</history></law>