<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-12</section_number>
<catch_line>Additional restrictions on sales of animals.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001324</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-12. Additional restrictions on sales of animals.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to possess, sell, or otherwise transfer within the County any dyed or artificially colored rabbit or other animal, baby chicken, duckling or other fowl.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to sell, offer for sale, or otherwise transfer a live turtle except where adequate bacteriological proof is submitted to the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health that such turtles are free from salmonella contamination. Adequate bacteriological proof as used herein shall consist of a statement issued by the chief public health official of the State from which the lot of turtles is shipped certifying that the turtles have been found free of salmonella based upon laboratory examination, and stating the examinations upon which the statement is based. Such certificates shall accompany and be provided to the dealer of any turtle to be sold from an approved lot. The Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health may, in addition thereto, withhold approval of any lot of turtles whether certified or not, until a series of at least six (6) consecutive cultures taken at intervals of not less than one (1) week have been found negative for salmonella in a laboratory approved for this purpose by the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health. The results of such examinations shall be submitted on a form to be provided by the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health. The Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Public Health or his duly authorized representative may at any time take samples of tank water or any other appropriate samples from turtles offered for sale and order the immediate euthanasia or transshipment of any lot of turtles found contaminated with salmonella.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The following warning shall be posted conspicuously at every display of turtles for retail sale:<section>CAUTION. Turtles may transmit bacteria causing disease in humans. It is important to wash the hands thoroughly after handling turtles or material in a turtle bowl; not to allow water or any other substance from a turtle bowl to come into contact with your food or areas where your food is prepared; and to make sure that these precautions are followed by children or others handling turtles.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08)</history></law>