<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-13.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Guard dogs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001326</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-13.1. Guard dogs.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions. For purposes of this section, the following terms shall have the meanings provided herein.<section prefix='(1)'>Guard dog shall mean any type of dog used for the purpose of defending, patrolling, or protecting property or life at any nonresidential establishment or which resides on the nonresidential property. The term "guard dog" shall exclude any stock dogs used primarily for handling and controlling livestock or farm animals.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Guard dog service shall mean any person, business, or corporation that trains, sells, rents, or leases guard dogs for the purpose of defending, patrolling, or protecting property or life at any nonresidential establishment in Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Guard dog license.<section prefix='(1)'>Any person seeking to operate a guard dog service or who owns a guard dog shall obtain a guard dog license.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each guard dog license shall be renewed annually. All licenses shall expire on September 30 of each year. Each licensee shall be responsible for renewing the license on or before October first of each year as long as the guard dog or guard dog service operates in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A guard dog license shall not be transferable, assignable, or refundable.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The license fee shall be established by implementing order approved by the Board of the County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Obtaining a guard dog license.<section prefix='(1)'>Application for a license shall be on a form prescribed by the Director.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The license application shall include but is not limited to the following information:<section prefix='a.'>The name, address and telephone number of the applicant and a description of the location(s) at which guard dogs will be maintained;</section><section prefix='b.'>A statement as to whether the applicant or any officer or employee of the guard dog service has ever been convicted of an offense involving cruelty to animals or has had a final judgment entered against that person under Section 828.073, Florida Statutes or any other statute prohibiting animal neglect or mistreatment;</section><section prefix='c.'>The breed, sex, age, color(s), guard dog license tag number, and electronic animal identification device (EAID) number of each dog that will be used as a guard dog;</section><section prefix='d.'>If applicable, a complete list containing the name, address, and telephone number of every customer procuring the use of a guard dog and the physical location of every guard dog (identified by license tag number), if different than the customer's address;</section><section prefix='e.'>The name, address and telephone number of the applicant's veterinarian(s);</section><section prefix='f.'>The name, address and telephone number(s) of the person(s) responsible for training and/or providing food, water, exercise and care to each guard dog; and</section><section prefix='g.'>If applicable, proof of business tax receipt from the Miami-Dade County tax collector.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>The applicant shall complete an application, supply all information requested by the Department, and pay the applicable license fee. No application shall be deemed complete and reviewable until the license fee is paid.</section><section prefix='(4)'>License applications shall be valid for thirty (30) days in order for applicants to make corrections to meet minimum compliance specifications.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>License denial, revocation, and suspension.<section prefix='(1)'>The Director may deny, suspend, or revoke a license or renewal where:<section prefix='a.'>There has been a material misstatement or misrepresentation in the license application or in any information or documents required to be maintained or provided to the Department;</section><section prefix='b.'>The applicant/licensee has refused to allow the Department to inspect the premises on which animals are kept, the location where services are provided to animals, or the records required to be maintained by this chapter or by state law, provided that the first such refusal shall result in suspension of the license until inspection is allowed;</section><section prefix='c.'>The applicant/licensee has outstanding unpaid fines for violations of this chapter;</section><section prefix='d.'>The applicant/licensee has been found guilty of repeat violations of this chapter;</section><section prefix='e.'>The applicant/licensee or an employee has been found guilty of animal cruelty or neglect under this chapter, Chapter 828, Florida Statutes, or the laws of any other state;</section><section prefix='f.'>The applicant/licensee has been an officer, principal, director, partner, division, shareholder owning or controlling ten (10) percent or more of the stock, or other organizational element of a business organization recognized by the State of Florida that meets any of the criteria specified in subsections (a) through (e) above; or</section><section prefix='g.'>The applicant/licensee is a business organization recognized by the State of Florida, and any of its officers, principals, directors, partners, divisions, shareholders owning or controlling ten percent or more of the stock, or other organizational elements meet any of the criteria specified in subsections (a) through (f) above.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Appeal process. The applicant/licensee shall receive written notice of the Director's determination to deny, suspend, or revoke a license or renewal. The Director's determination may be appealed by providing, within seven (7) calendar days of receipt of the written notice, a written request for an administrative hearing; the request shall be delivered to the address provided on the written notice. If a request for a hearing is received more than seven (7) calendar days from the date of the written notice, the hearing officer shall be precluded from exercising jurisdiction, and the appeal shall be dismissed as untimely. An administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions set forth in Chapter 8CC of this Code. No person aggrieved by a determination of the Director may apply to the Court for relief unless they have first exhausted the remedies provided for herein and taken all available steps provided in this section. While an appeal is pending, the Director's determination shall be stayed.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No license fee shall be refunded for a license that is revoked or suspended. For a license that is denied after review and inspection, the license fee shall be refunded as provided by implementing order approved by the Board of the County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Requirements following notice of adverse action and/or appeal.<section prefix='(1)'>If the notice of denial, revocation or suspension of a guard dog license is not timely appealed, the applicant or license holder shall immediately cease and desist operation of a guard dog service or use of a guard dog.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any person whose license has been revoked may not reapply for a period of one (1) year.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Each reapplication for a license shall be accompanied by a fee established by implementing order approved by the Board of the County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A person who has been found guilty of animal cruelty or neglect under this chapter, Chapter 828, Florida Statutes, or the laws of any other state within the past five (5) years may not hold a license to operate a guard dog service in the county.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Owning a guard dog or operating a guard dog service after suspension, revocation, or denial of a license or renewal is a violation of this section.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Registration of guard dogs.<section prefix='(1)'>Guard dog services and guard dog owners shall annually register each guard dog owned or used in Miami-Dade County with the Department. The registration shall include the following information for each dog:<section prefix='a.'>Name, address and telephone number of the owner and/or manager;</section><section prefix='b.'>The breed, sex, weight, age, and color(s) of the guard dog;</section><section prefix='c.'>A color photograph of the guard dog;</section><section prefix='d.'>Other distinguishing physical features of the guard dog;</section><section prefix='e.'>Certification of rabies vaccination;</section><section prefix='f.'>The guard dog license number;</section><section prefix='g.'>The guard dog's electronic animal identification device number (EAID);</section><section prefix='h.'>Proof of ownership (i.e., bill of sale, receipt or notarized affidavit), including the name and address of the person from whom the dog was obtained;</section><section prefix='i.'>A notarized affidavit signed by the previous owner acknowledging that the dog will be used as a guard dog. This requirement may be waived if the dog has been previously registered to the guard dog owner for more than one (1) year in the county.</section><section prefix='j.'>A current certification from a veterinarian who is licensed in Florida stating that the guard dog has been examined and is healthy and physically fit to perform service as a guard dog. The owner shall obtain the certification form from the Department and shall provide it to the examining veterinarian for completion.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>At least every six (6) months, each guard dog shall be examined by a veterinarian who is licensed in Florida to determine whether the dog is healthy and physically fit to perform service as a guard dog. The owner shall obtain the certification form from the Department, shall provide it to the examining veterinarian for completion, and, upon completion, shall provide it to the Department.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Newly acquired dogs shall be immediately vaccinated against rabies, licensed, and registered with the Department as a guard dog before being used as a guard dog.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The fee to register a guard dog with the Department shall be established by implementing order approved by the Board of the County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A guard dog license shall be an annual requirement. The guard dog license is available only through the Department. The fee for a guard dog license shall be established by implementing order approved by the Board of the County Commissioners. The guard dog license shall be worn at all times or shall be fastened to each guard dog's enclosure when the guard dog is inside it.</section><section prefix='(6)'>No dog shall be used as a guard dog unless and until the dog has been registered with the Department.</section><section prefix='(7)'>No dog shall be registered or used as a guard dog if a veterinarian deems that the dog is unfit to perform service as a guard dog.</section><section prefix='(8)'>No dog shall be used as a guard dog while it is pregnant or lactating.</section><section prefix='(9)'>If any dog is used as a guard dog prior to being registered, a double registration fee shall be imposed to register the guard dog.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Each guard dog must be implanted with an EAID used and approved by the Department.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Maintenance of guard dog registration system; transfer, death, disappearance, and rabies inoculation as affecting registration system. The Department shall maintain a guard dog registration system which shall contain all data required by the Department. Immediately upon transfer of ownership, death, or disappearance of a guard dog, the guard dog service or guard dog owner shall notify the Department. Upon receipt of the information, the appropriate entry shall be made in the guard dog registration system. If the dog has disappeared, an entry should be made to reflect the location of such disappearance.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Inspection/records.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be a condition of the issuance of any guard dog license and guard dog registration that officers of the Department shall at any reasonable time, unannounced, have the right to enter the premises and inspect:<section prefix='a.'>All dogs and all premises where such dogs are trained, in use, or kept.</section><section prefix='b.'>All records for each guard dog including but not limited to vaccination, veterinary, and medical treatment records.</section><section prefix='c.'>All records concerning the training, sale, or use of a guard dog.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Refusal to allow inspection of a guard dog, premises, or records shall be a violation of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Guard dog services shall require any customer that procures the use of a guard dog to sign an agreement authorizing officers of the Department to perform unannounced inspections of any guard dog and premises where the guard dog is being used as a guard dog.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Guard dog services shall maintain records identifying the name, address, and telephone number of each customer procuring the use of a guard dog and the physical location of each guard dog (with registration number), if different than the customer's address.</section><section prefix='(5)'>On a bi-weekly basis, guard dog services shall provide the Department with complete records identifying the name, address, and telephone number of every customer procuring the use of a guard dog and the physical location of every guard dog (with license number).</section><section prefix='(6)'>Guard dog services and guard dog owners shall immediately notify the Department in writing when a guard dog is temporarily or permanently removed from service due to sickness, injury, a medical condition, or death.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Guard dog services and guard dog owners shall maintain records of the acquisition, transfer of ownership, death, or disappearance of a guard dog.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The records required to be maintained herein shall be maintained for a period of at least five (5) years from the date of creation and shall be provided to the Department upon request unless otherwise provided herein.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Transportation of guard dog.<section prefix='(1)'>Every vehicle transporting a guard dog must be clearly marked, showing that it is transporting a guard dog. A compartment separate from the driver is required and shall be arranged to ensure maximum ventilation for the dog.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No guard dog shall be transported in violation of Section 5-15 of this chapter.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>General requirements for guard dogs.<section prefix='(1)'>Guard dog enclosures shall be a minimum of one hundred (100) square feet if one (1) dog is present and one hundred fifty (150) square feet if two (2) dogs are present. No more than two (2) dogs shall be maintained in an enclosure.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Only compatible dogs may be kept m the same enclosure.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Unaltered dogs of the opposite sex shall not be maintained in the same enclosure unless the guard dog service or guard dog owner has an appropriate breeding license issued by the Department.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The guard dog enclosure shall be made of chain link or similar material with a solid roof over the entire enclosure. The enclosure shall contain a shelter inside the enclosure large enough to allow all dogs present to comfortably stand up, turn around and lie down in the shelter simultaneously. The shelter within the enclosure shall provide protection from the direct rays of the sun and direct effect of the wind and rain, a wind and rain break, and ventilation. The shelter shall be raised off the ground at least six (6) inches, have a solid roof, have flooring made of a nonporous easily cleanable surface, have at least three (3) covered sides and an opening large enough for each guard dog to access the shelter, and have adequate ventilation with windows or openings to allow air to circulate. Enclosures or shelters that are covered on all sides in a manner that prevents ventilation are prohibited.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The shelter shall have clean, dry bedding or a reasonably soft comfortable surface for each dog to lie down on to prevent a dog from getting calluses or pressure sores.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Guard dog enclosures and the area immediately surrounding the enclosures shall be cleaned at least once a day to remove any excrement and to sanitize all surfaces coming into contact with a guard dog. All excrement and waste shall be removed from the property.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Guard dogs shall have access to clean fresh water at all times. Each guard dog enclosure shall be checked three (3) times a day to ensure that clean fresh water is available.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Each guard dog shall be examined daily for signs of illness or injury. Any guard dog that is sick, injured, lame, or diseased shall be immediately examined by a licensed veterinarian and removed from use as a guard dog until deemed healthy by the veterinarian. If, during an inspection, the Department determines that a guard dog on commercial premises is sick, injured, lame, or diseased, the dog shall be immediately impounded by the Department and may be redeemed in accordance with Section 5-18 of this chapter, unless a petition for custody is filed under Section 828.073, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Guard dogs maintained in an enclosure shall have at least one-half (½) hour of exercise within each twelve (12) hours of confinement. Guard dog services and guard dog owners shall maintain a daily record identifying each guard dog by license number and providing the date, time, location, and name of the person who exercised the guard dog.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Guard dogs must be given a humane existence, and shall at all times be maintained in accordance with Section 5-9 of this chapter, unless otherwise specified in this section.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Any person who uses the service of a guard dog shall be responsible to assure that the guard dog is provided a humane existence in accordance with Section 5-9 of this chapter, unless otherwise specified in this section, and shall immediately contact the Department to report any guard dog that is sick, diseased, lame, or injured.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Any guard dog on commercial premises that is not registered as a guard dog shall be impounded by the Department and may be redeemed m accordance with Section 5-18 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Each person or business that rents or uses a guard dog to patrol the premises after that business's operating hours shall provide adequate fencing or some other confining structure to keep the guard dog within the premises.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Each person or business that rents or uses a guard dog on commercial premises shall at each entry point and at fifty-foot intervals along the property's fence perimeter, post a readily visible sign including the words "Guard Dog."</section><section prefix='(15)'>Entry points of commercial premises that use a guard dog shall have a sign posted with the telephone number of the guard dog's trainer, handler, and/or owner in case of an emergency.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Each person or business that rents or uses a guard dog on commercial premises shall at each entry point and on the guard dog enclosure post a readily visible sign that notifies members of the public to report guard dog complaints to the Department. Such signs will be available through the Department for a fee established by implementing order approved by the Board of the County Commissioners.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-49, § 1, 6-4-13)</history></law>