<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Trapping of dogs and cats.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001327</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-14. Trapping of dogs and cats.<section prefix='(a)'>Trapping of dogs and cats shall be conducted in a humane manner and shall comply with the following minimum standards:<section prefix='(1)'>Traps shall be in good condition in that they will not cause any bodily injury to the trapped animal and a trapped animal shall have access to adequate food, water, and shelter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Use of poisons, poisoned substances or stupefying substances in a trap shall be prohibited.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All traps shall be plainly identified with the name, telephone number, address, and Department-issued trapping license number of the owner of the trap, if applicable.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All traps shall be inspected daily, and no animal shall remain in a trap for longer than twelve (12) hours.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Traps shall be removed in the event of a hurricane warning or tropical storm warning.</section><section prefix='(6)'>All animals that have been trapped shall be brought to the Department, a County-approved animal rescue organization, or a licensed veterinarian for proper disposition.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to disturb the trap of another.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Department may provide traps for rent for private, noncommercial use. In that event, the Department may collect a rental fee and may also collect a deposit that shall be refunded upon return of the trap. The amount of the rental fee and the deposit shall be established by implementing order approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08)</history></law>