<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-17.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Time for compliance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001336</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-17.6. Time for compliance.<section prefix='(a)'>All persons subject to this article shall have ninety (90) days from the effective date of this section [April 14,1989] to comply with all confinement and registration and requirements. The provisions of Section 5-17.3, entitled "Liability Insurance or Other Evidence of Financial Responsibility Required to be Maintained by Owner of Pit Bull Dogs," shall be effective on January, 1, 1990.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No pit bull dogs may be sold, purchased, obtained, brought into Miami-Dade County, or otherwise acquired by residents of Miami-Dade County anytime after the passage of ninety (90) days after the effective date of Ordinance Number 89-22. No such newly acquired pit bull dogs may be kept, maintained, or otherwise harbored within Miami-Dade County, and each day any such newly acquired pit bull is so kept, maintained, or harbored shall constitute a separate violation of this section.<section prefix='(1)'>Violation of subsection (b) may result in the issuance of a civil violation notice, and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Humane destruction of the pit bull dog by order of a court of competent jurisdiction. The County Manager or his designee may apply to the court for such order pursuant to this paragraph.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Failure to register a pit bull dog as required by this article within the ninety-day grace period shall be prima facie evidence that the pit bull dog is a newly acquired pit bull dog.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-22, ยง 8, 4-4-89; Ord. No. 89-63, ยง 1, 7-11-89)</history></law>