<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001314</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-2. Enforcement.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this chapter shall apply in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. The Department, through Miami-Dade County Animal Control Officers, shall be responsible for enforcing the sections of this chapter. County and municipal law enforcement officers shall also be authorized to enforce the provisions of this chapter relating to cruelty to animals and confiscation of dangerous dogs and dogs subject to dangerous dog investigations. The Director shall have the authority to amend and modify the administration of the Department's operating procedures and to establish rules, procedures, and forms to carry out the Department's responsibilities pursuant to this chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In addition to any other responsible party described in this chapter, the owner of any real property upon which any animal regulated herein is maintained, shall be responsible for that animal to the same extent as the responsible party.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It shall not constitute a trespass for Animal Control Officers, in the performance of their lawful duties, to enter with any necessary equipment upon any public or private property in Miami-Dade County, except a building designated for and used for residential purposes. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to authorize an Animal Control Officer to enter upon private property without consent of the property owner or without a valid warrant where such warrant is required; provided, however, that an Animal Control Officer or law enforcement officer may take custody of a neglected or mistreated animal as provided in Section 828.073, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(d)'>It shall be unlawful to resist, obstruct, or oppose the Director or designee or any Animal Control Officer in the discharge of their duties under this chapter.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any person who shall violate a provision of this chapter, or fail to comply therewith, or with any of the requirements thereof, shall, upon conviction thereof in the County Court, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any person who violates or fails to comply with this chapter shall also be subject to civil penalties in accordance with Chapter 8CC of this Code. Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense. In addition to any other surcharges provided in Chapter 8CC, a five dollar ($5.00) surcharge shall be added to each civil penalty provided for in this chapter; proceeds shall be used to pay the costs of training for animal control officers. Civil penalties imposed pursuant to this provision may be appealed in accordance with Chapter 8CC, or in accordance with any other procedure allowed by law; it is provided, however, that the filing of any appeal shall be deemed to be a waiver of any other available appeal.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Any person who violates a provision of this chapter or any lawful rule, regulation, or written order promulgated under this chapter is subject to injunction or other equitable relief to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of this chapter. Further, such person is liable for any damage to Miami-Dade County caused by such violation, and for the reasonable costs and expenses incurred by Miami-Dade County in enforcing the provisions of this chapter, including but not limited to the costs of enforcement inspections, preparation of enforcement reports, attorney's fees, photographs, title searches, postage, and other demonstrable administrative costs for enforcement and collection. All such sums shall become immediately due and payable upon expenditure by the County and shall become delinquent if not paid within thirty (30) days after receipt by the violator of the Department's bill itemizing the enforcement costs incurred in enforcing the provisions of this chapter (the "due date"). All such delinquent sums shall bear interest at the rate of twelve (12) percent per annum.</section><section prefix='(h)'>In addition to the foregoing, any person who violates a provision of this chapter or any lawful rule, regulation, or written order promulgated under this chapter is subject to the judicial imposition of a civil penalty for each offense of an amount not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) per offense, except that violations of Sections 5-22 and 5-23 of this chapter, related to dangerous dogs, are subject to the judicial imposition of a civil penalty for each offense of an amount not to exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per offense. In assessing the penalty, the court may receive evidence in mitigation. Each day during any portion of which a violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this State against any person and in favor of the Director or the County in any action to enforce compliance with or prohibit the violation of the provisions of this chapter, the court shall adjudge or decree against that person and in favor of the Director or the County a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the attorney acting on behalf of the Director or the County in the suit in which recovery is had. Such fees or compensation shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions filed after the effective date of this ordinance. Cessation of the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter prior to rendition of a judgment or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action has been filed by the Director or the County to enforce the provisions of this chapter, shall be deemed for the purposes of this section the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director or the County, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded as set forth in this section.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The Director is hereby authorized to institute actions on behalf of the County in any court of competent jurisdiction in this State to seek enforcement of this chapter and all remedies for violations thereof.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The Director or designee may, in his or her discretion, terminate an investigation or an action commenced under the provisions of this chapter upon execution of a written consent agreement between the Director or designee and the persons who are the subject of the investigation or action. The consent agreement shall provide written assurance of voluntary compliance with all the applicable provisions of this chapter by such persons. The consent agreement may in addition provide for the following: Mitigation of injuries accruing on account of the violation investigated or sued upon; compensatory damages; punitive damages; civil penalties; costs and expenses of enforcement; attorneys' fees; and remedial or corrective action. Except as expressly and specifically provided in the executed written consent agreement, an executed written consent agreement shall neither be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter nor shall such agreement be deemed to impose any limitation or action by the Director or the County in enforcing any of the provisions of this chapter, nor shall the agreement constitute a waiver of or limitation upon the enforcement of any federal, state, or local law or ordinance. Each violation of any of the terms of an executed written consent agreement shall constitute a separate violation under this chapter by the persons who executed the agreement and by their respective officers, directors, agents, servants, employees, attorneys, heirs, successors and assigns, and by any persons in active concert or participation with any of the foregoing persons and who have received actual notice of the consent agreement. Each day during any portion of which each such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this chapter.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit or require the Director to bring an action on behalf of any private person.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect the powers and duties of: the Department of Planning and Zoning to enforce Chapter 33 of this Code; municipal zoning authorities to enforce municipal zoning regulations; or the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission to regulate animals subject to Chapter 372, Florida Statutes, including without limitation wild animals, birds, freshwater organisms, marine life, fur-bearing animals, and reptiles.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08; Ord. No. 12-80, ยง 1, 10-2-12)</history></law>