<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Cruelty to animals.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001316</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-4. Cruelty to animals.<section prefix='(a)'>Legislative intent. It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida, to provide an orderly and consolidated procedure wherein cruelty to animals may be corrected and the animals protected.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Acts deemed cruelty to animals. It shall be unlawful to commit any act that constitutes cruelty to animals. The following acts shall be deemed cruelty to animals (see Sections 828.12, 828.13 and 828.16, Florida Statutes):<section prefix='(1)'>To torture, torment, mutilate, kill, or unnecessarily overdrive any animal or to cause the same to be done.</section><section prefix='(1.1)'>To engage in animal fighting, including, without limitation, dog fighting or cock fighting. For purposes of this section, to be engaged in animal fighting means to instigate, promote, assist, hold, manage, stage, conduct, be employed in connection with, be present for the preparation of, provide an animal for, allow one's own real or personal property to be used for, gamble on, be a spectator at, or profit from an exhibition, contest, or event featuring the fighting of an animal with another animal during which an animal may be injured, maimed, or killed. The practice of "trunking," in which two animals are locked in the trunk of a car and induced to fight in the confined space, shall be deemed animal fighting.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To intentionally commit an act to any animal which results in the cruel death of the animal, or the excessive or repeated infliction of unnecessary pain or suffering to the animal, or to cause the same to be done.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To deprive an animal of necessary sustenance, whether by neglect or refusal. For purposes of this section, "necessary sustenance" means: food and water that is of sufficient quantity and nutritive value to meet the minimal daily requirements for the condition and size of the animal as set forth by the commercial food industry or by a licensed veterinarian; food and water that is free of contaminants and vermin and insect infestation; and proper medical attention for any illness, injury, infection, skin disorder, and internal parasite. Feeding a cow on feed that produces impure or unwholesome milk shall be deemed to be a violation of this section.</section><section prefix='(4)'>To deprive an animal of shelter.</section><section prefix='(5)'>To impound or confine an animal in any place and during such confinement: to fail to supply the animal with a sufficient quantity of good and wholesome food and water; to fail to provide the animal with wholesome exercise and change of air; to keep the animal in an enclosure that does not permit the animal to make normal postural movements; to keep the animal in an enclosure that contains excess excreta. Enclosing an animal in a vehicle without adequate ventilation shall be deemed to be a violation of this provision.</section><section prefix='(6)'>For a responsible party to abandon an animal in a street or other public place, or to abandon an animal if it is maimed, infirm, or diseased. For purposes of this section, "abandon" means to forsake an animal for which one is responsible without providing for its care, necessary sustenance, protection, and shelter.</section><section prefix='(7)'>If an animal is known to have or to have been exposed to a contagious or infectious disease: to transfer possession of such animal without first disclosing the condition of the animal to the person to whom the animal is transferred; to knowingly permit such animal to run at large; or to knowingly permit such animal to come into contact with any animal of another person without the other person's knowledge or permission.</section><section prefix='(8)'>To transfer or offer to transfer ownership of any live animal as a prize in any game, drawing, sweepstakes or other promotion.</section><section prefix='(9)'>To intentionally trip, fell, rope, or lasso the legs of a horse by any means for the purpose of entertainment or sport. As used in this subsection, "trip" means any act that consists of the use of any wire, pole, stick, rope, or other apparatus to cause a horse to fall or lose its balance, and "horse" means any animal of any registered breed of the genus Equus, or any recognized hybrid thereof. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply when tripping is used:<section prefix='(i)'>To control a horse that is posing an immediate threat to other livestock or human beings;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>For the purpose of identifying ownership of the horse when its ownership is unknown; or</section><section prefix='(iii)'>For the purpose of administering veterinary care to the horse.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Enforcement.<section prefix='(1)'>Whenever any person complains of cruelty to animals or upon independent observation of an Animal Control Officer, an Animal Control Officer will attempt to ascertain and investigate whether the facts alleged in the complaint or observation constitute an act of cruelty to animals. Nothing contained herein shall authorize an Animal Control Officer to enter upon private property without consent of the property owner or without a valid warrant where such warrant is required; provided, however, that an Animal Control Officer or law enforcement officer may take custody of a neglected or mistreated animal as provided in Section 828.073, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the Animal Control Officer has reason to believe, subsequent to his investigation, that an act of cruelty to animals may have been committed, the Department will immediately institute appropriate proceedings against the person responsible for the act of cruelty, issue the appropriate civil violation notice, and/or, where appropriate, seek custody of the animal as provided in Section 828.073, Florida Statutes. Nothing herein contained shall restrict a private citizen from instituting an appropriate proceeding pursuant to the Florida Statutes. Nothing contained in this section shall restrict enforcement by criminal penalty pursuant to Chapter 828, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 8CC-4 governing the penalties for repeat or continuing violations, for enforcement by civil penalty in accordance with Chapter 8CC of this code, a second violation of this section shall carry a civil penalty of 2.5 times the penalty listed in Section 8CC-10, a third violation shall carry a civil penalty of 3 times the listed penalty, and each subsequent violation shall carry a civil penalty of 3.5 times the listed penalty.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08; Ord. No. 12-77, ยง 1, 10-2-12; Ord. No. 13-85, ยง 1, 9-17-13)</history></law>