<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Adoption of animals from the department; sterilization requirements; requirements for animal rescue organizations; authority to negotiate and enter into agreements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001317</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-5. Adoption of animals from the department; sterilization requirements; requirements for animal rescue organizations; authority to negotiate and enter into agreements.<section prefix='(a)'>The Department shall encourage the adoption of animals in its custody. The Department may charge fees for transferring ownership of such animals and for vaccination, sterilization, and other medical care provided to such animals. Fees shall be fixed by implementing order approved by the Board of County Commissioners, provided that animal rescue organizations and other adopters acquiring ownership of animals may be charged reduced fees in accordance with this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Prior to transferring ownership of a dog or cat to any person, the Department shall sterilize the animal, except that the Department may release unsterilized animals in either of the following circumstances.<section prefix='(1)'>The new owner enters into a written agreement guaranteeing that sterilization will be performed within thirty (30) days from the date custody is acquired or as soon as sterilization is medically permissible. Breach of the agreement shall be a separate violation of this section. A person acquiring ownership of an intact dog or cat from the Department shall also give the Department a sufficient, refundable deposit per animal to ensure that the animal will be sterilized, as required by Section 823.15, Florida Statutes. The Department shall refund the deposit upon presentation of written evidence by the veterinarian performing the sterilization that the animal has been sterilized. The amount of the deposit shall be established by implementing order approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Department may, at its sole discretion, transfer unsterilized animals to animal rescue organizations that comply with the requirements set forth in subsection (c).</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The Department may, at its discretion, transfer animals to an animal rescue organization for medical care, for adoption, for adoption to third parties, or for any other lawful purpose, in accordance with the following provisions:<section prefix='(1)'>The animal rescue organization shall be registered with the Department and shall provide proof that it is duly registered with the Florida Department of State and the Florida Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and properly organized as a charitable organization under ยง 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The animal rescue organization shall enter into a written agreement signed by the Director and approved by the County Attorney's Office as to form and legal sufficiency that provides for the following: a guarantee that the organization will comply with the sterilization requirements set forth in Section 823.15(2)(b), Florida Statutes; a requirement that the organization periodically report to the Department on the disposition of animals acquired from the Department; and that the Department shall have the right to reclaim animals that are being maintained in violation of this chapter or other provisions of this Code. Breach of the agreement shall be a separate violation of this section.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In deciding whether to transfer animals to an animal rescue organization, the Director may consider, among other factors:<section prefix='(i)'>The resources of the organization to care for animals.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The facilities where the animals will be kept.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The prior experience of the organization or its members or agents in the field of animal care.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Whether the organization or its members or agents are, or have previously been found to be, operating in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, of any federal, state, or local laws governing public health or sanitation, or of the applicable zoning code governing the keeping of animals.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Any additional burdens on the Department for partnering with the organization.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>[Authority.] The Director is hereby delegated the authority to negotiate and enter into agreements, which require no expenditure of additional funds by the County, with other persons to encourage the adoption of animals or to provide for animals in the custody of the Department.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08; Ord. No. 12-80, ยง 2, 10-2-12)</history></law>