<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-7</section_number>
<catch_line>License tags required for all dogs; conditions for issuance of tags.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001319</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-7. License tags required for all dogs; conditions for issuance of tags.<section prefix='(a)'>Every person owning, keeping, or harboring any dog over four (4) months of age within Miami-Dade County, Florida, or bringing any dog over four (4) months of age into this County shall, within thirty (30) days of the dog entering this County, register the dog with the Department and obtain a license tag, which the dog shall wear at all times.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department shall require, as a prerequisite to the issuance of a license tag for any dog, satisfactory proof that such dog has been vaccinated against rabies in accordance with the provisions of Section 5-6. The official certificate prescribed pursuant to Section 5-6 shall be accepted as conclusive evidence as to the fact and time of vaccination, or a certificate providing that vaccination for rabies would endanger the health of the particular dog, as provided by Section 5-6 of this chapter, may be accepted.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each license tag shall be renewed annually by the anniversary of the dog's most recent rabies vaccination, even if the rabies vaccination is effective for more than one year; it is provided, however, that the Department may issue a multi-year license tag that is valid for the duration of a multi-year rabies vaccination, and such license tag shall not require renewal until the revaccination is due. If the dog is not timely revaccinated, and the license tag not timely renewed, then the responsible party shall be subject to civil penalties in accordance with this chapter, but thereafter the due date for the renewal of the license tag shall be the anniversary of the untimely revaccination.</section><section prefix='(d)'>License fees shall be established by implementing order approved by the Board of County Commissioners based on the following categories:<section prefix='(1)'>Sterilized dog 12 months old or more;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Intact dog 12 months old or more;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Dog between 4 months old and 12 months old ("Junior tag");</section><section prefix='(4)'>Dog less than 4 months old ("Puppy tag"), which shall be provided free of charge;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Dog owned by an indigent person as defined by implementing order approved by the Board of County Commissioners; and</section><section prefix='(6)'>Replacement for a lost or damaged license tag.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Service animals and working police dogs and fire rescue dogs shall be exempt from license fees.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>It shall be a violation of this section to fail to timely register a dog, to fail to timely obtain or renew a license tag, or to fail to have the dog wear the license tag.<section prefix='(1)'>The Department may issue a courtesy notice before the dog is due for registration or the license tag is due for renewal. It is provided, however, that issuance of a courtesy notice shall not be deemed to be a prerequisite to enforcement of the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any person who is fined under this section for an intact dog may have the penalty reduced to the level of a sterilized dog by having the dog sterilized within thirty (30) days of receipt of the civil violation notice.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any indigent person who obtained a Department-issued license tag at a reduced fee prior to the effective date of this ordinance shall be deemed to have complied with the registration and licensing requirements of this section until the expiration of that license tag.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Exemptions. This section shall not apply to greyhounds kept, maintained or brought into the County for the purpose of racing at licensed greyhound tracks, or to dogs used as part of entertainment acts when properly controlled, or to dogs that remain in the County for a period of less than thirty (30) days.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08; Ord. No. 09-16, ยง 1, 3-3-09)</history></law>