<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='2'>Chapter 5 ANIMALS AND FOWL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Voluntary registration of cats.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001320</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 5-8. Voluntary registration of cats.<section>The Director is hereby authorized to establish a voluntary cat registration program. The Department shall require, as a prerequisite to the issuance of a registration tag for any cat, satisfactory proof that such cat has been vaccinated against rabies in accordance with the provisions of of this chapter. The official certificate prescribed pursuant to, or a certificate of a qualified veterinarian certifying that inoculation for rabies would endanger the health of the particular cat, as provided by of this chapter, may be accepted. Upon payment of the fee prescribed herein, a registration tag shall be issued to each cat owner for each cat, said tag to be worn at all times by the cat for which issued, unless the cat owner chooses to have the registration number tattooed on the inner thigh of the cat or to have the cat implanted with a microchip, which shall be registered with the applicable national registry as well as the Department. A record of the name and address of the cat owner and a description of the cat, as well as the registration number, microchip number, and other identifying information assigned thereto, shall be maintained by the Department on each cat registration, and such other information that the Director may deem proper. The registration fee shall be established by implementing order approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Registration shall be valid for the life of the cat. The fee may be reduced by one-half if a certificate that the cat has been sterilized is presented upon application for registration hereunder. There shall be a fee established by implementing order approved by the Board of County Commissioners for the duplication of a lost cat tag. Registration of cats shall be voluntary, and this section does not require a cat owner to purchase a tag as provided hereunder.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-10, ยง 1, 1-22-08)</history></law>