<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>ARTICLE 5. ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION AND PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5.03</section_number>
<catch_line>FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000027</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 5.03. FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION.<section prefix='A.'>The department of finance shall be headed by a finance director appointed by the Mayor and the Clerk of the Circuit and County Courts. The finance director shall have charge of the financial affairs of the county.</section><section prefix='B.'>Between June 1 and July 15, the County Mayor should prepare a proposed budget containing a complete financial plan, including capital and operating budgets, for the ensuing fiscal year. The budget prepared and recommended by the Mayor, shall be presented by the Mayor or his or her designee to the Commission on or before the Board adopts tentative millage rates for the ensuing fiscal year. A summary of the budget shall be published and the Board shall hold hearings on and adopt a budget on or before the dates required by law.</section><section prefix='C.'>No money shall be drawn from the county treasury nor shall any obligation for the expenditure of money be incurred except pursuant to appropriation and except that the Board may establish working capital, revolving, pension, or trust funds and may provide that expenditures from such funds can be made without specific appropriation. The Board, by ordinance, may transfer any unencumbered appropriation balance, or any portion thereof, from one department, fund, or agency to another, subject to the provisions of ordinance. Any portion of the earnings or balance of the several funds, other than sinking funds for obligations not yet retired, may be transferred to the general funds of the county by the Board.</section><section prefix='D.'>Contracts for public improvements and purchases of supplies, materials, and services other than professional shall be made whenever practicable on the basis of specifications and competitive bids. Formal sealed bids shall be secured for all such contracts and purchases when the transaction involves more than the minimum amount established by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance. The transaction shall be evidenced by written contract submitted and approved by the Board. The Board, upon written recommendation of the Mayor, may by resolution adopted by two-thirds vote of the members present waive competitive bidding when it finds this to be in the best interest of the county. Notwithstanding any other provision of the Charter to the contrary, in circumstances where the Mayor informs the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners in writing that he or she has a conflict of interest in the solicitation, evaluation, award, or recommendation of award of a contract, the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners and not the Mayor shall have all authority provided by this Charter or the Board to solicit, evaluate, award or recommend the award of such contract including, but not limited to, the authority to recommend a bid waiver in writing.</section><section prefix='E.'>Any county official or employee of the county who has a special financial interest, direct or indirect, in any action by the Board shall make known that interest and shall refrain from voting upon or otherwise participating in such transaction. Willful violation of this Section shall constitute malfeasance in office, shall effect forfeiture of office or position, and render the transaction voidable by the Board.</section><section prefix='F.'>Such officers and employees of the county as the Board may designate shall give bond in the amount and with the surety prescribed by the Board. The bond premiums shall be paid by the county.</section><section prefix='G.'>At the end of each fiscal year the Board shall provide for an audit by an independent certified public accountant designated by the Board of the accounts and finances of the county for the fiscal year just completed.</section><section prefix='H.'>The Budget Commission created by Chapter 21874, Laws of Florida, 1943, is hereby abolished, and Chapter 21874 shall no longer be of any effect.</section></section></text></law>