<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>ARTICLE 5. ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION AND PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5.04</section_number>
<catch_line>ASSESSMENT AND COLLECTION OF TAXES.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000028</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 5.04. ASSESSMENT AND COLLECTION OF TAXES.<section prefix='A.'>Commencing with the general election to be held in November 2008 and every four years thereafter, the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser shall be elected on a nonpartisan basis, by a majority of the qualified electors voting at a county-wide election held within Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='B.'>Beginning with the tax year 1961, the county tax rolls prepared by the county shall be the only legal tax rolls in this county for the assessment and collection of county and municipal taxes. Thereafter no municipality shall have an assessor or prepare an ad valorem tax roll. Each municipality shall continue to have the right to adopt its own budget, fix its own millage, and levy its own taxes. Each municipality shall certify its levies to the County not later than 30 days after the county tax rolls have been finally approved by the Board. Any municipality may obtain a copy of this tax roll upon payment of the cost of preparing such a copy, and copies of the tax rolls shall be available for public inspection at reasonable times. Maps showing the assessed valuation of each parcel of property may be prepared and made available for sale to the public at a reasonable price.</section><section prefix='C.'>All county and municipal taxes for the tax year beginning January 1, 1961, and all subsequent tax years, shall be collected by the county on one bill prepared and sent out by the county. The amounts of county and municipal taxes shall be shown as separate items, and may be paid separately.</section><section prefix='D.'>Delinquent municipal taxes shall be collected in the same manner as delinquent county taxes.</section><section prefix='E.'>All the tax revenues collected for any municipality shall be returned monthly by the county to the municipality.</section></section></text></law>