<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>ARTICLE 5. ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION AND PROCEDURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>5.05</section_number>
<catch_line>DEPARTMENT OF PERSONNEL.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000029</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 5.05. DEPARTMENT OF PERSONNEL.<section prefix='A.'>The Board of County Commissioners shall establish and maintain personnel and civil service, retirement, and group insurance programs. The personnel system of the county shall be based on merit principles in order to foster effective career service in county employment and to employ those persons best qualified for county services which they are to perform.</section><section prefix='B.'>The Mayor shall appoint a personnel director who shall head the department of personnel and whose duty it shall be to administer the personnel and civil service programs and the rules governing them. The standards of such programs shall not be less than those prevailing at the time of the effective date of this Charter.</section><section prefix='C.'>Except as provided herein, Chapter 30255, General Laws, 1955, as it exists on the effective date of this Charter, shall remain in effect until amended or changed by ordinance of the Board of County Commissioners adopted by two-thirds vote of the members present after recommendation from either the Personnel Advisory Board or the County Mayor.</section><section prefix='D.'>Employees of municipalities who, by merger, transfer, or assignment of governmental units or functions become county employees, shall not lose the civil service rights or privileges which have accrued to them during their period of employment with such municipality, and the county shall use its best efforts to employ these employees within the limits of their capabilities. However, if because of the merger of a department or division of a municipality with the county, all of the employees of such department or division are unable to be employed by the county either because of lack of funds or lack of work, the employee possessing the greater amount of service shall be retained in accordance with civil service rules and regulations. Those employees who are not retained shall be placed on a priority list for employment by the county subject to seniority. Any non-retained employee shall have the option, if a vacancy occurs or exists in another department, and if he is qualified to render the service required, to either accept such employment or remain on the priority list until such time as employment shall be available for him in his own or similar classification.</section><section prefix='E.'>The pension plan presently provided by the state for county employees shall not be impaired by the Board. Employees of municipalities, who by merger, transfer, or assignment of governmental units or functions become county employees shall not lose their pension rights, or any reserves accrued to their benefit during their period of employment with such municipality. The Board of County Commissioners shall provide a method by which these employees' rights and reserves shall be protected, and these employees shall continue until retirement, dismissal, or death in a pension status no less beneficial than the status held by them at the time of merger or assignment.</section><section prefix='F.'>The Board of County Commissioners shall provide and place into effect a practical group insurance plan for all county employees.</section></section></text></law>