<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='2'>Chapter 6 BLOOD DONOR FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>6-4.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Donor identification system for plasma donors and plasmapheresis facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001354</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 6-4.1. Donor identification system for plasma donors and plasmapheresis facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions. As used in this section the following terms shall be defined as hereinafter provided:<section prefix='(1)'>"Plasma donor" means an individual who undergoes venipuncture (or phlebotomy) to obtain the liquid portion of blood (plasma).</section><section prefix='(2)'>"Plasmapheresis" means the procedure whereby whole blood is removed from a plasma donor by venipuncture (or phlebotomy) and the plasma is separated therefrom.</section><section prefix='(3)'>"Plasmapheresis facility" means any facility, laboratory, or place of business where plasmapheresis is performed.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Plasma donor identification system. There shall be established, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Director of the Dade County Department of Public Health, a system for the registration and identification of and the gathering of medical data applicable to any person who shall undergo or attempt to undergo plasmapheresis in any plasmapheresis facility in Dade County. The information, data gathering, and registration system for which provision is herein made shall be known as the "Plasma Donor Identification System:"<section prefix='(1)'>Donor identification card required. Except as hereinafter provided, it shall be unlawful for any person to present himself for plasmapheresis and for any plasmapheresis facility to perform plasmapheresis on any individual, unless that individual shall first present to the plasmapheresis facility a valid donor registration card for which provision is made in subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Application for donor registration number and donor registration card. Each prospective plasma donor before undergoing plasmapheresis shall make application to the Department of Public Health, in a manner prescribed by that Department, for a donor identification number and a donor identification card. Each plasmapheresis facility shall be required to place and maintain upon the premises of the facility such photographic and other identification equipment as shall be required by the Director of the Dade County Department of Public Health for the maintenance of the plasma donor identification system.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Records and confidentiality. Records shall be kept by each plasmapheresis facility and by the Department of Public Health pertaining to each plasmapheresis procedure performed and each attempt by an individual to undergo plasmapheresis. Such records shall set forth the date of the aforementioned events, identifying information pertaining to the plasma donor or prospective plasma donor, and such other identifying and medical data as shall be required by the Department of Public Health. All of the aforementioned information shall be provided by plasmapheresis facilities to the Department of Public Health daily and the Department of Public Health shall compile such information and give prompt notification of any violation of this section or the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant hereto.<section>The Department of Public Health shall keep all its records in a manner which protects the rights of individuals to the confidentiality of their medical records. The disclosure of the identity of or other information relating to blood donors, except as such disclosure is directly related to and necessary for enforcement of this section is expressly prohibited.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Prohibited acts. It shall be unlawful for any person to obtain or attempt to obtain more than one (1) plasma donor identification card or more than one (1) plasma donor identification number, or for any person to attempt to utilize a donor identification card or donor identification number of another individual, or for any person to provide false information to a plasmapheresis facility or to the Department of Public Health in connection with the application for a donor identification card or identification number or in connection with any plasmapheresis procedure.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Fees. The Director of the Dade County Department of Public Health shall assess a fee upon each plasmapheresis facility for the purpose of paying the expense which the Department of Public Health shall incur in the implementation and maintenance of the plasma donor identification system.</section><section>   The fee shall be based upon the number of plasmapheresis procedures performed by a plasmapheresis facility, and shall be payable monthly by the facility upon receipt of an invoice from the Dade County Department of Public Health. The fee shall not exceed the amount of fifty cents ($0.50) for each plasmapheresis procedure which has been performed by the facility during the said month. The total of fees collected shall not exceed the cost to the Department of Public Health of administering the plasma donor identification system.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Penalties. In addition to the penalties otherwise provided by Ordinance 73-91 [Chapter 6], the following penalties may be imposed by the Director of the Department of Public Health upon his determination that an individual has violated a provision of this section:<section prefix='(1)'>For a violation by a person who is not a registered donor, a disqualification of that person from becoming a registered donor for a period not exceeding ninety (90) days for each violation.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For the first violation by a registered donor, suspension of the donor identification card and number and all the privileges incident thereto for a period not exceeding ninety (90) days.</section><section prefix='(3)'>For the second violation by a registered donor, suspension of the donor identification card and number and all the privileges incident thereto for a period not exceeding one (1) year.</section><section prefix='(4)'>For the third violation by a registered donor, suspension of the donor identification card and number and all the privileges incident thereto for a period not exceeding five (5) years, or permanent revocation of the donor identification card and registration number and all the privileges incident thereto.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-4, §§ 2, 3, 2-5-74; Ord. No. 74-50, § 1, 7-2-74)</history></law>