<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='2'>Chapter 6 BLOOD DONOR FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>6-5.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure for the denial, revocation, suspension, limitation, annulment or denial of renewal of the registration of any blood donor facility or license of blood donor facility personnel.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001357</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 6-5.1. Procedure for the denial, revocation, suspension, limitation, annulment or denial of renewal of the registration of any blood donor facility or license of blood donor facility personnel.<section>Notice of violation. Whenever the Director of the Department of Public Health or his duly authorized representative finds and determines that there has been a violation of the Dade County Blood Donor Facility Ordinance, he shall give notice of such violation to the party or parties responsible for such violations. Such notice shall be in writing and shall specify the violation and shall prescribe for a reasonable time for compliance, and shall be served upon the party or parties responsible for the violation. Such notice shall be deemed to be properly served and binding upon the party or parties responsible and upon the facility involved if a copy is served personally by certified mail, or if after diligent search and inquiry the party or parties responsible for the violation cannot be found or served by personal service or certified mail, a copy of the notice is posted in a conspicuous place on the facility involved. Such notice shall specify that the violation must be corrected within the time specified in the notice and that failure to comply within the time specified may result in the suspension or revocation of the party or parties registration and/or license. Such notice shall inform the party or parties to whom it is directed of the right to apply to the Health Appeals Board for a hearing and review of the matters specified in the notice.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-53, ยง 4, 7-2-74)</history></law>