<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='2'>Chapter 6 BLOOD DONOR FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>6-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement, inspection, penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001360</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 6-6. Enforcement, inspection, penalties.<section>It shall be the responsibility of the Director of the Dade County Department of Public Health or his duly authorized representative to enforce the provisions of this chapter throughout Dade County and the Director shall have the duty and authority to promulgate regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</section><section>The Dade County Department of Public Health shall make an inspection of each blood donor facility in Dade County not less frequently than once per month for the purpose of determining the existence of any violation of this chapter.</section><section>If the Director of the Department of Public Health or his designee shall determine that a violation of this chapter or of any regulation promulgated hereunder has occurred, the Director shall take one (1) or more of the following actions:<section prefix='(a)'>Service upon the person or facility in violation of a citation setting forth the violation and establishing a time within which such violation must be corrected.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Initiation of a procedure for the denial, revocation, suspension, limitation, annulment, or denial of renewal of the registration of any blood donor facility or the license of any blood donor facility personnel.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The initiation of a judicial procedure for injunctive action against any individual or organization violating this chapter, it being hereby declared that the operation or maintenance of any unregistered blood donor facility or the performance of any blood donor procedure or operation in violation of this chapter or any regulation promulgated hereunder is a nuisance inimical to the public, health, welfare, and safety.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Whenever the Director of Public Health shall have determined the existence of a violation of this chapter which constitutes an immediate threat to the health, safety, or welfare of a donor, a potential recipient of blood or plasma, or the public, and such condition cannot or will not be immediately corrected, the Director of Public Health may order the immediate closing of such blood donor facility until such time as the threat is found no longer to exist.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Referral of the matter to the State Attorney for criminal action against any person in violation of this chapter.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-91, ยง 6, 10-30-73)</history></law>