<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>ARTICLE 6. MUNICIPALITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>6.05</section_number>
<catch_line>CREATION OF NEW MUNICIPALITIES.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000038</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 6.05. CREATION OF NEW MUNICIPALITIES.<section prefix='A.'>The Board of County Commissioners and only the Board may authorize the creation of new municipalities in the unincorporated areas of the county after hearing the recommendations of the Planning Advisory Board, after a public hearing, and after an affirmative vote of a majority of the electors voting and residing within the proposed boundaries. The Board of County Commissioners shall appoint a charter commission, consisting of five electors residing within the proposed boundaries, who shall propose a charter to be submitted to the electors in the manner provided in Section 6.03. The new municipality shall have all the powers and rights granted to or not withheld from municipalities by this Charter and the Constitution and general laws of the State of Florida. Notwithstanding any provision of this Charter to the contrary, with regard to any municipality created after September 1, 2000, the pre-agreed conditions between the County and the prospective municipality which are included in the municipal charter can only be changed if approved by an affirmative vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the members of the Board of County Commissioners then in office, prior to a vote of qualified municipal electors.</section><section prefix='B.'>A new municipality may also be created by petition of electors residing in the area to be incorporated in accordance with the following process:<section prefix='1.'>An incorporation committee composed of a minimum of five (5) electors from the proposed area of incorporation will initiate the process by filing with the Clerk of the Circuit Court an initiatory petition on a form prescribed by the Clerk for such purpose. The form shall identify the names and addresses of the Incorporation Committee members and describe the proposed incorporation area. The form of the petition shall prominently state that a budgetary analysis and a copy of the proposed charter will be distributed to the electors within the area and made available, as required by this section. Within seven (7) days of receipt of the form, the Clerk will determine if the form is acceptable and if it is acceptable shall approve the form of petition and provide the Incorporation Committee the total number of the electors within the proposed incorporation area and the number of required signatures which shall be equal to twenty percent (20%) of the electors in the proposed incorporation area and shall notify the Board of County Commissioners. If the Clerk determines that the form of petition does not comply with the requirements of this Charter or inaccurately describes proposed boundaries, the Clerk may disapprove the form of petition and provide notification to the Incorporation Committee and the Board of County Commissioners of the disapproval. The Clerk shall advise the Incorporation Committee as to the reasons for disapproval and the Incorporation Committee may submit a new petition at any time. If the Clerk approves the form of the petition, the Incorporation Committee, within ninety (90) days of such approval, shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners a proposed municipal charter, which, at a minimum, shall set forth the form of government and governing body of the newly incorporated area as well as provide for the conditions for incorporation as set forth in Section 6.05(B)(7) below. During such ninety (90) day period, the incorporation committee shall hold at least three public hearings on the proposed municipal charter, in three different locations in the area proposed to be incorporated, notice of which shall be mailed to all electors within the area proposed for incorporation.</section><section prefix='2.'>No later than ninety (90) days from the date of approval of the above form by the Clerk, the Board of County Commissioners shall review the appropriateness of the petition for incorporation and proposed municipal charter and recommend any changes to the boundaries of the proposed municipality and proposed municipal charter to the Incorporation Committee at a public hearing.<section prefix='(b)'>At such public hearing, the Board of County Commissioners shall approve the proposed incorporation petition, as presented in the petition or as revised by the Incorporation Committee, or reject the incorporation petition as presented or as revised by the Incorporation Committee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County Commission's failure to review the incorporation petition within the time required by this paragraph is subject to mandamus by a court of competent jurisdiction.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>The Incorporation Committee will have six (6) months from the date by which the Board was required to have reviewed the incorporation petition to obtain signatures equal to twenty percent (20%) of the electors in the proposed incorporation area, with signatures on a petition provided by the Clerk. The petition shall require the name, address and signature of the elector and such signatures shall be notarized.</section><section prefix='4.'>The signed petitions will be submitted to the Supervisor of Elections, who shall have thirty (30) days to canvass the signatures contained therein.</section><section prefix='5.'>Upon certification of the sufficiency of the signatures on the petition, the Supervisor of Elections shall present the petition to the Board of County Commissioners at their next regularly scheduled meeting. After conducting a public hearing at such meeting, the Board of County Commissioners shall decide whether or not to call an election to authorize the creation of a city and approve a municipal charter for the proposed municipality. If the Board decides to call an election to authorize the creation of the municipality and approve the municipal charter, such election shall occur no sooner than ninety (90) and no greater than one hundred twenty (120) days from the date the Supervisor of Elections certifies the signatures. The election shall be held, whenever practicable, in conjunction with another election scheduled to occur within the prescribed time period. The election shall be decided by an affirmative vote of a majority of electors voting in the proposed incorporation area.</section><section prefix='6.'>During the sixty (60) days following the certification of the petition, the Board shall complete a budgetary analysis in cooperation with the Incorporation Committee of and on the proposed incorporation area and schedule at least one public hearing prior to the incorporation election. The budgetary analysis, including a response by the incorporation committee if submitted, shall be provided to the resident electors of the proposed municipality by mail and shall be made available at locations within the proposed municipality. The proposed municipal charter shall be made available at locations within the proposed municipality and made available electronically. Such budgetary analysis shall at a minimum estimate all of the identifiable revenues generated by the proposed incorporation area prior to incorporation, and present the operating expenses of comparable small, medium and large municipalities providing typical municipal services.</section><section prefix='7.'>The new municipality shall have all the powers and rights granted to or not withheld from municipalities by the County Home Rule Charter and the Constitution and general laws of the State of Florida; provided, however, any proposed municipality whose boundaries include any area outside the urban development boundary, as may be described in the County's Comprehensive Development Master Plan, shall abide by the permitted uses as set forth in such plan. It is further provided, as a condition of incorporation, that the new municipality shall provide in its charter: to remain a part of the Miami-Dade Fire Rescue District, to remain a part of the Miami-Dade Library System, to contract with Miami-Dade County for local patrol police services for a minimum of three years, for Miami-Dade County to retain authority for residential garbage and refuse collection and disposal within the proposed new municipality, and for the payment, assumption, or other satisfaction for that portion of the County's preexisting debts and obligations or other refundings secured by revenues or taxes collected within the proposed municipality's area and that neither the new municipality nor its electors shall take any action that would adversely affect the County's bond or other debt obligations that are secured by taxes or revenues from the area constituting the new municipality.</section></section></section></text></law>