<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Water Conservation District.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001363</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-1. Water Conservation District.<section prefix='(a)'>Established. The establishment of a Water Conservation District embracing all of Dade County, Florida, known as the "Dade County Water Conservation District," accomplished by Resolution No. 1988, is hereby ratified, confirmed and reestablished.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Salt barrier line fixed. The Dade County salt barrier line, shown, depicted and described upon the map hereto attached and made a part hereof by reference, is hereby fixed, established and set, and shall constitute the westerly limit beyond which no new uncontrolled canals, channels, or continuous excavations from any salt contaminated areas easterly thereof shall be excavated or constructed. Such map fixing and establishing the Dade County salt barrier line shall be filed for record with the Clerk of the Circuit Court, and shall supersede all prior maps, sketches or plans in respect to the location or establishment of a salt barrier line.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Penalties. It shall be unlawful for any person to violate, breach, or fail to observe or obey the salt barrier line herein fixed and established, or to violate any provision herein contained. It shall be the duty of all County and municipal officers, officials and employees to enforce the provisions of this section. No permit, license or authorization to excavate, create or construct any uncontrolled canal, channel, or continuous excavations from any salt contamination area easterly of said salt barrier line shall be granted or issued, and no subdivision plat shall be approved or filed for record that provides or contemplates any improvements which would violate, breach or in any way impair or constitute a waiver of the Dade County salt barrier line. The provisions of this section may be enforced by injunction, or other appropriate civil action. In addition to any civil remedies, any person convicted of a violation of the provisions of this section shall be punished by a fine or imprisonment, or both, in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction, as provided in Section 1-5 of this Code. (Ord. No. 60-33, §§ 1—3, 10-25-60)</section><section prefix='(d)'>Exception. The provisions of this section shall not be construed to prohibit construction of boat slips or similar bank line excavations within the reaches of existing canals at points westerly of the salt barrier line, when the Director of the Public Works Department certifies to the County Commission that any such proposed boat slip or bank line excavation will not increase salt intrusion or contamination of the area involved. No such permits shall be issued until authorized by the County Commission.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 61-32, § 1, 7-11-61)</history></law>