<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. MOTORBOATS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-22.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Metropolitan Dade County vessel registration fee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001370</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-22.1. Metropolitan Dade County vessel registration fee.<section>There is hereby imposed an annual County registration fee on vessels required to be registered by the State of Florida and which are operated or stored in Dade County, Florida. This fee shall be fifty (50) percent of the applicable State registration fee as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>The Tax Collector of Dade County is hereby authorized to collect the annual County vessel registration fee at the time when State vessel registration fees are collected and to issue a receipt for payment of the County fee. The first one dollar ($1.00) of every registration fee imposed under this section shall be remitted to the State for deposit in the Motorboat Revolving Trust Fund. All other monies received shall be deposited into the Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund.</section><section>Monies realized from the annual vessel registration fee and deposited in the Biscayne Bay Environmental Enhancement Trust Fund shall be used for:<section prefix='(a)'>Maintenance and installation of aids to navigation to protect valuable Bay habitats,</section><section prefix='(b)'>Fisheries enhancement and maintenance,</section><section prefix='(c)'>Habitat enhancement and maintenance,</section><section prefix='(d)'>Activities related to the preservation of manatees and their habitat,</section><section prefix='(e)'>Other water body maintenance, regulation, and enhancement activities.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-11, ยง 1, 2-19-85; Ord. No. 89-122, ยง 1, 12-5-89)</history></law>