<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. MOTORBOATS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-26</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibitions; motorboat restricted zones.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001374</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-26. Prohibitions; motorboat restricted zones.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to operate a motorboat on any waters lying within the boundaries of Dade County in violation of the rules, regulations and standards established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall operate a motorboat, or permit, allow or suffer a motorboat to be operated in the Miami River Idle Speed No Wake Zone at any speed greater than idle speed no wake. The Miami River Idle Speed No Wake Zone is hereby established to be all waters of the Miami River and its tributaries, the Tamiami Canal, Comfort Canal and Seybold Canal from their respective salinity control structures to the Intracoastal Waterway in Biscayne Bay at the mouth of the Miami River. The Miami River Idle Speed No Wake Zone shall be marked on the river with uniform waterway regulatory markers in accordance with applicable State and federal laws and regulations. The regulation of motorboat speed in the Miami River Idle Speed No Wake Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under authority and power granted in Section 7-27</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall operate a motorboat, allow or suffer a motorboat to be operated in the Little Maule Lake Idle Speed/No Wake Zone at any speed greater than idle speed, no wake. The Little Maule Lake Idle Speed/No Wake Zone is hereby established to be all the waters of Little Maule Lake. The Little Maule Lake Idle Speed/No Wake Zone shall be marked on the lake with uniform waterway regulatory markers in accordance with applicable State and federal laws and regulations. The regulation of motorboat speed in the Little Maule Lake Idle Speed/No Wake Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27</section><section prefix='(d)'>No person shall operate a motorboat, or permit, allow or suffer a motorboat to be operated in the Rickenbacker Causeway Motorboat Exclusion Zone. The Rickenbacker Causeway Motorboat Exclusion Zone is hereby established to be all waters within four hundred (400) feet south of the Rickenbacker Causeway from the east bulkhead of the West Bridge to the west bulkhead of the William M. Powell Bridge, including all improvements, recreational areas and property thereof measured from the mean low-water line; and that portion of the water area of Biscayne Bay on the southwesterly side of the Rickenbacker Causeway from the east bulkhead of the William M. Powell Bridge to the northwest bulkhead of the Seaquarium property, and northeasterly of the following described line of sight:<section>Begin at a point on the southern tip of the northern concrete bulkhead at the entrance to the circular cove of the west side of the property upon which the Seaquarium is situated; thence run northwesterly, in a straight line, to a point on the southwesterly tip of the concrete bulkhead at the east end of the William M. Powell and old Rickenbacker Causeway (Crandon Boulevard) Bridges.</section></section><section>A map reflecting the boundaries of the Rickenbacker Causeway Motorboat Exclusion Zone shall be available at the Metropolitan Dade County Public Works Department for reference by the public. The Rickenbacker Causeway Motorboat Exclusion Zone shall be marked on the waters with uniform regulatory markers in accordance with the applicable State and federal laws and regulations. The regulation of motorboat use in the Rickenbacker Causeway Motorboat Exclusion Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27, and Sections 327.46 and 327.60, Florida Statutes (1987).</section><section prefix='(e)'>No person shall operate a motorboat or permit, allow or suffer a motorboat to be operated in the Key Biscayne Hurricane Harbor and Pines Canal Idle Speed/No Wake Zone at any speed greater than idle speed no wake. The Key Biscayne Hurricane Harbor and Pines Canal Idle Speed/No Wake Zone is hereby established to be all waters of Hurricane Harbor to its mouth at Biscayne Bay and all waters of Pines Canal and adjoining canal systems to its mouth at Biscayne Bay. The Key Biscayne Hurricane Harbor and Pines Canal Idle Speed/No Wake Zone shall be marked on the waters with uniform waterway regulatory markers in accordance with applicable State and federal laws and regulations. The regulation of motorboat speed in the Key Biscayne Hurricane Harbor and Pines Canal Idle Speed/No Wake Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27, and Sections 327.46 and 327.60, Florida Statutes (1987).</section><section prefix='(f)'>No person shall operate a motorboat, or permit, allow or suffer a motorboat to be operated in the Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone at any speed greater than idle speed no wake. The Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone is hereby established to be all waters of the Oleta River from its intersection with Maule Lake at Snake Creek Canal to its mouth at the Intracoastal Waterway. The Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone shall be marked on the waters with uniform waterway regulatory markers in accordance with applicable State and federal laws and regulations. The regulation of motorboat speed in the Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27, and Sections 327.46 and 327.60, Florida Statutes (1987).</section><section prefix='(g)'>No person shall operate a motorboat, or permit, allow or suffer a motorboat to be operated in the Upper Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone at any speed greater than idle speed no wake. The Upper Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone is hereby established to be all waters of the Oleta River and adjoining canals and lakes from Ives Dairy Road to the intersection of the river with northwestern Maule Lake. The Upper Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone shall be marked on the waters with uniform waterway regulatory markers in accordance with applicable State and federal laws and regulations. The regulation of motorboat speed in the Upper Oleta River Idle Speed/No Wake Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27, and Sections 327.46 and 327.60, Florida Statutes (1987).</section><section prefix='(h)'>No person shall operate a boat, motorboat or personal watercraft (commonly known as jet skis), or permit, allow or suffer a boat, motorboat or personal watercraft to be operated in or allowed to moor or tie-up to any marker used within the Haulover/Sunny Isles Beach Boat, Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone. The Haulover/Sunny Isles Beach Boat, Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone is hereby established to be all waters within 195th Street to the north and southward to the northside of Bakers Haulover Cut, including all improvements, recreational areas and property thereof measured from the mean low water line; and that portion of the water area of the Atlantic Ocean, extending up to a minimum of 300 feet off shore on the southside of 195th Street to the northside of the Bakers Haulover Cut described as a direct line of sight. There will be Idle Speed Zones established to allow concessions and others to make landfall through these zones. Each of the zones will be clearly marked and equally spaced throughout the entire length of the "Exclusion Zone." No person shall be allowed to moor outside the "Exclusion Zone" and swim towards the shoreline or a swimmer to swim from the shoreline to a boat moored outside the "Exclusion Zone." Emergency or chase boats, motorboats or personal watercrafts used solely for the purpose of affecting an emergency/sea rescue or for the purpose of ensuring compliance with federal or state laws or city or county ordinances are excluded from this ordinance. A map reflecting the boundaries of the Haulover/Sunny Isles Beach Boat, Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone shall be available at the Metropolitan Dade County Park and Recreation Department for reference by the public. After the effective date of this ordinance, the areas located on the public beaches within the Haulover/Sunny Isles Beach areas, as previously described shall be known as restricted swim areas and shall be governed by the provision set forth in this ordinance. The Haulover/Sunny Isles Beach Boat, Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone shall be marked on the water with uniform regulatory markers in accordance with the applicable state and federal laws and regulations. The provisions of this ordinance shall be enforced by the Metropolitan Dade County Police Department's Marine Patrol and other state and federal authorities having jurisdiction over the water located within the "Exclusion Zone." Any person, corporation, partnership, limited partnership, association or other business entity which is convicted of violating this ordinance shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment in the County jail for not more than thirty (30) days or by both such fine and imprisonment. The regulation of a boat, motorboat, or personal watercraft use in the Haulover/Sunny Isles Beach Boat, Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27, and Sections 327.46 and 327.60, Florida Statutes (1995). The effect of this section shall be subject to approval by the Department of Environmental Protection of the State of Florida of the restricted area established in this section pursuant to Section 327.46, Florida Statutes (1995).</section><section prefix='(i)'>No person shall operate a motorboat or personal watercraft, or permit, allow or suffer a motorboat or personal watercraft to be operated in or allowed to moor or tie-up to any marker used within the Crandon Park Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone. The Crandon Park Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone is hereby established within Crandon Park Lands extending south around the Bear Cut Preserve on the Atlantic Ocean side to the southern boundary of Crandon Park Lands extending up to 1,000 feet offshore. The waters through Bear Cut are excluded from this ordinance. No person shall be allowed to moor outside the "Exclusion Zone" and swim towards the shoreline or a swimmer to swim from the shoreline to a boat moored outside the "Exclusion Zone." Emergency or chase boats, motorboats or personal watercraft used solely for affecting an emergency/sea rescue or for ensuring compliance with Federal or State Laws or City or County Ordinances are excluded from this Ordinance. A map reflecting the boundaries of the Crandon Park Motorboat or Personal Exclusion Zone shall be available at the Miami-Dade Park and Recreation Department for reference by the public. After the effective date of this Ordinance, the areas located on the public beaches within the Crandon Park Lands, as previously described shall be known as restricted swim areas and shall be governed by the provisions set forth in this Ordinance. The Crandon Park Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone shall be marked on the water with uniform regulatory markers in accordance with the applicable Federal and State Laws and Regulations. The provisions of this Ordinance shall be enforced by the Miami-Dade Police Department, Marine Patrol Division and other Federal and State authorities having jurisdiction over the water located within the "Exclusion Zone." Any person, corporation, partnership, limited partnership, association or other business entity which is convicted of violating this Ordinance shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred ($500) dollars or by imprisonment in the County jail for not more than thirty (30) days or by both such fine and imprisonment. The regulation of motorboat or personal watercraft use in the Crandon Park Motorboat or Personal Watercraft Exclusion Zone as herein described has been established by the County Manager under the authority and power granted in Section 7-27, and Section 327.46 and 327.60, Florida Statutes (2001). The effect of this Section shall be subject to approval by the Department of Environmental Protection of the State of Florida of the restricted area established in this Section pursuant to Section 327.46, Florida Statutes (2001).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-15, § 3, 4-2-74; Ord. No. 83-113, § 1, 12-6-83; Ord. No. 86-80, § 2, 10-28-86; Ord. No. 87-16, § 1, 4-7-87; Ord. No. 89-40, § 1, 5-18-89; Ord. No. 89-60, § 1, 7-11-89; Ord. No. 89-91, § 1, 9-26-89; Ord. No. 89-93, § 1, 9-26-89; Ord. No. 96-88, § 1, 6-4-96; Ord. No. 03-48, § 1, 3-11-03)</history></law>