<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. MOTORBOATS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-26.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibitions; maximum sound level standards for vessels on County waters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001375</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-26.1. Prohibitions; maximum sound level standards for vessels on County waters.<section prefix='(1)'>Definitions: The following words and phrases when used in this section shall have the meaning respectively assigned to them in this subsection:<section prefix='(a)'>dBA means the composite abbreviation of the A-weighted sound level and the unit of sound level, the decibel.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Sound level means the A-weighted sound pressure level measured with fast response using an instrument complying with the specification for sound level meters of the American National Standards Institute, Inc., or its successor bodies, except that only a weighting and fast dynamic response need be provided.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Prohibition: No person shall operate or give permission for the operation of any vessel on the waters of Dade County, including the waters of the Florida Intracoastal Waterway, in such a manner as to exceed the following sound levels at a distance of fifty (50) feet from the vessel: For all vessels, a maximum sound level of ninety (90)dBA.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Penalty for refusal to submit to sound level test: Any person who refuses to submit to a sound level test when requested to do so by a law enforcement officer is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in Sections 775.082, 775.083 or 775.084, Florida Statutes.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 89-30, ยง 1, 4-18-89)</history></law>