<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Swimming or fishing from road bridges.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001365</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-3. Swimming or fishing from road bridges.<section prefix='(a)'>The County Manager shall cause to be investigated and determined whether it is detrimental to traffic safety or dangerous to human life for any person to swim or fish from any road bridge located in Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>After making an affirmative finding in writing as to any road bridge as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the County Manager shall cause to be designated, in writing, such bridge as one (1) from which swimming or fishing is prohibited and shall post official signs thereon declaring that swimming or fishing is prohibited.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When an official sign is erected giving notice thereof no person shall swim or fish from a bridge in violation of such sign.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Adult offenders of this section shall be tried in the court of appropriate jurisdiction of Dade County, Florida, and juvenile offenders of this section shall be tried in the Dade County Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Violations of this section may be punished by:<section prefix='(1)'>A fine not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200.00);</section><section prefix='(2)'>Imprisonment in the county jail for a period not to exceed thirty (30) days;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-13, §§ 1—5, 2-18-69; Ord. No. 69-57, § 1, 9-17-69; Ord. No. 10-52, § 1, 9-21-10)</history></law>