<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Mooring watercraft to bridges, fender systems, public bank, etc.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001366</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-4. Mooring watercraft to bridges, fender systems, public bank, etc.<section prefix='(a)'>No watercraft of any nature whatsoever shall be moored to public bridges, bridge approaches, fender systems, or piles driven for the protection of bridges or their approaches, or to any publicly owned bank or shore, unless under a lease or permit issued by the governmental body having jurisdiction thereof.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It is unlawful and a violation of this section to moor any watercraft in the area between the bank or shore owned by a public authority and the bridge fender system.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All violations under this section shall be punishable by a fine not to exceed two hundred and fifty dollars ($250.00) or imprisonment not to exceed thirty (30) days in the County Jail, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court of appropriate jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(d)'>This section shall not be interpreted to prohibit temporary docking to any structure listed in subsection (a) during an emergency. By temporary is meant a period of time not exceeding twenty-four (24) hours. By emergency is meant any structural defect in the watercraft, caused by either a normal breakdown or collision, which would render the watercraft a hazard to navigation if not immediately moored to structures listed in subsection (a), or any weather condition which seriously endangers a watercraft and which would render the watercraft a hazard to navigation if not moored to any of the structures listed in subsection (a).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-1, §§ 1—4, 1-7-69)</history></law>