<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. BARGES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-55</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001379</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-55. Definitions.<section>For purposes of this article, the term "Miami Harbor" shall include all navigable waters within the confines of Dade County.</section><section>[A "storm warning" is] a warning issued by the U.S. Weather Bureau that one (1) or more of the following dangerous weather conditions are expected in a specified coastal area in twenty-four (24) hours or less:<section prefix='(a)'>Tropical storm. A tropical cyclone with closed isobars and highest wind speeds of thirty-four (34) to sixty-three (63) knots (thirty-nine (39) to seventy-three (73) mph) inclusive.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Whole gale. Winds in the range of fifty-five (55) to seventy-three (73) miles per hour (forty-eight (48) to sixty-three (63) knots).</section></section><section>[A "hurricane warning" is] a warning issued by the U.S. Weather Bureau that one (1) or more of the following dangerous effects of a hurricane are expected in a specified coastal area in twenty-four (24) hours or less:<section prefix='(a)'>Hurricane force winds (seventy-four (74) miles per hour or higher).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Dangerously high water or a combination of dangerously high water and exceptionally high waves, even though winds expected may be less than hurricane force.</section></section><section>[A "barge" is] any vessel without sail or internal motive power of its own intended to be utilized by being towed by another vessel.</section><section>[An "undocumented barge" is] any barge which is not required to have, and does not have, a valid marine document issued by the U.S. Coast Guard or Bureau of Customs.</section><section>["Open water" is] all navigable water in Dade County not protected from wind and wave action on all points of the compass, including all of Biscayne Bay except sheltered coves.</section><section>["Sheltered waters" are] all navigable waters in Dade County protected from wind and wave action on all sides including the upper reaches of the Miami River and excluding all of Biscayne Bay except sheltered coves.</section><section>["Safe anchorage" is] a place for anchorage or mooring that is sheltered from the action of wind and wave, and provides adequate holding power for anchors or mooring lines utilized.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 67-51, ยง 1, 7-25-67)</history></law>