<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-10</section_number>
<catch_line>Permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001395</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-10. Permits.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to the requirements of Section 104 (Permits) of the Florida Building Code the following shall be required:<section prefix='(i)'>To be included drawings as applicable:</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Minimum information requirements for construction documents:</section></section><section>EXTERIOR ELEVATION INFORMATION</section><section>BUILDING SECTION AND DETAIL INFORMATION</section><section>FLOOR PLAN INFORMATION</section><section>(Recommend that same orientation as Site Plan be used)</section><section>FRAMING PLAN INFORMATION</section><section>(Required that same orientation as Floor Plan be used)</section><section>FOUNDATION PLAN INFORMATION</section><section>Recommend that same orientation as Floor Plan be used</section><section>ELECTRICAL, PLUMBING AND H.V.A.C. INFORMATION<section prefix='(iii)'>The following written requirements are to be followed by the delegated engineer in preparing his engineering documents on that portion of the project utilizing prefabrication components:<section prefix='1.'>All shop drawings shall be in conformity with the architect or engineer of record framing plans unless prior written approval is obtained from the architect or engineer of record. If re-framing is approved, the architect or engineer of record shall resubmit revised framing plans to the building official after receiving updated plans from the delegated engineer showing all adjustments necessary to safely transmit all applied loads to the foundation.</section><section prefix='2.'>All details and sections required to show the size and connections of all secondary members will be supplied on the delegated engineering plans and shall show all framing, connections and bracing on one or more primary plans.</section><section prefix='3.'>8½" × 11" cut sheets showing individual member design shall also be furnished to the architect or engineer of record, but it will be necessary to transfer all gravity and uplift loads shown on these cut sheets to the primary plans.</section><section>The intent of the above requirements is to provide all information on framing, connections and bracing on one composite set of plans approved by the architect or engineer of record to aid in the review, approval and field inspection for the portion of the property.</section></section><section prefix='(iv)'>The plans shall include a schedule similar to the one shown below to be filled by the Architect or Engineer of Record.</section></section><section>HVAC DESIGN REQUIREMENTS<section prefix='(v)'>Permits shall be required for the following low voltage work: fiber optics, telephone, television, communications, fire alarms, burglar alarms, computer systems, central vacuums and all other systems seventy-seven (77) volts or less.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Electrical permits shall be required for all appurtenances, apparatus, or equipment used in connection therewith, inside of or attached to any building or structure, lot, or premises.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The plans examiner shall examine all plans and specifications and if found to comply with the requirements of the Building Code, he or she shall mark the plans "REVIEWED FOR CODE COMPLIANCE".</section><section prefix='(c)'>Upon approval of plans, specifications and application for permit and the payment of the required fee, the Building Official shall issue a weatherproof permit card which shall bear the description of the property, the nature of the work being done, the name of the owner and contractor and other pertinent information: and such card shall be maintained in a conspicuous place on the front of the premises affected thereby during the entire time that the work authorized by the permit is in progress.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-112, § 1, 7-10-01)</history></law>