<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Special Hurricane Inspections.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001401</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-16. Special Hurricane Inspections.<section prefix='(a)'>During such periods of time as the National Weather Service has issued a severe weather advisory that is in effect for Miami-Dade County, best efforts must be used so that all furniture, display racks, material and similar loose objects in exposed outdoor locations, including loose material of projects under construction are secured or otherwise appropriately braced to rigid construction or stored in buildings to the extent practicable given the conditions. Orders shall be oral or written and shall be given to any person on the premises most logically responsible for maintenance and such orders shall be carried out before winds of tropical storm velocity are anticipated.</section><section prefix='(b)'>After winds of the velocity associated with a severe weather event are experienced and have subsided, the Building Official shall investigate to determine if damage has occurred to buildings or other structures.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No building or other structure or assembly or part thereof, which was damaged or collapsed or out of plumb or line shall be repaired or altered or otherwise returned to its original position without inspection and approval by the Building Official.</section><section prefix='(d)'>For the purposes of this section, "severe weather advisory" shall be defined as any one of the following: a tropical storm warning, a hurricane watch, or a hurricane warning and the term "severe weather event" shall be defined as a tropical storm or hurricane.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-112, ยง 1, 7-10-01; Ord. No. 06-7, ยง 1, 1-24-06)</history></law>