<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Required disclosure.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001403</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-18. Required disclosure.<section>In any contract for the sale to the original purchaser(s) of any new structure in Miami-Dade County, which structure was erected pursuant to the professional certification of plans and inspections by architects and engineers who have been privately retained by the owner and applicant for permits pursuant to state law as incorporated in Section 2-1265 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, the seller shall include in the contract, or in an Addendum to the contract that has been separately signed and acknowledged by the purchaser at closing, a disclosure in not less than ten-point bold-face type:<section>THIS STRUCTURE (HAS BEEN OR WILL BE) BUILT IN COMPLIANCE WITH THE FLORIDA BUILDING CODE AS DETERMINED BY STATE LICENSED AND REGISTERED ARCHITECTS AND ENGINEERS PRIVATELY HIRED BY THE OWNER AND APPLICANT FOR PERMITS TO PERFORM CERTIFICATION OF PLANS AND INSPECTIONS AS PROVIDED UNDER THE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION PROGRAM ESTABLISHED UNDER STATE LAW. THE NAME, ADDRESS, TELEPHONE NUMBER, AND STATE LICENSE NUMBER OF EITHER EACH INDIVIDUAL THAT IS WORKING ON HIS/HER OWN AS AN INDEPENDENT ARCHITECT OR ENGINEER OR THE PRINCIPAL OF THE COMPANY THAT IS USED TO EXAMINE PLANS AND INSPECT THIS STRUCTURE; ARE AS FOLLOWS:</section><section></section><section></section><section></section><section></section></section><section>If it is not known at the time the initial contract for sale is signed whether the owner and applicant for permits will use a privately hired architect or engineer, the Seller shall disclose the option to use such privately hired architects and engineers in the contract.</section><section>Once the Seller has retained a private architect or engineer, the Seller shall inform the buyer, by certified mail, return receipt requested, in not less than ten-point bold face type, that the owner and applicant for permits has retained a private architect or engineer to certify building plans and perform required inspections of the structure for compliance with the building code. This disclosure form shall at a minimum, include the name, address, telephone number and state license number of either each individual that is working on his/her own as an independent architect or engineer or the principal of the company that is used to examine plans and inspect the structure.</section><section>Violations of this Section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in above.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-219, ยง 1, 12-18-01)</history></law>