<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Incorporation of Florida Building Code; Adoption of Optional Provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001386</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-2. Incorporation of Florida Building Code; Adoption of Optional Provisions.<section>The provisions of the Florida Building Code as applicable to High Velocity Hurricane Zones are hereby incorporated by reference. The Florida Building Code will not be repeated or restated in this Chapter except where necessary to provide clarity. The following provisions of the Florida Building Code are hereby adopted and made applicable to Miami-Dade County:<section prefix='(a)'>The High Velocity Hurricane Zone roofing requirements with accompanying Roofing Application Standards (RAS) (Florida Building Code Sec. 1512.2).<section>Exception: The prescriptive BUR requirements in RAS 150 shall not be implemented in Miami-Dade County (Florida Building Code RAS 150).</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Appendix A—Weight of building materials.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Appendix B—Chapter 9B-52, Florida Standard for Passive Radon-Resistant New Residential Building Construction.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Appendix C—Chapter 9B-53, Standard for Mitigation of Radon in Existing Buildings.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Appendix D—The Secretary of the Interior's Standard for Rehabilitation and Guidelines for Rehabilitating Historic Buildings.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Appendix E—Chapter 9B-67, Florida Standard for Radon-Resistant New Commercial Building Construction.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Appendix F—Florida Standard for Radon-Resistant New Residential Building Construction.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Appendix G—Florida Standard for Radon-Resistant New Commercial Building Construction.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Appendix H—Florida Standard for Mitigation of Radon in Existing Buildings.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-112, § 1, 7-10-01)</history></law>