<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-21.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Appointment, powers and duties of chief electrical inspector, electrical inspector, and electrical plans examiner.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001408</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-21.3. Appointment, powers and duties of chief electrical inspector, electrical inspector, and electrical plans examiner.<section prefix='(a)'>The Chief Electrical Inspector shall have the responsibility and duty of enforcing the Electrical Code. The title, Chief Electrical Inspector, shall be construed to mean the chief or head of the division or department of electrical inspection. The Chief Electrical Inspector shall have the power to delegate powers and assignments, dealing with electrical inspections, to subordinate Electrical Inspectors and Plans Examiners working under his/her authority.<section prefix='(1)'>The appointing authority shall appoint a Chief Electrical Inspector. To be eligible for appointment as a Chief Electrical Inspector, an individual shall be certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals and shall be one of the following:<section prefix='(aa)'>A Master Electrician having held a certification issued by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board for a period of at least five years and having five years of field experience under that certification.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>A State Certified Electrical Contractor having held a certification issued by the Florida Electrical Contractor's Licensing Board for a period of at least five years and having five years of field experience under that certification.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>A Florida licensed professional engineer having obtained a license pursuant to examination in the electrical discipline and having had five years of field experience under that license.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>All Electrical Inspectors and Electrical Plan Examiners shall be certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals and shall be one of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>INSPECTORS:<section prefix='(a)'>Each Electrical Inspector shall have:<section prefix='(aa)'>At least five years of field experience as a Certified Journeyman Electrician or Master Electrician issued by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board; or,</section><section prefix='(bb)'>At least five years of field experience as a state Certified Electrical Contractor issued by the Electrical Contractors' Licensing Board.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Each Electrical Sign Inspector shall have:<section prefix='(aa)'>At least five years of field experience as a Certified Electrical Sign Journeyman or Sign Master, issued by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board; or,</section><section prefix='(bb)'>At least five years of field experience as a state Certified Electrical Contractor or Sign Specialty Electrical Contractors license issued by the Electrical Contractor's Licensing Board in that category.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>The Chief Electrical Inspector shall have the power to delegate powers and assignments, dealing with electrical sign inspections only, to subordinate Electrical Sign Inspectors working under his/her authority.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>APPOINTMENT OF ELECTRICAL PLANS EXAMINERS<section>The appointing authority shall appoint and assign duties to the Electrical Plans Examiner and such person shall meet the same qualification and certification requirements as the Chief Electrical Inspector.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>APPOINTMENT OF ELECTRICAL PLANS EXAMINERS (RESIDENTIAL)<section>Electrical Plans Examiner (Residential) shall be appointed and assigned duties in relation to R3 Occupancy only. Each Electrical Plans Examiner (Residential) shall be qualified by:</section><section prefix='(aa)'>At least five years of field experience as a Journeyman or Master Electrician Certified by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board and having worked as a Master Electrician for a minimum of one year within the areas of jurisdiction of this Chapter; or</section><section prefix='(bb)'>Having been certified as an Electrical Contractor by the Electrical Contractors' Licensing Board with five years of field experience under that certification and having worked as an Electrical Contractor for a minimum of one year within the areas of jurisdiction of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>POWERS AND DUTIES:<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be the duty of the Electrical Inspector and the Electrical Sign Inspector to inspect all wiring, apparatus and equipment, and installations for light, heat, power, and low voltage systems and to enforce all the laws, rules and regulations relating thereto in the area of jurisdiction and to enforce all the provisions of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Electrical Inspector and the Electrical Sign Inspector will issue an approval on the wiring installations, apparatus, equipment or light fixtures provided they comply with the rules and regulations of the Building Code. At the time of inspection, if defects, omission, or violations exist on any other part of the wiring system, the issuance of an approval will be withheld until corrections have been made to the defective portion of the wiring system, and the same are made to comply with this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A 30-day temporary electric service connection may be approved for a facility by the Electrical Inspector if the wiring installation, apparatus, or equipment are found to be in a safe operating condition and provided an urgent necessity for electric current exists. Under these circumstances, an application for temporary service must be made in writing by the electrical contractor, firm, corporation, or owner requesting the temporary service connection to the public utility system or isolated generating plant.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Electrical Inspector/Electrical Sign Inspector are hereby empowered to inspect or reinspect any wiring, equipment or apparatus conducting or using electric current for light, heat, power and low voltage systems, and if conductors, equipment or apparatus are found to be unsafe to life or property, the inspector shall serve notice in writing to the owner and/or operator of the hazardous wiring or equipment, to correct the condition within a reasonable period of time.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Electrical Inspector/Electrical Sign Inspector are hereby given the power to disconnect extension cords, temporary wiring, branch circuits, sub-feed conductors, or the main service supplying electrical energy to any portion of an electrical wiring system on or in buildings, or on premises, if this wiring is in the opinion of the inspector considered to be hazardous to life or property. Any person, firm or corporation supplying current, must disconnect service from source of supply upon instructions from the Electrical Inspector/Electrical Sign Inspector where hazards are deemed to exist, after receiving written notice from the Electrical Inspector/Electrical Sign Inspector.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The power and duties of the Electrical Inspector shall be subject to the powers vested in the Board of Rules and Appeals as set forth in Section 8-4 of this Code.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, ยง 1, 10-19-04; Ord. No. 06-69, ยง 1, 5-9-06)</history></law>