<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-21.12</section_number>
<catch_line>Existing certifications.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001419</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-21.12. Existing certifications.<section prefix='(a)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code regarding the requirements for certification of Officials, Inspectors or Plans Examiners, in the event that the Board of Rules and Appeals has at any time prior to January 1, 1992 issued a certification to any person as Official, Inspector or Plans Examiner, the following provisions of the Code shall govern the certification and recertification of such persons before the Board of Rules and Appeals.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any and all certifications of the Board of Rules and Appeals shall be considered to be valid and fully effective in connection with the following persons:<section prefix='(1)'>Any person who obtained the position he or she occupied on January 1, 1992 on or before May 24, 1983, and who at the time he or she obtained the employment met the qualification requirements of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any person who obtained the position he or she occupied on January 1, 1992 on or before May 24, 1983, and at the time he or she obtained the employment this Chapter did not specify any requirements for the position.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Any and all certifications issued by the Board of Rules and Appeals prior to January 1, 1992, shall be considered to be valid and fully effective notwithstanding other requirements of this Code for qualifications of the applicant, provided that the person receiving such certification complies with one of the following conditions:<section prefix='(1)'>On or before January 1, 1992, such person must have the specific license required by this Chapter to occupy the position for which such person has been certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals regardless of the amount of time that such license has been held; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>In the event that this Chapter requires a master's license or other license from the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board, such person must, on or before January 1, 1994, successfully complete the examination in connection with the license required for the position for which he or she has been certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals. Provided that the person has been certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals prior to January 1, 1992, the Construction Trades Qualifying Board shall administer the examination to that person, notwithstanding other requirements of license or certification under Chapter 10 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Successful completion of the examination shall entitle the person to continue to occupy the position that he or she has been certified to occupy by the Board of Rules and Appeals, but shall be of no other force or effect, and shall specifically not be construed as license or certification under Chapter 10 of the Code of Miami-Dade County unless such person complies with all requirements contained in Chapter 10 for license or certification; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>On or before January 1, 1992, such person occupied the position for which he or she has been certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals and such person had been certified by the State of Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board as a contractor in the trade related to the position certified.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>The provisions of this Section shall not affect the continuing education requirements of the Code or the powers of the Board of Rules and Appeals to suspend or revoke a certification as set forth in other provisions of this Chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, ยง 1, 10-19-04)</history></law>