<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-21.3(c)</section_number>
<catch_line>Appointment, powers and duties of chief mechanical inspector, mechanical inspector and mechanical plans examiner.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001410</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-21.3(c). Appointment, powers and duties of chief mechanical inspector, mechanical inspector and mechanical plans examiner.<section prefix='(a)'>Such person shall hereinafter be termed the Chief Mechanical Inspector. The Chief Mechanical Inspector shall have the power to delegate powers and assignments, dealing with mechanical inspections, to subordinate Mechanical Inspectors and Plans Examiners working under his/her authority.<section prefix='(1)'>There shall be appointed by the appointing authority person or persons qualified as set forth herein to serve as Chief Mechanical Inspector and Mechanical Plans Examiner. These individuals shall be qualified as one of the following:<section prefix='(aa)'>A Master General Mechanical Contractor having held a certification by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board for a period of at least five years and having five years of field experience under that certification.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>A State Certified Mechanical Contractor having held a certification by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board for a period of at least five years and having five years of field experience under that certification.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>A Florida licensed Professional Engineer having obtained a license pursuant to examination in the mechanical discipline and having had five years of field experience under that license.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>All Mechanical Inspectors and Mechanical Plan Examiners shall be certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals and shall be one of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>INSPECTOR<section>Each such inspector shall have:</section><section prefix='(aa)'>At least five years of field experience as a Certified Journeyman General, Master Mechanical or Specialty Mechanical Contractor issued by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board; or</section><section prefix='(bb)'>At least five years field experience as a state Certified Mechanical Contractor issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board with not less than five years of field experience working in the areas of jurisdiction of this Chapter.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>APPOINTMENT OF MECHANICAL PLANS EXAMINER<section>The appointing authority shall appoint and assign duties to the Mechanical Plans Examiner, and such person shall meet the same qualification and certification requirements as the Chief Mechanical Inspector.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>APPOINTMENT OF MECHANICAL PLANS EXAMINER (RESIDENTIAL)<section>Mechanical Plans Examiner (Residential) shall be appointed and assigned duties in relation to Group R3 Occupancy only. Each Mechanical Plans Examiner (Residential) shall be qualified by:</section><section prefix='(aa)'>At least five years of field experience as a Journeyman General or Master General Mechanical certified by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board and having worked as a Master Mechanical for a minimum of one year within the areas of jurisdiction of this Chapter; or</section><section prefix='(bb)'>Having been certified as a Mechanical Contractor by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board with five years of field experience under that Certification and having worked as a Mechanical Contractor for a minimum of one year within the areas of jurisdiction of this Chapter.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>POWERS AND DUTIES: The Chief Mechanical Inspector is hereby authorized and directed to interpret and enforce all of the mechanical provisions of this Chapter, subject to the powers vested in the Board of Rules and Appeals as set forth in this Chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, ยง 1, 10-19-04; Ord. No. 06-69, ยง 1, 5-9-06)</history></law>