<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-21.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Appointment of chief building inspector, building plans examiner, structural plans examiner and building inspector.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001407</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-21.2. Appointment of chief building inspector, building plans examiner, structural plans examiner and building inspector.<section prefix='(a)'>APPOINTMENT OF A CHIEF BUILDING INSPECTOR, BUILDING PLANS EXAMINER, AND STRUCTURAL PLANS EXAMINER: There shall be appointed by the appointing authority person or persons qualified as set forth herein to serve as Chief Building Inspector, Building Plans Examiner and Structural Plans Examiner. The above positions may be occupied by one or more persons who comply with all requirements of this Chapter to occupy those positions.</section><section prefix='(b)'>POWERS AND DUTIES: The Chief Building Inspector, Building Plans Examiner and Structural Plans Examiner shall be subject to the powers vested in the Board of Rules and Appeals as set forth in Section 8-4 herein and the Building Official as set forth herein. The Chief Building Inspector may delegate to certified inspectors such powers, duties and assignments as he or she may deem advisable to carry out the provisions of this Chapter and the directives of the Building Official. It shall be the duty and responsibility of the Chief Building Inspector to coordinate the work of all subordinate inspectors. The Structural Plans Examiner shall be the only person qualified to perform structural review of plans.</section><section prefix='(c)'>CERTIFICATION OF CHIEF BUILDING INSPECTOR OR BUILDING PLANS EXAMINER: To be eligible for appointment as a Chief Building Inspector or Building Plans Examiner, an individual shall be certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals and shall be one of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>A Florida Registered Professional Engineer having practiced within the area of jurisdiction of this Chapter for at least five years.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A Florida Registered Architect having practiced within the area of jurisdiction of this Chapter for at least 5 years.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A licensed General Contractor with five years experience, all of which shall have been within the jurisdiction of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A currently certified Building Official, Plans Examiner or Inspector having five years of experience in such position(s), three years of which shall have been within the jurisdiction of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A currently certified Building Inspector having an Associate of Science Degree in a course of education accepted by the Board of Rules and Appeals and having five years experience as a licensed General Contractor, two years of which shall have been within the jurisdiction of this Chapter; or three years experience as a Building Official, Plans Examiner or Inspector, all of which shall have been within the jurisdiction of this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(6)'>This criterion shall apply only to individuals holding one of the following:<section prefix='(aa)'>A General Contractor's license issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board, provided the license number is less than #7837 or,</section><section prefix='(bb)'>A General Contractor's license issued by Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board; or</section><section prefix='(cc)'>A General Contractor's license issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board with license number #7837 or greater and holding a Certification as roofing contractor or inspector issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board or Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board.</section><section prefix='(dd)'>Any General Contractor's license issued subsequent to a proctored examination graded by an independent testing agency approved by the Board of Rules and Appeals.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>CERTIFICATION OF STRUCTURAL PLANS EXAMINER: To be eligible for appointment as a Structural Plans Examiner, an individual shall be certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals and shall be a Florida licensed professional engineer who has obtained such license by examination under the structural discipline or who obtained licensure prior to March 1, 1993 by examination in either the civil/structural or civil/structural/sanitary categories and who has practiced as a structural engineer within the jurisdiction of this Chapter for a period of 5 years.</section><section prefix='(e)'>BUILDING INSPECTOR: (STRUCTURAL)<section prefix='(1)'>A Building Inspector, if properly qualified, may be certified and assigned duties in more than one category.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building Inspectors shall have the powers and duties as may be delegated by the Chief Building Inspector or Building Official.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To be certified in the category of Building Inspector (Structural), individuals shall have at least one of the following:</section><section prefix='(4)'>Five years construction experience in a supervisory capacity and at least one of the following:<section prefix='(aa)'>A General Contractor's license and a current Certificate of Competency issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board; or</section><section prefix='(bb)'>A General Contractor's license issued and a current Certificate of Competency by Miami-Dade County Construction Trade Qualifying Board or</section><section prefix='(cc)'>A General Contractor's license issued subsequent to a proctor examination, graded by an independent testing agency approved by the Board of Rules and Appeals.<section>EXCEPTION: Individuals holding licenses as a Residential Contractor and/or Building Contractor, with a current Certificate of Competency issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board or Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board, may be certified as an entry level inspector with duties limited to the type and size of work for which they are certified to build. Inspectors employed under this exception shall be required to attend the first available formal educational course as approved by the Board of Rules and Appeals immediately following employment. In order to maintain eligibility for appointment, inspectors certified under this exception shall obtain a Certificate of Competency and General Contractor's license issued by Miami-Dade County, or a State Certified General Contractor's license, within 18 months of the date of original appointment.</section></section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Two years construction experience and possessing an Associate of Science Degree in Building Code Enforcement or other construction related curriculum awarded for completion of an educational course accepted by the Board of Rules and Appeals and possessing a current certificate of competency as a general contractor, in the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A current license from the State of Florida as an Architect or Engineer and building construction experience.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>BUILDING INSPECTOR (RESIDENTIAL)<section prefix='(1)'>A Building Inspector, if properly qualified, may be certified and assigned duties in more than one category.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building Inspectors shall have the powers and duties as may be delegated by the Chief Building Inspector or Building Official.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To be certified in the category of Building Inspector (Residential), individuals shall possess at least one of the following:<section prefix='(aa)'>A State of Florida Registered Professional Engineer license with not less than one year experience under that registration.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>A State of Florida Registered Architect license with not less than one year experience under that registration.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>A current Certificate of Competency as a General Contractor issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board with not less than one year experience under that license.</section><section prefix='(dd)'>A current Certificate of Competency as a General Contractor issued by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board with not less than one year experience under that license.</section><section prefix='(ee)'>A current Certificate of Competency as a Building Contractor issued by the Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board with not less than one year experience under that license.</section><section prefix='(ff)'>A current Certificate of Competency as a Sub-General Building Contractor issued by the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board with not less than one year experience under that license.</section></section></section><section prefix='(g)'>BUILDING INSPECTOR (COMMERCIAL ROOFING)<section prefix='(1)'>A Building Inspector, if properly qualified, may be certified and assigned duties in more than one category.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building Inspectors (Commercial Roofing) shall have the powers and duties as may be delegated by the Chief Building Inspector or Building Official in connection with the review and approval of roofing permit applications, enforcement and inspections of the roofing sections of the Building Code and other applicable Codes and Standards for all occupancies provided in the Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To be certified in the category of Building Inspector (Commercial Roofing) candidates shall have at least one of the following:</section><section prefix='(4)'>Five years of experience in the roofing industry, two of which shall have been in a supervisory capacity and holding a current certificate as a Roofing Contractor issued by:<section prefix='(aa)'>The Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board; or</section><section prefix='(bb)'>Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Five years experience in the roofing industry and certification as a Building Inspector in Miami-Dade County and holding a personal certificate from the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board as a Roofing Inspector or Contractor.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Five years experience in the roofing industry and certification as a Building Inspector in Miami-Dade County and holding a personal certificate as a General Contractor issued by either:<section prefix='(aa)'>The Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board, provided the number of the license shall be less than #7837; or</section><section prefix='(bb)'>The Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Five years experience in the roofing industry and holding a current license from the State of Florida as a registered Architect or Engineer.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Any person holding a current certificate from the Board of Rules and Appeals as a Building Inspector who will perform roofing inspections shall hold a certificate and/or license as a Roofing Contractor or inspector and be certified as a Roofing Inspector by December 31, 1992. After that date such persons shall not be eligible for certification to perform roofing inspections in Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>BUILDING INSPECTOR (RESIDENTIAL ROOFING)<section prefix='(1)'>A Building Inspector, if properly qualified, may be certified and assigned duties in more than one category.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Building Inspectors (Residential Roofing) shall have the powers and duties as may be delegated by the Chief Building Inspector or Building Official in connection with enforcement and inspections of the roofing sections of the Building Code and other applicable Codes and Standards for Group R3 Occupancies only.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To be certified in the category of Building Inspector (Residential Roofing) candidates shall have at least one of the following:<section prefix='(aa)'>A current roofing contractor certificate issued by:<section prefix='(1)'>The Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board.</section></section><section prefix='(bb)'>A current certification as a Building Inspector in Miami-Dade County and holding a personal certificate from the Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board as a Roofing Inspector or Contractor.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>A current certification as a Building Inspector in Miami-Dade County and holding a personal certificate as a General Contractor, Building Contractor or Sub General Building Contractor issued by either:<section prefix='(1)'>The Florida Construction Industry Licensing Board, provided the number of the license shall be less than #7837; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Miami-Dade County Construction Trades Qualifying Board.</section></section><section prefix='(dd)'>A current license from the State of Florida as a registered Architect or Engineer with roofing experience in Miami-Dade County under the Building Code.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, ยง 1, 10-19-04; Ord. No. 06-69, ยง 1, 5-9-06)</history></law>