<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-21.10</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibited acts and omissions—Inspectors and building officials.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001417</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-21.10. Prohibited acts and omissions—Inspectors and building officials.<section>It shall be unlawful for any Inspector, Plans Examiner or Building Official employed anywhere within Miami-Dade County to commit any one or more of the following acts or omissions:<section prefix='(a)'>Misrepresent any material fact in an application or supporting papers to obtain a certificate as a Building Inspector or Building Official.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Grant or deny inspection approval of work at a construction site without the work having been properly inspected or before obtaining a certification from the applicable design professional, where such certification is required by this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Falsify building inspection results in the official records maintained by the building permit issuing authority.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Grant inspection approval of work at a construction site with knowledge of the fact that the work does not comply with the provisions of the Building Code.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Commit any act as an inspector or Building Official which significantly impairs the legal rights of another, including failure to give final approval for issuance of a permit or certificate of occupancy without just cause.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Fail to comply with any rule or regulation established by the Board of Rules and Appeals or by the building authority having jurisdiction.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, § 1, 10-19-04)</history></law>