<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-21.11</section_number>
<catch_line>Recertification.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001418</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-21.11. Recertification.<section prefix='(1)'>Applications for recertification, with pertinent data contained herein, must be submitted to the Board of Rules and Appeals by the inspection authority before December 15 of each calendar year in order to be considered for certification for the following year.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All Building Officials, Chiefs, Inspectors and Plans Examiners presently certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals may be recertified when meeting the following criteria:<section prefix='(aa)'>The individuals are currently certified by the Miami-Dade County Board of Rules and Appeals.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>The individuals are employed by an inspection authority regulated by this Code.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>The individuals have attended continuing education classes, or seminars in their respective fields for a minimum of 16 hours during the previous two calendar years. Of the hours required, a minimum of 12 hours shall be satisfied by attendance at courses and/or seminars provided by the Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department, and a maximum of four hours may be satisfied by attendance at programs certified by the State of Florida Building Code Administrators and Inspectors Board, Contruction Industry Licensing Board, or the Electrical Contractors Licensing Board, Board of Professional Engineers and the Board of Registered Architects. In the event that any courses satisfy the educational requirements of more than one discipline regulated by this Code, the Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department shall certify the course, in whole or in part, to satisfy the educational requirements applicable to each discipline.</section><section prefix='(dd)'>Fire Inspectors shall meet the recertification and education requirements of Section 633.08112 of the Florida Statutes and the rules and regulations of the Division of State Fire Marshal.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Certifications allowed to lapse will not be recertified until meeting the requirements of Subparagraph 8-21.11 herein.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In addition to all the minimum requirements set by this Code, individuals applying for recertification must hold a valid certificate issued by the State of Florida Department of Business and Professional Regulation Board of Building Code Administrators and Inspectors, Board of Professional Engineers and the Board of Registered Architects in the category and discipline he/she is seeking recertification.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, ยง 1, 10-19-04; Ord. No. 10-64, ยง 6, 9-24-10)</history></law>