<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-21.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Certification and recertification.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001412</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-21.5. Certification and recertification.<section prefix='(a)'>CERTIFICATION, DEFINED<section prefix='(1)'>The term "certification" shall mean compliance with the minimum qualification and experience for Building Officials, Chiefs, Inspectors, and Plans Examiners established by this Code, and approval by the Miami-Dade County Board of Rules and Appeals.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Only such persons in the categories of Building Official, Chief, Inspector, and Plans Examiner as are examined and certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals may be employed by any inspection authority regulated by this Chapter.<section>EXCEPTION: Fire Inspectors possessing a State of Florida Fire Safety Inspector Certificate of Compliance as prescribed in F.S. Section 633.081(2) of the Florida Statutes and the rules and regulations of the Division of State Fire Marshal shall be eligible for certification by the Board of Rules and Appeals in the category of Plans Examiner, Fire.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>In the event that an inspection authority intends in good faith to employ an applicant for any of the categories regulated by this Chapter, it shall make application for certification. Applications for certification shall be made to the Secretary of the Board of Rules and Appeals on forms approved by the Board of Rules and Appeals and shall provide all relevant and necessary information prior to appointment by an inspection authority. Within ten (10) days of receipt of a properly completed application, the Secretary of the Board of Rules and Appeals shall, based on a preliminary review of the applicant's fulfillment of the qualifications contained in the law, as represented in the application, grant temporary certification or deny it, stating the reasons for denial. Pending review by the Board of Rules and Appeals, the inspection authority shall not employ any person for any position regulated by this Code without first obtaining temporary certification from the Secretary of the Board of Rules and Appeals. The Secretary of the Board of Rules and Appeals shall schedule the application for certification for consideration by the Board of Rules and Appeals at the earliest available meeting. The temporary certification shall only be effective through the date of final action by the Board of Rules and Appeals with respect to the application. The determination of the Secretary of the Board of Rules and Appeals to grant or deny certification shall not be binding upon the Board of Rules and Appeals. The determination of the Board of Rules and Appeals to grant or deny certification shall be final, subject to appeal as provided in section 8-4 of this code.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Certification shall be valid, for the calendar year and shall be renewed each January 1st in accordance with the procedure established in Subsection 8-21.11</section><section prefix='(5)'>Upon resignation, retirement, or termination of a certified individual, Building Officials, Chiefs, Inspectors, and Plans Examiners shall be placed on an inactive list until such time as they again apply for employment and will be recertified if approved, in accordance with Subsection 8-21.11 herein. The building official shall notify the Board of Rules and Appeals upon any termination of employment of an inspector within 30 days of such action.</section><section prefix='(6)'>All applications for certification shall be accompanied by a written authorization from an inspection authority regulated by this Chapter.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The Board of Rules and Appeals, after application and review, shall certify the applicant, deny certification, or limit certification to a particular category.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Once issued, a certification may be revoked or suspended only in accordance with the procedures established herein.</section><section prefix='(9)'>In the event that the Building Official is not available to perform his/her duties, the appointing authority shall appoint an Interim Building Official to perform the duties of Building Official. Such Interim Building Official must hold a current and valid certificate, issued by the Board of Rules and Appeals, as a Building Official, Chief, Plans Examiner or Inspector and meet the same minimum requirements for Building Officials. The appointing authority shall notify the Secretary of the Board of Rules and Appeals, in writing, of the starting date and period of time that such appointment will be in effect. The name of the Interim Building Official will be recorded with the Board of Rules and Appeals but no certification card will be issued.</section><section prefix='(10)'>In addition to satisfying the other minimum requirements contained in this Code, individuals applying for certification must hold a valid certificate issued by the State of Florida Building Code Administrators and Inspectors Board in the category and discipline he/she is seeking certification.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>RECERTIFICATION: (See Section 8-21.11</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, ยง 1, 10-19-04; Ord. No. 10-64, ยง 6, 9-24-10)</history></law>