<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BUILDING INSPECTORS, PLANS EXAMINERS, BUILDING OFFICIALS, CHIEF INSPECTORS AND SPECIAL INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-22</section_number>
<catch_line>Special building inspector.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001420</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-22. Special building inspector.<section prefix='(1)'>Special Building Inspectors, retained by the owner, shall inspect and supervise:<section prefix='(a)'>The compaction of fill under slabs on grade.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The installation of structural piles.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The construction of reinforced masonry structures.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Welding and high-strength bolting.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The fabrication and installation of curtain wall systems on threshold buildings.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The fabrication and installation of structural glazed panels.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Special Building Inspector: A Florida Registered Architect or Professional Engineer retained to provide professional services consisting of observation and inspection of construction for conformance with the permit documents and the Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>When one or more of the following conditions exist the Building Official may elect to directly employ a Special Building Inspector for the inspection of the exterior cladding, firestopping, railings and safeguards, framing, roofing or any part of the building, except that inspections of plumbing, electrical or mechanical systems, inspections of required features of handicap accessibility and final inspections shall not be performed by a Special Building Inspector:<section prefix='(a)'>The building is of unusual size or height, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>The method of design or construction is unusual or complex, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>The method or pace of the construction requires continuous inspection or</section><section prefix='(d)'>In the opinion of the Building Official, additional inspections are required in order to ensure compliance with the Florida Building Code.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Prior to issuance of the permit and for cases governed by Section 8-22.(3) herein above, the Building Official shall require that each Special Building Inspector be certified by the Board of Rules and Appeals as a Special Building Inspector in compliance with Section 8-4 of this Chapter. Such Special Building Inspector shall be a Registered Architect or a Professional Engineer licensed in the State of Florida; qualified by training and experience to perform the inspections for which he or she will be retained. Any and all inspections required and authorized to be performed by a Special Building Inspector pursuant to this Section shall be performed by persons who shall have the knowledge, expertise, and if required the appropriate licensing board's certification related to the specialty or discipline involved in the inspection.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Building Official shall specify the scope and nature of the inspections to be performed, or shall require that the Architect or Engineer of Record submit an inspection plan for approval. The Special Building Inspector or his duly authorized representative shall make all inspections in accordance with the approved inspection plan.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Building Official shall be promptly informed of the results of all inspections in reports signed by the Special Building Inspector(s). Prior to the issuance of a Certificate of Occupancy, each Special Building Inspector shall submit to the Building Official a statement indicating the scope of his inspections and attesting that, to the best of his knowledge, belief and professional judgment, the work is in substantial compliance with the permit documents.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Special Building Inspectors shall be responsible to the Building Official. The Building Official shall periodically visit the construction site to monitor, review, evaluate and approve the work of the Special Building Inspector(s). The Building Official is empowered to direct, as necessary, the work of the Special Building Inspector(s) and may, at any time, remove a Special Building Inspector for failure to perform his or her duties in accordance with the provisions of this section. In that event, the Building Official may also require or permit the owner, within such time as the Building Official may reasonably establish, to employ an alternate Special Building Inspector.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The Building Official may conduct mandatory inspections as required herein through a Special Building Inspector subject to the limitations given in Paragraph 8-22.(3) herein.</section><section prefix='(9)'>For any project constructed pursuant to an Aviation Department contract, the County Manager may authorize the Aviation Department to employ or engage the services of Special Building Inspectors for the inspection of any part of the project, including inspections of plumbing, electrical or mechanical systems, inspections of required features of handicap accessibility. All Special Building Inspectors shall comply with applicable certification requirements provided by State law. The Building Official shall conduct all final inspections.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-191, ยง 1, 10-19-04)</history></law>