<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. FLORIDA BUILDING CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-31</section_number>
<catch_line>Local technical amendments to Florida Building Code.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001422</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-31. Local technical amendments to Florida Building Code.<section prefix='(A)'>The County hereby adopts the following local technical amendments to Chapter 6 (Plumbing) of the Florida Building Code.</section><section>Maximum flow and water consumption.</section><section>The maximum water consumption flow rates and quantities for all plumbing fixtures, fixture fittings and appliances shall be in accordance with Table 604.4. Effective January 1, 2009, permit applications for new residential and commercial structures shall include high efficiency plumbing fixtures, fixture fittings and appliances as provided in Table 604.4. Such high efficiency plumbing fixtures, fixture fittings and appliances shall comply with the specifications in Table 604.4 or have received the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) WaterSense Label.</section><section>Exceptions:<section prefix='1.'>Blowout design water closets [3.5 gallons (13L) per flushing cycle].</section><section prefix='2.'>Vegetable sprays.</section><section prefix='3.'>Clinical sinks [4.5 gallons (17 L) per flushing cycle].</section><section prefix='4.'>Service sinks.</section><section prefix='5.'>Emergency showers.</section></section><section></section><section>TABLE 604.4MAXIMUM FLOW RATES AND CONSUMPTION FORPLUMBING FIXTURES, FIXTURE FITTINGS AND APPLIANCES</section><section>For SI:<section>1 gallon = 3.785 L1 gallon per minute = 3.785 L/m1 pound per square inch = 6.895 kPa.</section></section><section> A hand-held shower spray is a shower head.</section><section> Consumption tolerances shall be determined from referenced standards.</section><section> Water factor in gallons per cycle per cubic foot.</section><section></section><section prefix='(B)'>The County hereby adopts the following local technical amendments to Chapter 29 (Residential) of the Florida Building Code.</section><section>Maximum flow and water consumption.</section><section>The maximum water consumption flow rates and quantities for all plumbing fixtures, fixture, fittings and appliances shall be in accordance with Table P2903.2a. Effective January 1, 2009, permit applications for new residential structures shall include high efficiency plumbing fixtures, fixture fittings and appliances as provided in Table P2903.2a. Such high efficiency plumbing fixtures, fixture fittings and appliances shall comply with the specifications in Table P2903.2a or have received the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) WaterSense Label.</section><section></section><section>TABLE P2903.2aMAXIMUM FLOW RATES AND CONSUMPTION FORPLUMBING FIXTURES, FIXTURE FITTINGS AND APPLIANCES</section><section>For SI:<section>1 gallon = 3.785 L1 gallon per minute = 3.785 L/m1 pound per square inch = 6.895 kPa.</section></section><section> A handheld shower spray is a showerhead.</section><section> Consumption tolerances shall be determined from referenced standards.</section><section> Water factor in gallons per cycle per cubic foot.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-14, § 1, 2-5-08; Ord. No. 08-100, § 1, 9-2-08)</history></law>