<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. FLORIDA BUILDING CODE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-32</section_number>
<catch_line>Local Administrative Amendments.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001423</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-32. Local Administrative Amendments.<section prefix='(a)'>The County hereby adopts the following Local Administrative Amendment modifying Chapter 1 of the Florida Building Code.</section><section>SECTION 103POWERS AND DUTIES OF THEFLOODPLAIN ADMINISTRATOR<section>In accordance with F.S. sec. 553.73, the Appointing Authority of Miami-Dade County and the Municipalities may delegate the authority to enforce the floodplain provisions of the Florida Building Code to a floodplain administrator, the Building Official, or any other appropriate agency or combination thereof.</section><section>A floodplain administrator, the Building Official or any other appropriate agency or combination thereof, as designated, is authorized and directed to administer and enforce the flood provisions of the Florida Building Code and any adopted flood hazard ordinances. The designated authority shall delegate such duties and assignments as may be deemed necessary to carry out provisions of the Florida Building Code and any adopted flood hazard ordinances, to render interpretations consistent with the intent and purpose of these codes and may establish policies and procedures in order to clarify the application of their provisions.</section><section>Where, in any specific case, different sections of the Florida Building Code or adopted flood hazard ordinances specify different materials, methods of construction or other requirements, the most restrictive shall govern.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-57, ยง 1, 7-3-12)</history></law>