<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PRODUCT APPROVAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-40</section_number>
<catch_line>Product approvals.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001425</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-40. Product approvals.<section>Any person desiring to use materials/products used for protection of the envelope of the structure, limited to windows, exterior glazing, wall cladding, roofing, exterior doors, skylights, glass block, siding and shutters shall obtain a high wind velocity zone approval from the Florida Building Commission or shall obtain a local approval in accordance with Sections 553.842 and 553.8425 of the Florida Statutes.<section prefix='(a)'>Local approval of construction products and assemblies.<section prefix='(1)'>Any person or firm, not having an approval from the Florida Building Commission and desiring to supply, furnish, manufacture or fabricate construction products or assemblies, to the extent required by the Building Code shall make application for approval to the Director of the Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department, in accordance with the administrative order governing product approval.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The application for local product approval shall be made in accordance with the administrative order governing product approval and shall set forth and describe plant methods, personnel, equipment, control procedure, and such other information as may be required to insure compliance of the product or assembly with the Building Code.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department may approve such product, plant or manufacturing procedure and issue a Certificate of Competency or issue a product approval, as appropriate, after payment of the required fee, upon a finding that such project, plant or manufacturing procedure complies with the Building Code. The Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department will recommend the establishment of conditions and limitations on the use of any product submitted for approval.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Product approvals given by the Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department shall be valid countywide.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department may deny, suspend or revoke a product approval or Certificate of Competency upon a finding that a product, plant or procedure does not comply with the Building Code or violates a condition of its approval. Appeal from this decision of the Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department shall be to the Board of Rules and Appeals.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The manufacturer's or fabricator's name or insignia shall be clearly indicated on each prefabricated structural assembly.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Appeal from a decision of the Building Official to refuse to accept a product or assembly, which has been previously approved by the Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department, shall be to the Board of Rules and Appeals.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-112, ยง 1, 7-10-01; Ord. No. 10-64, ยง 6, 9-24-10)</history></law>