<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='2'>Chapter 8 BUILDING CODE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. ADMINISTRATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Building Code Administration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001392</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8-8. Building Code Administration.<section>The Building and Neighborhood Compliance Department through the Director or his or her designees shall perform the following duties and functions throughout the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County:<section prefix='(1)'>Administrative and legal support for the Board of Rules and Appeals and the Unsafe Structures Board. The Director or his or her designee shall serve as Secretary to the Board of Rules and Appeals and Unsafe Structures Board;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Conducting studies and investigations to enable it to recommend appropriate revisions to the Building Code to keep abreast of new developments in building design, construction, and standards;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Dissemination of interpretations and rulings made by the Board of Rules and Appeals and the Florida Building Commission;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Registration, certification, recertification and decertification of construction enforcement personnel;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Codification and writing of amendments to the Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Providing guidance in the resolution of citizen complaints regarding Building Code violations;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Investigations, preparation and prosecution of enforcement activities pursuant to the Building Code, or actions pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Code which are governed by the Building Code;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Prevention of any imminent threat of any violation of the Building Code;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Training and testing of building inspectors, plans processors and code compliance officers; and</section><section prefix='(10)'>Approval, disapproval or conditional approval of the local use of construction products, materials and assemblies or alternate construction materials and assemblies in accordance in accordance with administrative order of the County Manager to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Determine if a licensee, certificate holder, or registrant licensed under Ch. 455, 471, 481, or 489 of the Florida Statutes has committed a material violation of the Florida Building Code, and impose fines and penalties in the amount set forth in Section 8-16 of this Chapter and otherwise provided by law.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-112, ยง 1, 7-10-01; Ord. No. 10-64, ยง 6, 9-24-10)</history></law>