<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='2'>ARTICLE 8. INITIATIVE, REFERENDUM, AND RECALL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8.01</section_number>
<catch_line>INITIATIVE AND REFERENDUM.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000045</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 8.01. INITIATIVE AND REFERENDUM.<section>The electors of the county shall have the power to propose to the Board of County Commissioners passage or repeal of ordinances and to vote on the question if the Board refuses action, according to the following procedure:<section prefix='1.'>The person proposing the exercise of this power shall submit the proposal, including proposed ballot language to the Clerk of the Circuit Court who shall without delay approve as to form a petition for circulation in one or several copies as the proposer may desire. A public hearing shall be held on the proposal at the next Board of County Commissioner meeting subsequent to the date the Clerk approves the petition as to form.</section><section prefix='2.'>The person or persons circulating the petition shall, within 120 days of the approval of the form of the petition, obtain the valid signatures of voters in the county in numbers at least equal to four percent of the registered voters in the county on the day on which the petition is approved, according to the official records of the County Supervisor of Elections. In determining the sufficiency of the petition, no more than 25 percent of the valid signatures required shall come from voters registered in any single county commission district. Each signer of a petition shall place thereon, after his name, the date, and his place of residence or precinct number. Each person circulating a copy of the petition shall attach to it a sworn affidavit stating the number of signers and the fact that each signature was made in the presence of the circulator of the petition.</section><section prefix='3.'>The signed petition shall be filed with the Board which shall within 30 days order a canvass of the signatures thereon to determine the sufficiency of the signatures. If the number of signatures is insufficient or the petition is deficient as to form or compliance with this Section, the Board shall notify the person filing the petition that the petition is insufficient and has failed.</section><section prefix='4.'>The Board may within 30 days after the date a sufficient petition is presented adopt the ordinance as submitted in an initiatory petition or repeal the ordinance referred to by a referendary petition. If the Board does not adopt or repeal the ordinance as provided above, then the proposal shall be placed on the ballot without further action of the Board.</section><section prefix='5.'>If the proposal is submitted to the electors, the election shall be held either:<section prefix='(a)'>In the next scheduled county-wide election, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the petition contains the valid signatures in the county in numbers at least equal to eight percent of the registered voters in the county, the election shall take place on the first Tuesday after 120 days from certification of the petition. The result shall be determined by a majority vote of the electors voting on the proposal.</section></section><section prefix='6.'>An ordinance proposed by initiatory petition or the repeal of an ordinance by referendary petition shall be effective on the day after the election, except that:<section prefix='(a)'>Any reduction or elimination of existing revenue or any increase in expenditures not provided for by the current budget or by existing bond issues shall not take effect until the beginning of the next succeeding fiscal year; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Rights accumulated under an ordinance between the time a certified referendary petition against the ordinance is presented to the Board and the repeal of the ordinance by the voters, shall not be enforced against the county; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Should two or more ordinances adopted at the same election have conflicting provisions, the one receiving the highest number of votes shall prevail as to those provisions.</section></section><section prefix='7.'>An ordinance adopted by the electorate through initiatory proceedings shall not be amended or repealed by the Board for a period of one year after the election at which it was adopted, but thereafter it may be amended or repealed like any other ordinance.</section></section></section></text></law>