<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 1' order_by='00002' level='1'>PART I CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT AND CHARTER</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='2'>ARTICLE 8. INITIATIVE, REFERENDUM, AND RECALL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8.02</section_number>
<catch_line>RECALL.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000046</order_by>
<text><section>SECTION 8.02. RECALL.<section>Any member of the Board of County Commissioners, the Mayor, or the Property Appraiser may be removed from office by the electors of the county, district, or municipality by which he was chosen. The procedure on a recall petition shall be identical with that for an initiatory or referendary petition, except that:<section prefix='1.'>The Clerk of the Circuit Court shall approve the form of the petition.</section><section prefix='2.'>The person or persons circulating the petition must obtain signatures of electors of the county, district, or municipality concerned in numbers at least equal to four percent of the registered voters in the county district or municipality on the day on which the petition is approved, according to the official records of the County Supervisor of Elections.</section><section prefix='3.'>The signed petition shall be filed with and canvassed and certified by the Clerk of the Circuit Court.</section><section prefix='4.'>The Board of County Commissioners must provide for a recall election not less than 45 nor more than 90 days after the certification of the petition.</section><section prefix='5.'>The question of recall shall be placed on the ballot in a manner that will give the elector a clear choice for or against the recall. The result shall be determined by a majority vote of the electors voting on the question.</section><section prefix='6.'>If the majority is against recall the officer shall continue in office under the terms of his previous election. If the majority is for recall he shall, regardless of any defect in the recall petition, be deemed removed from office immediately.</section><section prefix='7.'>No recall petition against such an officer shall be certified within one year after he takes office nor within one year after a recall petition against him is defeated.</section></section></section></text></law>