<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE VIIA. MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIR ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-161.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Application for registration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001512</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-161.5. Application for registration.<section prefix='(a)'>Each application for registration, renewal registration, and duplicate registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and shall be accompanied by a fee in such amount as shall be established by administrative order of the county manager. Said fee shall be effective upon approval by the Commission.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The fees payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate county fund and shall be used exclusively by the Director for the administrative and enforcement functions of the Director set forth in this article. No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each application for registration shall contain the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>The name, address, and form of ownership of the motor vehicle repair shop, and for a corporation, the date and place of incorporation.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The name and address of each of the motor vehicle repair shop's resident agents, officers, directors, and partners in the state and outside of the state.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A description of the motor vehicle repair shop applying for registration which shall include:<section prefix='a.'>The types of businesses operated.</section><section prefix='b.'>The types of repair work performed.</section><section prefix='c.'>The number and types of motor vehicle mechanics, master mechanics, specialty mechanics, paint/body technicians, mechanic apprentices, and paint/body apprentices employed for the performance of repair work.</section><section prefix='d.'>In the case of motor vehicle body repair facilities and motor vehicle painting facilities, designation by the applicant as one (1) of the following:<section prefix='1.'>Collision, structural repair and repaint facility;</section><section prefix='2.'>Structural repair facility; or</section><section prefix='3.'>Cosmetic and paint repair facility.</section></section></section><section prefix='(4)'>A copy of each of the documents, instruments, forms, contracts, or other papers used by the applicant for registration when dealing with the public with respect to repair work, including, but not limited to, estimates, diagnoses, invoices, warranties, and all documents otherwise used to comply with this article, including all documents upon which the motor vehicle repair shop requires the customer's signature.</section><section prefix='(5)'>State sales tax number certificate of registration.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Federal Employer Identification Number.</section><section prefix='(7)'>County Occupational License.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Municipal occupational license, if appropriate.</section><section prefix='(9)'>County Hazardous Waste Permit.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Fictitious Name Registration or Articles of Incorporation Certificate.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Other information and items as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>A person operating a motor vehicle repair shop at more than one (1) location in Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall file a single application for registration annually, which, together with the other information required by this article, shall clearly indicate the location of and the individual person in charge of each motor vehicle repair shop location. Application fees shall be required for each motor vehicle repair shop location.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the name or address of the motor vehicle repair shop changes but such change does not involve a change in ownership, the motor vehicle repair shop shall notify the Director in writing of the change within ten (10) days of such change. Appropriate changes shall be made on the renewal registration application when due.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Change of ownership.<section prefix='(1)'>In the event of a change of ownership of a motor vehicle repair shop, a new registration and payment of new registration fees shall be required. The motor vehicle repair shop may continue to operate provided that the motor vehicle repair shop has filed a completed application for registration with the Director and paid all applicable fees. For purposes of this subsection "change of ownership" shall mean a change in the ownership or operators of a motor vehicle repair shop which is either a sole proprietorship or partnership.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Corporations owning or operating a motor vehicle repair shop which has a change of ten (10) percent or more of the ownership of the corporation shall notify the Director of the change no later than thirty (30) days after the date of change.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>A motor vehicle repair shop registration shall become effective upon the date the application is approved by the Director. Notwithstanding any provision in this article, the Director may stagger the registration over an annual period, may shorten or extend the one-year period to facilitate the workload, and prorate the fee accordingly. A motor vehicle repair shop registration shall be renewed annually by the motor vehicle repair shop. A motor vehicle repair shop shall file the application for renewal of the registration with the Director no later than thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of the registration of the motor vehicle repair shop.</section><section prefix='(h)'>A motor vehicle repair shop may continue to operate after the expiration date of the registration, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director, if the completed renewal application with applicable fees has been received by the Director on or before the expiration date. If a completed renewal application with applicable fees is filed after the expiration date, the motor vehicle repair shop may operate from and after the date on which the completed application with applicable fees is received by the Director, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director. A renewal fee in such amount as established by administrative order of the County Manager shall be required by the Director if the application for renewal registration is received by the Director after the expiration date of the registration.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-38, ยง 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 98-77, ยง 1, 6-2-98)</history></law>