<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-1.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Requiring rental car companies to make county approved visitor information maps available to visitors renting cars.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001427</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-1.1. Requiring rental car companies to make county approved visitor information maps available to visitors renting cars.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>An applicant is any person, rental car company, or other business or entity that submits a Visitor Information Map to the Director for County approval.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A car is any motor vehicle primarily intended for passenger use, including, but not limited to, minivans.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Director shall be the County Manager or his or her designee.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A rental car company is any person, business, or other entity whose principal commercial interest is to rent or lease motor vehicles for periods of less than six (6) months, which involve the relinquishing of control of the motor vehicle to the renter. However, no rental car company or car rental which otherwise meets the definitions of this section is exempt from the requirements of this section merely because a rental period exceeds six (6) months.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A visitor or visitor renter is any person who, when renting a car, designates his or her principal residence as being outside of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Any rental car company that rents cars in Miami-Dade County shall make available to each visitor renter at its locations in Miami-Dade County a Visitor Information Map approved by the Director indicating the major thoroughfares to and from the airport to major destinations, hotel areas, and attractions. Except for rental car companies that choose to offer Visitor Information Maps to all their renters regardless of whether they are visitors, rental car companies shall ascertain the place of principal residence for all persons renting cars in Miami-Dade County and provide such information on all rental contracts.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The County Manager shall, within thirty (30) days after the date of enactment of this subsection, promulgate administrative regulations providing standards for producing Visitor Information Maps which promote tourist safety and a method for approving such maps to indicate the major thoroughfares to and from the airport to major destinations, hotel areas, and attractions. The County Manager shall also consider and include, within such standards, any safety tips or travel advisories that he deems appropriate. The standards shall be promulgated after consultation by the County Manager with the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau, the police chiefs of each of the municipal police forces in the County and the Director of the Miami-Dade Police Department, and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Any subsequent changes to the standards shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(d)'>To fulfill the requirements of subsection (b), a Visitor Information Map must be approved by the Director prior to distribution to visitor renters. Any Visitor Information Map which has not been disapproved by the Director by written notice to the applicant within thirty (30) business days after submission shall be considered County approved and shall receive an approval designation as set forth under the standards promulgated pursuant to subsection (b).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Rental car companies may satisfy the requirements of subsection (b) utilizing one or more of the following methods:<section prefix='(1)'>Each rental car company shall obtain from the visitor renting the car a signed or initialed acknowledgment that a County approved Visitor Information Map was received when executing the rental contract or a signed or initialed acknowledgment of waiving the right to receive such map. Rental car companies which do not ascertain the renter's principal place of residence shall obtain the above acknowledgment from all persons renting cars, whether said person resides inside or outside Miami-Dade County. The acknowledgment and waiver form shall be a part of or attached to the rental contract. Rental contracts and acknowledgments and waivers shall be retained by rental car companies for a period of no less than one (1) year. Upon request of the Director, each rental car company shall make available to the County all rental contracts together with the acknowledgments and waivers collected by that company during the period specified in the request; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Each rental car company shall post a clear and conspicuous sign in plain view to all potential visitors or visitor renters at each business premises location stating the following in the languages of English, Spanish, French, German, Portuguese and Italian: "You have the right to obtain a Visitor Information Map upon request" and upon request provide the visitor renter with a Visitor Information Map. The sign shall not measure less than two (2) feet in width and three (3) feet in length.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Rental car companies shall place no other warnings, notices, alterations, or modifications on such maps once they have been approved. However, rental car companies at their option may add symbols or notations to show the location of their facilities. Additionally, advertisements may be added to or deleted from the maps without County approval so long as they do not project into the depiction of streets, any safety tips, or other standards promulgated pursuant to subsection (b) which the map contains. No other modifications of a County approved map shall be permitted.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The proceeds of any penalties assessed for violation of this section shall be deposited in the Miami-Dade Victim's Assistance Program.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Unless otherwise mandated by state or federal law, violation of this section shall not be admitted into evidence in any civil proceeding whatsoever, other than those initiated by the Director in order to enforce the provisions of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-57, ยง 1, 6-1-93; Ord. No. 95-100, ยง 1, 6-20-95; Ord. No. 09-94, ยง 1, 11-3-09)</history></law>