<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY ANTENNA TELEVISION SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-140</section_number>
<catch_line>Ownership, control, transfer of License.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001483</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-140. Ownership, control, transfer of License.<section prefix='(a)'>The Licensee shall at all times be the sole owner or lessee of all the facilities and property, real and personal, of the CATV business operating under License issued by Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any change of thirty (30) percent or more of the ownership of the Licensee's business or transactions which may later affect the transference of the ownership shall be submitted to the County Manager for prior approval. By its acceptance of a License under this article the Licensee specifically acknowledges and agrees that any such change in ownership and control occurring without prior approval of the County Manager shall constitute a violation of the terms of the License, and render it subject to cancellation at the discretion of the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Upon the foreclosure or other judicial sale of all or a substantial part of the system, or upon termination of any lease covering all or a substantial part of the system, the Licensee shall notify the Commission of such fact, and such notification shall be treated as a notification that a transfer of License has taken place, and the provisions of Section 8A-140(d) of this Code governing the consent of the County Manager to such transfer of License shall apply.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No assignment of any License granted hereunder shall be valid and effective to transfer any interest or to bind the County without prior approval of the County Manager. In considering any request for transfer of License the County Manager may require such information, records, books of accounts, or other data as it may deem necessary and proper to evaluate the qualifications of the proposed assignee.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 24, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 11, 12-20-77)</history></law>