<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY ANTENNA TELEVISION SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-131</section_number>
<catch_line>Number of channels, channel reservation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001474</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-131. Number of channels, channel reservation.<section prefix='(a)'>The Licensee shall provide minimum requirements in accordance with Section 76.252 of the Federal Communications Commission Rules.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Licensee shall agree to provide one (1) outlet CATV service without charge to each public school and recognized public institution of higher learning. This does not include commercial educational enterprises (computer schools, beauty schools, etc.).</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Licensee shall provide without charge, subject to the rules and regulations of the FCC, public emergency broadcast capabilities whereby, at the request of designated County official(s) service on all channels may be interrupted in order to make such public emergency broadcasts.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Licensee shall provide, to the extent not inconsistent with FCC requirements, facilities capable of allowing each subscriber's standard television receiver to receive all standard broadcast television signals and all regular, required nonbroadcast services at no additional charge above the standard monthly rate.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Licensee shall provide and maintain at least one (1) specially designated and noncommercial public access channel which shall be operated in accordance with prevailing federal regulations.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Licensee shall provide and maintain, without charge, at least four (4) specially designated channels for use and programming by local tax supported educational authorities in the elementary, secondary and college level fields, as well as instructional television for adults. This does not include commercial educational enterprises (computer schools, beauty schools, etc.). Initially, only one (1) such channel shall be required from the Licensee, unless and until the County Manager determines the need for additional educational channels does exist and so notifies the Licensee. The Licensee, after such notification by the County Manager, shall provide such required channels forthwith.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Licensee shall provide and maintain, without charge, at least one (1) specially designated channel for local government use.</section><section prefix='(h)'>At those daily time segments during which no signals are transmitted over public access channels or local government channels the Licensee may utilize such channels for any purpose consistent with the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The Licensee may be required to interconnect its system with other cable systems operating in Miami-Dade County, to the extent that such interconnection is done at the request of and in conjunction with County and local school officials who seek such interconnection to foster educational goals.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The Licensee shall provide two-way capability pursuant to the rules and regulations of the FCC and shall provide the following at no charge to Miami-Dade County:<section prefix='(1)'>Two-way capability to be made available without charge to the Miami-Dade County School Board to be used and programmed as desired by such School Board. The system shall provide interconnecting terminals to provide signal into the system at locations designated by the Board. Public tax-supported institutions of higher education also shall be provided with such two-way capability. The two-way capability referred to here applies to those channels required by Section 8A-131(f).</section><section prefix='(2)'>Two-way channel of secure, wideband capability for local governmental use, as provided in Section 8A-131(g), at no additional charge, except for such special terminal devices (converters) as may be required. The Licensee shall provide the interconnecting terminals to provide entrance into the system, but the County shall provide the programming and programming equipment necessary to use the service of this channel.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>The Licensee shall provide that the signal of each television station carried shall be received at a designated place on the subscriber's channel selector as prescribed by the County Manager, which shall be uniform for every CATV system in the County insofar as technology permits.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 15, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 6, 12-20-77)</history></law>