<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-1.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Public Notices to be Provided at Car Rental Facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001428</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-1.2. Public Notices to be Provided at Car Rental Facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Rental Car Facility shall mean any physical location where cars, trucks, automobiles, motorcycles, or other vehicles suitable for travel on public highways are rented or leased to members of the public, if such Facility has three or more such vehicles customarily available for rent or lease.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Equipment Fees shall mean any surcharge, levy, extraction, tariff, or other monetary obligation imposed on any customer of a rental car facility for use of any Sunpass equipment provided with any rental vehicle, or for the administrative costs of processing tolls through such equipment. For the purposes of the Section, a fee shall not be construed to mean toll payments made through any such Sunpass equipment.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Posting of Equipment Fee. If the owner or operator of a Rental Car Facility imposes an Equipment Fee, notice of such fee must be provided at such Rental Car Facility. This notice shall be posted conspicuously in the public area of the Rental Car Facility in such location as to provide notice to customers prior to their entering into any contract for the leasing or renting of any vehicle, and written in a legible manner in English, Spanish and Creole.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Provisions Cumulative. The provisions of this section shall be cumulative and in addition to and not in derogation of any and all other provisions or laws.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Applicability. The provisions of this ordinance shall apply throughout the incorporated and unincorporated area of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-89, ยง 1, 11-15-11)</history></law>