<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE VII. TRUTH IN MOTORBOAT REPAIRS AND ESTIMATES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-156</section_number>
<catch_line>Estimate of repairs required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001501</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-156. Estimate of repairs required.<section>A person engaged in the business of motorboat repairs shall furnish to the customer a written estimate of repairs which shall state the total estimate cost of (1) parts: parts shall be listed with reasonable particularity and identified by brand name and designation as to whether new or used parts are to be installed; (2) labor; (3) incidental services; (4) the charges, if any, for the release of the motorboat in the event that the motorboat is not repaired; and (5) the charges, if any, for making the estimate. The customer may, in writing, waive this requirement. If no charge is recorded for the making of an estimate, it shall be unlawful to so charge for an estimate. No person shall be required to prepare a written estimate of repairs for jobs under fifty dollars ($50.00) nor until such person has made a visual inspection of the motorboat to be repaired; provided, however, that if inspection indicates an estimated repair cost in excess of fifty dollars ($50.00), an estimate in accordance with the terms and provisions of this article shall be required prior to the commencement of repair work. The customer shall be given a signed copy of the written estimate of repairs. No person engaged in the business of motorboat repairs shall solicit or demand a waiver of any customer's rights herein enumerated as a pre-condition to acceptance of repair work.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-20, ยง 3, 2-16-71; Ord. No. 71-79, ยง 1, 10-5-71; Ord. No. 92-38, ยง 1, 5-19-92)</history></law>