<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY ANTENNA TELEVISION SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-133</section_number>
<catch_line>Minimum reception standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001476</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-133. Minimum reception standards.<section>The Licensee shall establish and guarantee minimum technical reception standards at the terminals of each television set services, said standards to be approved by the Commission. The following minimum technical reception standards are herewith established:<section prefix='(a)'>The Licensee shall maintain and operate the system in accordance with technical and measurement standards currently in effect under the rules and regulations of the Federal Communications Commission and the rules and regulations of the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Licensee shall maintain and operate the system and render efficient service in accordance with the rules and regulations established or to be established by the Commission. Provided, however, the Licensee shall not exceed the radiation limits established in Section 76.605 of the Federal Communications Commission Rules adopted February 2, 1972, thereby operating the system so as to cause the least amount of interference with television reception, radio reception, telephone communications or other installations which are now or may hereafter be installed and in use in the County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The television signals carried by the Licensee at no time shall be altered, interrupted, or blacked out in any way by the Licensee except as authorized by appropriate law or regulation and as may be necessary for technical adjustments or for the signal changes provided by such equipment as set-top converters.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Licensee shall provide and make available accurately calibrated test equipment for the testing of all service and operational standards outlined herein and shall conduct tests as requested by the County under the supervision of a County representative in order to establish the level of performance of the system.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Licensee shall provide a local service channel in addition to the six (6) channels required by Section 8A-131 herein. The local service channel shall provide local weather information and time with continuous FM background music. Further use for public service, civic organizations, and charitable causes is also hereby authorized.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Licensee shall render efficient service, make repairs promptly, and interrupt service only for good cause and for the shortest time possible. Such interruption insofar as possible shall be preceded by notice and shall occur during periods of minimum use of the system.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The Licensee shall maintain an office in the County which shall be open during all usual business hours, have a listed telephone, and be so operated that complaints and requests for repairs or adjustment may be received at any time. The Licensee shall respond to all service calls promptly and correct malfunctions as promptly as possible, but in any event within forty-eight (48) hours after notice thereof, except where the cause and extent of failure-causing damage is beyond the control of the Licensee.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 17, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 7, 12-20-77)</history></law>