<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE VIIA. MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIR ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-161.34</section_number>
<catch_line>Items required for motor vehicle body repair facilities and motor vehicle paint facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001541</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-161.34. Items required for motor vehicle body repair facilities and motor vehicle paint facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, each motor vehicle body repair facility and each motor vehicle paint facility shall have the following:<section prefix='(i)'>Proof of garage liability insurance in an amount not less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00), combined single limit, and garage-keepers legal liability insurance.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>A complete set of current printed or electronic crash manuals for repair work performed by the motor vehicle body repair facility or motor vehicle paint facility.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Evidence of active management participation in the operation of the motor vehicle body repair facility or motor vehicle paint facility in such form as required by the Director.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, each cosmetic and paint repair facility shall have the following:<section prefix='(i)'>An on-site spray booth in good working order.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Guarantees for workmanship of repair work, including paint and material, if any, shall be prominently displayed to the public on the premises, and shall state the mileage or time periods for which the guarantees are effective.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>An operable paint application system with the ability to produce an appropriate finish.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, each structural repair facility shall have the following in good working order, as applicable:<section prefix='(i)'>An operable metal inert gas welder (MIG).</section><section prefix='(ii)'>An ability to raise (lift, rack or bench) motor vehicles for inspection.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Source of dimensions covering frames, upper body dimensions and wheel alignment specifications (blueprints) for the types of motor vehicles upon which repair work will be performed.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>A measuring device suitable for each type of motor vehicle upon which repair work will be performed, symmetrical or asymmetrical, as well as body structural dimensions including the upper body.</section><section prefix='(v)'>A four-point anchoring system to hold motor vehicles in a stationary position during structural and body pulls and which is suitable for the type of motor vehicle upon which repair work is being performed.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Electrical or hydraulic equipment to make multiple and structural pulls for straightening.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Guarantees for workmanship, including parts and materials (subject to manufacturer's warranty), if any, shall be prominently displayed to the public on the premises of the motor vehicle repair shop and shall state the mileage or time periods for which the guarantees are effective.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, each collision, structural repair and paint facility shall comply with all the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) hereinabove.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding the foregoing, each motor vehicle body repair facility and motor vehicle paint facility which holds itself out as providing specified repair services and does not itself meet the specialized equipment requirements of this section, may be deemed to comply, provided:<section prefix='(i)'>The motor vehicle body repair facility and motor vehicle repair facility has disclosed on its application that it subcontracts with a motor vehicle repair shop and the subcontracted motor vehicle repair shop maintains such specialized equipment in good and working order and has received a motor vehicle repair registration from the Director; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The motor vehicle body repair facility and motor vehicle paint facility obtains from the customer, prior to the commencement of the repair work, a signed acknowledgment which discloses the following language in no less than ten-point bold face type:<section>This shop does not have certain specialized equipment required for (describe the type of repair work). Repairs of this type will be subcontracted to another motor vehicle repair shop identified as MVR (state the registration number).</section></section><section prefix='(iii)'>However, if the customer leaves the motor vehicle at the motor vehicle body repair facility or motor vehicle paint facility during hours when the shop is not open or if the customer permits the shop or another person to deliver the motor vehicle to the motor vehicle body repair facility or motor vehicle paint facility, the customer must be notified, prior to the commencement of any repair work, by telephone, facsimile, mail or any other means, that the motor vehicle body repair facility or motor vehicle paint facility does not have certain specialized equipment required for the type of repair work involved and repairs of this type are subcontracted to another motor vehicle body repair facility or motor vehicle paint facility identifying the MVR facility by the registration number.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-38, ยง 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 97-69, ยง 2, 6-2-97)</history></law>