<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE VIIA. MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIR ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-161.31</section_number>
<catch_line>Mechanic and technician certification; criterion for issuance; effective date; renewal; conditions, limitations, and restrictions; functioning as mechanic or technician after expiration date.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001538</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-161.31. Mechanic and technician certification; criterion for issuance; effective date; renewal; conditions, limitations, and restrictions; functioning as mechanic or technician after expiration date.<section prefix='(1)'>A master or specialty mechanic's certification, motor vehicle body repair technician certification, and motor vehicle paint technician certification shall become effective upon the date the certification is approved in writing by the Director. A certification may be renewed annually upon payment of the required renewal fee and submission of a completed renewal application prescribed by the Director. Notwithstanding any provision in this article, the Director may stagger the certification over an annual period, may shorten or extend the one-year period to facilitate the workload, and prorate the fee accordingly.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The criterion for issuance of a certificate by the Director shall be compliance by the applicant with all the applicable provisions of this article and submission to the Director of a completed application for certification and applicable fees. Certificates may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions imposed by the Director as the Director deems necessary to protect customers and consumers, provided such conditions, limitations, and restrictions are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violation of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a certificate shall be a violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A specialty or master mechanic, motor vehicle body repair technician or motor vehicle paint technician who has obtained a certificate may continue to be employed as a specialty or master mechanic or paint/body technician after the expiration date of said mechanic's or technician's certificate, pending approval of the renewal application for the certificate, if the renewal application has been received by the Director on or before the expiration date of the certificate. If a renewal application is filed after the expiration date, the specialty or master mechanic or paint/body technician may temporarily be so employed without a valid and current certificate after the date upon which the application for renewal is received by the Director, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director. A renewal fee in such amount as established by administrative order of the County Manager shall be required if the application is filed with the Director after the expiration date of the certificate.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Effective January 1, 2000, renewal of the certificate may only be obtained if the mechanic or paint and body technician has earned sixteen (16) annual hours of continuing education in accordance with an approved program, pursuant to Section 8A-161.28</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-38, ยง 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 98-77, ยง 1, 6-2-98)</history></law>