<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY ANTENNA TELEVISION SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-128.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Jurisdiction and powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001470</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-128.5. Jurisdiction and powers.<section>The County Manager shall exercise jurisdiction and have the power and authority to regulate and supervise each License as defined herein in respect to service and Service Areas within Miami-Dade County, in accordance with the standards set by the provisions of this article. This jurisdiction shall be exclusive and superior to that of all other boards, agencies, commissions, political subdivisions, and municipalities in Miami-Dade County, Florida, and in case of conflict all lawful acts, orders, rules and regulations of the County Manager shall in each instance prevail, subject to the Constitution and General Laws of the State of Florida. In the exercise of such jurisdiction, the County Manager shall be vested with the power, and it shall be the County Manager's duty, to prescribe classifications, standards of quality and measurement and redundancy factors, and service rules and regulations to be observed and complied with by each Licensee embraced within the terms of this article, with the exception of the public access channels, to prescribe uniform systems and classifications of accounts for each CATV Licensee, as defined herein, which, among other things, shall set up adequate, fair and reasonable depreciation rates and schedules; to require each Licensee to furnish and file periodic reports and other reasonable information and data for the proper administration and enforcement of the provisions of this article; to require appropriate administrative personnel or departments of the County government to perform the work of compiling factual data and information necessary or reasonably required by the County Manager for the proper performance of the duties and functions imposed upon it by the provisions of this article; and to take such actions necessary for the protection and preservation of the public safety and welfare in respect to the transmission of CATV systems furnished within Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with the terms and provisions of this article. The County Manager shall further insure that the Licensee serve the best interest of the total community in Miami-Dade County, Florida, and provide full television service to the extent permitted by the FCC.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 11, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 4, 12-20-77)</history></law>