<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE VIIA. MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIR ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-161.34.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Items required for motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001542</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-161.34.1. Items required for motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, all motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities shall have the following:<section prefix='(i)'>Proof of garage liability insurance in an amount not less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00), combined single limit, and garage-keepers legal liability insurance.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Evidence of active management participation in the operation of the motor vehicle mechanical repair facility in such form as required by the Director.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Set of current manuals for motor vehicles to be repaired.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, all motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities performing repair work upon suspensions or steering shall have the following equipment, in good working order:<section prefix='(i)'>Wheel alignment system.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Wheel balancer.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, all motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities performing repair work upon brake systems shall have the following equipment, in good working order:<section prefix='(i)'>Pressure bleeder.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Asbestos collection equipment.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Micrometer and drum gauge.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, all motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities performing repair work upon electrical systems shall have the following, in good working order:<section prefix='(i)'>Battery charger.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Battery/charging/starting systems tester.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, all motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities performing repair work upon heating and air-conditioning systems shall have the following, in good working order:<section prefix='(i)'>Recycling or recovery equipment.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Leak detector.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Air-conditioning charging station.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>In addition to all other requirements of this article, all motor vehicle mechanical repair facilities performing repair work upon engines, including but not limited to tune-ups, shall have the following, in good working order:<section prefix='(i)'>Engine analyzer with or in addition to a gas analyzer.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Data stream access device.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Notwithstanding the foregoing, each motor vehicle mechanical repair facility which holds itself out as providing specified repair services and does not itself meet the specialized equipment requirements of this section, may be deemed to comply, provided:<section prefix='(i)'>The motor vehicle mechanical repair facility has disclosed on its application that it subcontracts with a motor vehicle repair shop and the motor vehicle repair shop maintains such specialized equipment in good and working order and has received a motor vehicle repair registration from the Director; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The motor vehicle mechanical repair facility obtains from the customer, prior to the commencement of the repair work, a signed acknowledgment which discloses the following language in no less than ten-point bold face type:<section>This shop does not have certain specialized equipment required for (describe the type of repair work). Repairs of this type will be subcontracted to another motor vehicle repair shop identified as MVR (state the registration number).</section></section><section prefix='(iii)'>However, if the customer leaves the motor vehicle at the motor vehicle mechanical repair shop during hours when the shop is not open or if the customer permits the shop or another person to deliver the motor vehicle to the motor vehicle repair shop, the customer must be notified, prior to the commencement of any repair work, by telephone, facsimile, mail or any other means, that the motor vehicle repair shop does not have certain specialized equipment required for the type of repair work involved and repairs of this type are subcontracted to another motor vehicle repair shop identifying the MVR facility by the registration number.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-38, ยง 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 97-69, ยง 2, 6-3-97)</history></law>