<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY ANTENNA TELEVISION SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-126</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001463</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-126. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>CATV (community antenna television system) shall mean any facility that, in whole or in part, receives directly, or indirectly over the air, and amplifies or otherwise modifies the signals transmitting programs broadcast by one (1) or more television or radio stations and distributes such signals by wire or cable to subscribing members of the public who pay for such service, but such terms shall not include:<section prefix='(1)'>Any such facility that serves fewer than fifty (50) subscribers, or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any such facility that serves only the residents of one (1) or more apartment dwellings under common ownership, control, or management, and commercial establishments located on the premises of such an apartment house.</section></section><section>CATV shall be deemed to include all transmission and distribution facilities located in, under, over, along, across or upon any highway, street, alley, right-of-way, easement or any public property.</section><section prefix='(b)'>County shall mean Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, or its representative.</section><section prefix='(d)'>License shall mean the License granted to the applicant for permission to install and operate CATV systems in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Distribution System shall include all means of transmission of all signals.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Lead-in shall be the individual lead wire or cable from the distribution system to each individual household or connection.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Licensee shall be the corporation, partnership, individual, or other entity granted a License for CATV by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(h)'>County Manager shall mean the Miami-Dade County Manager, as appointed by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Gross Receipts shall mean all revenue derived directly or indirectly by the Licensee, its affiliates, subsidiaries, parents and any person in which the Licensee has a financial interest, from or in connection with the furnishing of regular subscriber services, the carriage of broadcast signals and required nonbroadcast services. Gross Receipts may include all revenues from services upon which the FCC's regulations allow application of percentage franchise fees.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Federal Communications Commission (FCC) shall mean that agency as presently constituted by the United States Congress, or any successor agency.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Priority Service Area shall mean that area of the County assigned by the Commission wherein the Licensee is authorized to provide CATV service. The Priority Service Area need not include all licensed areas.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 4, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 82-66, § 1, 7-20-82)</history></law>