<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. COMMUNITY ANTENNA TELEVISION SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-134</section_number>
<catch_line>Installation of Distribution System.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001477</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-134. Installation of Distribution System.<section prefix='(a)'>The entire Distribution System of the Licensee, including poles, wires, cables, appurtenances and facilities, shall be located or relocated and so erected as not to interfere with travel over, in, on or under any public way and with reasonable ingress and egress to abutting property. All installations shall be in accordance with County standards and specifications and under permit issued by the Public Works Department. The construction, operation and maintenance of the system by the Licensee shall be in accord with good engineering practices and shall be in full compliance with the National Electric Safety Code and applicable laws, regulations and ordinances and as from time to time such are amended and revised.</section><section prefix='(b)'>When any portion of any public way within the unincorporated or incorporated areas of the County is required to be excavated for the purpose of installing any portion of the Licensee's Distribution System or lead-in system, such excavation shall be at the expense of the Licensee and under inspection by the County appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction. Repair and replacement of the property so excavated shall not be restricted to the actual trench, ditch or path excavated but shall include any and all portions of the public way disturbed, including pavement, curbing, sidewalks, drainage facilities, swales, parkways, and grassed areas, and shall conform to the standards prescribed by the manual of public works construction.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The conditions on street occupancy shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>All transmissions and distribution structures, poles, fixtures, lines, and equipment erected by the Licensee within the County shall be so located as to cause minimum interference with the proper use of streets, alleys, and other public ways and places, and to cause minimum interference with the rights and reasonable convenience of property owners who may join any of the said streets, alleys or other public ways and places. All facilities shall be placed in such a manner as will not interfere with the usual travel on any public way.</section><section prefix='(2)'>In case of disturbance of any street, sidewalk, alley, public way, or paved area, the Licensee shall, at its own cost and expense and in a manner approved by the appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction replace and restore such street, sidewalk, alley, public way, or paved area in as good a condition as before the work involving such disturbance was done.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If at any time during the period of the License any appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction shall lawfully elect to alter or change the grade of any street, sidewalk, alley, or other public way, the Licensee, upon reasonable notice by such governmental agency, shall move, remove, or adjust its poles, wires, cables, underground conduits, manholes, and other fixtures at its own expense. However, if such activities as are delineated in this subsection are undertaken pursuant to any urban renewal projects, then the Licensee shall be treated in a manner similar to other utilities with regard to responsibility for payment for such removal, adjustments of poles, wires, etc., as may be required.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The Licensee shall, on the request of any person holding a building moving permit issued by any appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction, temporarily raise or lower its wires to permit the moving of buildings. The expense of such temporary removal or raising or lowering of wires shall be paid by the person requesting the same, and the Licensee shall have the authority to require such payment in advance. The Licensee shall be given forty-eight (48) hours advance notice to arrange for such temporary wire changes.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Licensee shall have the authority to trim trees upon, and overhanging, streets, alleys, sidewalks, and public ways and places of the County so as to prevent the branches of such trees from coming in contract with the wires and cables of the Licensee. Such trimming work shall be done by the Licensee at its own expense, and it shall be subject to the prior approval and inspection of the appropriate governmental agency having jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(6)'>In all sections of the County where the cables, wires or other like facilities of public utilities are placed underground, either by voluntary action on the part of any utility or by requirement of an existing or subsequent statute, ordinance or other enactment of law the Licensee shall place its cables, wires, or other like facilities under- ground, without cost to Miami-Dade County and without right to any reimbursement from Miami-Dade County for any costs incurred by the Licensee.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-88, §§ 2, 18, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 77-91, § 8, 12-20-77)</history></law>