<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE VIIA. MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIR ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-161.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001508</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-161.1. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Advertise shall mean to advise, announce, apprise, command, give notice of, inform, make known, or publish any material which calls to the attention of the public availability of motor vehicle products offered for sale by motor vehicle repair shops or repair work.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Article shall mean Article VIIA of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and any rules, regulations, and standards promulgated pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(b-1)'>ASE shall mean the certification examinations designed and administered by the National Institute for Automotive Service Excellence.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Automobile and light truck shall mean a motor vehicle which has a gross vehicle weight of less than ten thousand (10,000) pounds.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Certification or certificate shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for repair work to be performed by a master mechanic, specialty mechanic, motor vehicle body repair technician, or motor vehicle paint technician.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Collision, structural repair and paint facility shall mean a motor vehicle repair shop which rebuilds, repairs, restores or alters motor vehicles by mending, straightening, replacing, adding or customizing parts or portions of the body of a motor vehicle or performing structural repair work on a motor vehicle, including all repair work which may be performed by a structural repair facility and a cosmetic and paint repair facility pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Charge shall mean money, fee, emolument, quid pro quo, barter, remuneration, pay, reward, indemnification or satisfaction.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Contract shall mean a written or oral agreement, understanding, arrangement or similar circumstances whereby a person agrees that another person shall perform repair work, including, but not limited to, labor, diagnosis, repair, reconditioning, replacement, adjustment, or alteration, directly or indirectly, upon a motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Cosmetic and paint repair facility shall mean a motor vehicle repair shop which paints or repaints motor vehicles which are owned by other persons and which does not perform repair work such as replacement of any body panels, bumpers or repair of any structural damage of motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Customer shall mean a person who inquires about, makes a request for, or purchases motor vehicle products or repair work from a motor vehicle repair shop or a person who seeks repair work or motor vehicle products under the terms of a warranty issued by a motor vehicle repair shop. This term shall include "customer" as defined by Section 559.903(1), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time, and includes the owner, the agent or authorized representative of the owner of the motor vehicle or a person in lawful possession of the motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Director shall mean the County Manager or his designee. This definition shall apply to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, when utilizing the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Heavy-duty truck shall mean a motor vehicle which has a gross vehicle weight of ten thousand (10,000) pounds or more and includes both single unit and combination tractor trailer or tractor semitrailer vehicles.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Lien shall mean a charge, security, or encumbrance upon a motor vehicle, including when the law itself, without the stipulation of the parties, raises an implication or legal consequence from the relationship of the parties or the circumstances of their dealings.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Master mechanic shall mean a motor vehicle mechanic or specialty mechanic who has obtained a certificate from the Director in all of the specific motor vehicle mechanic repair work categories pursuant to this article. This term shall also include a master heavy-duty truck mechanic.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Material fact shall mean a fact which is used by a person as a premise upon which a conclusion is based.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Mechanic apprentice shall mean a person who desires to learn through on-the-job training to become a specialty mechanic or a master mechanic and has obtained a permit from the Director pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Minor repair services shall mean the replacement or installation of motor vehicle light bulbs, tires, lamp globes, air filters, oil filters, windshield wiper blades, minor or ornamental accessories, or motor vehicle lubrications or oil changes. This term shall also include the replacement, adjustment, repair, or servicing of the following motor vehicle parts and assemblies:<section prefix='(1)'>Air cleaner element.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Brake pedal pads.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Carburetor air cleaner.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Clutch pedal pads.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Trunk latch.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Wheel covers or hubcaps.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Wheels or tire mounting, except alignment.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Windshield washer hose.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Windshield washer tank.</section></section><section prefix='(r)'>Motor vehicle shall mean:<section prefix='(1)'>Motor vehicle, as defined by Section 559.903(6), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section></section><section prefix='(s)'>Motor vehicle body repair facility shall mean a motor vehicle repair shop which rebuilds, repairs or restores physically-damaged motor vehicles by mending, straightening, or replacing a portion or portions of the body of a motor vehicle or performing structural repairs on a motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Motor vehicle body repair technician or body technician shall mean any person who repairs, rebuilds, or restores the bodies of motor vehicles owned by other persons and has obtained a certificate pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Motor vehicle mechanic shall mean a person who performs mechanical repair work on motor vehicles, including the reconditioning, replacement, adjustment, or alteration of the operating condition, including any component or subassembly of a motor vehicle. Motor vehicle mechanics shall be limited to those persons who have received a permit or certification from the Director.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Motor vehicle mechanical repair facility shall mean a motor vehicle repair shop which performs any type of repair work other than the kinds of repair work performed by: a motor vehicle body repair facility; motor vehicle painting facility; collision, structural repair and paint facility; or cosmetic and paint facility.</section><section prefix='(w)'>Motor vehicle paint technician or paint technician shall mean any person who paints, repaints, or refinishes motor vehicles owned by other persons and has obtained a certificate pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(x)'>Motor vehicle painting facility shall mean a motor vehicle repair shop which paints, repaints, or refinishes motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(y)'>Motor vehicle products shall mean any goods sold or offered for sale by a motor vehicle repair shop in conjunction with the provision of repair work.</section><section prefix='(z)'>Motor vehicle repair shop shall mean any person advertising, offering to perform or performing repair work on motor vehicles owned by other persons and includes, but is not limited to, new car dealers and used car dealers, garages, service-stations, self-employed individuals, truck stops, paint and body shops, brake, muffler or transmission shops and shops doing upholstery or glass work, as well as employees of any of the foregoing who perform repair work, but excluding the following:<section prefix='(i)'>A person performing repair work on the motor vehicles of a single commercial or industrial establishment or governmental agency.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>A person performing repair work on his own or the person's family member's car.</section></section><section prefix='(aa)'>Paint/body apprentice shall mean a person who desires to learn through on-the-job training to become a motor vehicle body repair technician or a motor vehicle paint technician, as the case may be, and has obtained a permit from the Director pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(bb)'>Permit shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for a person to learn through on-the-job training to become a specialty mechanic, master mechanic, motor vehicle body repair technician or a motor vehicle paint technician.</section><section prefix='(cc)'>Person shall mean an individual, partnership, joint venture, association, corporation, trustee or any other legal entity.</section><section prefix='(dd)'>Registration shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for the operation of a motor vehicle repair shop in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(ee)'>Repair work shall mean the reconditioning, adjustment, alteration, maintenance, or diagnosis of the operating condition of a motor vehicle, with or without the replacement of any component or subassembly of a motor vehicle. This term shall include "repair work" as defined by Section 559.903(9), Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time. This term shall also include the provision of motor vehicle products.</section><section prefix='(ff)'>Representation shall mean a statement made by a motor vehicle repair shop or by any officer, agent, servant, or employee thereof to a customer with respect to some past, present, or future fact, circumstance, or set of facts pertinent to the contract with the customer.</section><section prefix='(gg)'>Specialty mechanic shall mean a motor vehicle mechanic who has obtained a certificate from the Director for a specific motor vehicle mechanic repair work category pursuant to this article. This term shall also include a specialty heavy-duty truck mechanic.</section><section prefix='(hh)'>Structural repair facility shall mean a motor vehicle repair shop which performs structural restoration repair work on motor vehicles owned by other persons, both frame or unibody construction, including suspension and alignment.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Warranty shall mean an express or implied guarantee provided by a motor vehicle repair shop to a customer with respect to the merchantability, the integrity of the subject of a contract or of the motor vehicle repair shop's responsibility for the replacement or repair of defective motor vehicle products or repair work, or both, assuring performance, product, or conditions as promised or declared.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-38, § 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 93-142, § 1, 12-14-93; Ord. No. 95-136, § 1, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 95-137, § 5, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 97-69, § 2, 6-3-97; Ord. No. 97-70, § 1, 6-3-97; Ord. No. 98-77, § 1, 6-2-98)</history></law>