<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE VIIA. MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIR ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-161.26</section_number>
<catch_line>Certification required; contents of application.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001532</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-161.26. Certification required; contents of application.<section>Any person seeking or obtaining employment as a specialty or master mechanic, motor vehicle body repair technician, or motor vehicle paint technician shall first apply for and obtain a certificate for such employment from the Director. Applications for a specialty or master mechanic certificate or for a motor vehicle body repair technician certificate or for a motor vehicle paint technician certificate shall be made on a form prescribed by the Director and shall include:<section prefix='(a)'>The name and home address of the applicant.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The motor vehicle mechanic repair work category or paint/body technician category for which the applicant is applying and the verified results of the required examination.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Documentation demonstrating that the applicant has successfully passed the ASE examination, or other examination approved by the Director, in the specific repair work categories for which the applicant is applying.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Effective January 1, 2000, documentation that the applicant has earned the continuing education hours required by Section 8A-161.31, in accordance with an approved program, pursuant to Section 8A-161.28</section><section prefix='(e)'>Other relevant information as the Director shall require.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-38, ยง 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 98-77, ยง 1, 6-2-98)</history></law>