<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>ARTICLE VIIA. MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIR ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-161.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Records; inspection; complaint retention and handling.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001514</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-161.7. Records; inspection; complaint retention and handling.<section prefix='(a)'>All motor vehicle repair shops shall maintain intact and in legible condition all the records required by this article for a period of two (2) years from the date of the creation of the particular record. All motor vehicle repair shops shall keep on file all written customer complaints presented to the shop for a period of two (2) years. The premises of all motor vehicle repair shops shall be open to the Director for inspection, investigation, sampling, testing or for such other purposes as are necessary for the enforcement and administration of this article during the business hours of the motor vehicle repair shop and in no event not less than between the hours of 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. Monday through Friday.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each complaint filed with the Director against a motor vehicle repair shop shall be provided to the motor vehicle repair shop by the Director and the motor vehicle repair shop shall promptly and thoroughly investigate said complaint. If the complaint cannot be satisfied within ten (10) days from receipt by the motor vehicle repair shop, the motor vehicle repair shop shall advise the Director of the status of the complaint and the reason for the delay. A motor vehicle repair shop shall object to or satisfy the complaint filed by the consumer and provide the Director with a written response stating the disposition of the complaint, the specific reasons for the objection, if applicable, and the name(s) of the person(s) involved in the repair work, no later than twenty (20) days after receipt of the complaint by the motor vehicle repair shop.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-38, ยง 2, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 97-70, ยง 1, 6-3-97)</history></law>