<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-2.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Hotel and motel employee's identification card.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001430</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-2.1. Hotel and motel employee's identification card.<section prefix='(a)'>All persons including partners, officers, and directors employed in or by a hotel or motel located in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, shall apply to the Miami-Dade Police Department for a hotel and motel employee's identification card within five (5) days from the date of their employment. It shall be unlawful for any such person to remain so employed without applying for an identification card.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Application for a hotel and motel employee's identification card shall be made in writing to the Miami-Dade Police Department and shall be accompanied by an application fee which shall be utilized to defray the cost of enforcement of this section; provided, that the amount of fee to be charged shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The application forms shall require the applicant to be fingerprinted and photographed. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall issue an identification card within ten (10) days from the date of such application.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All identification cards issued pursuant to this section shall be serially numbered and shall bear the date of issuance, the applicant's name, home address, birth date, physical description, full-face photograph, Social Security number, and shall be signed by the holder.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Every person who is convicted for violation of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) or by imprisonment in the County Jail not to exceed thirty (30) days or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Miami-Dade Police Department shall maintain a suitable file of all identification cards issued pursuant to this section. Such records shall contain a copy of the identification card, together with the application therefor.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All identification cards issued under this section shall expire three (3) years from the date of issue.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 72-3, §§ 1—6, 1-4-72; Ord. No. 75-95, § 1, 11-4-75)</history></law>