<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-262</section_number>
<catch_line>Unlawful practices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001708</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-262. Unlawful practices.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be a violation of this article for any person to sell, offer for sale, expose for sale, serve, or have in said person's possession with intent to sell, by any of the following means, in any restaurant, hotel, food cart, store or catering facility or any other place, any meat, poultry, food or food product which is falsely represented to be "Kosher," "Kosher for Passover," "under Rabbinical Supervision," "pareve" or as having been prepared according to or with a product sanctioned by the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch:<section prefix='(1)'>By direct statements, orally or in writing; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>By display of the word "Kosher" in English or Hebrew letters, or by display of any sign, emblem, insignia, six-pointed star, symbol or mark in simulation of the word Kosher; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>By inscription on any meat, poultry, food or food products, or its package, container or contents, the word "Kosher," "Pareve," "Glatt," or "Rabbinical Supervision" in English or Hebrew letters, or by display or inscription of any sign, emblem, insignia, six-pointed star, symbol or mark in simulation of the word Kosher; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>By display on any interior or exterior sign or menu or otherwise, the words "Kosher-Style," "Kosher-Type," "Jewish," "Hebrew," "Holiday (Jewish) Foods," "Traditional (Jewish)," or other similar words, either alone or in conjunction with the word "Type," "Style" or other similar expression, unless there is clearly and conspicuously stated a disclaimer in the same size type or letters in some prominent place or location that these terms refer to non-Kosher meat, poultry, food or food products or any non-Kosher food-handling facility; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>By advertisement, either oral or in writing, using the words "Kosher-Style," "Kosher-Type," "Jewish," "Hebrew," "Holiday (Jewish) Food," "Traditional (Jewish)," or other similar words, either alone or in conjunction with the word "Type," "Style" or other similar expression, unless there is clearly and conspicuously stated a disclaimer in type no smaller than the smallest type in the advertisement, and in no event less than 10-point type, that the product or products offered for sale are non-Kosher.<section prefix='(i)'>The disclaimer shall appear in a box within the advertisement and shall be preceded with the word "NOTICE," or other similar word, in not smaller than bold 14-point type.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>An advertisement that utilizes any Kosher symbol that also promotes the sale of non-Kosher meat, poultry, food or food products is in violation of this article unless there is clearly and conspicuously stated in the advertisement a disclaimer, in accordance with the requirements of this paragraph, that some of the meat, poultry, food or food products offered for sale are non-Kosher, or</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>By unauthorized use of a Kosher food symbol including, but not limited to OU, OK, VH, NK, SK, CRC, KAJ, KOF-K.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>