<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='3'>ARTICLE XIII. COMMERCIAL VEHICLE IDENTIFICATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-276</section_number>
<catch_line>Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001726</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-276. Requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions. When used herein:<section prefix='(1)'>The words "commercial vehicle" shall mean any vehicle whether horse-drawn, motor-driven or towed, and used, constructed, or equipped for the transportation of goods, wares, merchandise, tools, or equipment in trade, commerce, or industry. The following vehicles shall be excluded from the effect of this article: Passenger automobiles including station wagons, vehicles constructed for recreational purposes or other noncommercial purposes, vehicles used by governmental agencies for official business, and other vehicles which are or may be required to be similarly identified by State or federal law.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Vehicles, markings of. Every commercial vehicle operated on the streets of the County shall at all times display, permanently affixed and plainly marked on both sides in letters and numerals not less than three (3) inches in height, the name, address and telephone number of the owner thereof. The numbers of all occupational and business licenses issued to the owner thereof shall be similarly displayed along with and in addition to the other information required by this paragraph. If a vehicle is rented, the information required by this paragraph but applicable to the lessee or user, not the owner, must be affixed to the vehicle and may be affixed to signs made of paperboard and attached by means of tape at the time such vehicle is delivered to the user or lessee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Violations. Any person convicted of:<section prefix='(1)'>A violation of this section shall be punished by:<section prefix='a.'>Not more than thirty (30) days imprisonment;</section><section prefix='b.'>A fine of not more than two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00);</section><section prefix='c.'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='d.'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='e.'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>A second violation of this section shall be punished by:<section prefix='a.'>Not more than thirty (30) days imprisonment;</section><section prefix='b.'>A fine of not more than five hundred dollars ($500.00);</section><section prefix='c.'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='d.'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='e.'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Any subsequent violations of this section shall be punished by:<section prefix='a.'>Not more than thirty (30) days imprisonment;</section><section prefix='b.'>A fine of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000.00);</section><section prefix='c.'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='d.'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='e.'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to Implementing Order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Applicability. This article shall be applicable in all the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Waiver. Upon written application, the Miami-Dade Police Department may grant a waiver of the requirements of this section where it is demonstrated that compliance with this section may constitute a security risk to the commercial vehicle or its passengers.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Farm Vehicle Exemption.<section prefix='(1)'>A vehicle, owned or operated by a farmer, or lessee, or his or her designee, on a farm, grove, or nursery actively engaged in the production of agricultural or horticultural pursuits. Such vehicle is only operated incidentally on the roads, to go to or from the owner's or operator's headquarters or farm, grove or nursery and return.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A vehicle, used principally for the transport of plows, harrows, fertilizer distributors, spray machines, or other farm, grove or nursery equipment ancillary to a bona-fide agricultural use. Such vehicle only uses the roads incidentally to go to or from the owner's or operator's headquarters or farm, grove or nursery and return.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A vehicle with a gross vehicle weight rating ("GVWR") of 10,000 lbs. or less which is owned and operated by a farmer or lessee in the support of an active farm, grove or nursery operation.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-84, §§ 1, 2, 10-15-75; Ord. No. 79-32, § 1, 5-1-79; Ord. No. 95-186, § 1, 10-17-95; Ord. No. 00-70, § 1, 5-23-00; Ord. No. 10-52, § 3, 9-21-10)</history></law>