<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-269</section_number>
<catch_line>Inspection of Kosher meat dealers, Kosher poultry dealers and dealers in Kosher food or food products.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001715</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-269. Inspection of Kosher meat dealers, Kosher poultry dealers and dealers in Kosher food or food products.<section prefix='(a)'>The inspections provided for by this section shall only be conducted by authorized inspectors of the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division.</section><section prefix='(b)'>When conducting an inspection as provided for by this article, the authorized inspectors shall utilize the inspection report form approved by the Director to report the date of the inspection, the nature and scope of the inspection and the findings of the inspection.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For the purpose of making any inspections under this section, the authorized inspectors of the Director shall have a right of entry to, upon and through the business premises of all Kosher meat dealers, Kosher poultry dealers, and dealers in Kosher food or food products.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Authorized inspectors of the director shall make inspections of Kosher meat dealers, Kosher poultry dealers and dealers in Kosher food or food products for the purpose of:<section prefix='(1)'>Determining by examination of the meat, poultry, food, food products, tags, plumbas, or any other proper identification and by inspection of the records whether or not the establishment under inspection is in compliance with this article.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>The scope and manner of inspections shall be as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>At the commencement of all inspections provided for by this section, the authorized inspectors of the Director shall present appropriate identification of themselves to the Kosher meat dealer, Kosher poultry dealer or Kosher food or food products dealer, owner, manager or any sales person and shall advise said person of the purposes of the inspection to be conducted under the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All inspections provided for by this section shall be limited to:<section prefix='(i)'>The meat and poultry and other food and food products located on the business premises of the Kosher meat dealer, Kosher poultry dealer or Kosher food or food products dealer. The business premises shall include all places of storage of meats, poultry and food or food products, all places where meat, poultry and food or food products are cut, sliced, carved, broken down, or divided into smaller quantities or portions and all places where meat, poultry and food or food products are prepared and sold to customers; and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The records required to be kept by Kosher meat dealers and Kosher poultry dealers under the provisions of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>The inspections provided for by this section shall be made during the regular business hours of the Kosher meat dealer, Kosher poultry dealer or Kosher food or food products dealer, and at any time, including non-business hours, when deliveries of meat, poultry and food or food products are made to any of the aforesaid dealers or when any of the aforesaid dealers is engaged in the cutting, slicing, carving, breaking down, preparing, packaging, processing, or dividing of meat, poultry or food or food products into smaller quantities or portions.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In carrying out the requirements of this section, no advance notice of an inspection shall be required to be provided to any person.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All inspections of the meat, poultry or food or food products located on the business premises of Kosher meat dealers, Kosher poultry dealers and Kosher food or food products dealers and all inspections of the records required to be kept by said persons under the provisions of this article shall be conducted in such a manner so as to not unduly interfere with the regular business operations of the Kosher meat dealers, Kosher poultry dealers and Kosher food or food products dealers.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>A failure to allow an authorized inspector a right of entry upon the business premises of a Kosher meat dealer, Kosher poultry dealer or Kosher food or food products dealer in accordance with the requirements of this article shall be a violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(g)'>At the completion of all inspections provided for by this section, the authorized inspectors of the Director shall prepare an inspection report which shall indicate the date of the inspection, the nature and scope of the inspection and the findings of the inspection. A copy of the inspection report shall be filed in the records of the Director.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Inspectors authorized by the Director may, under the following circumstances, tag meat, poultry or food or food products as evidence of a possible violation of this article.<section prefix='(1)'>Upon reasonable belief that certain meat, poultry or food or food products in the possession of a Kosher meat dealer, Kosher poultry dealer or Kosher food or food products dealer is not Kosher.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Upon discovery that certain meat or poultry in the possession of the Kosher meat dealer or Kosher poultry dealer is not identified in accordance with this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Upon discovery that certain meat or poultry in the possession of the Kosher meat dealer or Kosher poultry dealer has not been maintained in accordance with this article:<section prefix='(i)'>A Kosher meat dealer, Kosher poultry dealer or Kosher food or food products dealer whose meat is tagged as evidence in accordance with (h) above shall not remove the tag or dispose of the meat, poultry or food or food products for a period of seventy-two (72) hours unless notified otherwise by an authorized representative of the Director. Removal of the aforesaid tag or disposal of tagged meat, poultry or food or food product in violation of this paragraph shall constitute a violation of this article.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>