<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. FAIR CREDIT DISCLOSURE AND REPORTING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-274.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Qualifications of field representatives.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001724</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-274.3. Qualifications of field representatives.<section prefix='(a)'>All field representatives shall be of good moral character and reputation. The consumer reporting agency shall conduct a background investigation on all prospective field representatives to include information about the person's moral character and reputation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The consumer reporting agency shall require each field representative to submit to a written examination approved by the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division concerning the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act and the Miami-Dade County Fair Investigative Consumer Reporting and Disclosure Ordinance to affirmatively show that such field representative is familiar with the provisions of said statute and ordinance. Such examination shall be administered by the consumer reporting agency. The consumer reporting agency shall maintain evidence in its personnel files showing that each field representative has satisfactorily completed the examination.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A consumer reporting agency shall furnish to each field representative an identification card which shall contain the field representative's name, physical description, and the name and business address of the consumer reporting agency. The identification card shall at all times be kept in the possession of the field representative and upon request the same shall be produced for inspection.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Each consumer reporting agency shall notify the Director, Consumer Protection Division, Miami-Dade County, Florida, within five (5) working days of a field representative's employment and termination of employment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-87, ยง 5(3), 10-15-74; Ord. No. 75-51, ยง 7, 7-2-75)</history></law>