<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-268</section_number>
<catch_line>Records required to be maintained by Kosher meat dealers and Kosher poultry dealers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001714</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-268. Records required to be maintained by Kosher meat dealers and Kosher poultry dealers.<section prefix='(a)'>Complete and accurate records of all purchases of properly identified Kosher meat, properly identified Kosher poultry, non-Kosher meat, non-Kosher poultry from slaughterhouses, wholesalers or any other source shall be kept by every Kosher meat dealer and by every Kosher poultry dealer, including the name and address of the slaughterhouse, wholesaler or other source from which such purchases are made, the dates, quantities and identity or nature of the meat or poultry included in all such purchases, and copies of all invoices and bills of sale relating to all such purchases. Kosher meat dealers and Kosher poultry dealers shall retain all such records for a two-year period following the purchase of the particular properly identified Kosher meat, properly identified Kosher poultry, non-Kosher meat, and non-Kosher poultry. Records shall be separated into two (2) sets, one (1) set for Kosher meat and poultry and one (1) set for non-Kosher meat and poultry.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Kosher meat dealers and Kosher poultry dealers shall not remove the attached plumbas or tags or any duly affixed identifications affixed thereto by the slaughterhouse from any Kosher meats, Kosher poultry, or any other Kosher products received therefrom until the time immediately preceding the point in time when said Kosher meat, Kosher poultry, or product, whenever appropriate, is ready to be cut, sliced, carved, broken down, or divided into smaller quantities or portions.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>