<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='3'>ARTICLE XIV. BACKGROUND CHECKS FOR PERSONNEL IN CHILD CARE AND CERTAIN OTHER FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-282</section_number>
<catch_line>Application for and extent of investigation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001729</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-282. Application for and extent of investigation.<section>The Miami-Dade Police Department shall provide an application form, which will require the submission of identifying information by the applicant, including name, past name, aliases, sex, race, date of birth, place of birth, Social Security number and physical description. The application, which must be sworn to by each applicant, shall contain an authorization to conduct and release, as allowed by law, a background investigation report, showing whether the applicant has a record of any arrests or convictions within the State of Florida, an outstanding warrant for his or her arrest, or is named on a wanted list and the nature of the offense with which the applicant is connected. An applicant must present two (2) forms of identification to the Miami-Dade Police Department at the time of application. Each application shall also be accompanied by an application fee which shall be utilized to defray the cost of conducting the background investigation and enforcing the provisions of this article. The fee to be charged shall be established by administrative order. Upon receipt of a fully completed application, the Miami-Dade Police Department will provide a receipt of application to the applicant and the facility at which the applicant is employed. Upon receipt of a fully completed application form, the Miami-Dade Police Department shall conduct a background investigation, which shall be concluded within sixty (60) days of the date an application is received and shall mail a copy of the report derived from the investigation to the applicant, the facility at which the applicant is employed, and the Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services, State of Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-1, ยง 3, 1-8-85)</history></law>