<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. UNIFORM MEAT IDENTIFICATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-252</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001698</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-252. Definitions.<section>As used in relation to meat sold or offered for sale at retail and as used in this article:<section prefix='(A)'>Sale of retail means a transaction wherein a person sells meat to the consumer, whether at the place of business of such person or whether such sale is consummated by mail, by telephone or in writing at a place other than at the place of business. Places of business carrying on the aforesaid transaction include, but are not limited to, supermarkets, grocery stores, butcher shops, food freezer dealers and food plan companies.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Meat means the edible part of the muscle of cattle, swine or sheep which is skeletal or which is found in the tongue, in the diaphragm, in the heart or in the esophagus, with or without the accompanying or overlying fat and portions of bone, skin, nerve and blood vessels which normally accompany the muscle tissue and which are separate from it in the process of dressing. It does not include the muscle found in the lips, snout or ears.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Ground beef, ground veal, ground lamb, or ground pork means chopped, fresh and/or frozen meat, other than the heart, esophagus, tongue or cheeks, of the species indicated without the addition of fat as such and shall not contain more than thirty (30) percent fat and shall not contain added water, binders or extenders.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Stew beef means meat, other than from the heart, esophagus, tongue or cheeks, which is derived from cattle, sliced into cubes and commonly used for stewing.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Hanging tender means meat derived from the thick, muscular dorsal attachment (pillar) of the diaphragm of cattle. Whenever such meat is labeled or advertised for sale at retail, the term "hanging tender," and only said term, shall be used in said labeling or advertising and then only if in conjunction with the term "pillar of diaphragm."</section><section prefix='(F)'>Skirt steak means meat derived from the diaphragm of cattle.</section><section prefix='(G)'>Sirloin knuckle means meat derived from the beef round by a straight cut from the knee cap parallel to and along the femur on the inside of the round and the natural seam of the outside of the round.</section><section prefix='(H)'>T-bone steak means meat derived from the short loin of cattle and which exhibits not less than one-half inch diameter of tenderloin (psoas muscle).</section><section prefix='(I)'>Porterhouse steak means meat derived from the short loin of cattle and which exhibits not less than one and one-fourth (1¼) inches in diameter of tenderloin (psoas muscle).</section><section prefix='(J)'>Sirloin steak means meat derived from the posterior portion of the loin of cattle after removal of the short loin.</section><section prefix='(K)'>Sirloin is the posterior portion of the loin of cattle and is obtained by a straight cut made perpendicular to the contour of the outer skin surface and perpendicular to the split surface of the lumbar vertebrae and which passes flush with the ilium (pelvic bone) leaving a small part of hip bone in the short loin.</section><section prefix='(L)'>Short loin is the anterior portion of the loin of cattle remaining after the removal of the posterior portion (sirloin) of the loin and is obtained by straight cut perpendicular to the contour of the outer skin surface and perpendicular to the split surface of the lumbar vertebrae and which passes through the ilium (pelvic bone) leaving a small part of hip bone in the short loin.</section><section prefix='(M)'>Strip loin steak or shell steak means meat derived from that portion of the short loin of cattle remaining after the tenderloin (psoas muscle) has been removed.</section><section prefix='(N)'>Top sirloin butt means meat derived from the posterior portion of the loin of cattle after removal of the short loin and which is the thick upper portion (dorsal side) of the sirloin after removal of the bottom sirloin (ventral side) by a cut following the natural muscle seam (blue tissue).</section><section prefix='(O)'>Bottom sirloin butt means meat derived from the posterior portion of the loin of cattle after removal of the short loin and which is the lower portion (ventral side) of the sirloin after removal of the top sirloin butt (dorsal side) by a cut following the natural muscle seam (blue tissue).</section><section prefix='(P)'>Tenderloin means meat derived from the psoas muscle of cattle, sheep or swine.</section><section prefix='(Q)'>Spare ribs means ribs which are removed from the belly portion of the pork carcass midsection extending from the scribe line at the fatback side of the belly to and including portions of the rib cartilages, with or without the skirt (diaphragm) remaining. Use of such term shall be confined to labeling or advertising the said meat as herein defined.</section><section prefix='(R)'>Back ribs means ribs derived from the rib area of pork loin.</section><section prefix='(S)'>True name means the genus or species of animal, i.e., beef, veal, lamb or pork, and the primal source or area of the animal carcass from which meat is derived and shall consist of one (1), but not more than one (1), of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>For beef—Cheeks, tongue, gullets or esophagus, heart, neck, shoulder, brisket or breast, foreshank, chuck, diaphragm, rib, plate, hind shank, round, rump, loin, flank or pillar of diaphragm.<section>As used in relation to beef herein:</section><section prefix='(a)'>"Neck" is derived from the area of the chuck containing atlas bone through the fifth cervical vertebra.</section><section prefix='(b)'>"Shoulder" is derived from the area of the chuck which includes clod, forearm, brisket muscle and arm bone and may include cross sections of the ribs.</section><section prefix='(c)'>"Brisket" or "breast" is derived from the area of the chuck which includes part of ribs one (1) through five (5) and the sternum (breast bone).</section><section prefix='(d)'>"Foreshank" is derived from the upper portion of the fore leg and contains the upper shank bone.</section><section prefix='(e)'>"Chuck" is derived from that area of the forequarter containing ribs one (1) through five (5) without the neck, brisket and foreshank.</section><section prefix='(f)'>"Diaphragm" is derived from the forequarter and includes the muscles and tendon attachments which separate the thoracic (chest) cavity from the abdominal cavity.</section><section prefix='(g)'>"Rib" is derived from the forequarter and includes the sixth through the twelfth ribs after removal of the plate approximately ten (10) inches from the chine bone.</section><section prefix='(h)'>"Plate" is derived from the forequarter and includes the sixth through twelfth ribs cut approximately ten (10) inches from the chine bone.</section><section prefix='(i)'>"Hind shank" is derived by cutting through the stifle joint severing the shank meat and shank bone from the round.</section><section prefix='(j)'>"Round" is separated from the full beef loin by a straight cut which starts at a point on the backbone at the juncture of the last (fifth) sacral vertebra and the first tail (caudal) vertebra, passes through a second point which is immediately anterior to the protuberance of the femur bone and exposes the ball of the femur and then continues in the same straight line beyond the second point to complete the cut.</section><section prefix='(k)'>"Rump" is derived from the round and is removed therefrom by a straight cut perpendicular to the outer skin surface immediately posterior to, and parallel with, the long axis of the exposed surface of the aitch bone.</section><section prefix='(l)'>"Loin" is located between the rib and the round and is removed by a cut between the twelfth and thirteenth ribs (posterior end of the rib) and contains the thirteenth rib vertebra, six (6) lumber vertebrae and five (5) sacral vertebrae.</section><section prefix='(m)'>"Flank" is derived by stripping the serous membrane from over the abdominis muscles (flank steak) by pulling the abdominis muscles from the thick membrane which lies underneath.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>For veal—Cheeks, tongue, gullets or esophagus, heart, neck, shank, breast, shoulder, rib, loin, sirloin, rump or leg.<section>As used in relation to veal herein:</section><section prefix='(a)'>"Neck" is derived from the shoulder by a straight line cut in front of the blade bone approximately between the fourth and fifth cervical vertebrae and parallel to the rib end of the shoulder.</section><section prefix='(b)'>"Shank" is derived from the leg bone (tibia) or the arm bone (radius).</section><section prefix='(c)'>"Breast" is derived by a cut perpendicular to the outer surface which passes through the cartilaginous juncture of the first rib and anterior extremity of the sternum and perpendicular to the long axis of the twelfth rib approximately four (4) inches from the eye of the rib, and contains the sternum, first twelve (12) ribs and all overlaying muscle, except the foreshank.</section><section prefix='(d)'>"Shoulder" is the section remaining after removal of the foreshank, breast and neck and contains the first through the fifth ribs.</section><section prefix='(e)'>"Rib" is removed from the shoulder by cutting between the fifth and sixth ribs and contains featherbone, chine bone and rib bones.</section><section prefix='(f)'>"Loin" is located between the sirloin and rib and is removed from the rib by a cut between the twelfth and thirteenth ribs and from the sirloin but a cut perpendicular to the outer surface immediately anterior to and flush with the ilium (pelvic bone) leaving no part of the hip bone in the loin and includes the thirteenth rib vertebra and five (5) lumbar vertebrae.</section><section prefix='(g)'>"Leg" is removed from the sirloin and rump by a straight line cut perpendicular to the outer skin surface immediately posterior to and parallel with the long axis of the exposed surface of the aitch bone, leaving no part of the aitch bone in the leg. The separation of the sirloin and rump from the leg is completed by sawing through the round bone (femur) immediately posterior to the ball joint.</section><section prefix='(h)'>"Rump" is removed from the leg as aforesaid and is removed from the loin by a cut perpendicular to the outer skin surface and perpendicular to the backbone at the anterior end of the hip bone leaving all the hip bone in the rump.</section><section prefix='(i)'>"Sirloin" is derived from the anterior end of the rump by a cut perpendicular to the dorsal side starting at any point on the backbone between the juncture of the last (fifth) sacral vertebra and the anterior end of the ilium (pelvic bone) or between the fifth and sixth lumbar vertebrae.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>For lamb—Cheeks, tongue, gullets or esophagus, heart, neck, shank, breast, shoulder, rib, loin or leg.<section>As used in relation to lamb herein:</section><section prefix='(a)'>"Neck" is derived from the anterior area of the shoulder and contains the atlas and cervical vertebrae.</section><section prefix='(b)'>"Breast" is cut from the loin, neck and shoulder starting at the cod or udder to and through the shank just above the elbow.</section><section prefix='(c)'>"Shoulder" is separated from the ribs by cutting between the fifth and sixth ribs.</section><section prefix='(d)'>"Rib" is separated from the loin by cutting between the last two (2) ribs.</section><section prefix='(e)'>"Loin" is separated from the leg by cutting just in front of the hip bone.</section><section prefix='(f)'>"Leg" is the portion remaining after the loin has been removed as aforesaid.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>For pork—Cheeks, tongue, gullets or esophagus, heart, tail, jowl, shoulder, shoulder picnic, shoulder butt, feet, side, spareribs, loin, loin-shoulder end, loin-rib end, loin-center cut, loin-loin end, fat back, ham or hock.<section>As used in relation to pork herein:</section><section prefix='(a)'>"Jowl" shall be removed closely to the body of the shoulder on a line approximately parallel to the opposite straight cut side of the shoulder, starting behind the "ear dip" which must remain on the jowl, and continuing the cut so as to remove the entire jowl.</section><section prefix='(b)'>"Shoulder" includes the shoulder picnic and shoulder butt and is derived by a cut starting at a point in the armpit that is not more than one (1) inch posterior to the elbow joint, but does not expose the elbow joint, and continues reasonably straight across the hog side. The foot, ribs and related cartilages, breast bone, intercostal meat, breast flap, and neck bones shall be excluded.</section><section prefix='(c)'>"Shoulder picnic" is separated from the "shoulder butt" by a cut which is reasonably straight and perpendicular to the outside skin surface (not slanted or under cut) and approximately parallel to the breast side of the shoulder leaving all the major shoulder bone (humerus) and not less than one (1) nor more than two (2) inches of the blade bone (scapula) in the shoulder picnic.</section><section prefix='(d)'>"Side" (belly) shall be separated from the fat back on a straight line not more than three-fourths inch beyond the outermost curvature of the scribe line. The belly must be boneless and the major cartilages of the sternum and the ribs must be closely and smoothly removed without deep scoring. Any enlarged soft, porous, or seedy mammary tissue and the pizzle recess of barrow bellies must be removed.</section><section prefix='(e)'>"Loin" is removed from the middle portion by a cut (scribe) extending from a point on the first rib of the loin which is not more than one and three-fourths (1¾) inches from the junction of the foremost rib and the foremost thoracic vertebra to a point on the ham end which is immediately adjacent to the major tenderloin muscle. The loin shall be removed from the fat back and shall contain eleven (11) or more ribs, seven (7) lumbar vertebrae and at least three (3) sacral vertebrae.</section><section prefix='(f)'>"Loin-shoulder end" or "loin-rib" is derived from the anterior end of the loin by a cut perpendicular to the length of the loin flush with the last rib and usually includes the blade bone.</section><section prefix='(g)'>"Loin-center cut" is derived from the pork loin after the shoulder end has been removed by cutting crosswise to the length of the loin at a point posterior to the edge of the scapular cartilage and from the ham end of the loin has been removed by cutting crosswise to its length anterior to the cartilage on the tuber coxae.</section><section prefix='(h)'>"Loin-loin end" is derived from the posterior end of the loin by a cut perpendicular to the length of the loin flush with the last rib and usually includes the hip (pelvic) bone.</section><section prefix='(i)'>"Fat back" is the section remaining after removal of the loin and side.</section><section prefix='(j)'>"Ham" is the posterior portion of the hog side removed by a cut two and one-fourth (2¼) to two and three-fourths (2¾) inches anterior to the knob end of the aitch bone. The cut shall be at right angles to an imaginary line from the top of the aitch bone through the center of the ham and shank. At the flank pocket the cut shall divert at a forty-five (45) degree angle posteriorly.</section></section><section>The true name for pork chops shall consist of one (1) of the following primal sources: Shoulder or blade, rib, loin, center, or loin end or sirloin.</section></section><section prefix='(T)'>Veal cutlet means a single slice of veal derived from the leg and contains top, bottom, eye and sirloin tip and cross section of the leg bone. If the word "cutlet" is used in labeling or advertising a single slice of meat derived other than from the leg of veal, the species of animal and primal source from which such meat is derived shall precede the word "cutlet" in at least the same size and style lettering and on the same background as the word "cutlet", for example: VEAL SHOULDER CUTLET.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 73-90, § 2, 10-16-73; Ord. No. 85-61, § 4, 9-3-85)</history></law>