<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibiting certain bumper sticker, advertising, or insignias on rental cars.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001429</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-2. Prohibiting certain bumper sticker, advertising, or insignias on rental cars.<section prefix='(a)'>Prohibited activity. It shall be a violation of this section to rent in Miami-Dade County to any person a rental car that displays any bumper stickers, insignias, or advertising that identifies the vehicle as a rental car, that indicates that the car is owned by a rental car company, or that exhibits the name of the rental car company.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Rental car as used in this section means a motor vehicle designed to transport ten (10) or less persons and rented for any period of time less than ninety (90) days; but the term does not include taxis, chauffeured limousines, or other vehicles in which a paid driver with a chauffeur's license is being provided with the rental car as part of the rental agreement.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Bumper stickers, insignias, or advertising as used in this section means one (1) or more decals, paintings, emblems, attachments, bumper stickers, or other identifying markings that are affixed to the exterior of a rental car; but the term does not include (A) any emblem less than two (2) inches by four (4) inches that is placed on the rental car for inventory purposes only; or (B) any license plate required by State law.</section><section prefix='(3)'>To rent in Miami-Dade County as used in this section means to sign a rental contract in Miami-Dade County or to deliver a car to renter in Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Penalties. Any person found in violation of the provisions of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of one hundred dollars ($100.00).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-109, ยง 2, 10-1-91)</history></law>