<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. FAIR CREDIT DISCLOSURE AND REPORTING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-271</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001718</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-271. Definitions.<section>As used herein:<section prefix='(a)'>Consumer reporting agency means any individual, partnership, corporation, trust, estate, cooperative, association, or other entity which is defined as a consumer reporting agency by the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, including amendments thereto, and which does business in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Consumer means an individual.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Investigative consumer report means a report which is subject to the provisions of the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, including amendments thereto, as they relate to investigative consumer reports.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Field representative means any person who collects information in Miami-Dade County on a consumer's character, general reputation, personal characteristics or mode of living through personal interviews with neighbors, friends, associates or acquaintances of the consumer reported for the purpose of preparing investigative consumer reports. The term includes agents and employees of consumer reporting agencies.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Medical information means information or records obtained, with the consent of the individual to whom it relates, from licensed physicians or medical practitioners, hospitals, clinics, or other medical or medically related facilities.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 74-55, ยง 1, 7-2-74; Ord. No. 74-87, ยง 1, 10-15-74; Ord. No. 75-51, ยง 1, 7-2-75)</history></law>