<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-265</section_number>
<catch_line>Filling requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001711</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-265. Filling requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person operating a restaurant, hotel, store, catering facility, food cart, or any other place which advertises, represents or holds itself out as selling, serving or offering for sale exclusively Kosher meat, poultry, food or food products, shall file with the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division a document from a supervising rabbi or rabbinical organization that said establishment complies with the dietary requirements of the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch or, if said establishment is not under rabbinical supervision, so advise the Director in writing. The Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division shall be notified in writing, within ten (10) business days, of any change in the Kosher or rabbinical supervision status referred to above. Failure to notify the Director of a change in the Kosher or rabbinical supervision status as provided herein shall constitute a violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any person providing Kosher supervision to any restaurant, hotel, store, food cart, catering facility, slaughterer, or any other place shall file with the Director of Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division a document listing the name, address and type of establishment that the person is supervising. The Director shall be notified, in writing, within ten (10) business days by said person of the date of termination of such supervision. Failure to notify the Director of said termination shall constitute a violation of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>