<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-264</section_number>
<catch_line>Identification requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001710</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-264. Identification requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>All meats sold as Kosher, regardless of the size of the portion, shall have affixed thereto at the slaughterhouse a tag or plumba. The tags shall be affixed as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For all forequarters of steers, cows, bulls, heifers, and yearling calves, the following Kosher identifications shall be affixed to each of the following parts:<section prefix='(i)'>Breast, rib, plate (outside), plate pieces (inside), chuck, shoulder, heart, lung, oxtail, tripe, milt (spleen), tenderloin (hanger): Plumba and tag;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Liver: Two (2) Kosher brands and two (2) plumbas, one (1) of each to the opposite ends of the liver, so that if the liver is cut in half through the vein each half will bear one (1) plumba and one (1) Kosher brand;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Feet: Plumba and tag to each foot;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Breads: Plumba and tag to each pair;</section><section prefix='(v)'>Brains: Plumba to each brain, when sold separately from the head;</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Tongue: Plumba and tag at the tip, and a Kosher brand at the tip on a smooth surface;</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Breastbone: Incisions in the form of Hebrew characters, showing the date of slaughter.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>For all foresaddles of veal, the following Kosher identifications shall be affixed to each of the following parts:<section prefix='(i)'>Breast: Incision on each in the form of Hebrew characters, showing the date of slaughter;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Rack: Two (2) incisions on the inside, one (1) of them on each side of the spine, in the form of Hebrew characters, showing the date of slaughter;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Shoulder: Plumba and tag;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Liver: Plumba affixed to the center of the liver at the vein, and a Kosher brand on the upper surface of the liver;</section><section prefix='(v)'>Haslett: Plumba and tag through the heart and milt;</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Lung: Plumba and tag;</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Feet: Plumba and tag to each foot;</section><section prefix='(viii)'>Breads: One (1) tag, and one (1) plumba drawn through three (3) pairs;</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Brains: Plumba to each brain, when sold separately from the head;</section><section prefix='(x)'>Tongue: Plumba and tag at the tip, and a Kosher brand at the tip of the smooth surface.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>For all foresaddles of lamb and mutton, the following Kosher identifications shall be affixed to each of the following parts:<section prefix='(i)'>Breast: Incision on each in the form of Hebrew characters, showing the date of slaughter;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Racks: Two (2) plumbas and two (2) tags, one (1) of each to either side of the spine;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Shoulder: Plumba and tag;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Haslett: Plumba and tag through the liver and milt;</section><section prefix='(v)'>Tongue: One (1) tag, and one (1) plumba drawn through each group of six (6);</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Brains: Plumba to each brain, when sold separately from the head;</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Liver: Plumba and tag at the center of the liver, when sold separately from the haslett.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The slaughterer and wholesaler of Kosher poultry is responsible to ensure that plumbas are affixed and remain on each and every portion. A Miami-Dade County-based slaughterer or wholesaler shall not refuse to accept returned poultry that is missing the necessary plumbas and shall provide a refund for same.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>