<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-263</section_number>
<catch_line>Display and handling requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001709</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-263. Display and handling requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Kosher meats, Kosher poultry, and Kosher food or food products sold by a restaurant, hotel, store, catering facility, food cart, or any other place which advertises, represents or holds itself out as selling, serving or offering for sale both Kosher and non-Kosher meats, poultry, food or food products shall be deemed to be falsely represented to be Kosher within the meaning of this article and a violation of this article unless the following display and handling requirements are observed:<section prefix='(1)'>Interior display and handling requirements are as follows:<section prefix='(i)'>Kosher meats, Kosher poultry, and Kosher food or food products which are not prepared, cut, sliced, carved, broken down or divided into smaller portions on the premises of the place in which they are offered for sale, and which are contained in properly sealed packages, may be commingled with non-Kosher meats, non-Kosher poultry, and non-Kosher food or food products, provided, however, that if a person indicates by sign or label that Kosher products are contained in a separate display cabinet or section, only Kosher products shall be contained therein.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Kosher meats, poultry, food or food products which are prepared, cut, sliced, carved, broken down or divided into smaller portions on the premises of the place in which they are offered for sale shall not be commingled with non-Kosher meats, poultry, food or food products. Kosher meats, poultry, food or food products shall be kept in a separate display cabinet which shall not contain any non-Kosher meat, non-Kosher poultry, non-Kosher food or food products, or any dairy products and shall be completely separated from any non-Kosher meats, non-Kosher poultry, non-Kosher food or food products or any dairy products by a clearly visible divider.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>There shall be a clearly visible sign in block letters affixed to the separate display cabinet or Kosher section of said cabinet indicating that only Kosher food is contained therein and indicating which section contains only dairy products and which section contains only meat.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Kosher dairy foods shall be prepared in utensils that are separate and distinct from those used to prepare Kosher or non-Kosher meats and poultry and all servicing and eating utensils shall be kept separate and apart as either meat or dairy. Such Kosher meat, poultry, and food or food products shall be sliced with a separate knife, and on a separate cutting board, or on a separate slicing machine, used solely for Kosher meat, Kosher poultry, Kosher food or food products and labelled "Kosher" in clearly visible block letters affixed to the knife or, in the case of a slicer, either affixed to the slicer or displayed in a prominent place on the premises where the slicer is maintained.</section><section prefix='(v)'>No articles of food or food products, including meats and poultry, shall be sold as Kosher or Kosher for Passover unless a Kosher or Kosher for Passover identification is securely affixed thereto by the processor, manufacturer or packer at its premises. No person other than such processor, manufacturer or packer shall possess or affix such marks of identification.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>No raw meat or poultry shall be sold or offered for sale as Kosher unless the words "soaked and salted," "Not soaked and salted" or "soaked and salted upon request only," as the appropriate case may be, is prominently displayed on a sign in conjunction with the product. If the raw meat or poultry is packaged, the words "soaked and salted" or "not soaked and salted" shall be marked on the package label in lieu of, or in addition to, the above requirement, but in no event shall packaged raw meat or poultry be sold or offered for sale as Kosher without the date of packaging clearly marked on the label. No person shall sell or offer for sale, as Kosher, any raw meat or poultry that is identified as "soaked and salted" unless the product has been soaked and salted in a manner which makes it Kosher.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Washing and deveining requirements are as follows:<section prefix='(i)'>Kosher meats shall be maintained Kosher and shall be properly deveined and, with the exception of liver, washed within seventy-two (72) hours after slaughter, and within each subsequent seventy-two (72) hour period, in accordance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch. The date and time of the day (A.M. or P.M.) of each washing and the name of the person performing such duty shall be legibly indicated on all tags attached to said meat.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Meats to be washed en route shall be packed in such a manner as to allow washing to be done as prescribed above. The date and time of day of the washing shall be indicated on all tags or by means of a written statement securely attached inside the car or other vehicle and signed by the person supervising the washing. Upon receipt of the meat so washed en route, the information contained in the written statement shall be legibly transferred to tags attached to the meat by the person receiving the meat.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>When tongues, offal and other parts of meat that are packed in containers and are not deveined, soaked, salted and rinsed in a manner which would make them Kosher prior to shipping, said parts of meat shall be packed in containers that are sufficiently perforated to permit the free flow of water to reach all sides of said tongues, offal and other parts of meat packed therein and to enable the water to freely flow out again.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>When calves are shipped unflayed and part of the skin is detached from the meat, the water shall also reach every portion of the meat under the detached skin.</section><section prefix='(v)'>All marks of Kosher identification shall be removed by the owner or consignee from meat which has not been properly washed immediately after the time of washing has expired provided, however, that liver shall be excepted from the requirements of this paragraph. All marks of Kosher identification shall be removed by the owner or consignee from meat on which the date and time of day (A.M. or P.M.) of each washing has not been properly indicated and incisions of Kosher marks of identification impressed on the meat shall be removed by the owner or consignee by blotting out or obliterating such marks of identification.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Exterior sign requirements are as follows:<section prefix='(i)'>Any restaurant, hotel, store, food cart, catering facility or any other place as is described in (a) above shall display in a prominent place in its front window or pedestrian entrance area the following sign which shall be printed in block letters at least four (4) inches in height:<section>"KOSHER AND NON-KOSHER FOOD PRODUCTS SOLD HERE."</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>