<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='3'>ARTICLE XII. FAIR CREDIT DISCLOSURE AND REPORTING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-274</section_number>
<catch_line>Provisions as to liability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001721</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-274. Provisions as to liability.<section>No consumer may bring any action or proceeding in the nature of defamation, invasion of privacy, or negligence with respect to the reporting of information against any consumer reporting agency, any user of information, or any person who furnishes information to a consumer reporting agency based on information disclosed pursuant to ordinance except as to false information furnished with malice or willful intent to injure such consumer, and then only to the same extent and under the same circumstances as provided for by, U.S.C., Section 1681n and Section 1681o, which are incorporated herein by reference, to wit:<section>"Civil liability for willful noncompliance.</section><section>Any consumer reporting agency or user of information which willfully fails to comply with any requirement imposed under this subchapter with respect to any consumer is liable to that consumer in an amount equal to the sum of—<section prefix='(1)'>any actual damages sustained by the consumer as a result of the failure;</section><section prefix='(2)'>such amount of punitive damages as the court may allow; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>in the case of any successful action to enforce any liability under this section, the costs of the action together with reasonable attorney's fees as determined by the court.</section></section><section>"Civil liability for negligent noncompliance.</section><section>Any consumer reporting agency or user of information which is negligent in failing to comply with any requirement imposed under this subchapter with respect to any consumer is liable to that consumer in an amount equal to the sum of—<section prefix='(1)'>any actual damages sustained by the consumer as a result of the failure;</section><section prefix='(2)'>in the case of any successful action to enforce any liability under this section, the costs of the action together with reasonable attorney's fees as determined by the court."</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 75-51, § 4, 7-2-75)</history></law>