<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-270</section_number>
<catch_line>Applicability; conflict; municipalities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001716</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-270. Applicability; conflict; municipalities.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this article shall apply in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and shall be deemed supplemental to all County and Municipal ordinances.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event of a conflict between the provisions of this article and the provisions of any County or municipal ordinance, the provision which establishes the more stringent requirement shall prevail.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The provisions of this article shall not apply within any municipality which files with both the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners and the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division certified copies of a resolution of the governing body of such municipality which notifies the Board of County Commissioners and the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division that the municipality exercises thereby its option to exempt the municipality from the provisions of this article, provided, however, such certified copies are filed as set forth above no later than sixty (60) days from the date of enactment of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>