<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='3'>ARTICLE XIA. REPRESENTATIONS CONCERNING AND REQUIREMENTS FOR THE SALE OF KOSHER PRODUCTS; INSPECTION OF KOSHER MEAT DEALERS, KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS, AND DEALERS IN KOSHER FOODS AND FOOD PRODUCTS; RECORDS REQUIRED TO BE MAINTAINED BY KOSHER MEAT DEALERS AND KOSHER POULTRY DEALERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-261</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001707</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-261. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>The following words and terms when used in this article shall have the following meanings, unless the context indicates otherwise:<section prefix='(1)'>Advertises, represents or holds itself out shall mean engaging in any kind of promotional activities including but not limited to posters, newspaper, radio and television advertising and distribution of fliers.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Kosher shall mean a food product intended for human consumption which is prepared and maintained in strict compliance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Kosher brand shall mean a mark of a type approved by the United States Department of Agriculture.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Kosher for Passover shall mean a Kosher food or food product which is prepared and maintained in strict compliance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch with respect to the Jewish holiday of Passover.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Kosher-style, Kosher-type, Jewish, Hebrew or other similar words shall mean a non-Kosher food or food product which has not been prepared or maintained in strict compliance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch, but rather has either been prepared in such a way as to stimulate the taste, appearance or consistency of a Kosher food or food product or has originally been prepared in accordance with the above religious requirements but has not been maintained in the proper manner in order to remain Kosher.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Pareve shall mean a Kosher food or food product which is prepared and maintained in strict compliance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch and which is neither a meat nor a dairy product or by-product.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Person shall mean an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two (2) or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity. When used in this article "person" shall include, in addition to all retail establishments, all dealers in Kosher meat, poultry, food or food products, Miami-Dade County-based manufacturers, wholesalers, processors, slaughterhouses and all others along the chain from the time the product is manufactured or, in the case of meat or poultry from the time of the slaughter, to the time of its sale, and who hold themselves out as Kosher or dealing in Kosher meat, poultry, food or food products.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Plumba shall mean the tin seal commonly used in the Kosher food industry with the word "Kosher" indicated thereon either in English or Hebrew letters, and with certain letters, figures or emblems indicated thereon which will positively identify such seal with the particular slaughterhouse where the animal was slaughtered or processed.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Properly sealed packages shall mean those packages placed on or around the Kosher meat, Kosher poultry, or Kosher food or food product by the processor or manufacturer.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Tag shall mean a tag in any form bearing the name and address of the slaughterhouse where the animal was slaughtered, the name of the person who sanctioned the Kosher slaughtering of meat or poultry at the slaughterhouse named and the date of the slaughter.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Dealer in Kosher food or food products shall mean any store, restaurant, hotel, food cart, catering facility or any other place where foods or food products are sold or offered for sale or served as Kosher or as having been prepared according to or with a product sanctioned by the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Kosher meat dealer or Kosher poultry dealer shall mean any person engaged in the slaughtering or wholesaling of properly identified Kosher meat or properly identified Kosher poultry, as the case may be, or who purchases, obtains or receives properly identified Kosher meat or properly identified Kosher poultry, as the case may be, from slaughterhouses, wholesalers or other sources and who cuts, slices, carves, breaks down or divides such Kosher meat or such Kosher poultry into smaller quantities or portions intended for sale to a customer as Kosher meat or Kosher poultry, as the case may be. Places of business performing the aforesaid operations include, but are not limited to: Caterers, hotels, summer camps, butcher shops, delicatessens, supermarkets, grocery stores, freezer dealers and food plan companies. Such places of business may also purchase, sell, handle, package and process non-Kosher meat, non-Kosher poultry, and other Kosher and non-Kosher food products.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Non-Kosher meat or non-Kosher poultry shall mean meat or poultry, as the case may be, which is obtained from animals which are not approved or which are not slaughtered in strict compliance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch, and which does not have affixed thereto the Kosher plumba or Kosher tag placed on such Kosher meat or such Kosher poultry, as the case may be, at the slaughterhouse where the animal was slaughtered. Non-Kosher meat or non-Kosher poultry, also shall mean meat or poultry, as the case may be, which is obtained from animals which are approved and slaughtered in strict compliance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch but which does not have affixed thereto the Kosher plumba or Kosher tag placed on such meat or poultry, as the case may be, at the slaughterhouse where the animal was slaughtered.</section><section prefix='(14)'>Properly identified Kosher meat or properly identified Kosher poultry shall mean Kosher meat or Kosher poultry, as the case may be, which is obtained from animals which are approved and slaughtered in strict compliance with the Code of Jewish Laws as set forth in the Shulchan Aruch and which has affixed thereto the Kosher plumba or Kosher tag placed on such Kosher meat or Kosher poultry, as the case may be, at the slaughterhouse where the animal was slaughtered.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-65, ยง 1, 6-20-91)</history></law>