<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-340</section_number>
<catch_line>Director's duties, functions and powers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001757</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-340. Director's duties, functions and powers.<section>The duties, functions, powers and responsibilities of the Director shall include the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Enforce all of the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Upon receipt of complaints or upon the Director's initiative, investigate, inspect, sample, and test any matters regulated hereunder.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Institute civil actions or proceedings to enforce all the provisions of this article and subpoenae issued by the Director, including seeking mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, the imposition and recovery of civil penalties and such other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-348 of this Code. Such civil actions or proceedings may be instituted by the Director regardless of whether a cease and desist order or notice to correct the violation or other lawful order of the Director has been issued or other administrative proceeding is pending.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Prosecute through the State Attorney in the criminal courts for violations of this article.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Deny, revoke, suspend and issue registration certificates and impose conditions, limitations, and restrictions upon same in accordance with Sections 8A-327 and 8A-343 of this Code. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration certificate by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-349 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Issue subpoenae to compel the presence of any person or document or thing at any hearing, conference or proceeding authorized herein upon information or belief by the Director that a violation of any provision of this article has occurred or may occur.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Inquire into the practices, functions and policies of movers and make such recommendations to the Commission as the Director may deem necessary.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Administer oaths and certify official acts of the Director.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Investigate, upon the Director's initiative, the practices of any mover.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Apply to any judge of the circuit or county court, criminal or civil division, for the issuance of an administrative search warrant.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Conduct a program for monitoring consumer satisfaction levels in the field of moving and make such monitoring information available to the Commission and the public.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Render, in the Director's discretion, assistance and technical advice to movers.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Institute informal conferences for discussing and resolving any matter covered by this article.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Publish and disseminate information to the public concerning movers.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Submit to the Commission proposed rules, regulations, and standards to effectuate the purposes of this article. No such proposed rules, regulations, and standards shall become effective until approved by the Commission by ordinance.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Provide movers with information concerning the rules, regulations, and standards enacted during the immediate past year.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Issue cease and desist orders, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director which shall briefly set forth the general nature of the violation of this article and specify the time within which the violation shall be rectified or stopped. If an order to cease and desist or notice to correct violations or any other lawful order of the Director is not obeyed, the Director shall have the power and authority to revoke or suspend the registration certificate, if any has been issued, or deny the issuance of a registration certificate and take such other action authorized by this article. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a registration certificate by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to Section 8A-349 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later. Orders to cease and desist, notices to correct violations, and any other lawful orders of the Director hereunder may be enforced by the institution by the Director of civil actions for mandatory and prohibitory injunctions, civil penalties and other remedies and attorney's fees as set forth in Section 8A-348 of the Code of Miami-Dade County in a court of competent jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Appoint and designate, in the Director's discretion, various technical advisory panels.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-342 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this article.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Enter into a cooperative agreement with the Florida Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, subject to approval by the Board of County Commissioners, for the referral, investigation and prosecution of consumer complaints related to the intrastate transportation of household goods pursuant to Section 507.13, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(u)'>The powers of the Director enumerated in this article shall be in addition to and not a limitation of any other powers of the Director pursuant to any other provisions of this article or any other provisions of law or ordinance.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 97-69, ยง 3, 6-3-97; Ord. No. 05-52, ยง 1, 3-1-05)</history></law>