<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY REMETERING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-391</section_number>
<catch_line>Denial, suspension and revocation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001806</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-391. Denial, suspension and revocation.<section prefix='(a)'>The Director may deny, suspend, or revoke a registration issued pursuant to the provisions of this article if the Director determines that the applicant or registrant has:<section prefix='(1)'>Submitted an application that is not filed in accordance with Section 8A-382, is incomplete or untrue in whole or in part.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Violated any provision of this article.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Misrepresented or concealed a material fact on the application, renewal application or replacement application.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Aided or abetted a person who has not obtained a registration to evade or avoid the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Engages in fraudulent conduct in connection with remetering.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Violated any condition, limitation or restriction of a registration imposed by the Director.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the trade or business of remetering or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this article.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation, written assurance of compliance or any other lawful order of the Director.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding the foregoing, no denial, suspension or revocation of a registration by the Director shall be effective until the rendition by the hearing officer of the appeal, if any, of such denial, suspension or revocation pursuant to Section 8A-397 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history></law>