<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-327</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001743</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-327. Registration required.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall engage in business or advertise to engage in the business of moving or offer to move any person in this county as a mover of household goods without first obtaining a registration certificate from the Director pursuant to this article and maintaining such registration certificate as required herein.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each mover shall register every year with the Director and, where applicable, provide to the Director: its legal business and trade name, current mailing address, and current business location for each place from which the mover operates either a main or branch office; a designation of which location constitutes its principal place of business; the full names, current mailing addresses, current telephone numbers, and social security numbers or federal tax identification numbers of its owners or corporate officers and directors; the Florida registered agent of the corporation; a statement listing the names of any other corporations, entities, or trade names through which any owner or director of the registrant was known or did business as a mover within the five (5) calendar years immediately preceding the date upon which the mover is submitting the application for registration; proof of vehicle liability insurance and general liability insurance; vehicle identification numbers; motor vehicle license tag numbers; gross weight of each commercial motor vehicle; the number of employees who are currently employed; proof of workers' compensation insurance coverage, as required by Chapter 440 of the Florida Statutes, or a State certificate of exemption, or a letter from the registrant affirming that such coverage is not required by law; proof of all insurance and liability coverage required by Section 8A-329 of this Code; a printed copy of each of the documents, instruments, forms, contracts, or other materials used by the registrant when dealing with the public with respect to the shipment of household goods, including, but not limited to bills of lading, contracts and disclosure statements; and other information and items as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any mover desiring to change its registered name, business location, or registered agent shall notify the Director of such change. No registration shall be valid for any mover under any other name or at any place other than that designated in the registration unless the Director is notified in writing within thirty (30) days of the change.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Director shall require any person desiring to obtain a registration as a mover to do so on forms prescribed by the Director. Renewal of registrations may be staggered over the annual period by the Director to facilitate the workload. When obtaining a registration or renewing a registration as required by this article, each mover shall furnish to the Director a registration fee, to be established by administrative order of the County Manager. Said fee shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this article. No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Director shall issue to each registrant a registration certificate in the form and size as prescribed by the Director. Such certificate shall be prominently displayed to the public in the mover's primary place of business. The registration number appearing on the registration certificate shall appear on all advertisements, forms, and commercial motor vehicles of the mover. For the purposes of this section, any advertisement shall be defined to include any announcement, listing, display, entry or other written statement of whatever nature or kind, and specifically to include a name and address or telephone number placed under a heading, where the heading describes or encompasses any kind of work regulated under this article.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The criteria for issuance of a registration certificate by the Director shall be compliance by the applicant with all the applicable provisions of this article and submission to the Director of a completed application for registration and applicable fees. An incomplete application shall be considered to be abandoned if an applicant fails to complete his or her application within sixty days from the date that the application was filed with the Director. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application. Registration certificates may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions imposed by the Director as the Director deems necessary to protect customers and consumers, provided such conditions, limitations, and restrictions are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violation of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration certificate shall be a violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Change of ownership.<section prefix='(1)'>In the event of a change of ownership of a moving business, a new registration and payment of new registration fees shall be required. The moving business may continue to operate provided that the moving business has filed a completed application for registration with the Director and paid all applicable fees. For purposes of this subsection, "change of ownership" shall mean a change in the ownership or operators of a moving business which is either a sole proprietorship or partnership.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Corporations or other legal entities, other than sole proprietorships or partnerships, owning or operating a moving business which have a change of ten (10) percent or more of the ownership shall notify the Director of the change no later than thirty (30) days after the date of change.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, ยง 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, ยง 1, 3-1-05)</history></law>