<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-329</section_number>
<catch_line>Valid certificate of insurance for cargo legal liability valuation and insurance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001746</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-329. Valid certificate of insurance for cargo legal liability valuation and insurance.<section prefix='(a)'>The registrant shall furnish the Director with a valid certificate of insurance for cargo legal liability valuation and insurance which shall be valid for the period of registration and shall include at a minimum the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Valuation of sixty cents ($0.60) per pound per article; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Insurance for loss or damage to household goods as a result of loss or damage to any commercial motor vehicle, with the exception of loss or damage as the result of acts of God, in the amount of no less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) per shipment; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Motor vehicle combined bodily liability insurance and property damage liability insurance which shall be issued by an insurance carrier or company which is a participant in the Florida Insurance Guaranty Association and which shall be in accordance with the following:<section prefix='a.'>Fifty thousand dollars ($50,000.00) per occurrence for a commercial motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight of less than 35,000 pounds.</section><section prefix='b.'>One hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) per occurrence for a commercial motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight of 35,000 pounds or more, but less than 44,000 pounds.</section><section prefix='c.'>Three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence for a commercial motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight of 44,000 pounds or more.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The insurance carrier or company shall qualify as an insurance company authorized to transact insurance in the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Said insurance shall be kept in full force and effect by the certificate holder at all times. Failure to file evidence of such insurance with the Director, or failure to maintain the same in full force and effect, may be cause for the suspension or revocation of the registration certificate of the mover. Said insurance shall provide that the certificate holder's insurance coverage may neither expire nor be canceled prior to thirty (30) days after the Director receives written notice of said expiration or cancellation from the carrier.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94)</history></law>