<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LOCKSMITH ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-361</section_number>
<catch_line>Application for registration of locksmith business; renewal registration; and replacement registration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001778</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-361. Application for registration of locksmith business; renewal registration; and replacement registration.<section prefix='(a)'>Each application for registration, renewal registration and duplicate registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and shall be accompanied by a fee in such amount as shall be established by administrative order of the county manager. Said fee shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate county fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this article. No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Each application for registration shall contain the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>Legal business and trade name;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Current telephone number and mailing address from which the locksmith business operates a main office and, if applicable, branch office(s);</section><section prefix='(3)'>Proof of registration of fictitious name;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Proof of occupational license(s);</section><section prefix='(5)'>Federal tax identification number;</section><section prefix='(6)'>If the application for registration is by an individual, then the applicant's full name, current address, telephone number, and the full name, current address and telephone number of the individual to be actively in charge of the locksmith business for which registration is sought;</section><section prefix='(7)'>If the application for registration is by a partnership, then the full names, current addresses, and telephone numbers of all general partners, the Florida registered agent if a limited partnership, and the full name, current address and telephone number of the individual to be actively in charge of the locksmith business for which the registration is sought;</section><section prefix='(8)'>If the application for registration is by a corporation, then the full names, addresses, and phone numbers of its owners or corporate officers and directors, the federal tax identification number of the corporation, the Florida registered agent of the corporation, the date and place of incorporation, a statement listing the names of any other corporations, entities or trades names through which any owner, director or officer of the registrant was known or did business as a locksmith within five (5) calendar years preceding the date upon which the corporation is submitting the application for registration, and the full name, current address and telephone number of the individual to be actively in charge of the locksmith business for which the registration is sought;</section><section prefix='(9)'>The full name, current address and license number of all locksmiths who are currently employed with the locksmith business for which registration is sought;</section><section prefix='(10)'>The full name, current address and permit number of all apprentices in the employ of the locksmith business.</section><section prefix='(11)'>Minimum of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) in combined liability insurance;</section><section prefix='(12)'>Worker's compensation insurance as required by Chapter 440 of the Florida Statutes, a State certificate of exemption, or a letter from the registrant affirming that such coverage is not required by law;</section><section prefix='(13)'>One set of fingerprints and two (2) photographs taken by Miami-Dade Police Department for the individual applicant, for each general partner of a partnership, or for each owner, officer or director of a corporation;</section><section prefix='(14)'>List of all convictions, in any jurisdiction, whither or not adjudication has been withheld, for felonies, misdemeanors or ordinance violations (excluding traffic violations), for robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of a stolen car, breaking and entering, or any other crime related to locksmithing for the past five (5) years for the individual applicant, for each general partner of a partnership or for each owner, officer or director of a corporation;</section><section prefix='(15)'>List of all convictions, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or as a habitual violent felony offender.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Such other relevant items or information as may be required by the Director which are consistent with the provisions of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The application shall be subscribed, verified and signed by the individual applicant, all general partners of a partnership, or any authorized officer or director of the corporation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A person operating a locksmith business at more than one (1) location in Miami-Dade County, Florida shall file a single application for registration annually, which together with the other information required by this article, shall clearly indicate the location of and the individual in charge of each locksmith business location. Application fees shall be required for each locksmith business location.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Renewal of locksmith business registration.<section prefix='(1)'>Renewal of registration may be staggered by the Director to facilitate the workload.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The renewal registration application shall be accompanied by a fee as prescribed in Section 8A-361(a).</section><section prefix='(3)'>A locksmith business may continue to operate after the expiration date of the registration, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director, if the completed renewal application with applicable fees has been received by the Director on or before the expiration date. If a completed renewal application with applicable fees is filed after the expiration date, the locksmith business may operate from and after the date on which the completed application with applicable fees is received by the Director, pending approval of the renewal application by the Director. A late renewal fee in such amount as established by administrative order of the County Manager shall be required by the Director if the application for renewal registration is received by the Director after the expiration date of the registration.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A locksmith's suspended registration is subject to expiration and shall be renewed as provided in this article. Application for renewal of the registration does not entitle the locksmith to engage in locksmith work and the Director shall not issue a renewal registration until the period of suspension is terminated.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Any person who operates a locksmith business who desires to change any material aspect of the locksmith business shall provide the Director with written notice and proof of the change accompanied by the required fee, if a replacement registration is required. No registration shall be valid for any locksmith business under any other name or at any place other than that designated in the registration unless the Director is notified in writing no later than thirty (30) days after occurrence of the change.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Change of ownership.<section prefix='(1)'>In the event of a change in ownership of a locksmith business, a new registration and payment of new registration fees shall be required. The locksmith business may continue to operate provided the locksmith business has filed a completed application for registration with the Director and paid all applicable fees. For purposes of this subsection "change of ownership" shall mean a change in the ownership or operators of a locksmith business which is individually owned or a partnership.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Corporations owning or operating a locksmith business which has a change of ten (10) percent or more of the ownership of the corporation shall notify the Director of the change no later than thirty (30) days after the date of the change.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-23, ยง 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-110, ยง 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 01-03, ยง 1, 1-23-01)</history></law>