<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-330</section_number>
<catch_line>Contract for service and disclosure statement required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001747</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-330. Contract for service and disclosure statement required.<section prefix='(a)'>In any agreement for service, the mover shall prepare a written contract for service. The contract for service shall be provided by the mover to the shipper for the shipper's written authorization and signature before commencing the performance of any transportation or accessorial services.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A contract for service shall clearly and conspicuously disclose, at a minimum, the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The name and telephone number of the mover and the address of the mover at which employees of the mover are on duty during business hours.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The name of the shipper, the addresses at which the items are to be picked up and delivered, if available; and a telephone number where the shipper may be reached, if available.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The agreed pickup and delivery date, or the period of time within which pickup, delivery, or the entire move will be accomplished, if provided.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A description of the transportation and accessorial services expected to be provided during a move.</section><section prefix='(5)'>In the event that no estimate has been provided pursuant to this article, the total cost of the transportation and accessorial services to be provided.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The method of payment, subject to the provisions of Section 8A-334 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(7)'>In the event that an estimate has been provided pursuant to this article, the maximum amount required to be paid by the shipper to the mover at the time of delivery, subject to the provisions of Section 8A-332 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The name and telephone number of any other person who may authorize pickup or delivery of any items to be transported, if the shipper designates such a person in writing.</section><section prefix='(9)'>A statement regarding the mover's limitation of liability, subject to the provisions of Section 8A-336 of this Code.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A brief description of the procedures for shipper inquiry and complaint handling and a telephone number which the shipper may use to communicate with the mover, accompanied by a statement disclosing who shall pay for such calls if other than the mover.</section><section prefix='(11)'>If the cost for services provided is based on weight, a statement that the shipper has a right to observe any weighing before and after loading.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The contract for service provided by a mover to a shipper shall include the following language in bold capitalized letters of at least 12-point type:<section>PLEASE READ CAREFULLY:</section><section>THIS CONTRACT FOR SERVICE IS REQUIRED BY COUNTY LAW AND MUST INCLUDE THE TERMS AND COSTS ASSOCIATED WITH YOUR MOVE. IN ORDER FOR THE CONTRACT FOR SERVICE TO BE ACCURATE, YOU MUST DISCLOSE ALL INFORMATION RELEVANT TO THE MOVE TO THE MOVER. COUNTY LAW REQUIRES THAT A MOVER RELINQUISH POSSESSION OF YOUR GOODS AND COMPLETE YOUR MOVE UPON PAYMENT OF NO MORE THAN THE SPECIFIED MAXIMUM AMOUNT DUE AT DELIVERY.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Prior to beginning the move, the mover shall present to the shipper a copy of the Moving Consumer Bill of Rights and Disclosure Statement (Disclosure Statement) on its letterhead in the form approved and as amended by the Director. The Disclosure Statement shall be signed by the mover and shipper and shall indicate the time of each signature.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Disclosure Statement, once signed and dated by the mover and shipper, shall be incorporated in the mover's contract for services and shall bind all parties.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Failure to present the Disclosure Statement shall constitute a violation of this Section and shall be subject to civil penalties described in this Chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, ยง 1, 6-19-01)</history></law>