<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-331</section_number>
<catch_line>Estimates of moving costs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001748</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-331. Estimates of moving costs.<section prefix='(a)'>A mover shall provide to the shipper a written estimate of the costs for moving the shipper's household goods, to include all transportation and accessorial services. No mover shall charge for preparing an estimate unless, prior to preparing the estimate, the mover:<section prefix='(1)'>Clearly and conspicuously discloses in writing to the customer the amount of the charge for preparing the estimate or, if the amount cannot be determined, the complete basis upon which the charge will be calculated, and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Obtains the customer's written authorization on the written estimate to prepare an estimate.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>It is unlawful for a mover to require a shipper to waive the shipper's right to a written estimate. A shipper cannot waive the shipper's right to a written estimate.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The written estimate provided to the shipper shall, at a minimum, include the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The total cost for transportation and accessorial services to be provided.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A description of the transportation and accessorial services to be provided.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A listing of the basis for which any charges may be assessed for the transportation and accessorial services to be provided.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The following language in bold capitalized letters of at least 12-point type:<section>UNDER COUNTY LAW YOU ARE ENTITLED TO A WRITTEN ESTIMATE OF THE TOTAL COST OF YOUR MOVE AND A COPY OF THE DISCLOSURE STATEMENT. PLEASE REVIEW THESE DOCUMENTS TO MAKE SURE THEY ARE COMPLETE.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>A copy of the estimate, signed by the mover, shall be delivered to the shipper prior to performing any transportation or accessorial service and a copy shall be maintained by the mover as part of the mover's records.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Nothing in this article shall be construed to require a customer to enter into a contract for service with a mover based upon the issuance of an estimate.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The estimate and disclosure may be provided on the same form as the contract for service.</section><section prefix='(g)'>No mover shall provide an oral estimate to any customer.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Mover shall provide to the consumer, at the time of performing a moving estimate, a copy of Moving Consumer Bill of Rights and Disclosure Statement on its letterhead, in the form approved and as amended by the Director.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Failure to present the Disclosure Statement shall constitute a violation of this Section and shall be subject to civil penalties described in this Chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, ยง 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, ยง 1, 3-1-05)</history></law>