<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-326</section_number>
<catch_line>Intent and application.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001742</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-326. Intent and application.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this article shall be construed liberally to promote the following policies:<section prefix='(1)'>To establish the law governing moving practices within this county with regard to the transportation of household goods.</section><section prefix='(2)'>To address moving practices in this county in a manner that is not inconsistent with federal law and the laws of this state relating to consumer protection and moving.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The provisions of this article apply to the operations of any mover engaged in the intrastate transportation of household goods, except that this article shall not be construed to include shipments contracted by the United States, the state, or any local government or subdivision thereof. The provision of this article shall only apply to the transportation of household goods originating in Miami-Dade County and terminating in Miami-Dade County, Broward County or Palm Beach County, or originating in Broward County or Palm Beach County and terminating in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>It is the intent of this article to seek to secure the satisfaction and confidence of customers and members of the public when utilizing a mover. This article shall be effective in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes set forth herein and to protect the public. This article shall be known and cited as the "Miami-Dade County Moving Ordinance."</section><section prefix='(d)'>Nothing in this article shall be construed to remove the authority or jurisdiction of any state or local agency with respect to goods or services regulated or controlled under other provisions of law or ordinance.</section><section prefix='(e)'>This article is not applicable to an act or practice required or specifically permitted by federal law or the law of this state.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The provisions of this article shall be deemed supplemental to all county and municipal ordinances. In the event of a conflict between any of the provisions of this article and any provision of any county or municipal ordinance, the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94)</history></law>