<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-339</section_number>
<catch_line>Claims.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001756</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-339. Claims.<section prefix='(a)'>No claim against a mover for damage under this article shall be denied solely because the damage was not noted at the time of delivery. If a customer files a claim for loss or damage not noted at the time of delivery, a mover remains obligated to investigate such claim.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Whenever a mover requires a signed statement acknowledging delivery or receipt of items, the statement shall include a clear and conspicuous notice that the shipper may make notations regarding the household goods as delivered, and that the shipper may file a claim with the mover for lost or damaged household goods.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A shipper shall have a period of up to sixty (60) days after the completion of delivery of the household goods to notify a mover in writing of any claim for loss, damage, or delay resulting from the performance of its contract for service.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Each claim filed against a mover shall be promptly and thoroughly investigated by the mover. If the claim cannot be satisfied within thirty (30) days, the mover shall advise the claimant of the status of the claim and the reason for the delay. A mover shall object to or satisfy a claim filed by a shipper no later than ninety (90) days after receipt of the claim.</section><section prefix='(e)'>When an asserted claim made to a mover for loss of an item or an entire shipment cannot be otherwise authenticated upon investigation, the mover may request from the shipper, and the shipper shall be required to sign, a sworn statement in writing that the household goods for which the claim is filed has not been received from any other source. If the shipper presents a false or fraudulent statement, the shipper shall be liable for damages to the mover.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94)</history></law>