<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00018' order_by='00018' level='3'>ARTICLE XV. CONVENIENCE STORE SECURITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-302</section_number>
<catch_line>Security requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001737</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-302. Security requirements.<section>Each convenience store as defined above shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Be equipped with the following security devices:<section prefix='a.'>A silent alarm that notifies local law enforcement or a private security agency that a robbery is taking place.</section><section prefix='b.'>A security camera system capable of retrieving an image to assist in the identification and apprehension of a robber.</section><section prefix='c.'>A drop safe or cash management device that provides minimum access to the facility's cash receipts.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Lighted parking lots illuminated at an intensity of two (2) footcandles per square foot with a uniformity ratio of no more than five to one (5:1) at eighteen (18) inches above the surface.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Post a conspicuous sign in the convenience store entrance which states that the cash register contains fifty dollars ($50.00) or less.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Maintain window signage so that there is a clear and unobstructed view of the cash register and transaction area.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Prohibit window tinting on the windows of the establishment if such tinting reduces exterior or interior viewing during the hours of operation to which this act is applicable.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Install height markers at the entrance of the establishment which display height measures from the floor.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Establish a cash management policy to limit the amount of available cash on hand between the hours of 9 p.m. and 6 a.m.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-124, ยง 2, 11-27-90)</history></law>