<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LOCKSMITH ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-368</section_number>
<catch_line>Apprentice locksmith permit; criteria for issuance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001786</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-368. Apprentice locksmith permit; criteria for issuance.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person unable to obtain a license as a locksmith as provided in this article who desires on-the-job training to learn to become a licensed locksmith shall apply to the Director for an apprentice locksmith permit on a form prescribed by the Director. The criteria for issuance of an apprentice locksmith permit by the Director shall be compliance by the applicant with all of the applicable requirements set forth in this article and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated thereunder, submission to the Director of a completed application for a permit and applicable fees, and meeting the requirements of Sections 8A-366(a)(4) and (5). A permit may be renewed annually or biannually upon payment of the required renewal fee and submission of a completed renewal application as prescribed by the Director. Renewal of permits may be staggered by the Director to facilitate the workload. A late renewal fee in such amount as established by administrative order of the County Manager shall be required if the application is filed with the Director after the expiration of the permit. Permits may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions necessary to protect customers provided said conditions, limitations, and restrictions are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violation of such a condition, limitation or restriction of a permit shall be a violation of this article. An apprentice locksmith shall be employed by a locksmith business which has obtained a registration and shall be required to work under the supervision of a licensed locksmith during the entire time of the apprentice locksmith's employment as an apprentice locksmith; provided, however, the apprentice locksmith shall be under direct supervision of a licensed locksmith for the initial 120 days of employment.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Upon determining that the applicant has qualified for a permit, pursuant to this article, the Director shall issue a permit card in the form and size as prescribed by the Director. Such permit card shall be prominently displayed on the individual at all times when performing locksmith work whether on or off the premises of the individual's primary place of work.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-23, ยง 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-110, ยง 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 01-03, ยง 1, 1-23-01)</history></law>