<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LOCKSMITH ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-370</section_number>
<catch_line>Denial, revocation and suspension of business registration, locksmith license or apprentice permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001788</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-370. Denial, revocation and suspension of business registration, locksmith license or apprentice permits.<section>The Director may deny, revoke, or suspend a business registration, locksmith license, or apprentice permit issued pursuant to the provisions of this article if the Director determines that the applicant has:<section prefix='(a)'>Violated any provision of this article;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Engaged in a prohibited practice as prescribed in Section 8A-369</section><section prefix='(c)'>Aided or abetted a person who has not obtained a registration, license or permit to evade or avoid provisions of this article;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Misrepresented or concealed a fact on the application, renewal application or replacement application for registration, license or permit;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Violated any condition, limitation, or restriction of a registration, license or permit imposed by the Director;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in the trade or business of locksmithing or was enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to any of the requirements of this article;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Failed to comply with the terms of a cease and desist order, notice to correct a violation, written assurance of compliance, or any other lawful order of the Director;</section><section prefix='(h)'>Was convicted of a violation of this article;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, has been found guilty, has been convicted or has obtained a withhold of adjudication within the past five (5) years, in any jurisdiction, of robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of stolen car, breaking and entering or any crime related to locksmithing.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Pled nolo contendere, pled guilty, has been found guilty, or has been convicted, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or as a habitual violent felony offender.</section></section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing, no revocation or suspension of a license, registration or permit by the Director shall be effective until the rendition of the appeal, if any, of such revocation or suspension pursuant to of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or until the time period for filing such appeal has expired, whichever is later.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-23, ยง 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 97-69, ยง 4, 6-3-97; Ord. No. 01-03, ยง 1, 1-23-01)</history></law>