<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY REMETERING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-396</section_number>
<catch_line>Attorney's fees and costs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001811</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-396. Attorney's fees and costs.<section prefix='(a)'>Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this article, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against such person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgement or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this article by the Director. Cessation of any violation of any of the provisions of this article whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or entry of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the provisions of this article, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director, for which attorney's fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth herein above.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All judicial and administrative remedies in this article are independent and cumulative.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96)</history></law>