<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY REMETERING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-386</section_number>
<catch_line>Submeters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001801</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-386. Submeters.<section prefix='(a)'>Submeter requirements are as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Use of submeter. All water resold by an Owner shall be charged for by submeter measurements. The submeter shall conform to AWWA Standards C700, C708 or C710. All submeters shall be rated for a working pressure of at least 150 psi.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Installation by Owner and/or Remeterer. Each Owner and/or Remeterer shall be responsible for providing, installing and maintaining in good working condition all submeters necessary for the measurement of water service to the Residents. A shut-off valve shall be installed on the water line on the inlet side of the submeter.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Tamper-proof seal. Each submeter must have a tamper-proof seal or device. This seal or device shall be clearly noticeable to detect if the submeter has been tampered with.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Submeter readings. Each submeter shall indicate clearly the gallons and/or ccf of water for which charge is made to the Resident.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Location of submeters. Submeters and shut-off valves used in conjunction with the submeters shall be installed in accordance with AWWA Standards, and shall be accessible for reading, testing and inspection where such activities will cause minimum interference and inconvenience to the Resident.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Submeter testing.<section prefix='(1)'>[Tested and inspected for applicable size and type submeter.] All submeters must be tested and inspected, within the time intervals recommended by the AWWA for the applicable size and type submeter, by a facility that is accredited and in compliance with AWWA Standards.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Accuracy requirements for submeters. Submeters shall be tested for accuracy of registration at flow rates and test flow quantities in accordance with the applicable AWWA Standard.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Submeter tests requested by the Resident. Each Owner shall, upon a reasonable written request from the Resident and, if the Resident so desires, in the presence of the Resident or their authorized representative, perform a test of the accuracy of the submeter. Prior to scheduling the test, the Resident shall be advised of their liability, if any, for the testing and plumbing charge pursuant to paragraph (4) below. The test shall be made during normal business hours (normally, Monday through Friday between the hours of 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m.), at a time convenient to the Resident desiring to observe the test. Submeter tests must be performed by an accredited and certified water meter testing facility.</section><section prefix='(4)'>[Test results.] Following completion of any test pursuant to paragraph (3) above, the owner shall advise the Resident in a timely manner but not to exceed sixty (60) days, in writing, of the test results. if the test results are within the AWWA Standard for the applicable water meter, the Owner may charge a reasonable testing and plumbing charge to the Resident. If the submeter's accuracy is not within the appropriate accuracy standards, no charge shall be made to the Resident for the test.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Submeter tests prior to installation. No submeter shall be placed into service unless it has been factory tested or tested by a certified testing facility to comply with AWWA Standards for accuracy. A certification of accuracy shall be required and made available to the CSD upon request. If any submeter is removed from service and replaced by another submeter for any purpose whatsoever, the CSD must be notified, in writing, of the serial number of the new submeter placed in the unit.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Submeter testing facilities and equipment.<section prefix='(1)'>Each Owner shall provide or have access to suitable measuring instruments for insuring the accuracy of shop and portable instruments used for testing submeters used in billing.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All testing equipment shall be submitted once each year to a standardizing laboratory of recognized standing, for the purpose of testing and adjustment, and shall be accurate to within twenty-five hundredths (0.25) percent of the actual quantity of water, in accordance with AWWA Standards. Owners and Remeterers who do not own testing equipment must use an AWWA accredited facility to do testing when needed and obtain from them proof that instruments used have been tested and adjusted yearly.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All shop and portable instruments used for testing submeters used in billing shall be calibrated by comparing them with a reference standard at least once each year. Test equipment shall at all times be accompanied by a certified calibration card signed by an AWWA approved facility, giving the date when it was last certified and adjusted. Records of certifications and calibrations shall be kept on file in the office of the Remeterer, Owner or the Owner's designee for no less than four (4) years.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 03-44, § 1, 3-11-03)</history></law>