<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LOCKSMITH ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-351</section_number>
<catch_line>Intent and application.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001768</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-351. Intent and application.<section prefix='(a)'>It is the intent of this article to seek to secure the satisfaction and confidence of customers and members of the public when utilizing a locksmith by regulating locksmiths and locksmith businesses. It is further the intent of this article to protect customers and the members of the public from unscrupulous locksmiths, persons purporting to be locksmiths, and persons who would use locksmiths to gain unauthorized access into residences, motor vehicles, and commercial establishments belonging to members of the public. In a time when home invasion and car theft are a common occurrence, it is the intent of this article to assure that persons possessing locksmithing tools have legitimate purposes for possessing such tools and that locksmiths use their knowledge and skills, whether knowingly or unknowingly, for only lawful business purposes. This article shall be effective in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes set forth herein and to protect the public. This article shall be known and cited as the "Miami-Dade County Locksmith Ordinance."</section><section prefix='(b)'>The provisions of this article shall be deemed supplemental to all county and municipal ordinances. In the event of a conflict between any of the provisions of this article and any provision of any county or municipal ordinance, the provision which establishes the most stringent standard shall prevail.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-23, ยง 1, 2-7-95)</history></law>