<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-332</section_number>
<catch_line>Charges in excess of written estimate; unlawful charges; refusal to relinquish goods prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001749</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-332. Charges in excess of written estimate; unlawful charges; refusal to relinquish goods prohibited.<section prefix='(a)'>A mover shall not charge more than the total amount of the written estimate unless there is a change in the requested services. If a change in the requested services results in additional cost, the mover shall prepare and execute a new contract for services consistent with such changes prior to the performance of any transportation or accessorial services.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It is unlawful for a mover to fail to relinquish to a shipper any of the shipper's household goods or to fail to timely complete all transportation and accessorial services required to be performed pursuant to the contract for service because the shipper has refused to pay for charges in excess of the amount set forth in (a) above or in excess of the total amount set forth in the contract for service as required by Section 8A-330(b)(5).</section><section prefix='(c)'>The mover shall relinquish possession of all of the shipper's household goods to the shipper and timely complete all transportation and accessorial services required to be performed pursuant to the contract for service upon payment of the total amount set forth in the contract for service as required by Section 8A-330(b)(5).</section><section prefix='(d)'>It is unlawful for a mover to charge a consumer for equipment. However, the shipper may purchase, lease or rent the equipment, if necessary, for storage purposes only at a location other than the mover's storage facility.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, ยง 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 01-108, ยง 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, ยง 1, 3-1-05)</history></law>