<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='3'>ARTICLE XVIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY REMETERING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-382</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001797</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-382. Registration required.<section prefix='(a)'>Initial and annual registrations are required of owners and Remeterers. Each application for initial registration, renewal registration and duplicate or amended registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and shall be accompanied by a fee in such amount as shall be established by Administrative Order of the County Manager. Such fees shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate County fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this article. No part of such fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.<section prefix='(1)'>Each application for registration by an Owner shall contain the following information:<section prefix='a.'>Name, address and type of property to be remetered; Owner's name, telephone number and tax identification number and/or social security number, legal business and trade name, if applicable; names and addresses of any partners, officers, other corporations, entities or trade names through which business is conducted; number of units being remetered; name, address, contact person and telephone number of Remeterer; and name, address, contact person and telephone number of management company, if applicable.</section><section prefix='b.'>Copy of sample lease or condominium agreement that states individual unit is or may be submetered.</section><section prefix='c.'>Date billing is to begin and copy of bill format that meets the requirements of Section 8A-385(a)(3)f.</section><section prefix='d.'>Copies of plumbing and electrical permits, where applicable.</section><section prefix='e.'>Specifications, as approved by AWWA Standards, of submeters and testing equipment to be used.</section><section prefix='f.'>Schedule of submeter installations pursuant to Section 8A-387(d), if applicable.</section><section prefix='g.'>Comparison report of Owner's regular water service charges from WASD and charges billed to the Residents by the Owner for the same period of time. This requirement is not necessary during initial registration.</section><section prefix='h.'>A list of all properties served in Miami-Dade County to include the property name, service address, contact person and telephone number.</section><section prefix='i.'>Other additional information and items as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Each application for registration by a Remeterer shall contain the following information:<section prefix='a.'>Company's legal business and trade name, principal or main address and telephone number, tax identification number and/or social security number, names and addresses of any other corporations, entities or trade names through which business is conducted; and names and addresses of Business Owners or Corporate Officers.</section><section prefix='b.'>Copy of occupational license permitting company to do business in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='c.'>Copy of Certificate of Competency as a registered or certified plumbing contractor from Miami-Dade County or the State of Florida, if applicable.</section><section prefix='d.'>Proof of workers' compensation insurance coverage, as required by Chapter 440 of the Florida Statutes, or a state certificate of exemption.</section><section prefix='e.'>Proof of comprehensive general liability which shall have a minimum limit of three hundred thousand dollars ($300,000.00) per occurrence combined single limit for bodily injury and property damage liability.</section><section prefix='f.'>Specifications, as approved by AWWA Standards, of submeters and testing equipment to be used.</section><section prefix='g.'>Other additional information and items as the Director shall require to enforce the provisions of this article.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Each initial application for registration by an Owner or Remeterer who has installed submeters and has been individually billing Residents for water service usage prior to the adoption of this article shall contain, in addition to the requirements in paragraphs (1) and (2) above, the following information:<section prefix='a.'>Comparison report of Owner's regular water service charges from WASD and charges billed to the Residents by the Owner for the same period of time.</section><section prefix='b.'>Copy of the signed plumbing and/or electrical permit card or other form of approval issued by the appropriate governmental agency of jurisdiction for the installed submeters.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Any change in ownership, address, telephone number, contact person or other information recorded on a registration application shall be reported to the Director, in writing, within ten (10) days of the change.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Registrations shall become effective upon the date the application is approved by the Director. Completed renewal applications must be submitted to the Miami-Dade County Consumer Services Department, by mail or in person, at least thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of the registration. An incomplete application shall be considered abandoned if an applicant fails to complete their application within sixty days from the date that the application is filed with the CSD. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 96-137, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-96; Ord. No. 03-44, § 1, 3-11-03)</history></law>