<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-327.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Decals; moving vehicle signage.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001744</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-327.1. Decals; moving vehicle signage.<section prefix='(a)'>No moving company shall engage in moving household goods without first obtaining a decal from the Director for each vehicle used by the mover for moving household goods. The Director is authorized to charge a non-refundable vehicle decal fee for each moving vehicle in an amount set forth by administrative order of the county manager. Such fees shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate County fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this section. Except for short term rental vehicles, such decal shall be affixed to the lower left corner of the front window in the vehicle at all times, upon issuance of a vehicle decal. The vehicle decal remains the property of Miami-Dade County and shall be used only under the authority of the Director. No vehicle decal may be sold, assigned or otherwise transferred. If a vehicle is destroyed or sold, the mover must remove the vehicle decal (if in existence) and surrender the remains to the Director.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Vehicle decals issued to moving companies who use short term rental vehicles must be visible in the lower left corner of the front window or affixed to a magnetic sign on the driver's side of the vehicle.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Each vehicle decal issued pursuant to this section shall be renewed annually in the same manner as original application is made, upon application to the Director evidencing continued compliance with the provisions of this section. The Director is authorized to charge a non-refundable renewal fee in an amount set forth by administrative order of the county manager. Such fees shall be effective upon approval by the Commission. All fees collected shall be deposited in a separate County fund to be utilized solely for the administration and enforcement of this section. Decals shall expire concurrent with the expiration of the moving registration certificate.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The decal for each moving vehicle shall at all times be displayed and available for inspection by any police officer or by personnel authorized by the Director to perform enforcement duties.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Each moving vehicle must clearly display signage, on the exterior of the driver and passenger sides, with letters at least three (3) inches high and in contrasting colors, the moving company's name, physical address, telephone number and moving registration certificate number. If the short term use of a rental vehicle by a moving company is necessary, at a minimum, the same information and requirements must be affixed to the vehicle through the use of magnetic signs.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-108, ยง 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, ยง 1, 3-1-05)</history></law>