<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LOCKSMITH ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-350</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001767</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-350. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Apprentice locksmith shall mean a person who desires to learn the locksmithing trade through on-the-job training under the direct supervision of a licensed locksmith and has obtained a permit from the director pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Article shall mean Article XVII of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Licensed locksmith shall mean an individual who has been an apprentice locksmith for a minimum of one (1) year and who has obtained a license from the Director.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Compensation shall mean money, fee, emolument, quid pro quo, barter, remuneration, pay, reward, indemnification or satisfaction.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Customer shall mean a person who inquires about, makes a request for or purchases locksmith goods or services from a locksmith business.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Director shall mean the Director of the Consumer Services Department or the Director's designee. This definition shall apply to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, when utilizing the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Employer shall mean a person who legally employs an individual for wages or salary, lists the individual on the employer's payroll records, and withholds and transmits all legally required deductions and contributions.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Employee shall mean an individual who legally works for an employer, is listed on the employer's payroll records, and is under the employer's direction and control. An independent contractor is not an employee pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Key shall mean a properly combinated device which is or most closely resembles the device specifically intended by a lock manufacturer to operate the corresponding lock.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Key duplication machine shall mean any device that is capable of copying or reproducing keys.</section><section prefix='(n)'>License shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for a licensed locksmith to perform locksmith work.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Locksmith shall mean any individual who for compensation, wages or salary engages in locksmith work and who has received a license under this article. This definition shall not include any person whose activities are limited to making a duplicate key from an existing key.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Locksmith business shall mean any person advertising, offering to perform or performing locksmith work for compensation, including but not limited to locksmith contractors, mobile locksmith business operators, locksmith shops and sole proprietors.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Locksmith work or locksmith services shall mean the installing, repairing, rebuilding, rekeying, repinning, recoding, servicing, adjusting, opening or modifying locks, mechanical and electronic security locking devices and peripherals, safes, vaults, safe deposit boxes and closed circuit television systems. It shall also mean originating keys for locks and the operation of mechanical or electronic security locking devices and peripherals, safes, vaults or safe deposit boxes by any means other than the means which is intended by the manufacturer.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Locksmithing tool shall mean any tool which is designed or used to open a mechanical or electronic locking device by any means other than the means which is intended by the manufacturer.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Permit shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for a person to become an apprentice locksmith by learning through on-the-job training under the supervision of a licensed locksmith.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Person shall mean any natural person, individual, public, or private corporation, trust, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, municipality, governmental agency, political subdivision, public officer, or any other entity whatsoever, or any combination of the foregoing, jointly or severally.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Registration or registration certificate shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article for the operation of a locksmith business in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Safe-opening tools shall mean any tool which is designed or used to open a safe, vault, safe deposit box, or similar object by means other than the means which is intended by the manufacturer.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-23, § 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 95-137, § 7, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 97-69, § 4, 6-3-97; Ord. No. 97-110, § 1, 7-8-97; Ord. No. 98-110, § 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 01-03, § 1, 1-23-01)</history></law>