<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XVII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY LOCKSMITH ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-366</section_number>
<catch_line>Criteria for issuance of locksmith license; issuance of locksmith license.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001784</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-366. Criteria for issuance of locksmith license; issuance of locksmith license.<section prefix='(a)'>The criteria for issuance of a license by the Director shall be:<section prefix='(1)'>Compliance by the applicant with all the applicable provisions of this article and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated thereunder;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Timely submission to the Director of a completed application and applicable fees;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Absence of any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt, conviction or withhold of adjudication within the past five (5) years, in any jurisdiction, of a felony, misdemeanor or ordinance violation for robbery, burglary, larceny, theft, possession of stolen goods, possession of stolen car, breaking and entering, or any crime relating to locksmithing. Effective with applications submitted on or after October 1, 2000, any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt or withhold of adjudication shall only be considered if the applicant files an application for the first time or has not filed timely and successive renewal applications.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Absence of any plea of nolo contendere, plea of guilt, finding of guilt, or conviction, in any jurisdiction, whether or not adjudication has been withheld, of any felony involving moral turpitude relating to sex, the use of a deadly weapon, homicide, violence against a law enforcement officer, or as a habitual violent felony offender.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Incomplete applications shall be considered to be abandoned if an applicant fails to complete his or her application within sixty days from the date that the application was filed with the Consumer Services Department. An application submitted subsequent to the abandonment of a former application shall be treated as a new application. Licenses may be issued by the Director subject to such conditions, limitations, and restrictions necessary to protect customers, provided said conditions, restrictions and limitations are consistent with the provisions of this article. Violations of such a condition, limitation, or restriction of a license shall be a violation of this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Upon determining that the applicant has qualified for a license pursuant to this article, the Director shall issue a license card in the form and size as prescribed by the Director. Such license card shall be prominently displayed on the individual at all times when performing locksmith work whether on or off the premises of the individual's primary place of work.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 95-23, ยง 1, 2-7-95; Ord. No. 98-110, ยง 1, 7-21-98; Ord. No. 01-03, ยง 1, 1-23-01)</history></law>