<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='3'>ARTICLE XVI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MOVING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-325</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001741</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-325. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Accessorial services shall mean any service performed by a mover which results in a charge to the shipper and is incidental to the transportation service, including, but not limited to, preparation of a written inventory, packing, unpacking, or crating of articles, hoisting or lowering, waiting time, overtime loading and unloading, reweighing, disassembly or reassembly, elevator or stair carrying, boxing or servicing of appliances, and furnishing of packing or crating materials. Accessorial services include services not performed by the mover but by a third party at the request of the shipper or mover if the charges for such services are to be paid to the mover prior to or at the time of delivery.</section><section prefix='(a.5)'>Advertise shall mean to advise, announce, give notice of, publish or call attention by use of oral, written or graphic statement made in a newspaper or other publication or on radio or television, any electronic medium, or contained in any notice, handbill, sign (including signage on vehicle), flyer, catalog, or letter, or printed on or contained in any tag or label attached to or accompanying any good.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Article  shall mean Article XVII of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Commission shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Compensation shall mean money, fee, emolument, quid pro quo, barter, remuneration, pay, reward, indemnification or satisfaction.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Contract for service or bill of lading shall mean a written document prepared by the mover and approved by the shipper in writing, prior to the performance of any service, that authorizes services from a named mover and lists the services and costs associated with the transportation of household goods and accessorial services.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Customer shall mean a person who inquires about, makes a request for or enters into a contract for service.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Director shall mean the Director of the Consumer Services Department or his/her designee. This definition shall apply to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, when utilizing the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(g.5)'>Equipment shall mean those items utilized by the mover to secure, deliver, transport and/or protect the shipper's household goods. Such equipment includes, but is not limited to, dollies, hand trucks, pads, blankets, and straps.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Estimate shall mean a written statement given by the mover to the shipper which sets forth the total cost of and the basis of the charges related to a shipper's move, such as, but not limited to, transportation or accessorial services.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Household goods shall mean personal effects, or other personal property, found in a home or personal residence, or found in a storage facility owned or rented by the shipper, where the shipper is the owner or the agent of the owner of the items. This definition does not include freight or personal property moving to or from a factory or store or other place of business.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Mover shall mean any person who engages in the transportation of household goods for compensation or any person who holds himself or herself out to the general public as engaging in the transportation of household goods for compensation.</section><section prefix='(j.5)'>Packing material shall mean the container utilized by a mover to package, deliver, transport, and/or protect the shipper's household goods. If a mover charges for packing material, the mover shall only charge for such material on a per container basis. This container charge shall include the cost for each container and any wrap, tape or other materials utilized by mover to pack the container.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Person shall mean any natural person, individual, public, or private corporation, trust, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, municipality, governmental agency, political subdivision, public officer, or any other entity whatsoever, or any combination of the foregoing, jointly or severally.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Registration or registration certificate shall mean the authorization by the Director required by this article before a person is authorized to engage in business in Miami-Dade County as a mover of household goods.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Shipper shall mean any person who contracts with a mover for the transportation of household goods. This term shall include any other person whom the shipper designates in writing.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-136, § 1, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 95-137, § 6, 7-25-95; Ord. No. 97-69, § 3, 6-3-97; Ord. No. 01-108, § 1, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 05-52, § 1, 3-1-05)</history></law>