<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='3'>ARTICLE XXII. PERSONAL INJURY PROTECTION MEDICAL PROVIDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-426</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration Denial or Revocation of Registration; Grounds.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001837</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-426. Registration Denial or Revocation of Registration; Grounds.<section prefix='(a)'>The Department Director may deny or revoke a PIP Medical Provider registration upon the occurrence of one or more of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>An application contains material false information or missing information;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The PIP Medical Provider, as a clinic and/or individual, is not registered or licensed, as applicable, in accordance with state law, or has had its registration and/or license suspended or revoked by the State of Florida;</section><section prefix='(3)'>A current business tax receipt is not submitted with the application for each PIP Medical Provider;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Failure to allow an inspection for compliance with this article by a Department designee, code enforcement officer, law enforcement officer, or any other person authorized to enforce ordinance violations in Miami-Dade County at any reasonable hour;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Failure of the PIP Medical Provider to notify the Department in writing of a change in the designated physician within fifteen (15) days pursuant to Section 8A-424</section><section prefix='(6)'>Failure of the PIP Medical Provider to notify the Department in writing of any change in the registration application information within fifteen (15) days pursuant to Section 8A-424</section><section prefix='(7)'>Failure to abide by any provision of this article; or</section><section prefix='(8)'>If the payment for the application fee or registration fee is invalid or uncollectible for any reason.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-08, ยง 2, 2-21-12)</history></law>