<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='3'>ARTICLE XXII. PERSONAL INJURY PROTECTION MEDICAL PROVIDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-421</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001832</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-421. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Applicant shall mean the owner or a person or persons authorized by the owner to complete a registration application to operate as a PIP Medical Provider in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Department shall mean the Miami-Dade County Sustainability, Planning and Economic Enhancement Department or its successor department.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Operating as a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider, or Operation of a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider or Operate as a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider shall mean to conduct the affairs of or manage the operations of a Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider including, but not limited to, any one or more of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Scheduling or accepting appointment(s) for services including, but not limited to, diagnosis, treatment, and/or therapy which are billed for payment to a PIP insurance provider;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Prescribing, dispensing, or administering any medicine, medical or physical treatment, medical or physical therapy, massage treatment or therapy, or acupuncture treatment or therapy;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Accepting payments from one or more PIP Insurance providers for any of the events listed in paragraphs (1) and (2) above; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Employing or contracting with any person for compensation to work in connection with the provision of services for a PIP Medical Provider business.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Person shall mean an individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider or PIP Medical Provider shall mean any person, clinic, facility, location, or other business that provides medical or physical therapy treatment to patients or clients claiming an injury from an automobile accident and which derives:<section prefix='(1)'>Ninety (90) percent or more of the PIP Medical Provider's monthly gross income from billing PIP Insurance providers; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000.00) or more in gross income during a twelve (12) month period from the billing of PIP Insurance providers.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Personal Injury Protection Medical Provider or PIP Medical Provider shall not mean any business or a facility:<section prefix='(1)'>Licensed as a facility pursuant to Chapter 395, Florida Statutes;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where the majority of the physicians, who provide services in the facility, primarily provide surgical services for the facility;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Owned by a publicly held corporation whose shares are traded on a national exchange or on the over-the-counter market and whose total assets at the end of the corporation's most recent fiscal quarter exceeded fifty million dollars ($50,000,000.00);</section><section prefix='(4)'>Affiliated with an accredited Florida medical school for the education of physicians licensed under Chapter 458, 459, or 460 of the Florida Statutes, at which training is provided for medical, osteopathic, or chiropractic students, residents, or fellows;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Owned by a corporate entity exempt from federal taxation under U.S.C. 501(c)(3) or (4);</section><section prefix='(6)'>That perform only magnetic resonance imaging, static radiographs, computed tomography, or position emission tomography; or</section><section prefix='(7)'>Accredited by the Joint Commission as an Outpatient/Ambulatory Care clinic.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Physical Therapy shall mean any type of massage therapy provided in response to a doctor's prescription or direction.</section><section prefix='(h)'>PIP shall mean personal injury protection.</section><section prefix='(i)'>PIP Insurance shall mean personal injury protection insurance.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-08, ยง 2, 2-21-12)</history></law>