<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='3'>ARTICLE XX. PAIN MANAGEMENT CLINICS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-414</section_number>
<catch_line>Application; review.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001825</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-414. Application; review.<section prefix='(a)'>Any pain clinic operating in Miami-Dade County shall file a sworn and notarized application which shall include proof of the following:<section prefix='(1)'>That the applicant is registered with the State Department of Health as required by state law and is in good standing with the Department of Health, has not received notification of a pending investigation by the Department of Health, has not received a probable cause finding as a result of a Department of Health investigation, is not currently suspended, and has not received notice of any deficiencies from most recent Department of Health inspection;</section><section prefix='(2)'>That the pain clinic is fully owned by a duly licensed medical or osteopathic physician or group of medical or osteopathic physicians, or is licensed as a health care clinic under F.S. Ch. 400, Pt. X; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>That all physicians who own the clinic or are employed by or have a contractual relationship with the clinic: have never had a Drug Enforcement Administration number revoked; have never had a license to prescribe, dispense, or administer a controlled substance denied by any jurisdiction; and have never been convicted of or pled guilty or nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, an offense that constitutes a felony for receipt of illicit and diverted drugs, including a controlled substance listed in Schedule I, Schedule II, Schedule III, Schedule IV or Schedule V of F.S. ยง 893.03, or of any state or the United States; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Ownership in other pharmacies or pain clinics and the percentage of such ownership by any and all physicians who own the clinic seeking registration.</section><section prefix='(5)'>In addition, the application shall designate a physician who is responsible for complying with all requirements related to registration and operation of the clinic. If that physician ceases to be affiliated with the pain clinic, another physician must be so designated within ten (10) days. The designated physician must have a clear and active license under F.S. Ch. 458 (medical) or under F.S. Ch. 459 (osteopathic), an active DEA registration; and shall practice at the clinic location for which the physician has assumed responsibility.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Any and all physicians associated with the pain clinic as owners, employees, contractors and specifically the physician designated to comply with all the requirements of registration and operations of the clinic shall provide the following:<section prefix='a.'>Sworn and notarized statement that attests: the physician owns, is employed by or has a contractual relationship with the pain clinic; and when applicable, agrees and accepts the designation to comply with all the requirements of registration and operations of the clinic;</section><section prefix='b.'>A copy of the physician's driver's license or other government issued photographic identification; and</section><section prefix='c.'>A copy of the physician's active State of Florida medical license.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department may require any physician identified in subsection (a)(6) to complete an in-person interview to verify the information in the application and/or notarized statement.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Within thirty (30) days of submission, the Department shall verify the information in the application and determine whether or not the applicant meets all the criteria established in subsection (a) above.<section prefix='(1)'>If the applicant satisfies all the criteria in subsection (a), the pain clinic shall be registered within thirty (30) days of submission.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the application is deemed incomplete, the applicant shall be notified in writing of the deficiencies within thirty (30) days of submission. The applicant shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of such notice to correct the deficiencies and complete the application. Failure to respond or make the corrections within the fifteen (15) days shall be considered a withdrawal of the application. The Department shall notify the applicant of the withdrawal upon expiration of the fifteen (15) days. If the applicant corrects the deficiencies within the fifteen (15) days, the Department shall have fifteen (15) additional days to verify that the application is complete and if complete, register the pain clinic.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If the applicant does not satisfy the criteria in subsection (a), the clinic shall not be registered. The applicant shall be notified in writing of the decision to not register the pain clinic and of the reasons for not registering the clinic within thirty (30) days of submission or fifteen (15) days from the date that the applicant corrects deficiencies. The applicant shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of such notice to request a hearing in writing before the Department Director or designee. The Department Director or designee shall conduct the hearing within twenty (20) days of the date of the request for hearing. The Department Director or designee shall issue a written decision within fifteen (15) days of the hearing.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-61, ยง 2, 8-2-11)</history></law>