<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='3'>ARTICLE XXII. PERSONAL INJURY PROTECTION MEDICAL PROVIDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-423</section_number>
<catch_line>Designated Department.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001834</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-423. Designated Department.<section prefix='(a)'>The Department shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Conduct the registration process;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Establish a database of PIP Medical Providers operating in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Enforce the provisions of this article; and</section><section prefix='(4)'>Charge a reasonable application and registration fee for processing applications, enforcing this article, and maintaining the database.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department shall establish policies and procedures necessary to implement the registration process, maintain the database, enforce this article, and through an implementing order, charge reasonable application and registration fees.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Department is authorized to inspect any PIP Medical Provider for proof of registration at any reasonable hour without prior notice. However, in no event shall any inspection violate any medical records privacy requirements, including HIPPA, or involve the inspection of private or confidential medical information without appropriate authorization or permission.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Department shall provide written notice to the State of Florida of any PIP Medical Provider or any person employed or associated with a PIP Medical Provider who fails to maintain a professional and/or clinic license or registration required by state law or applicable state agency.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-08, ยง 2, 2-21-12)</history></law>