<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='3'>ARTICLE XXII. PERSONAL INJURY PROTECTION MEDICAL PROVIDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-424</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration Application and Process; Requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001835</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-424. Registration Application and Process; Requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Application Required: Any PIP Medical Provider, as defined in Section 8A-421, must complete an application available from the Department, which shall at a minimum require the applicant to provide the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>Proof of applicable professional and/or clinic license or registration required by state law, the Florida Agency for Health Care Administration, and/or the Florida Department of Health;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Designation of the physician who shall be responsible for complying with all requirements related to registration and Operation of the PIP Medical Provider. The designated physician must have a clear and active license under Chapter 458, 459, 460 or 466, Florida Statutes. If that physician ceases to be affiliated with the PIP Medical Provider, another physician must be so designated within fifteen (15) days.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A list of all persons associated with the management or Operation of the PIP Medical Provider, including persons involved with rendering medical care and/or billing PIP insurance providers, whether paid or unpaid, part-time or full-time, including all contract labor and independent contractors. This list includes, but is not limited to, all owners, operators, employees, and volunteers. For persons listed, the following additional information must be provided:<section prefix='a.'>The person's title;</section><section prefix='b.'>A copy of the person's license, if required by state law, issued by the State Department of Health or applicable agency, to engage in the practice of:<section prefix='1.'>Acupuncture pursuant to Chapter 457, Florida Statutes,</section><section prefix='2.'>Medicine pursuant to Chapter 458, Florida Statutes,</section><section prefix='3.'>Osteopathic Medicine pursuant to Chapter 459, Florida Statutes,</section><section prefix='4.'>Chiropractic Medicine pursuant to Chapter 460, Florida Statutes,</section><section prefix='5.'>Dentistry pursuant to Chapter 466, Florida Statutes,</section><section prefix='6.'>Massage Therapy pursuant to Chapter 480, Florida Statutes, or</section><section prefix='7.'>Physical Therapy pursuant to Chapter 486, Florida Statutes;</section></section><section prefix='c.'>The person's current home address, telephone number, and date of birth;</section><section prefix='d.'>A list of all criminal convictions, guilty pleas, or nolo contendere, whether misdemeanor or felony for that person;</section><section prefix='e.'>A copy of a current Florida driver's license or a current government issued photo identification card issued to that person; and</section><section prefix='f.'>If that person is an owner, the percentage of ownership for each owner or shareholder.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>The property owner's name, address, and telephone number;</section><section prefix='(5)'>A copy of a current business tax receipt required pursuant to Chapter 205, Florida Statutes;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Whether the PIP Medical Provider dispenses controlled substances;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any other reasonable information the Department Director deems necessary; and</section><section prefix='(8)'>A sworn and notarized statement from both the designated physician and the PIP Medical Provider business owner(s) attesting to the veracity and accuracy of the information provided in the application. The Department may require the designated physician and the PIP Medical Provider business owner(s) to complete an in-person interview to verify the information in the application and/or notarized statement.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Application Process: Within thirty (30) days of submission, the Department shall verify the information in the application and determine whether or not the applicant meets all the criteria established in subsection (a) above.<section prefix='(1)'>If the applicant satisfies all the criteria in subsection (a), the PIP Medical Provider shall be registered.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the application is deemed incomplete, the applicant shall be notified in writing of the deficiencies within thirty (30) days of submission. The applicant shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of such notice to correct the deficiencies and complete the application. Failure to respond or make the corrections within the fifteen (15) days shall be considered a withdrawal of the application. The Department shall notify the applicant of the withdrawal upon expiration of the fifteen (15) days. If the applicant corrects the deficiencies within the fifteen (15) days, the Department shall have fifteen (15) additional days to verify that the application is complete and, if complete, register the PIP Medical Provider.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If the applicant does not satisfy the criteria in subsection (a), the PIP Medical Provider shall not be registered. The applicant shall be notified in writing of the decision to not register the PIP Medical Provider, including the reasons for denying registration, within thirty (30) days of submission of a new or renewal application or fifteen (15) days from the date that the applicant corrects deficiencies. The applicant shall have fifteen (15) days from the date of such notice to request a hearing in writing before a Hearing Officer pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The request for a hearing shall be filed with the Department. The Department Director or any PIP Medical Provider regulated by this article who is aggrieved by any decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal a final order of the Hearing Officer by filing a notice of appeal in the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, in accordance with the procedures and within the time provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure for review of administrative action.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Failure of the Department to meet any of the time requirements set forth herein shall not constitute an automatic registration of the PIP Medical Provider.</section><section prefix='(d)'>In the event that any information provided in the application changes, the designated physician and the PIP Medical Provider business owner(s) must file a notarized statement providing the updated information with the Department within fifteen (15) days of the change.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 12-08, ยง 2, 2-21-12)</history></law>