<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Disclosure requirements for retail shutter sales.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001438</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-6. Disclosure requirements for retail shutter sales.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be an unlawful business activity and a deceptive trade practice for any vendor, contractor, material supplier, individual, business association, corporation or firm to sell or offer for sale at retail shutters without making the disclosure required in this section. For purposes of this section, shutters shall mean shutters intended to protect the exterior windows and other openings of a structure in the event of a hurricane or other storm, and which have not been approved by the Office of Building Code Compliance of Miami-Dade County as having complied with the wind load tests enacted pursuant to Ordinance 93-14, as amended, and impact tests enacted pursuant to Ordinance Number 93-141, as amended.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any and all establishments where shutters are sold or offered for sale at retail shall publicly and continuously display and maintain on the premises of such establishment, within one hundred (100) feet of the area where the shutters are being sold or offered for sale at retail, a clear and legible sign stating:<section>CERTAIN LAWS HAVE BEEN ENACTED SUBJECTING SHUTTERS TO IMPACT AND WIND LOAD REQUIREMENTS. THESE LAWS BECOME EFFECTIVE ON SEPTEMBER 1, 1994. SOME OR ALL OF THE SHUTTERS OFFERED FOR SALE AND WHICH YOU MAY BE PURCHASING MAY NOT SATISFY THOSE REQUIREMENTS. THE INSTALLATION OF SHUTTERS REQUIRES A PERMIT FROM YOUR BUILDING DEPARTMENT. IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS CONTACT YOUR BUILDING DEPARTMENT.</section><section>SE HAN PROMULGADO CIERTAS LEYES SOMETIENDO A LAS CONTRAVENTANAS (SHUTTERS) A REQUERIMIENTOS DE IMPACTO Y DE VELOCIDAD DE VIENTO QUE ENTRARAN EN VIGOR EL PRIMERO DE SEPTIEMBRE DE 1994. ES POSIBLE QUE ALGUNAS O TODAS LAS CONTRAVENTANAS QUE ESTEN A LA VENTA Y QUE USTED DESEE COMPRAR NO SATISFAGAN ESTOS REQUERIMIENTOS. LA INSTALACION DE CONTRAVENTANAS REQUIERE UN PERMISO DE SU DEPARTAMENTO DE CONSTRUCCION. SI TIENE ALGUNA PREGUNTA, POR FAVOR COMUNIQUESE CON SU DEPARTAMENTO DE CONSTRUCCION.</section><section>GEN SETEN LWA KI PASE KI MANDE KE YO TESTE TOUT PARAVAN KONT CHOK AK KONT GWO FOS VAN. LWA SA-YO AP EFEKTIV A PATI LER SEPTAM 1994. GEN SETEN PARAVAN OUSNON TOUT PARAVAN KI DISPONIB SOU MACHE-A KE OU TA VLE ACHETE KAPAB PA REPONN A EKZIJANS LWA-SA YO. TOUT INSTALAYSON PARAVAN EKZIJE YOUN PEMI DEPATMAN KI OKIPE AFE KONSTRIKSYON. SI OU GEN YOUN KESYON SOU ZAFE-SA-A, KONTAKTE BIWO DEPATMAN-AN KI NAN ZON LAKAY-OU.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Any proposed contract for the retail sale of a shutter shall contain or be accompanied by a disclosure document which contains the disclosure language set forth in subsection (b) above.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Shutters which have not met the impact and wind load tests shall be separately identified as not having satisfied those tests by a sign displayed prominently and continuously within one hundred (100) feet of the area where being sold and offered for sale at retail. Such sign shall also identify which products offered for sale, if any, have satisfied the impact and wind load tests. Any product sold which satisfies the impact and wind load tests shall be accompanied by a copy of the letter of acceptance from the Office of Building Code Compliance certifying the product's compliance.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The County Manager or his designee may institute a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction to seek injunctive relief to enforce compliance with this section. The court may award to Miami-Dade County reasonable costs for investigation, enforcement, and attorneys' fees in any civil action authorized herein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-81, ยง 1, 5-5-94; Ord. No. 94-102, ยง 1, 5-17-94; Ord. No. 94-145, ยง 1, 7-14-94)</history></law>