<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-8.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001442</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-8.2. Definitions.<section>For the purpose of Sections—8A-8.4, the following definitions shall apply:<section prefix='(a)'>Business means any sole proprietorship, joint venture, corporation or other business formed for profit making or non-profit purposes in both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, including retail establishments where goods or services are sold.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Characterizing flavor means a distinguishable taste or aroma, other than the taste or aroma of tobacco, menthol, mint or wintergreen, imparted either prior to or during consumption of a tobacco product or component part thereof, including, but not limited to, tastes or aromas relating to any fruit, chocolate, vanilla, honey, candy, cocoa, dessert, alcoholic beverage, herb or spice; provided, however, that no tobacco product shall be determined to have a characterizing flavor solely because of the use of additives or flavorings or the provision of ingredient information.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Component part means any element of a tobacco product, including, but not limited to, the tobacco, filter and paper, but not including any constituent.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Constituent means any ingredient, substance, chemical or compound, other than tobacco, water or reconstituted tobacco sheet that is added by the manufacturer to a tobacco product during the processing, manufacture or packing of the tobacco product. Such term shall include a smoke constituent.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Flavored tobacco product means any tobacco product or any component part thereof that contains a constituent that imparts a characterizing flavor. A public statement or claim made or disseminated by the manufacturer of a tobacco product, or by any person authorized or permitted by the manufacturer to make or disseminate public statements concerning such tobacco product, that such tobacco product has or produces a characterizing flavor shall constitute presumptive evidence that the tobacco product is a flavored tobacco product.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Person means any individual, partnership, cooperative association, private corporation, personal representative, receiver, trustee, assignee, or other legal entity.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Self-service merchandising means the open display of tobacco products to which the public has access without the intervention of the vendors, store owner, or other store employee.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Smoke constituent means any chemical or chemical compound in mainstream or sidestream tobacco smoke that either transfers from any component of the tobacco product to the smoke or that is formed by the combustion or heating of tobacco, additives or other component of the tobacco product.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Tobacco products means any substance which contains tobacco, including, but not limited to, cigars, chewing tobacco, pellets, film strips, twisted sticks, other forms designed to look like candy, loose tobacco leaves, and products made from tobacco leaves, in whole or in part, and cigarette wrappers, which can be used for smoking, sniffing, or chewing.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Tobacco retailer means any person or business that operates a store, stand, booth, concession, or other place at which sales of tobacco products are made to purchasers for consumption or use.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Vendor-assisted means the customer has no access to tobacco produces without the assistance of the vendor, store owner, or other store employee.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 02-20, § 1, 1-29-02; Ord. No. 13-07, § 1, 1-23-13)</history></law>