<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE IA. JUNK DEALERS AND SCRAP METAL PROCESSORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-9.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001446</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-9.1. Definitions.<section>In construing this section, unless the context requires otherwise, the following words or phrases shall mean:<section prefix='(a)'>Ferrous metals means any metals containing significant quantities of iron or steel.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Fixed location means any site occupied by a secondary metals recycler as owner of the site or as lessee of the site under a lease or other rental agreement providing for occupation of the site by the secondary metals recycler for a total duration of not less than 364 days.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Junk means old or scrap copper, brass, rags, batteries, paper, trash, rubber, debris, waste, junked, dismantled or wrecked automobiles or parts thereof, iron, steel, and other scrap ferrous or nonferrous material.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Junk dealer means any person who is not a traveling junk dealer within the purview of Section 8A-204 or 8A-237.1 and is engaged in the business of maintaining and operating a junkyard and includes a secondary metals recycler as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Junkyard means an establishment or place of business which is maintained, operated, or used for storing, keeping, buying, or selling junk, or for the maintenance or operation of an automobile graveyard, and the term shall include garbage dumps and sanitary fills.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Nonferrous metals means metals not containing significant quantities of iron or steel, including, without limitation, copper, brass, aluminum, bronze, lead, zinc, nickel, and alloys thereof, excluding precious metals such as gold, silver and platinum.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Person means any individual, agency, firm, association or corporation.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Personal identification card means a valid Florida driver license, Florida identification card issued by the Department of Highway and Safety and Motor Vehicles, an equivalent form of identification issued by another state, a passport, or an employment authorization issued by the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services that contains an individual's photograph and current address.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Purchase transaction means a transaction in which a junk dealer, scrap metal processor or secondary metals recycler gives consideration for regulated metals property.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Regulated metals property means any item composed primarily of any nonferrous metals. The term shall include, without limitation, copper, brass, and bronze pipe, piping and tubing and wire which is or can be used for transmission or distribution in a utility or communications system. The term shall also include stainless steel beer kegs and manholes but shall not include aluminum beverage containers, used beverage containers, or similar beverage containers.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Restricted regulated metals property means any regulated metals property listed in Section 8A-9.4, the sale of which is restricted as provided in Section 8A-9.3</section><section prefix='(l)'>Scrap metal processing plant means an establishment or place of business maintaining and operating machinery and equipment used to process scrap iron, steel and other metals to specifications prescribed by, and for sale to, mills and foundries.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Scrap metal processor means any person maintaining and operating a scrap metal processing plant and shall include a secondary metals recycler as defined herein.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Secondary metals recycler means any person who:<section prefix='(1)'>Is engaged, from a fixed location or otherwise, in the business of gathering or obtaining ferrous or nonferrous metals that have served their original economic purpose or is in the business of performing the manufacturing process by which ferrous metals or nonferrous metals are converted into raw material products consisting of prepared grades and having an existing or potential economic value; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Has facilities for performing the manufacturing process by which ferrous metals or nonferrous metals are converted into raw material products consisting of prepared grades and having an existing or potential economic value, other than by the exclusive use of hand tools, by methods including, without limitation, processing, sorting, cutting, classifying, cleaning, baling, wrapping, shredding, shearing, or changing the physical form or chemical content thereof.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-17, ยง 4, 4-4-11; Ord. No. 13-48, ยง 1, 6-4-13)</history></law>