<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE IA. JUNK DEALERS AND SCRAP METAL PROCESSORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-9.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Recordkeeping.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001447</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-9.2. Recordkeeping.<section prefix='(a)'>Every person engaging in or operating as a junk dealer or scrap metal processor shall maintain a legible record of all purchase transactions to which such junk dealer or scrap metal processor is a party.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The following information must be maintained on a form approved by the applicable law enforcement agency for each purchase transaction:<section prefix='(1)'>The name and address of the junk dealer or scrap metal processor.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The name, initials, or other identification of the individual entering the information on the ticket.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The date and time of the transaction.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The weight, quantity, or volume, and a description of the type of regulated metals property purchased in a purchase transaction. Every scrap metal processor and junk dealer shall further identify the type of regulated metals property using the code of classifications for regulated metals property and restricted regulated metals property provided by the Miami-Dade Police Department.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The amount of consideration given in a purchase transaction for the regulated metals property.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A signed statement from the person delivering the regulated metals property stating that she or he is the rightful owner of, or is entitled to sell, the regulated metals property being sold. If the purchase involves a stainless steel beer keg, the seller must provide written documentation from the manufacturer that the seller is the owner of the stainless steel beer keg or is an employee or agent of the manufacturer.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The distinctive number from the personal identification card of the person delivering the regulated metals property to the junk dealer or scrap metal processor.</section><section prefix='(8)'>A description of the person from whom the regulated metals property were acquired, including:<section prefix='a.'>Full name, current residential address, workplace, and home and work phone numbers.</section><section prefix='b.'>Height, weight, date of birth, race, gender, hair color, and any other identifying marks.</section><section prefix='c.'>The right thumbprint, free of smudges and smears.</section><section prefix='d.'>Vehicle description to include the make, model, and tag number of the vehicle and trailer of the person selling the regulated metals property.</section><section prefix='e.'>Any other information required by the form approved by the applicable law enforcement agency.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>A photograph, videotape, or digital image of the regulated metals being sold.</section><section prefix='(10)'>A photograph, videotape, or similar likeness of the person receiving consideration in which such person's facial features are clearly visible taken at the time of the purchase transaction.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>For the purchase of articles other than regulated metals property, the purchaser shall keep a full and complete record showing from whom and when each article was purchased or acquired and to whom sold and the date of each sale.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The records required to be kept by sub-paragraphs (a), (b) and (c) and Section 538.19, Florida Statutes, shall be maintained by the purchaser on a form approved by the applicable law enforcement agency for a period of not less than five (5) years and shall at all reasonable times be subject to inspection by any local law enforcement officer commissioned in the State and the Miami-Dade Inspector General's Office. Local law enforcement shall implement a regular inspection process of secondary metal recyclers. The process shall include a report being automatically generated and sent to the Florida Department of Revenue for every violation of this ordinance and of Part II of Chapter 538 of the Florida Statutes. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall provide a report annually to the Board of County Commissioners on compliance and enforcement of this ordinance and Part II of Chapter 538 of the Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the purchase transaction involves the transfer of regulated metals property from a secondary metals recycler registered with the State to another secondary metals recycler registered with the State, the secondary metals recycler receiving the regulated metals property shall record the name and address of the secondary metals recycler from which it received the regulated metals property in lieu of the requirements of paragraph (b)(8) above.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Every junk dealer and scrap metal processor shall post notice of the prohibition of cash transactions contained in this ordinance and the prohibition of certain acts and practices contained in section 8A-9.5 herein at every junkyard, scrap metal processing plant and any other facility where a junk dealer or scrap metal processor conducts business. The notice shall be in English, Spanish and Creole.</section><section prefix='(g)'>In the event of an emergency or act of God such as a hurricane, every scrap metal processor and junk dealer shall comply with an evacuation order or any other order issued by an authorized official of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-17, ยง 4, 4-4-11; Ord. No. 13-48, ยง 1, 6-4-13)</history></law>