<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE IA. JUNK DEALERS AND SCRAP METAL PROCESSORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-9.7</section_number>
<catch_line>Penalty.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001452</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-9.7. Penalty.<section>Any person violating, or shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment in the County jail for not more than 60 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. Each violation shall be deemed a separate offense for which a separate fine shall be assessed regardless of whether two or more violations occurred in one transaction. Any person who is convicted of a second or subsequent violation of, or shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or by imprisonment in the County jail not to exceed six (6) months or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section><section>Any person who violates or fails to comply with any provision of this ordinance shall also be subject to a fine in the amount of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) in accordance with of this Code. is hereby amended to include such fine. Each item of restricted regulated metals property listed in that a scrap metal processor or junk dealer purchases in violation of this ordinance shall be deemed a separate violation for which a separate fine shall be assessed. The County, in addition to the sanctions contained herein, may take any other appropriate legal action, including, but not limited to emergency prohibitory and mandatory injunctive action, to enforce the provisions of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-17, ยง 4, 4-4-11; Ord. No. 13-48, ยง 1, 6-4-13)</history></law>