<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE IA. JUNK DEALERS AND SCRAP METAL PROCESSORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-9.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Limitation on Cash Transactions for Regulated Metals Property and Prohibitions of Cash Transactions for Restricted Regulated Metals Property.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001448</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-9.3. Limitation on Cash Transactions for Regulated Metals Property and Prohibitions of Cash Transactions for Restricted Regulated Metals Property.<section prefix='(a)'>Consideration for the purchase of regulated metals property that exceeds $1,000.00 shall be made by check issued to the seller and payable to the seller of the regulated metals property or by a voucher issued to the seller of the regulated metals property which can be used at an on-site electronic device which produces, retains and stores an accounting of all of the information required in section 8A-9.2</section><section prefix='(b)'>A junk dealer or scrap metal processor shall not enter into any cash transaction for the purchase of restricted regulated metals property listed in section 8A-9.4</section><section prefix='(c)'>Consideration for the purchase of restricted regulated metals property shall be made by check issued to the seller of the restricted regulated metals property and payable to the seller in accordance with the procedure for payment provided in section 538.235 of the Florida Statutes or by a voucher issued to the seller which can be used at an on-site electronic device which produces, retains and stores an accounting of all of the information required in Section 8A-9.2</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-17, ยง 4, 4-4-11; Ord. No. 13-48, ยง 1, 6-4-13)</history></law>