<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE IA. JUNK DEALERS AND SCRAP METAL PROCESSORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-9.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Applicability, enforcement and training.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001451</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-9.6. Applicability, enforcement and training.<section prefix='(a)'>This ordinance shall apply to and be enforced in both the incorporated areas and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. This ordinance shall not apply to purchases of regulated metals property from sellers exempt pursuant to Section 538.22, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Every junk dealer and scrap metal processor shall receive training from the Miami-Dade Police Department on the requirements of the Junk Dealers and Scrap Metal Processors Ordinance and Chapter 538 Part II of the Florida Statutes. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall issue a certificate upon completion of such training. No permit under Section 15-17 of this Code shall be issued or renewed to a junk dealer or scrap metal processor without providing a certificate of completion of training. Every junk dealer and scrap metal processor owner must receive training. Every junk dealer and scrap metal processor that owns more than one location must have at least one employee from each location receive training. Within thirty (30) days of issuance from the Department of Revenue of a temporary registration or registration renewal, every junk dealer or scrap metal processor shall schedule training with the Miami-Dade Police Department. The junk dealer and scrap metal processor must complete training no later than 60 days from the Department of Revenue's issuance of the temporary registration or registration renewal. The Miami-Dade Police Department shall charge and collect fees for training at the rates established by separate implementing order, which shall not become effective until approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 11-17, ยง 4, 4-4-11; Ord. No. 13-48, ยง 1, 6-4-13)</history></law>