<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PUBLIC RIGHTS-OF-WAY REGULATIONS FOR COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-159</section_number>
<catch_line>Location/Relocation of Facilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001961</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-159. Location/Relocation of Facilities.<section prefix='(a)'>Unless controlling law provides otherwise, a Provider's system shall be installed underground in areas where existing power or telephone facilities are underground. If both power and telephone facilities are installed above ground, the Provider shall install its facilities underground at the request of a resident or property owner when the resident or property owner agrees to pay the additional cost of such installation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Provider shall not place any fixtures or equipment where the same will interfere with any existing gas, electric, cable system, telephone, sewer, drainage, or water lines, fixtures or equipment. The Provider shall locate its lines and equipment in such a manner as not to interfere unnecessarily with the usual travel on streets; with the installation or operation of gas, electric, Cable System, telephone, water, drainage, or sewer line equipment, or with the rights of owners of property which abuts any Public Right-of-Way.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Unless controlling law provides otherwise, Providers shall relocate any above ground portion of their systems underground in any easement or right-of-way area where existing power or telephone facilities are hereafter so relocated. Any such relocation shall be at the Provider's expense, and such relocation shall be accomplished concurrently with relocation of any such power and telephone facilities.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Provider shall have the authority to trim trees upon or overhanging streets, alleys, sidewalks and public ways and places of the County so as to prevent the branches of such trees from coming in contact with the wires and cables of the Provider, in a manner approved by and acceptable to the County. When the County determines such trimming is necessary to protect the health safety and welfare of the public, such trimming may be done by it or under its supervision and direction at the expense of the Provider, if prior notification has been given to the Provider and the Provider thereafter failed to respond.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A Provider shall promptly and at the Provider's own expense protect, support, temporarily disconnect, remove, modify or relocate any part of their system when required by the County by reason of traffic conditions, public safety, road construction, change of street grade, installation of sewers, drains, water pipes, power lines, signal devices, tracks, any other type of County improvement project, or to accommodate the abandonment of any street. Such work shall be completed no later than 30 days after receiving notice from the County or such longer period as may be agreed to by the County. In the event such contingency occurs, and the Provider fails to remove or modify its system, the County may, upon notice to the Provider, make the necessary removals and charge the Provider for the cost. Nothing in this Section shall be construed to waive any rights the Provider may have under state or federal law to be reimbursed for relocation expenses.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Each Provider shall, on the request of any person holding a building moving permit issued by the County, temporarily remove, raise or lower its wires to permit the moving of buildings. The expense of such temporary removal or raising or lowering of wires shall be paid by the person requesting same, and the Provider shall have the authority to require such payment in advance. The Provider shall be given not less than seven (7) days advance notice to arrange for such temporary wire changes.</section><section prefix='(g)'>When placed underground, all service lines, drops, or laterals that connect the end user customer to the Provider's distribution system shall be buried as follows: (a) on easements and public rights-of-way at the depth as established by the Public Works manual or regulations; and (b) on private property at a sufficient depth so that no portion of the line is exposed. The County may impose a specific depth requirement for such lines on private property.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Except for relocation expenses when authorized by state or federal law, the Provider shall not be entitled to any compensation for damages from the County as a result of having to remove or relocate its property, lines and cable from such public property or public rights-of-way in the event the County determines that a necessity exists for such removal or relocation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 5, 6-19-01)</history></law>