<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-76</section_number>
<catch_line>Appeal.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001917</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-76. Appeal.<section prefix='(a)'>All civil penalties enforced pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 8CC, Code of Miami-Dade County, may be appealed as provided in that chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All decisions of the Director may be appealed to the County Manager within fifteen (15) days.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All decisions of the County Manager may be appealed within thirty (30) days by filing a written notice of appeal with the clerk of the Board of County Commissioners and providing copies to the County Manager, the Director and the County Attorney. The notice of appeal shall state the decision which is being appealed, the grounds for the appeal, a brief summary of the relief which is sought and be accompanied by a nonrefundable fee of five hundred dollars ($500.00) to be used solely to defray the cost of processing and hearing the appeal. The County Commission shall conduct a public hearing at which time they may affirm, modify or reverse the decision of the County Manager. The County Manager shall notify any party who has filed a written request for such notification of the date when the matter will be presented to the Board of County Commissioners. Nothing contained herein shall preclude the County Commission from seeking additional information prior to rendering a final decision. The decision of the County Commission shall be in writing and a copy of the decision shall be forwarded to the County Manager, the Director and the appealing party.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Within the time prescribed by the appropriate Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure, a party aggrieved by a decision of the County Commission may appeal an adverse decision to the Circuit Court in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida. The party making the appeal shall be required to pay to the Clerk of the Board the sum of five hundred dollars ($500.00) to defray the costs of preparing the record on appeal.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, ยง 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, ยง 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>