<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Communications Services Tax.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001858</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-16. Communications Services Tax.<section prefix='(a)'>Each Licensee shall collect and remit to the Florida Department of Revenue the Communications Services Tax pursuant to chapter 202, Florida Statutes and Chapter 29 Article IV-A of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Collection and remittance of the Communications Services Tax do not include the following:<section prefix='(1)'>In the case of any license granted after December 30, 1984, capital costs which are required by the license to be incurred by the cable operator for public, educational or governmental access facilities;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Requirements or charges incidental to the awarding or enforcing of the license, including payments for bonds, security funds, letters of credit, insurance, indemnification, penalties, or liquidated damages; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any fee imposed under title 17, United States Code.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event that state law is amended to allow collection of license fees from Cable Services Providers, or in the event that state law preempting the collection of such license fee is declare void by a court of competent jurisdiction, the license fee provisions contained in this section shall automatically revert to those provisions contained in this section in effect on the date of adoption of this chapter to the extent those provisions are not inconsistent with state law.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All municipal ordinances, franchises and licenses in conflict with this section are hereby superseded to the extent of such conflict.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Nothing in this section shall limit the licensee's liability to pay other local taxes, fees, charges, or assessments to the County and other taxing and governmental authorities.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 90-104, § 1, 9-25-90; Ord. No. 92-97, § 3, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 01-109, § 2, 6-19-01)</history></law>