<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-21</section_number>
<catch_line>Insurance; policy limits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001863</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-21. Insurance; policy limits.<section>(a) Within thirty (30) days after the effective date of the license, and prior to any operations under the license, the licensee shall provide proof of the required insurance. The licensee shall maintain said insurance throughout the term of the license and said insurance shall include, at a minimum, the following types of insurance coverage in amounts not less than shown:<section prefix='(1)'>Worker's compensation: Coverage to apply for all employees for statutory limits in compliance with the applicable State and federal laws. The policy must include employers' liability with a limit of five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000.00) each accident.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Comprehensive general liability: Shall have minimum limits of two million dollars ($2,000,000.00) per occurrence combined single limit for bodily injury liability and property damage liability. This shall include premises and/or operations, independent contractors, and subcontractors and/or completed operations, broad form property damage, XCU coverage, and a contractual liability endorsement.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Business auto policy: Shall have minimum limits of one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) per occurrence combined single limit for bodily injury liability and property damage liability. This shall include owned vehicles, hired and non-owned vehicles.</section></section><section>(b) The insurance coverage obtained by the licensee in compliance with this section shall be approved by the Risk Management Division of the General Services Administration and the County Attorney, and such insurance policies, along with written evidence of payment of required premiums, shall be filed and maintained with the Director or his designee during the term of the license.</section><section>(c) Upon thirty (30) days notice, the insurance coverage and policy requirements may be changed and increased from time to time at the discretion of the Board of County Commissioners to reflect changing liability exposure and limits.</section><section>(d) Nothing herein is intended as a limitation to the extent of any legal liability of the licensee.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>