<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-54</section_number>
<catch_line>Annual reports.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001895</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-54. Annual reports.<section>(a) In addition to the above, the licensee shall file the following information with the quarterly report due January 25th of each year:<section prefix='(1)'>A summary of the previous year's activities in the development of the system, including, but not limited to, services begun or dropped, the previous year's construction activities and a summary of any policy changes taking effect during the year.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A current copy of the subscriber service agreement, a current list of all rates, charges and available services, a current channel list, a copy of all the licensee's published rules and regulations applicable to subscribers and users of the cable system, and a summary of the licensee's hours of operation.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A summary of subscriber or consumer complaints, identifying complaints by number and category, and their disposition. Where complaints involve recurrent system problems, the nature of each problem and what steps have been taken to correct it shall be identified.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A copy of updated maps depicting the location of all trunks and areas by megahertz capacity, separately identifying those areas where there was construction in the year of the report.</section><section prefix='(5)'>For information purposes only, a listing of licensee's closings or holidays for the year.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Demonstration of compliance with Section 2-8.1.5 of the Code of Miami-Dade County with regard to nondiscrimination, and a report on the number of personnel employed by the licensee within Miami-Dade County, including gender, racial, and ethnic group classifications to include white non-Hispanics, Hispanics, black, and other categories, in accordance with Section 2-8.1(d)(iii) of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section>(b) Within four (4) months of the close of its fiscal year, the licensee shall file an annual report to the County that includes the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>A list of all persons owning or controlling five (5) percent or more of the stock, partnership shares or assets of the licensee; and a list of any parent corporation, parent entity or holding company that owns, or by ownership of other entities controls, the licensee.</section><section prefix='(2)'>If the licensee is a corporation, a list of officers and members of the board and officers and board members of any parent corporation; and where a parent corporation's stock is publicly traded, two (2) copies of its annual report.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Two (2) copies of each of the licensee's balance sheet applicable to its operations in Miami-Dade County. All reports shall be certified by an independent certified public accountant and prepared in accordance with Generally Accepted Auditing Standards (GAAS) as promulgated by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 01-109, § 2, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>