<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PUBLIC RIGHTS-OF-WAY REGULATIONS FOR COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-152</section_number>
<catch_line>Use of County Public Rights-of-Way; Construction Requirements; Alteration of the System; Access by County.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001952</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-152. Use of County Public Rights-of-Way; Construction Requirements; Alteration of the System; Access by County.<section>Subject to all applicable provisions of the County, Provider may perform all necessary work to construct, occupy and maintain its Facilities. The Provider must comply at all times with all policies, procedures and directives of the Public Works Department, the Planning and Zoning Department and the Building Department. Prior to the installation, placement or removal of any conduits, cables or pole lines, facilities, or the start of any other type of construction on the County's public rights-of-way, the Provider shall, pursuant to the requirements of existing or subsequently enacted County ordinances, obtain all permits from, and where applicable pay all fees to, the Public Works Department, the Planning and Zoning Department and the Building Department. The issuance of a permit by the County shall not be construed by the Provider as a warranty that the placement by the Provider of its conduits, cables or pole lines, facilities, or the start of construction, is in compliance with any applicable rules, regulations or laws. All construction and maintenance of the Provider's Facilities within County public rights-of-way incident to Provider's provision of service shall, regardless of who performs installation and/or construction, be and remain the responsibility of the Provider.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 5, 6-19-01)</history></law>