<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Authority of the Director.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001857</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-15. Authority of the Director.<section>(a) The Director shall have the responsibility for overseeing the day-to-day administration of this chapter and licenses granted hereunder. The Director, or any member of the Director's staff so designated by the Director, may administer oaths, certify to official acts, issue subpoenas, and compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of papers, account books, contracts, documents and other records, data or information, when necessary, convenient, or appropriate in the discharge of the duties of his office. The Director shall be empowered to take all administrative actions on behalf of the County, including adopting forms for application and reporting and other administrative procedures as are necessary, except for those actions specified in this chapter which are reserved to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>(b) The Director shall exercise jurisdiction and have the power and authority to regulate and supervise each license as defined herein in respect to service and license areas within Miami-Dade County, in accordance with the standards set by the provisions of this chapter. This jurisdiction shall be exclusive and superior to that of all other boards, agencies, commissions, political subdivisions, and municipalities in Miami-Dade County, Florida, and in case of conflict all lawful acts, orders, rules and regulations of the Director shall in each instance prevail, subject to the Constitution and general laws of the State of Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>