<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Public hearing for initial and expansion licenses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001849</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-7. Public hearing for initial and expansion licenses.<section>(a) The County Manager shall prepare a report to the Commission regarding the award of a license to the applicant, which report shall consider and respond to any comments received and shall contain the County Manager's recommendations concerning the application. The County Manager shall schedule a public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners to consider the application and the County Manager's report. Notification of any cable license hearing must be published in a paper of general circulation in the County. The notice shall name the applicant, describe the proposed license area, and set a time and date certain, The public hearing may be continued from time to time and from place to place as determined to be necessary by the Commission. The County shall make a final determination on the application within eight (8) months of the date a completed application was received unless it is determined that the applicant has caused the delay.</section><section>(b) The Commission shall consider all factors required by State or federal law, including, among other factors the applicant's character, technical, legal, and financial qualifications to construct and operate the facilities proposed; the nature of the proposed system; the economic impact on private property within the proposed license area; the capability of the public rights-of-way to accommodate the proposed system; the present and future use of the rights-of-way to be used; the potential disruption to existing users of the right-of-way; whether the proposal will meet reasonably anticipated community needs and serve the public interest; and all other factors as the County may determine to be relevant. The Commission shall approve, disapprove or take any other action it finds to be in the public interest.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>