<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-61.01</section_number>
<catch_line>Rate regulation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001903</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-61.01. Rate regulation.<section prefix='[(1)'>Jurisdiction.]<section prefix='(a)'>Dade County has jurisdiction to regulate rates in (1) the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, and (2) the incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, provided that Miami-Dade County shall have no jurisdiction to regulate rates in any municipality while that municipality is certified by the FCC to regulate rates, except where Miami-Dade County and the municipality have been certified by the FCC to regulate rates jointly. At any particular time a cable operator in a single FCC community unit shall be subject to rate regulation only by either (1) the County, (2) the municipality, or (3) the County and municipality jointly regulating rates.</section><section prefix='(b)'>This section shall not be construed to create a private cause of action.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Compliance with F.C.C. regulations. In regulating any rates as allowed by Federal law, Miami-Dade County shall be governed by and shall comply with all controlling F.C.C. regulations and Federal Statutes.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Delegation to County Manager. Subject to appeals to the County Commission, the County Manager is delegated the authority to conduct all proceedings, and issue any final or interim orders provided for in this section.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Appeals. Any decision of the County Manager may be appealed to the County Commission pursuant to the provisions of Section 8AA-76, Miami-Dade County Code. The filing of an appeal of any interim, non-final determination shall not stay the information-gathering proceedings or form a basis for the licensee to refuse to disclose information.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Further regulations. Nothing herein shall be construed to limit the right of Miami-Dade County to modify, amend, or add to these regulations in order to comply with applicable law or to protect the interests of licensees or subscribers.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 93-120, ยง 1, 11-3-93; Ord. No. 95-212, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 01-44, ยง 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>