<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-105</section_number>
<catch_line>Audits; inspection of records.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001927</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-105. Audits; inspection of records.<section>All amounts paid under shall be subject to audit and recomputation by the County. Upon reasonable notice, the Registrant shall make available to the County once per year, during normal business hours and at the Registrant's local office, the books, records and accounts and other documentation of the Registrant (hereinafter collectively referred to as the "Reports") that are necessary to determine the accuracy of the calculations upon which the license fee payment is based. The Registrant shall maintain its records in such a manner as to clearly distinguish between linear foot calculations derived from operations in unincorporated Miami-Dade County and such linear foot calculations derived from operations in the municipalities and other jurisdictions. Miami-Dade County may waive this requirement with any particular Registrant if an agreement is reached that other methods will be utilized such as audit sampling techniques which can clearly isolate revenues and/or linear foot calculations to which the County is entitled. In the event the Reports are not made available within Miami-Dade County, the Registrant shall reimburse the County for the reasonable travel expense of the County's representative resulting from said representative's travel to the location where the Reports are maintained. The County shall maintain all books, records, accounts and other documentation of Registrant in strictest confidence to the extent allowed under the Public Records Act and other applicable Florida laws.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-167, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 4, 6-19-01)</history></law>