<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-4</section_number>
<catch_line>License application procedure; information required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001846</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-4. License application procedure; information required.<section>(A) All applications to construct, operate, or maintain any cable system in the unincorporated or incorporated areas or to traverse any portion of those areas for the transmitting or conveying of such service elsewhere, shall be filed with the Director. An application for the grant of an initial license may be filed pursuant to a request for proposals issued by the County or on an unsolicited basis. To be acceptable for filing, an original and two (2) copies of the application must be submitted and be accompanied by the application filing fee where required.</section><section>(B) Each application for an initial license shall set forth the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The name, address and telephone number of the applicant.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A detailed statement of the corporate or other business organization of the applicant, including but not limited to the following:<section prefix='(a)'>The names, business addresses, and state of residence of all general partners and corporate officers of the applicant.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The names, business addresses, and state of residence of all persons owning or controlling five (5) percent or more of the stock, partnership shares, or assets of the applicant and the respective ownership share of each such person.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The names and addresses of any parent corporation, parent entity, or holding company that owns or, by ownership of other entities, controls the applicant.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The names and addresses of any business entities owned or controlled by the applicant, including, but not limited to, SMATV or cable operations.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A detailed and complete financial statement of the applicant, prepared by a certified public accountant, for the five (5) fiscal years immediately preceding the date of the application, or a letter or other acceptable evidence in writing from a responsible lending institution or funding source, addressed to both the applicant and the County, setting forth a clear statement of its intent to provide the capital required to construct and operate the proposed system. If the corporate or business entity organization of the applicant has not been in existence for a full five (5) years, applicant shall submit a certified financial statement for the period of its existence.</section><section prefix='(f)'>A detailed description of all previous experience of the applicant in providing cable services or related or similar services which includes a statement identifying, by place and date, all other cable television licenses or franchises awarded to the applicant, its parent or subsidiary; the status of the licenses or franchises with respect to completion; the total cost of completion of such systems; and the amount of applicant's and its parent's or subsidiary's resources committed to such systems.</section><section prefix='(g)'>An indication of whether the applicant, or any person controlling the applicant, or any officer or major stockholder of the applicant, has been adjudged bankrupt, had a cable license or franchise revoked, or been found guilty by any court or administrative agency of a violation of a security or antitrust law, felony, or any crime involving moral turpitude; and, if so, identification of any such person and a full explanation of the circumstances.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>A detailed financial plan describing for the first five (5) years of the license, projected number of subscribers, rates, all revenues, operating expenses, capital expenditures, depreciation schedules, income statements, and statement of sources and uses of funds and schedule of all capital additions.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A detailed description of the proposed plan of operation of the applicant, which shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix='(a)'>A detailed map indicating all areas proposed to be served, a proposed time schedule for the installation of all equipment necessary to become operational throughout the entire area to be served, a description of the construction of the proposed system including an estimate of the above and below ground mileage and the projected total cost for construction of the system.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For informational purposes, a statement or schedule setting forth all proposed initial classifications of rates and charges to be made against subscribers and all rates and charges for each classification, including installation charges, service charges, or other charges. The purchase price, terms, and nature of any optional or required equipment, device, or other thing to be offered for sale to any subscriber shall be described and explained in detail.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A detailed statement describing the physical facility proposed, including channel capacity, technical design, the actual equipment, and the operational and technical standards proposed by the applicant.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A description of the services to be provided initially, including the broad categories of programming and all broadcast and non-broadcast signals to be carried and all non-television services to be delivered over the cable system, and if services will be offered by tiers, identification of the signals and/or services to be included on each tier.</section><section prefix='(e)'>A description of how the proposed system will reasonably meet the future cable-related needs and interests of the community, including how the proposed system will meet the needs described in any recent community needs assessment conducted by or for the County.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any other information as requested in order for the County to comply with State or federal law.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>A copy of the form of any agreement, understanding, or other instrument proposed to be entered into between the applicant and any subscriber.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A copy of any agreement covering the license area, if existing, between the applicant and any public utility providing for the use of any facilities of the public utility, including but not limited to poles, lines or conduits.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Copies of all reports filed with the FCC within the last twelve (12) months by the applicant or its parent relating to cable operations, including but not limited to the last and most current FCC Form 325.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Any other reasonable information which could materially affect the granting of the license and which is requested by the County.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The County at its discretion may decide to accept less than the documentation above if it can establish through other sources that the applicant can meet the technical, financial, legal, and character to establish that the applicant is competent to operate a cable system.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>