<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. PUBLIC RIGHTS-OF-WAY REGULATIONS FOR COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-160</section_number>
<catch_line>Work in the right-of-way.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001962</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-160. Work in the right-of-way.<section prefix='(a)'>The Provider must obtain any required permits before causing any damage or disturbance to public rights-of-way, easements or thoroughfares as a result of its construction or operations and must restore to their former condition such property in a manner approved by the County. If such restoration is not satisfactorily performed within a reasonable time, the County, after prior notice to the Provider, may cause the repairs to be made at the expense of the Provider. All additional or reoccurring repairs required as a result of the Provider's work may also be made at the expense of the Provider.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Providers granted Permits to Place or Maintain Facilities in the Public Rights-of-Way or utility easements shall provide at least seven (7) days' prior written notice to the residents of an area that Provider's construction or maintenance crews will be working in the area by mail and/or through the placement of notices on the front door knobs of the residents in the area, with such notices providing the provider's name and telephone number. Such notice shall be provided to residents whose property is directly affected, or adjacent to, the Public rights-of-way or utility easement impacted by the Provider's construction or maintenance. Such notice will inform customers that construction will take place and contain the anticipated duration, a brief and accurate statement of Provider's property and rights-of-way restoration obligations, name of contractor, if any, and list the telephone number of the Consumer Services Department if residents have complaints regarding construction, maintenance and/or restoration. The Director shall promulgate a model notice form. Use of that form, while not required, will constitute per se compliance with this notice requirement. The notice requirement in this Section shall not apply to service drops or emergency maintenance which is defined for purposes of this Section to mean repairs necessary to restore service or system performance as a result of an incident outside of the provider's control.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All vehicles utilized by Providers and subcontractors working for Providers in the construction, installation or maintenance of the Provider's system shall be clearly marked, providing the licensee's name and telephone number, and, if applicable, the CC# as required by Section 10-4 of the Miami-Dade County Code. Subcontractors working for multiple Providers may place magnetic signage on their vehicle(s) to meet the requirements of this subsection; provided, however, this provision does not affect the subcontractors Section 10-4 requirements. All personnel employed or subcontracted by Providers in the construction of the Provider's system shall possess identification providing the employee's name and the provider's name and telephone numbers.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Providers shall join and maintain a continuous membership in Sunshine State One Call of Florida, Inc. or other bona fide underground notification program accepted by Miami-Dade County and use its services prior to construction or maintenance. Only certified contractors may be utilized for the construction or maintenance.</section><section prefix='(e)'>All new pedestals, amplifiers and power supplies installed or worked on by the Provider shall be marked with the name of the Provider. The Provider will make all reasonable efforts to ensure that all existing pedestals, amplifiers and power supplies shall be marked during the normal course of business.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 5, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 03-122, ยง 3, 5-6-03)</history></law>