<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-69</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement; settlement authority, notice and cure provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001911</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-69. Enforcement; settlement authority, notice and cure provisions.<section>(a) Provisions of this chapter listed in of the Code of Miami-Dade County will be enforced pursuant to that chapter. The County Manager or his designee is hereby authorized to resolve by settlement any notice of violation of this chapter issued pursuant to. In deciding to settle a dispute over an alleged violation, the County shall consider: (1) the probability of success in proving the violation; (2) the nature and seriousness of the violation; (3) the licensee's past history concerning similar violations; (4) mitigating factors; and (5) the licensee's success in resolving this dispute with affected subscribers.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Prior to issuing a notice of violation pursuant to Chapter 8CC, the County will provide the licensee with notice and opportunity to cure. The notice shall state the Code section alleged to be violated, factual basis of the violation, the amount of the civil penalty, and the time period allowed to cure the violation without incurring a civil penalty. These notice and cure provisions will apply only to the subsections (1), (2) and (3) listed below.<section prefix='(1)'>Licensee shall have a notice and opportunity to cure time period of no less than forty-eight (48) hours for violations of the following provisions:</section><section prefix='(2)'>Licensee shall have a notice and opportunity to cure time period of no less than thirty (30) days from violations of the following provisions:</section><section prefix='(3)'>Licensee shall have a notice and opportunity to cure time period of no less than sixty (60) days for violations of the following provisions:</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 92-97, § 11, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>