<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-100</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001921</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-100. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Communications Facility or Facility or System shall mean any permanent or temporary plant, equipment and property, including but not limited to cables, wires, conduits, ducts, fiber optics, poles, antennae, converters, splice boxes, cabinets, hand holes, manholes, vaults, drains, surface location markers, appurtenances, and other equipment or pathway placed or maintained or to be placed or maintained in the Public Rights-of-Way of the County and used or capable of being used to transmit, convey, route, receive, distribute, provide or offer Communications Services.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Communications Services shall mean the transmission, conveyance or routing of voice, data, audio, video, or any other information or signals to a point, or between or among points, by or through any electronic, radio, satellite, cable, optical, microwave, or other medium or method now in existence or hereafter devised, regardless of the protocol used for such transmission or conveyance. Notwithstanding the foregoing, for purposes of this chapter "cable service", as defined in Section 202.11(2), Florida Statutes (2000), as it may be amended, is not included in the definition of "Communications Services," and cable service providers shall be subject to Article I of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Communications Service Provider shall mean any Person including a municipality or county providing Communications Services through the placement or maintenance of a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way. "Communications Services Provider" shall also include any Person that places or maintains a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way but does not provide Communications Services.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Consumer Services Department means the Consumer Services Department of Miami-Dade County or such other department or officer assigned by the County to administer registrations issued pursuant to this Article.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Director shall be the Director of the Consumer Services Department or his or her designee.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In Public Rights-of-Way or in the Public Rights-of-Way shall mean in, on, over, under or across the Public Rights-of-Way.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Person shall include any individual, children, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, estate, trust, business trust, syndicate, fiduciary, corporation, organization or legal entity of any kind, successor, assignee, transferee, personal representative, and all other groups or combinations.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Place or Maintain or Placement or Maintenance or Placing or Maintaining shall mean to erect, construct, install, maintain, place, repair, extend, expand, remove, occupy, locate or relocate. A Communications Services Provider that owns or exercises physical control over Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way, such as the physical control to maintain and repair, is "placing or maintaining" the Facilities.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Permit shall mean a construction permit issued by the Public Works Department.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Public Rights-of-Way shall mean a public right-of-way, public utility easement, highway, street, bridge, tunnel or alley for which the County is the authority that has jurisdiction and control and may lawfully grant access to and issue permits pursuant to applicable law, and includes the surface, the air space over the surface and the area below the surface. "Public Rights-of-Way" shall not include private property. "Public Rights-of-Way" shall not include any real or personal County property except as described above and shall not include County buildings, fixtures, poles, conduits, facilities or other structures or improvements, regardless of whether they are situated in the Public Rights-of-Way.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Registrant shall mean a Communications Services Provider that has registered with the Director in accordance with the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Registration or Register shall mean the process described in this chapter whereby a Communications Services Provider provides the required information to the Director.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-167, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 4, 6-19-01)</history></law>