<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-58</section_number>
<catch_line>Installations, outages and service calls.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001899</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-58. Installations, outages and service calls.<section>(a) Under normal operating conditions, each of the following four (4) standards will be met no less than ninety-five (95) percent of the time measured on a quarterly basis.<section prefix='(1)'>Standard installations will be performed within seven (7) business days after an order has been placed; provided the licensee has been able to obtain any necessary easements or other consents necessary to complete the installations. "Standard" installations are up to one hundred twenty-five (125) feet from the existing distribution system.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Excluding those situations beyond the control of the licensee, the licensee will respond to service interruptions promptly and in no event later than twenty-four (24) hours after the interruption becomes known. Other service problems will be responded to within twenty-four (24) hours during the normal work week.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The appointment window alternatives made available for installations, service calls, and other installation activities will be either a specific time, or a four (4) hour time block or shorter. If a licensee is running late for an appointment with a customer and will not be able to keep the appointment as scheduled, the licensee will contact the customer by telephone and reschedule as necessary at a time that is convenient for the customer. In such circumstances the licensee will use its best efforts to inform the customer of the delay before the scheduled time of the appointment. Additionally, based on community needs, licensees will schedule supplemental hours during which appointments can be set.</section></section><section>(b) Subscribers who have experienced one missed installation or service appointment due to the fault of the licensee shall receive installation free of charge. If the installation was to have been provided free of charge or if the appointment was for service or repair, the subscriber shall receive a credit on their bill of not less than twenty dollars ($20.00).</section><section>(c) New developments contiguous to the licensee's distribution system shall be wired for cable service within a reasonable amount of time, but at least within one hundred twenty (120) days after the development has reached seventy-five (75) percent occupancy, so long as the construction meets the density requirements of this chapter and provided the licensee has been able to obtain any necessary easements or other consents necessary to complete the installation. This section shall not apply to developments that are already served by another pay television service provider.</section><section>(d) Each licensee shall intentionally interrupt service only for good cause for the shortest time possible. Licensee shall use its best efforts to ensure that such interruptions shall occur only during the hours of 1:00 a.m. to 6:00 a.m. A written log shall be maintained for all service interruptions that includes a description of the equipment failure, location of the failed equipment, and the geographic area and number of subscribers affected by the service interruption. Upon written request, the licensee shall provide to the County a copy of the log.</section><section>(e) In the event of a service interruption to any subscriber for twenty-four (24) or more hours which interruption is within the control of the licensee, the licensee shall provide a credit or rebate to affected subscribers, upon the subscriber's written or verbal request, equal to twenty (20) percent of the monthly fees for each twenty-four-hour period during which the subscriber's service is interrupted. In the event of a service interruption to any subscriber for two (2) or more hours, the licensee shall provide a credit or rebate to affected subscribers, upon the subscriber's written or verbal request, equal to one-thirtieth of the monthly bill. For purposes of computing the time of interrupted service, the time shall begin when a complaint for interrupted service is received by the licensee or when the licensee has actual or constructive notice of the interruption, whichever occurs first. Nothing in this subsection limits the licensee from applying a rebate policy more liberal than the requirements. As used in this Section, service interruption shall mean the loss of picture or sound on one or more cable channels.</section><section>(f) In all situations where cable service is disrupted to five hundred (500) or more subscribers for a time period greater than four (4) hours, the licensee shall notify the Director or his designee immediately.</section><section>(g) All field employees must carry a picture identification indicating their employment with the licensee. This identification must be clearly visible to the public.</section><section>(h) A licensee shall disconnect any subscriber who so requests from the cable system of the licensee. No period of notice prior to voluntary termination of service may be required of subscribers by any license. No charge may be imposed by any licensee for such voluntary disconnection, or for any cable services delivered after the date of disconnect request. A subscriber may be asked to disconnect the equipment of the licensee and return it to the business office or make it available for the licensee to recover. Upon termination of service to any subscriber, the licensee shall promptly remove all portions of its system, facilities and equipment from the subscriber's premises upon request. Where removal is impractical, such as with buried cable or internal wiring, facilities and equipment may be disconnected rather than removed.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>