<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-53</section_number>
<catch_line>Quarterly reports.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001894</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-53. Quarterly reports.<section>(a) The licensee shall submit reports to the County quarterly on forms provided by the County. The quarterly reports shall be submitted according to the following schedule: January-March reports due April 25; April-June reports due July 25; July-September reports due October 25, and October-December reports due January 25 of each year.</section><section>(b) The report shall include, but not be limited to:<section prefix='(1)'>Number of homes passed and number of cable plant miles;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Telephone reports indicating the number of calls received, number of calls abandoned, number of calls receiving a busy signal, percentage of calls receiving a busy signal, where technologically possible, average duration of each call handled by a customer service representative, average length of time each caller waits before speaking directly to a customer service representative, number of calls answered by a customer service representative within 30 seconds, and number of customer service representatives staffed to handle telephone calls;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The number of total standard installations performed; the number of standard installations performed within seven (7) days; number of service interruptions reported; number of service interruptions responded to within twenty-four (24) hours; number of other service problems reported; number of other service problems responded to within thirty-six (36) hours; number of scheduled appointments; number of scheduled appointments responded to within four (4) hour window; number of planned service interruptions; number of service interruptions by day part (1 a.m. to 6 a.m., 6 a.m. to 6 p.m., 6 p.m. to 1 a.m., or, upon request of the County, based on shorter measurement intervals as licensee has available); number of service interruptions by duration; and all other information necessary to monitor the licensee's compliance with the consumer standards of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(4)'>The number of subscribers for each type of cable service offered.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-109, § 2, 6-19-01; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>