<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-22</section_number>
<catch_line>Insurance policy provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001864</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-22. Insurance policy provisions.<section>(a)  All insurance policies, letters of credit and bonds as are required of a licensee in this chapter shall be written by a company or companies authorized and qualified to do business in the State of Florida, and have a minimum rating of "A X" in Best's Rating Guide.</section><section>(b)  Certificates and renewals of all coverage required shall be promptly filed by the licensee with the Director or his designee. Each policy shall require notice and the licensee shall notify the County within thirty (30) days of any cancellation or modification of any insurance coverage required by this chapter, which notice shall be sent by registered mail to the Director or his designee. Renewal certificates shall be filed with the County no less than thirty (30) days prior to the policy expiration date.</section><section>(c)  Miami-Dade County shall be included as an additional insured on the comprehensive general liability.</section><section>(d)  Companies issuing the insurance policies shall have no recourse against the County for payment of any premiums or assessments, and same shall be the sole responsibility of the licensee.</section><section>(e) Neither the provisions of this section, nor the acceptance of any bonds by the County pursuant to this chapter, nor any damages received by the County thereunder, shall be construed to excuse performance by a licensee or limit the liability of a licensee for damages to the full amount of the bonds or otherwise.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 92-97, § 4, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>