<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-39</section_number>
<catch_line>Technical standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001880</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-39. Technical standards.<section>(a) Cable systems shall be installed and maintained in accordance with FCC technical specifications, and all State and local regulations.</section><section>(b) Any antenna structure used in the cable system shall comply with all construction, marking and lighting requirements of federal, State or local laws and accepted industry standards.</section><section>(c) All construction, installation, grounding, and maintenance shall comply with the current versions of the National Electrical Safety Code, the National Electrical Code, and the Bell System Code of Pole Line Construction.</section><section>(d) Systems shall be maintained in such a manner as to prevent signal leakage from the facilities in excess of the limits specified in applicable rules and regulations of the FCC. The licensee may disconnect any person who, in the licensee's judgment, is contributing to a signal leakage problem. Upon written request from the County, licensee shall provide a copy of the Cumulative leakage Index (CLI) report to the licensee's service area to the County.</section><section>(e) Underground construction in streets shall be of such quality as to assure continuity of service without the necessity of frequent street or pavement cutting and shall contain a self-sealing device to insure all such cables against leakage.</section><section>(f) All cables and wires shall be installed, where possible, parallel with electric and telephone lines.</section><section>(g) If the federal law preempting County regulation of technical standards is repealed, any technical standards imposed by the County shall be no stricter than the repealed federal standards or generally accepted standards in the cable television industry, whichever are greater.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 92-97, § 6, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>