<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Rights reserved to the County.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001860</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-18. Rights reserved to the County.<section>(a) The right is hereby reserved to the Commission to adopt, in addition to the provisions contained herein and in existing applicable agreements, such additional rules and regulations as it shall find necessary in the exercise of the police power, for the proper administration and enforcement of the provisions of this chapter; provided that such regulations shall be reasonable and shall conform with the terms and conditions of the licenses and the rights herein granted and shall not be in conflict with federal or State law. Rules and regulations promulgated by the County shall insure fair and equitable treatment for all municipalities affected by cable service. No such rules and regulations shall become effective until a public hearing has been held upon the proposed rules and regulations, and any amendments or modifications thereto, and the same have been filed with the Clerk of the Commission.</section><section>(b) The County shall have the right to install, maintain, and operate antennae, amplifiers, coaxial cable, wire, fiber optic cable fixtures and appurtenances necessary for a County communications system upon or within the communications facilities of the licensee on the condition that such installations do not interfere with the property or operations of the licensee and at no cost to the County except to reimburse the licensee for any additional costs incurred as a result of any such construction by County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90)</history></law>