<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-124</section_number>
<catch_line>Insurance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001936</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-124. Insurance.<section prefix='(a)'>The Registrant shall provide, pay for and maintain, throughout the term of its Registration, and with companies satisfactory to the County, the types of insurance described herein. All insurance shall be from responsible companies duly authorized to do business in the State of Florida and having a financial rating in Best's Insurance Guide of A X or better. The insurance coverage obtained by the Registrant shall be approved by the Risk Management Division of the General Services Administration. All liability policies shall provide that the County is an additional insured as to the operations under this Registration and shall provide the severability of interest provision. The required coverages must be evidenced by properly executed Certificates of Insurance. The Certificates must be manually signed by the authorized representative of the insurance Registrant. Thirty (30) days advance written notice by registered or certified mail must be given to the County of any cancellation, intent not to renew or reduction in the policy coverages, which notice shall be sent by registered mail to the Consumer Services Department. Companies issuing the insurance policies shall have no recourse against the County for payment of any premiums or assessments, and same shall be the sole responsibility of the Registrant.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The limits of coverage of insurance required shall be not less than the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Worker's Compensation and Employer's Liability Insurance as required by Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Comprehensive General Liability Bodily injury and property damage one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) combined single limit each occurrence.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Automobile Liability Bodily injury and property damage one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) combined single limit each accident covering all owned, non-owned, and hired vehicles.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Upon thirty (30) days notice, the insurance coverage and policy requirements may be changed and increased from time to time at the discretion of the Board of County Commissioners to reflect changing liability exposure and limits.</section><section prefix='(d)'>These insurance requirements may be met by evidence of participation of a bona-fide captive insurance or self insurance program that is established and regulated by a governmental entity.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-167, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 4, 6-19-01)</history></law>