<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-51</section_number>
<catch_line>Interconnection of cable systems.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001892</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-51. Interconnection of cable systems.<section>(a) A licensee shall interconnect the access channels of the cable system with any or all other cable systems in contiguous adjacent areas, upon the directive of the Director. Interconnection of cable systems may be done by direct cable connection, microwave link, satellite, or other appropriate method.</section><section>(b) Upon receiving the directive of the Director to interconnect, a licensee shall immediately initiate negotiations with the other affected cable system or systems in order that all costs may be shared equally among cable systems for construction, maintenance and operation of the interconnection link.</section><section>(c) A licensee may be granted reasonable extensions of time to interconnect or the County may rescind its order to interconnect upon petition by the licensee to the County. The County shall grant said request if it finds that a licensee has negotiated in good faith and has failed to obtain an agreement from the cable system or systems of the proposed interconnection or that the cost of the interconnection would cause an unreasonable or unacceptable increase in subscriber rates.</section><section>(d) A licensee shall cooperate with any interconnection corporation, regional interconnection authority or other County, State and federal regulatory agency which may be hereafter established for the purpose of regulating, financing, otherwise providing for the interconnection of cable systems beyond the boundaries of the County.</section><section>(e) In the event it becomes necessary, the licensee shall make reasonable efforts to ensure any interconnect needed for the simultaneous redistribution of the access channels provided for in this license. Any common costs associated with this interconnection shall be shared among all licensed operators based on their respective pro rata share of all Miami-Dade County subscribers.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>