<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-48</section_number>
<catch_line>Service to public buildings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001889</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-48. Service to public buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Within a reasonable amount of time, but at least within ninety (90) days following the request, a licensee shall be required to provide cable service, with converter or other necessary equipment, without installation or monthly charge to buildings within the County; provided that such buildings are passed by and within five hundred (500) feet of the licensee's existing distribution system and are owned by the County or occupied by a governmental entity for predominantly educational or governmental use, including libraries, public schools and other local tax supported elementary, secondary and college level institutions. The licensee may charge for service to that portion of the building used primarily for residential purposes. Such basic service shall be provided by means of a single drop extending to the facility. Such single drop may be internally extended by the governmental entity without cost to, or responsibility of the licensee, subject to the condition that all such internal distribution shall meet all FCC requirements relative to signal leakage. At the request of the County, the licensee shall install the additional service outlets in such facilities and shall charge only its time and material costs for such installations. At the request of the County, the licensee shall extend its distribution system to serve such buildings located more than five hundred (500) feet from the licensee's existing distribution system. In such circumstances, the government entity owning or occupying the building shall reimburse the licensee for the time and material costs incurred in extending the distribution system to within five hundred (500) feet of the building. The licensee shall remain responsible for all costs for the five hundred (500) feet adjacent to the building. The County shall not require permit fees for such installations. As used in this section 8AA-48, the term "cable service" shall include all channels except premium channels sold on a per-channel or pay-per-view basis. The intent of this section is for the licensee to continue providing a comparable level of programming services as provided by licensees on the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Licensee shall provide one (1) standard Internet service connection to the buildings in Section 8AA-48(a) at a mutually agreed discount if requested by the County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, ยง 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 92-97, ยง 8, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 01-44, ยง 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>