<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-63</section_number>
<catch_line>Discriminatory practices prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001905</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-63. Discriminatory practices prohibited.<section prefix='(a)'>A licensee shall not deny, delay or otherwise burden service or discriminate against subscribers or users on the basis of age, race, creed, religion, color, sex, disability, national origin, marital status, or political affiliation, and shall not deny cable service to any potential subscribers because of the income of the residents of the area in which the subscribers reside. A licensee may provide for discounts for senior citizens, the economically disadvantaged or disabled that are applied in a uniform and consistent manner. A licensee may also offer bulk discounts to multiple dwelling buildings to the extent such discounts are permissible by law.<section prefix='(2)'>A licensee may provide for discounts for subscribers residing in government owned housing, that are applied in a uniform and consistent manner; provided however if a licensee or its' parent company is offering discounts for subscribers residing in government owned housing anywhere within Miami-Dade County, then such discounts for subscribers residing in government owned housing shall be applied in a uniform and consistent manner throughout Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>A licensee shall not refuse to employ, nor discharge from employment, nor discriminate against any person in compensation or in terms, conditions or privileges of employment because of age, race, creed, religion, color, sex, handicap, national origin, marital status, or political affiliation.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A licensee shall comply at all times with the Equal Employment Opportunity provisions and reporting requirements contained in federal law. Upon written request, a copy of the licensee's annual report required by the FCC shall be submitted simultaneously to the Director.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No licensee shall require a minimum number of subscribers as a precondition to providing service to any multiple dwelling unit that is located in an area that meets the minimum density requirements of Section 8AA-27. This subsection shall not be applicable to hotels, motels and other multi-dwelling units in which more than a majority of the occupants have been residing there less than four (4) months or where a majority of the occupants have leases with terms for less than four (4) months.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 92-97, § 10, 9-15-92; Ord. No. 97-32, § 5, 4-15-97; Ord. No. 01-44, § 1, 3-20-01; Ord. No. 03-122, § 1, 5-6-03)</history></law>