<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. CABLE TELEVISION REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Licensing provisions; license required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001845</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-3. Licensing provisions; license required.<section prefix='(a)'>Any person desiring to install and/or operate any cable television system in the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County shall apply to the Commission for a license pursuant to this chapter. Any license granted by the County shall authorize and permit the licensee to engage in the business of installing, operating and maintaining a cable system(s) and providing cable services in the license area. For that purpose, subject to the approval of the Public Works Department and all existing permitting processes, the licensee is authorized to install, construct, maintain and operate in, along, under, over, through, across and upon any public right-of-way or street, such poles, wires, cables, conductors, ducts, conduits, vaults, manholes, amplifiers, appliances, attachments, and other property as may be necessary to the cable system. To the extent provided by State and federal law, the licensee shall be entitled to use easements dedicated for compatible uses.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall be a violation of this chapter to commence or engage in the construction, operation or maintenance of a cable system in Miami-Dade County without first having obtained a cable license awarded by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 90-73, ยง 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 01-44, ยง 1, 3-20-01)</history></law>