<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-107</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration application procedure; information required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001930</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-107. Registration application procedure; information required.<section prefix='(A)'>To obtain a Registration under this Article a person shall apply to the Director. To be acceptable for filing, an original and two (2) copies of the application must be submitted.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Each application for registration, renewal registration, and duplicate registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Director. Each application for an initial Registration shall set forth the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The name, address and telephone number of the applicant.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The name, address and telephone number of the applicant's primary contact person in connection with the Registration, and the person to contact in case of an emergency.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Identification of the applicant's fiscal year calendar.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A description of the general nature and size of the proposed communication system's plant and equipment that Registrant intends to have occupy the public rights-of-way, including a list with descriptions of the appurtenances such as manholes, pedestals, handholes, controlled environmental vaults, etc.</section><section prefix='(5)'>A copy of Federal and/or State certification authorizing the applicant to provide communications services.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A copy of any administrative or legal decision in which the applicant was determined to have violated a law or regulation governing the use of the public rights-of-way.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Within thirty (30) calendar days after the awarding of the Registration, the Registrant shall file with the Director its written acceptance of the Registration, together with the insurance policy and bonding documents required by this article, and its agreement to be bound by and to comply with all requirements pursuant to the provisions of this article and the Registration.</section><section prefix='(D)'>A Registrant may cancel a Registration upon written notice to the Director stating that it will no longer place or maintain any Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way within the and will no longer need to obtain permits to perform work in Public Rights-of-Way. A Registrant shall not cancel a Registration if the Registrant continues to place or maintain any Communications Facilities in Public Rights-of-Way.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Registration does not in and of itself establish a right to place or maintain or priority for the placement or maintenance of a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way within the County but shall establish for the Registrant a right to apply for a permit. Registrations are expressly subject to any future amendment to or replacement of this chapter and further subject to any additional County ordinances, as well as any State or Federal laws that may be enacted. In accordance with applicable County ordinances, codes or regulations, a permit may be required of a Communications Services Provider that desires to place or maintain a Communications Facility in Public Rights-of-Way. A Registration shall be a condition of obtaining a permit. Notwithstanding a Registration, permitting requirements shall apply. A permit may be obtained by or on behalf of a Registrant having a Registration if all permitting requirements are met.</section><section prefix='(F)'>A Communications Services Provider with an existing Communications Facility in the Public Rights-of-Way of the County has sixty (60) days from the effective date of this chapter to comply with the terms of this chapter, including, but not limited to, Registration, or be in violation thereof.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-167, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 4, 6-19-01)</history></law>