<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='2'>Chapter 8AA CABLE AND COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES PROVIDERS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8AA-102</section_number>
<catch_line>Rights granted by Registration.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001923</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8AA-102. Rights granted by Registration.<section prefix='(a)'>Subject to all existing permitting processes, the Registrant is authorized to occupy, install, lay, erect, construct, remove, relocate and maintain in, on, over or upon any and all of the public right-of-ways, as they now exist or may be hereafter constructed, opened, laid out or extended within the present limits of the County, or in such territory as may be hereafter added to, consolidated or annexed to unincorporated Miami-Dade County, any and all such conduits, cables, fiber optic lines, poles, wires, supports and other structures and appurtenances as may be reasonably necessary for the construction, maintenance and operation of a Communications System. Except as provided above, this Registration does not convey the right to attach cable or conduit to poles, or occupy or use real or personal property owned by Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the Metrorail and Metromover system.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any Registration granted under this article shall be non-exclusive, and the issuance of a Registration will not expressly or implicitly preclude the County from issuance of other Registrations to Communications Services Providers or affect the County's right to authorize use of public rights-of-way for other lawful purposes to other persons as it determines appropriate.</section><section prefix='(c)'>This Registration authorizes the Registrant to use the public rights-of-way to provide Communications Services only. Use of the public rights-of-way for any other purpose requires separate authorization.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-167, ยง 1, 12-16-99; Ord. No. 01-109, ยง 4, 6-19-01)</history></law>