<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='2'>Chapter 8B EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8B-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Emergency Operations Center Management.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001983</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8B-13. Emergency Operations Center Management.<section prefix='(1)'>The Director or designee will activate the Miami-Dade EOC in anticipation of, or in response to, a disaster. Pursuant to 8B-7(4)(a), assigned departmental or agency staff members will respond to the EOC when activated. Department directors will ensure that the Office of Emergency Management is maintained with accurate 24-hour contact information for each of these staff members and ensure that appropriate staff report to the EOC in a timely manner, upon activation. The Office of Emergency Management will assist directors to train the staff representatives in their role and function.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Director or designee is responsible for the constant readiness of the Miami-Dade EOC and the alert and notification of all representatives for the activation of the Miami-Dade EOC.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In accordance with the Plan, private agencies or organizations may be required by the Director to serve in the Miami-Dade EOC and provide a representative to the Miami-Dade EOC. These agencies or organizations will appoint no less than six (6) staff members who will form the pool of that agency's or organization's representatives that will be assigned to report to the EOC upon activation to represent their agency or organization or serve as lead agency for a specific function. Agency or organization directors will ensure that the Office of Emergency Management is maintained with accurate 24-hour contact information for each of these staff members and ensure that appropriate staff report to the EOC in a timely manner, upon activation. The Office of Emergency Management will assist directors to train the staff representatives in their role and function.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 03-178, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>