<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='2'>Chapter 8B EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8B-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers of the Board of County Commissioners.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001974</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8B-4. Powers of the Board of County Commissioners.<section>The Board accepts all powers vested in the Office of Emergency Management as created by and defined in Chapter 252, Florida Statutes.<section prefix='(1)'>Conduct of Board business in event of a disaster or emergency: If, due to a disaster or emergency as defined herein, it becomes impossible to conduct the affairs of Miami-Dade County government at regular or usual places, the Board, as the legislative body of Miami-Dade County, may meet upon the call of the Chairperson at any place within the territorial limits of Miami-Dade County. If relocation is required due to the effects of a disaster or emergency, the affairs of the Board shall be lawfully conducted at temporary location(s) until normal facilities can be restored. This section does not in any way dismiss the Board's responsibilities under the Florida State Open Government Sunshine Act, as amended. All reasonable attempts must be made to comply with the requirements of Florida Statutes 286.011.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Termination of a Local State of Emergency: If a Local State of Emergency has been declared by the Mayor or the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners in the absence of the Mayor or the Manager in the absence of the Mayor and the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners and exceeds thirty (30) days, the Board can terminate the Declaration of a Local State of Emergency by a two-thirds () majority vote of those present.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-51, ยง 3, 5-25-99; Ord. No. 03-178, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>