<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='2'>Chapter 8B EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8B-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers of the Mayor.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001976</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8B-6. Powers of the Mayor.<section>Pursuant to the Code and Florida State law, and to execute the policies and purposes of this Chapter, the Mayor, the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners in the absence of the Mayor or the Manager in the absence of the Mayor and the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners is authorized to:<section prefix='(1)'>Declare a Local State of Emergency: The Mayor or the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners in the absence of the Mayor may declare a Local State of Emergency for a period of up to thirty (30) days for any or all areas of Miami-Dade County in response to the imminent threat of, or an occurring emergency or disaster. The Mayor or the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners in the absence of the Mayor or the Manager in the absence of the Mayor and the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners must present to the Board and file with the Office of the County Manager an affidavit stating the reasons for the Declaration:<section prefix='(a)'>If the Declaration is to exceed thirty (30) days the Mayor, or the the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners in the absence of the Mayor or the Manager in the absence of the Mayor and the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners, shall present to the Board an additional affidavit stating the reasons for the extension.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A Local State of Emergency may be terminated by executive order once conditions that prompted the declaration are no longer a threat.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Ensure the coordination Local, State, or Federal agencies, and private entities to facilitate disaster or emergency operations.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Mayor shall be the official representative of Miami-Dade County and speak on behalf of its actions in response to disasters or emergencies.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-51, ยง 3, 5-25-99; Ord. No. 03-178, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>