<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='2'>Chapter 8B EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8B-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Duties of the Director of the Office of Emergency Management.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001978</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8B-8. Duties of the Director of the Office of Emergency Management.<section>The Director shall be responsible for the organization, administration and operation of the Office of Emergency Management, subject to the direction and control by the Manager. The Director shall coordinate the activities, services and programs for emergency management and disaster response within Miami-Dade County and shall maintain liaison with other emergency management organizations.<section prefix='(1)'>The Director or designee shall prepare a Comprehensive Emergency Management Plan and program for the emergency management of Miami-Dade County pursuant to F.S. 252, including, but not limited to elements addressing mitigation activities, preparedness, responses to disasters and emergencies, and recovery operations and submit the Plan and program to the Director of the Division of Emergency Management. State of Florida for review and certification for consistency with the State Comprehensive Emergency Management Plan and compliance with Federal emergency management mandates.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Director or designee shall monitor and advise the Mayor and Manager of any and all threats, emergencies or disasters that pose a risk to the lives and safety of the residents of Miami-Dade County, proposing solutions for their decision on how best to protect people and property from imminent danger, or from further damage.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Director or designee shall procure supplies and equipment, institute training programs, public preparedness information and education programs, manage and coordinate disaster drills and exercises in accordance with the Plan.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Provision of Shelter.</section><section prefix='(a)'>Public Shelter Manager: In cases of national emergency, or local disaster or emergency as defined herein, the Director or designee, may appoint Shelter Managers, who shall open public shelters; take charge of all stocks of food, water and other supplies stored in said shelter; admit the public according to Miami-Dade County's sheltering plan; and take whatever control measures are necessary for the protection and safety of the occupants.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event any of the aforementioned public shelters are not available or no longer suitable for use as a shelter for whatever reason, the Director or designee may cause to be opened any publicly owned building within Miami-Dade County for such use as deemed necessary by the Director or designee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Shelter Managers are authorized to use reasonable restraint against those who refuse to cooperate with the routine of shelter living under emergency conditions. Refusal to carry out the orders of the Shelter Manager and appointed staff shall be deemed an offense punishable by a fine of not more than five-hundred dollars ($500.00) or imprisonment in Miami-Dade County jail of not more than sixty (60) days or by both such fine and imprisonment.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The Director or designee shall, in consultation with all municipalities, concerned agencies, public utilities and state offices, develop an evacuation plan for Miami-Dade County. This plan should be usable for any or all types of emergencies or disasters. It should coordinate the efforts of all local entities allowing for rapid execution in the face of a sudden disaster.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Director is authorized by the Board to enter into mutual aid agreements in collaboration with other public and private agencies within the State for reciprocal disaster aid and assistance in the event of a disaster or emergency too great to be dealt with unassisted.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-51, §§ 1, 3, 5-25-99; Ord. No. 03-178, § 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>