<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='2'>Chapter 8B EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8B-9</section_number>
<catch_line>County Department Preparedness Contingency Plans.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001979</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8B-9. County Department Preparedness Contingency Plans.<section>To facilitate emergency preparedness planning for Miami-Dade County, as required by Florida Statute 252.38(1)(a), all Miami-Dade County departments, authorities, independent agencies, and constitutional officers shall prepare and periodically revise emergency preparedness contingency plans pursuant to directions and guidelines from the Office of Emergency Management. These emergency preparedness contingency plans must identify a baseline of preparedness for a full range of hazard-risks and potential emergencies and must establish a comprehensive and effective program that maintains the continuity of essential departmental functions during any emergency or other situation that disrupts normal operations. Miami-Dade County shall ensure that such contingency plans are consistent with the Plan.<section prefix='(1)'>These emergency preparedness contingency plans shall be submitted to the Office of Emergency Management by the last day of March each year in an Office of Emergency Management-approved format and shall address the following areas:<section prefix='(a)'>A departmental or agency risk assessment and vulnerability analysis;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Preparedness and mitigation activities including procedures for employees who perform pre-event activities or shut down critical operations;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Operational procedures of the departmental or agency operations center or command post;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Direction and control including authorities and responsibilities of key personnel and the chain-of-command;</section><section prefix='(e)'>Communications (primary and back-up) systems that will be used to keep employees, on-duty and off-duty, informed of departmental response activities, to coordinate employees in order to carry out departmental missions, to keep in contact with customers and suppliers, and to coordinate with the Miami-Dade EOC;</section><section prefix='(f)'>Life safety procedures including employee alert and notification, assembly and accountability, evacuation procedures, employee/family preparedness and welfare;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Protection of facilities, equipment, supplies, and vital records;</section><section prefix='(h)'>Recovery and restoration of services including employee support, critical asset repair/replacement, and the continuity of operations;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Operating procedures for documenting departmental or agency emergency personnel, equipment, services, and materials expenditures and for their recovery or reimbursement from appropriate local, state, and federal sources;</section><section prefix='(j)'>Public information;</section><section prefix='(k)'>Administration and logistics.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-51, ยง 3, 5-25-99; Ord. No. 03-178, ยง 1, 7-22-03)</history></law>