<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='2'>Chapter 8C BUILDING SECURITY MEASURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8C-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Illumination for open parking lots, alleys and access thereto and parking and nonenclosed areas under or within buildings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001991</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8C-3. Illumination for open parking lots, alleys and access thereto and parking and nonenclosed areas under or within buildings.<section prefix='(a)'>Generally:<section prefix='(1)'>This section applies to new construction and all existing buildings.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Open parking lots, alleys, and access thereto shall be illuminated as set forth below. For purposes of this paragraph, alley is defined as a narrow vehicular thoroughfare up to twenty-five (25) feet in width upon which service entrances or buildings abut and not generally used as a thoroughfare for general traffic; provided, however, alleys shall not include public rights-of-way.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Groups A (Assembly), D (Day Care) and E (Educational) occupancies:<section prefix='(1)'>Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn; provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Parking and nonenclosed areas under or within buildings at grade shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle of light on the parking and walking surfaces from dusk until dawn and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1); provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business one each operating day. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of  foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Groups F (Factory Industrial), H (Hazardous), I (Institutional), S (Storage) and R4 (Residential care/assisted living facilities) occupancies:<section prefix='(1)'>Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 0.5 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn; provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of  foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Parking and nonenclosed areas under or within buildings at grade shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle of light on the parking and walking surfaces from dusk until dawn and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1) provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The area immediately outside of exterior doors shall have security illumination and shall be activated during the dark period of every day.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Group B (Business) and M (Mercantile) occupancies:<section prefix='(1)'>Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1.0 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn; provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of  foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. This provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Parking and nonenclosed areas under, or within buildings shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1 foot-candle of light on the walking and parking surfaces from dusk until dawn, and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1); provided, however, the lighting level may be reduced by fifty (50) percent on non-business days and commencing thirty (30) minutes after the termination of business on each operating day. It is provided, however, that this provision shall not apply to governmental facilities not generally open to the public, and shall apply to those governmental facilities that are generally open to the public only during the dusk-to-dawn hours such facilities are open.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The area immediately outside of exterior doors shall have security illumination and shall be activated during the dark period of every day.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Group R1 (Residential transient) and R2 (Residential multiple dwelling) occupancies:<section prefix='(1)'>Open parking lots and access thereto shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1.0 foot-candle on the parking surface from dusk until dawn. The uniformity ratio shall not exceed a twelve to one ratio (12:1) maximum to minimum foot-candles. Alleys shall be provided with a maintained minimum of one-third () foot-candle on the alley surface from dusk to dawn.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Parking and nonenclosed areas under, or within buildings shall be provided with a maintained minimum of 1.0 foot-candle of light on the walking and parking surfaces from dusk until dawn, and the ratio of maximum to minimum illumination in foot-candles shall not exceed twelve to one (12:1).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-196, ยง 1, 11-20-01)</history></law>