<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='2'>Chapter 8C BUILDING SECURITY MEASURES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8C-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Public swimming pool, spa and hot tub barriers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001992</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8C-4. Public swimming pool, spa and hot tub barriers.<section>All new construction of public swimming pools, spas and hot tubs shall be provided with a permanent barrier complying with the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The top of the barrier shall be at least forty-eight (48) inches above grade measured on the side of the barrier which faces away from the swimming pool. The maximum vertical clearance between grade and the bottom of the barrier shall be two (2) inches measured on the side of the barrier which faces away from the swimming pool. Where the top of the pool structure. Where the barrier is mounted on top of the pool structure, the maximum vertical clearance between the top of the pool structure and the bottom of the barrier shall be four (4) inches.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Opening in the barrier shall not allow passage of 4-inch diameter sphere.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Solid barriers which do not have openings shall not contain indentations or protrusions except for normal construction tolerances and tooled masonry joints.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Where the barrier is composed of horizontal and vertical members and the distance between the tops of the horizontal members is less than forty-five (45) inches, the horizontal members shall located on the swimming pool side of the fence. Spacing between vertical members shall not exceed 1¾ inches in width.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Where the barrier is composed of horizontal and vertical members and the distance between the tops of the horizontal member is forty-five (45) inches or more, spacing between vertical members shall not exceed four (4) inches. Where there are decorative cutouts within vertical members, spacing within the cutouts shall not exceed 1¾ inches in width.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Maximum mesh size for chain link fences shall be a 2¼ inches square unless the fence is provided with slats fastened at the top or the bottom which reduce the openings to no more than 1¾ inches.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Where the barrier is composed of diagonal members, the maximum opening formed by the diagonal members shall be no more than 1¾ inches.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Pedestrian access gates with direct access to the pool, spa or hot tub, shall be equipped with self-closing and self-latching devices. The release mechanism on all such devices shall be located a minimum of fifty-four (54) inches above the pool deck floor or exterior grade level.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Where the release mechanism of the self-latching device is located less than fifty-four (54) inches from the bottom of the gate, the release mechanism shall be located on the pool side of the gate at least three (3) inches below the top of the gate and barrier shall have no opening greater than ½ inch within eighteen (18) inches of the release mechanism.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-196, § 4, 11-20-01)</history></law>