<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='2'>Chapter 8CC CODE ENFORCEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8CC-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Qualifications of officers and removal; organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001996</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8CC-2. Qualifications of officers and removal; organization.<section prefix='(a)'>The County Manager shall create a Hearing Officer Review Board, comprised of three (3) members from code enforcement departments, one (1) member from the County Clerk's Office, two (2) members from the public at large, and one (1) member from the Office of the County Attorney. The duty of the Board shall be to recommend new Hearing Officer appointments and review, on an annual basis, the performance of Hearing Officers and, as necessary recommend the removal or reappointment of Hearing Officers to the County Manager.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Hearing Officer Review Board shall use as its basis for recommendation for appointment, criteria to be developed by the Review Board for approval and concurrence of the County Manager and Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. Such appointments by the County Manager shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board for ratification by the Clerk.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Hearing Officers shall be residents of Miami-Dade County who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, interest, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability. Appointments shall be made by the County Manager or his designee upon recommendation of the Hearing Officer Review Board and on the basis of experience or interest in code enforcement. Such appointments shall be submitted to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners for ratification by the Clerk.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The County Manager or his designee shall appoint as many Hearing Officers as are deemed necessary. Appointments shall be made for a term of two (2) years. Upon recommendation of the Hearing Officer Review Board, any Hearing Officer may be reappointed at the discretion of the County Manager, subject to ratification by the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners. There shall be no limit on the number of reappointments that may be given to any individual Hearing Officer; provided, however, that a determination as to removal or reappointment must be made for each individual Hearing Officer at the end of each of his or her two-year term. The County Manager shall have authority to remove individual Hearing Officers with or without cause. Appointments to fill any vacancy shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Miami-Dade County Attorney's Office shall serve as general counsel to the Hearing Officers.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-33, § 1(2), 5-21-85; Ord. No. 86-22, § 1, 3-16-86; Ord. No. 90-6, § 1, 2-6-90; Ord. No. 99-55, § 1, 5-25-99; Ord. No. 05-19, § 1, 1-27-05; Ord. No. 09-17, § 1, 3-3-09)</history></law>