<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='2'>Chapter 8CC CODE ENFORCEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8CC-7</section_number>
<catch_line>Recovery of unpaid civil penalties; unpaid penalty to constitute a lien; interest to be paid on liens; foreclosure; prohibition of the issuance of permits, licenses, certificates of use and occupancy, or zoning approvals to violators with unpaid civil penalties or liens.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002002</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8CC-7. Recovery of unpaid civil penalties; unpaid penalty to constitute a lien; interest to be paid on liens; foreclosure; prohibition of the issuance of permits, licenses, certificates of use and occupancy, or zoning approvals to violators with unpaid civil penalties or liens.<section prefix='(a)'>Miami-Dade County may institute proceedings in a court of competent jurisdiction to compel payment of civil penalties.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A certified copy of an order imposing a civil penalty or an electronic copy of such order may be recorded in the public records and thereafter shall constitute a lien against the land on which the violation exists or upon any other real or personal property owned by the violator; and it may be enforced in the same manner as a court judgment by the sheriffs of this State, including levy against the personal property, but shall not be deemed to be a court judgment except for enforcement purposes. After one (1) year from the filing of any such lien which remains unpaid, Miami-Dade County may foreclose or otherwise execute on the lien. The lien created hereunder shall only attach to property owned by the violator named in the civil violation notice.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Liens created pursuant to Section 8CC-7 may be discharged and satisfied by paying to Miami-Dade County the amount specified in the notice of lien, together with interest thereon from the date of the filing of the lien computed at the rate of twelve (12) percent per annum, together with the administrative costs, filing and recording fees and fees paid to file a satisfaction of the lien in the public records. When any such lien has been discharged, Miami-Dade County shall promptly cause evidence of the satisfaction and discharge of such lien to be recorded in the public records. Any person, firm, corporation or legal entity, other than the present owner of the property involved, who pays any such unsatisfied lien shall be entitled to receive an assignment of the lien held by the County and shall be subrogated to the rights of the County in respect to the enforcement of such lien, as permitted by law.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant or issue any operating permit, license, building permit, certificate of use and occupancy, municipal occupational licenses, platting action, or zoning action to any named violator with (i) unpaid civil penalties; (ii) unpaid administrative costs of hearing; (iii) unpaid County investigative, enforcement, testing, or monitoring costs; or (iv) unpaid liens, any or all of which are owed to Miami-Dade County pursuant to the provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-33, § 1(7), 5-21-85; Ord. No. 99-55, § 5, 5-25-99; Ord. No. 00-53, § 4, 5-9-00; Ord. No. 09-17, § 1, 3-3-09; Ord. No. 12-99, § 1, 12-4-12)</history></law>