<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='2'>Chapter 8D CONSTRUCTION: FINANCING OF PUBLIC FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8D-1</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002008</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8D-1. Definitions.<section>As used in this chapter, the following words and terms shall have the following meanings, unless some other meaning is plainly intended:<section prefix='(a)'>Board. The word "Board" shall mean the Board of County Commissioners of the County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Project. The word "project" shall mean and shall include any one (1) or any combination of the following: airports; bridges, tunnels, viaducts, causeways; aquariums, oceanariums, marine laboratories; auditoriums; bathing beaches; hospitals, homes for aged and infirm; juvenile homes; reservations for water supply; roads; courthouses; ice plants, precooling and cold storage plants and warehouses; harbors, channels, jetties, breakwaters, public landings, wharves, docks, warehouses; and other improvements for harbors and shipping facilities; and shall include all property, rights, easements and franchises relating to any such project and deemed necessary or convenient for the operation thereof.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Cost. The word "cost" shall include the cost of construction or reconstruction, the cost of all labor, materials, machinery and equipment, the cost of all lands, property, rights, easements and franchises acquired, financing charges, interest prior to and during construction and for one (1) year after completion of construction, cost of plans and specifications, surveys and estimates of cost and of revenues, cost of engineering and legal services, and all other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of such construction or reconstruction, administrative expense and such other expenses as may be necessary or incident to the financing herein authorized. Any obligation or expense heretofore or hereafter incurred by the County in connection with any of the foregoing items of cost may be regarded as a part of such cost and reimbursed to the County out of the proceeds of bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Revenue bonds. The term "revenue bonds" shall mean special obligations of the County which are payable solely from revenues.</section><section prefix='(e)'>General obligation bonds. The term "general obligation bonds" shall mean general obligations of the County which are payable from unlimited ad valorem taxes or from such taxes and additionally secured by a pledge of revenues.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Bonds. The word "bonds" shall include both revenue bonds and general obligation bonds.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ch. 22960, ยง 1, Laws 1945; Ch. 27088, ยง 1, Laws 1951; Ord. No. 78-27, ยง 2, 4-4-78)</history></law>