<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='2'>Chapter 8D CONSTRUCTION: FINANCING OF PUBLIC FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8D-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers of Board generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002010</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8D-3. Powers of Board generally.<section>The Board of County Commissioners of Dade County is hereby authorized and empowered:<section prefix='(1)'>To construct, and to improve, extend, enlarge, reconstruct, maintain, equip, repair and operate a project financed under the provisions of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(2)'>To issue either revenue bonds or general obligation bonds of the County to pay all or a part of the cost of such construction or reconstruction;</section><section prefix='(3)'>To fix and collect rates, fees, rentals, tolls and other charges for the services and facilities furnished by any such project;</section><section prefix='(4)'>To acquire in the name of the County, either by purchase or the exercise of the right of eminent domain, such lands and rights and interests therein, including lands under water and riparian rights, and to acquire such personal property as it may deem necessary in connection with the construction, reconstruction, improvement, extension, enlargement or operation of any project or projects, and to hold and dispose of all real and personal property under its control;</section><section prefix='(5)'>To make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and the execution of its powers under this chapter, and to employ such consulting and other engineers, superintendents, managers, construction and accounting experts and attorneys, and such other employees and agents as may, in the judgment of the Board, be deemed necessary, and to fix their compensation; provided, however, that all such expenses shall be payable solely from funds made available under the provisions of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(6)'>To enter on any lands, water or premises located within the County to make surveys, borings, soundings or examinations for the purposes of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(7)'>To exercise jurisdiction, control and supervision over any project or projects owned, operated or maintained by the County and to make and enforce such rules and regulations for the maintenance and operation of any such project or projects as may, in the judgment of the Board, be necessary or desirable for the efficient operation of any such project or projects and for accomplishing the purposes of this chapter;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Subject to such provisions and restrictions as may be set forth in the resolution or trust agreement hereinafter mentioned authorizing or securing any bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter, to enter into contracts with the government of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof, or with any corporation, copartnership, association or individual providing for or relating to the operation of any such project;</section><section prefix='(9)'>To award any contract for the construction of any project or any part thereof upon any day at least fifteen (15) days after one (1) publication of the notice requesting bids upon such contract in a newspaper of general circulation in the County;</section><section prefix='(10)'>To receive and accept from any federal agency grants for or in aid of the planning, construction, reconstruction or financing of any project or projects, and to receive and accept contributions from any source of either money, property, labor or other things of value, to be held, used and applied only for the purposes for which such grants and contributions may be made;</section><section prefix='(11)'>To lease any aquarium, oceanarium or marine laboratory, or any combination of the same, to any established college or university in the State of Florida without the necessity of advertising or competitive bidding and upon such terms and conditions as the Board may see fit, and to do all acts and things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers expressly given in this chapter;</section><section prefix='(12)'>To operate or let unto others or contract with others for the operation of concessions in connection with any project or any combination of projects, of the kind and character usually operated in connection with any such project, including, but not limited to, restaurants, lunch stands, refreshment stands, beverage stands, camera and camera equipment shops, souvenir shops and curio shops, and to purchase for and sell thereat goods, supplies, foods, beverages and other articles of personal property usually sold at such shops and stands, without advertising for bids, sales, rentals, leases or operating agreements and without including any estimates of receipts therefrom or expenditures therefor in any budget; provided, however, that any exclusive concession shall be granted or leased in the manner provided by State law, as amended from time to time. The highest and best bid shall be accepted unless all bids are rejected. The Board may make purchases and sales as herein provided through any employee or employees of the County without official action to such Board other than a general grant of authority to such employee or employees. The Board may pledge any revenues realized as the result of the exercise of the powers granted in this paragraph to the payment of principal and interest of any bonds issued pursuant to this chapter.</section></section><section>All public or private property damaged or destroyed in carrying out the powers granted by this chapter shall be restored or repaired and placed in its original condition, as nearly as practicable, or adequate compensation made therefor, out of funds provided by this chapter.</section><section>The State of Florida hereby consents to the use of all State lands lying under water which are necessary for the accomplishment of the purposes of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ch. 22960, § 2, Laws 1945; Ch. 27088, § 2, Laws 1951; Ch. 30433, § 1, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 78-27, § 2, 4-4-78; Ord. No. 81-83, § 1, 7-7-81)</history></law>