<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='2'>Chapter 8E CRANES AND HOISTING EQUIPMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8E-8</section_number>
<catch_line>Building permits and inspections.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002026</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8E-8. Building permits and inspections.<section prefix='(a)'>Permits. In addition to the requirements of the Florida Building Code, and of Section 8-10 of this Code, the following shall apply to any construction involving the placement or erection of Hoisting Equipment regulated by this chapter. The structural building plan for any threshold building shall contain sufficient information for the Building Official to determine whether the Hoisting Equipment to be used in the construction complies with the standards set forth in this section. In the event that the complete fabrication, including the connection to the foundation, base structural support and attachment to the building structure, requires the preparation and approval of shop drawings, the Building Official may issue the building permit subject to permit holds. The permit holds shall be released upon completion and approval of all required information.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Inspections. In the event that any construction involves the use of Hoisting Equipment regulated by this chapter, the Building Official shall require the use of a Special Hoisting Equipment Inspector. The Special Crane Inspector shall perform the inspections set forth in the approved inspection plan and report to the Building Official the results of the inspections in forms designed for that purpose. The Building Official shall be authorized to suspend or revoke the building permit relating to any construction for gross negligence, gross incompetence, failures to correct any identified failures to comply with the applicable standards, or willful or repeated disregard of any occupational safety standard or order involving the crane. Decisions of the Building Official may be appealed to the Board of Rules and Appeals in the manner set forth in this Code.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Schedule. The inspection plan shall provide for crane inspection which shall occur at a minimum as follows:<section></section><section prefix='-'>After initial erection of crane</section><section prefix='-'>After each time top-climbing is completed on the crane and/or after each period of 6 months the crane has been erected on a construction project</section><section prefix='-'>After the passage of a hurricane or catastrophic wind event in the area of installation of the crane</section><section prefix='-'>After a major incident/accident involving the tower crane</section><section></section><section prefix='-'>Annual inspection with a rated load test within the configuration of the crane and the manufacturer's recommended load chart</section><section prefix='-'>After a major incident/accident involving the mobile crane</section><section prefix='-'>After the passage of a hurricane or catastrophic wind event in the area of an assembled and erected mobile crane</section><section></section><section prefix='-'>After initial erection of personnel/material hoist, including a full rated load drop test</section><section prefix='-'>Every 90 days, including a full load drop test</section><section prefix='-'>After a hurricane</section><section prefix='-'>After a major incident/accident involving the personnel/material hoist</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Hoisting equipment inspection companies. To perform inspections of Hoisting Equipment, companies and/or individuals shall comply at a minimum with the following requirements:<section prefix='-'>Incorporated or registered in the State of Florida conducting third party inspections on cranes and/or personnel/material hoists.</section><section prefix='-'>Cannot be wholly or partly owned by an Equipment Owner or Equipment Manufacturer in the crane and hoisting industry.</section><section prefix='-'>Cannot be receiving financial support from an equipment Owner or Equipment Manufacturer in the crane and hoisting industry.</section><section prefix='-'>Must carry a minimal of $1,000,000 professional liability insurance.</section><section prefix='-'>Must carry a minimal of $1,000,000 general liability insurance.</section><section prefix='-'>Must have in its full time employment an individual who is qualified to perform inspections as set forth in subpart (e) below.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Qualification of individuals performing crane inspections. To perform the requisite crane inspections, individuals must possess the following qualifications:<section prefix='-'>Minimal five (5) years of work experience in the crane industry specifically erecting, operating, maintaining, inspecting and supervising equipment. Two (2) of the five (5) years of documented work experience must be in the capacity of conducting inspections of cranes.</section><section prefix='-'>Must provide proof, reasonably satisfactory to the Certifying Entity, of completion of at least one (1) factory-sponsored or approved technical course to inspect the subject equipment.</section><section prefix='-'>Cannot be an employee of an Equipment Owner or Equipment Manufacturer in the crane and hoisting industry.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Qualifications of personnel/material hoist employee inspector. To perform the requisite inspections, an individual must possess the following qualifications:<section prefix='-'>Minimal five (5) years of work experience in the personnel/material hoisting industry, specifically erecting, operating, maintaining, inspecting and supervising of equipment. Two (2) years of the five (5) years of documented work experience must be in the capacity of conducting inspections of personnel/material hoists and following all applicable codes and standards.</section><section prefix='-'>Must provide proof, reasonably satisfactory to the Certifying Entity, of completion of at least one (1) factory-sponsored or approved technical course to inspect the subject equipment.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>[Certifying, decertifying and implementation.] The Office of Building Code Compliance of Miami-Dade County shall be the Certifying Entity responsible for certifying and decertifying Special Hoisting Equipment Inspectors in accordance with the provisions of this Chapter. To implement the provisions of this Chapter, the County Manager shall issue an implementing order to be approved by this Board.</section><section prefix='(h)'>[Appeals.] Decisions of the Building Official based on the application of this Chapter shall be appealed to the Board of Rules and Appeals in the manner set forth in this Code.</section><section prefix='(i)'>[Interpretation of provisions.] The Board of Rules and Appeals may interpret provisions of this Chapter in order to cover a special case if it appears the provisions do not definitely cover the point raised or if the intent of the provision is not clear, or that ambiguity exists in the wording, but shall have no authority to grant variances where this Chapter is clear and specific.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 08-34, ยง 1, 3-18-08)</history></law>