<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='2'>Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BISCAYNE BAY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>9-51</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002039</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 9-51. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>The term "mean sea level" refers to the datum plane or reference elevation established by the United States Coast and Geodetic Survey.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The term "mean low water" refers to the datum plane or reference elevation established for Biscayne Bay by the United States Army Corps of Engineers.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The term "project" as hereinafter employed includes any road or bridge, or modification thereof whether toll or free or any combination thereof, together with all related facilities, including but not limited to borrow pits or excavations, buildings, structures, causeways, approaches and other facilities related to or incidental to the foregoing, constructed or proposed to be constructed within any part of or across any part of the Biscayne Bay within Miami-Dade County, including the shoal areas within, and the seaward approaches to Biscayne Bay. The provisions of this article are not applicable to any existing project completed prior to April 15, 1966, nor to any work performed by the Corps of Engineers or its contractors under approved federal projects, but are otherwise applicable to projects owned, authorized or constructed by public entities and agencies as well as by private persons.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The definitions provided in Section 1-2, Metropolitan Code, are applicable to the provisions of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 66-15, ยง 1, 4-5-66; Ord. No. 85-56, ยง 1, 7-16-85)</history></law>