<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='2'>Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BISCAYNE BAY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>9-54</section_number>
<catch_line>Bridges.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002042</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 9-54. Bridges.<section>The project shall contain at least one (1) fixed span opening with a minimum vertical clearance of fifty-five (55) feet above mean sea level and a minimum horizontal clearance of ninety (90) feet or alternatively one (1) bascule bridge to be manned at all times with a minimum vertical clearance of twenty-five (25) feet above mean sea level and the minimum horizontal clearance above specified for each three (3) miles of length. If not provided through compliance with the foregoing requirement, the project shall include additionally a bridge with a minimum vertical clearance of sixteen (16) feet above mean sea level and a minimum horizontal clearance of ninety (90) feet across each existing navigational channel whether artificially maintained or natural which permits a draft of five (5) feet at mean low water and whether such channel be presently marked with navigational aids or not. Provided, however, where such navigational channel is uninterrupted by shoal water less than five (5) feet in depth below mean low water for a distance of one (1) statute mile along the centerline of the project, one (1) bridge shall be provided for each such statute mile measured along the centerline of the project. Each bridge shall be located at such point or points as is designated by the Corps of Engineers or in default of such designation by the County Manager. At least the existing depth of water through each bridge shall be maintained.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 66-15, ยง 4, 4-5-66)</history></law>