<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='2'>Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BISCAYNE BAY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>9-56</section_number>
<catch_line>Solid fill.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002044</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 9-56. Solid fill.<section>In order to minimize obstruction to the horizontal movement of waters in the Bay, destruction of marine life in the bay and interference with navigation, as much of the structure as is economically feasible shall be elevated. The following minimum requirements shall be observed:<section prefix='(a)'>No solid fill shall be employed within a linear distance of one hundred (100) feet bayward of the established bulkhead line.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Solid fill may not be employed for an aggregate total linear distance (exclusive of areas within the existing bulkhead lines) in excess of twenty-five (25) percent of the total linear distance of the project (exclusive of areas within existing bulkhead lines) unless supported by a hydraulic and tidal study prepared by a qualified professional engineer demonstrating the effect of the proposed obstruction upon horizontal water movement and unless the project is found by the Board of County Commissioners after public notice and hearing not to endanger life and property, private or public, in view of the obstruction to horizontal movement of bay waters and in the light of the study filed and any other studies or other evidence before the Board. The Board shall consider the unusual tides and winds to be expected with hurricanes.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If any part of the fill required for the project is to be dredged or excavated from the Bay, it shall be obtained from a person whose excavation and dredging at that time is limited to and restricted to furnishing fill for the project, and such person shall not excavate or dredge in such a manner as to produce more fill than is reasonably required in the construction of the project.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 66-15, ยง 6, 4-5-66)</history></law>