<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='2'>Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. BISCAYNE BAY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>9-57</section_number>
<catch_line>Causeway, bridge projects less than 2500 feet; exempted from certain provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002045</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 9-57. Causeway, bridge projects less than 2500 feet; exempted from certain provisions.<section>Sections through above shall not apply to causeway and bridge projects of two thousand five hundred (2,500) feet or less in length as measured along the centerline of the project from existing mean high water line at one (1) end to mean high water line at the other end. The design of all such projects shall be supported by a hydraulic and tidal study prepared by a qualified professional engineer; shall be subject to approval of the Public Works Department, the United States Army Corps of Engineers, and appropriate State agencies such as the Trustees of the Internal Improvement Fund and the Florida Board of Conservation; and shall be governed by the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Location and length of bridge portions and clearances, both vertical and horizontal, shall be based on a study of the location of the proposed crossing, the depth of water, the configuration of the bottom, tide and wind conditions of the area, requirements of navigation, and hydraulic analysis appropriate to good engineering practice.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Solid fill portions shall comply with the requirements of all applicable federal and State statutes and shall be designed and constructed in a manner that will not cause harmful obstruction to or alteration of the natural flow of water, or increase erosion, shoaling of channels, or create stagnant areas of water, or cause material injury or monetary damage to adjoining lands.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 66-15, ยง 7, 4-5-66)</history></law>