<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='2'>Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SUSTAINABLE BUILDINGS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>9-73</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002055</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 9-73. Definitions.<section>Unless specifically defined elsewhere in this Chapter, the definitions provided in this Section shall apply.<section prefix='(a)'>Green building is a structure that is designed, built, renovated, operated and reused in an ecological and resource-efficient manner.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Green building practices are environmentally and socially-conscious practices that emphasize processes and methods of design and construction that:<section prefix='(i)'>reduce exposure to noxious materials,</section><section prefix='(ii)'>conserve non-renewable energy and scarce materials,</section><section prefix='(iii)'>minimize life-cycle ecological impact of energy and materials,</section><section prefix='(iv)'>employ renewable energy or materials that are sustainably harvested,</section><section prefix='(v)'>protect and restore local air, water, soils, flora and fauna, and</section><section prefix='(vi)'>support pedestrians, bicycles, mass transit and other alternatives to fossil-fueled vehicles.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>New construction is the design and construction of any new building, or an addition to an existing building.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Major renovation/remodel is any design and construction project that alters the structure of an existing building where the cost of construction is equal to or exceeds 50% of the building's replacement cost.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Non-major renovation/remodel is any design and construction project that alters the structure of an existing building where the cost of construction is less than 50% of the building's replacement cost.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Renovate is to improve or repair the condition of a building.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Sustainable building means building processes that integrate materials and methods that promote environmental quality, economic vitality, and social benefit through the design, construction and operation of the built environment.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-65, ยง 3, 5-8-07)</history></law>