<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='2'>Chapter 9 STANDARDS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF COUNTY BUILDINGS, ROADS, BRIDGES AND CAUSEWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. SUSTAINABLE BUILDINGS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>9-75</section_number>
<catch_line>Measurement Standards and Compliance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002057</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 9-75. Measurement Standards and Compliance.<section prefix='(a)'>Rating System. The Sustainability Manager shall select a nationally-recognized rating system that sets standards for implementing green building practices in design and construction, which may include, but not be limited to, the Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design Rating System administered by the U.S. Green Building Counsel. This rating system will be used to measure compliance with the terms of this Article. The rating system selected for each category of construction by the Sustainability Manager shall be set forth in an Implementing Regulation to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Standard for County-owned buildings. All new construction, major renovations/remodels, and non-major renovations/remodels of County-owned buildings shall adhere to the nationally-recognized rating system standards designated by the Sustainability Manager for that particular category of construction, as described in subsection (a) above.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Standard for County-financed, County-leased, and County-operated buildings. The Sustainability Manager shall evaluate and propose criteria for the use of green building practices in connection with County-financed, County-leased, and County-operated buildings. The criteria shall be set forth in an Implementing Regulation to be approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Interpretations, exemptions and waivers. The Sustainability Manager shall establish such processes, policies, and procedures as may be necessary to guide the consideration of requests for interpretations of this Article, or for exemption or waiver from the requirements of this Article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 07-65, ยง 3, 5-8-07)</history></law>