<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00080' order_by='00080' level='2'>APPENDIX B ORDINANCES CHANGING MUNICIPAL BOUNDARIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>abc</section_number>
<catch_line>APPENDIX B ORDINANCES CHANGING MUNICIPAL BOUNDARIES</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004752</order_by>
<text><section>APPENDIX B ORDINANCES CHANGING MUNICIPAL BOUNDARIES<section>ORD. NO. 58-9. HIALEAH</section><section>(Adopted March 6, 1958)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and Section 5 of Article I of the Charter of the City of Hialeah (Chapter 30807, Laws of Florida, Acts of 1955) is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, namely:<section>Tract 8 and the E½ of Tract 9; all of Tracts 62 and 63 and the E½ of Tract 64, FLORIDA FRUIT LANDS COMPANY'S SUBDIVISION, in, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, according to the Plat thereof, recorded in Plat Book 2, at Page 17, of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida</section><section>Tract 43 in, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, of Florida Fruit Land Company's Subdivision, No. 1, according to the Plat thereof, recorded in Plat Book 2, at Page 17, of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida</section></section><section> AND<section>Tract 42 in, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, of FLORIDA FRUIT LAND COMPANY'S SUBDIVISION, No. 1, according to the Plat thereof, recorded in Plat Book 2, at Page 17, of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 58-12. SOUTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted April 22, 1958)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of South Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and Article I, Section 10 of the Charter of the City of South Miami, Florida, is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of South Miami of the following described lands situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>The N½ of the NE¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, also known and described as "Fuchs Park".</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 59-17. HIALEAH</section><section>(Adopted June 23, 1959)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>The South Half (S-1/2) of the Northwest Quarter (NW-1/4) of Section 36, Township 52 South, Range 40 East.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 59-19. CORAL GABLES</section><section>(Adopted June 30, 1959)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Coral Gables, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, but the annexation to the City of Coral Gables of a strip of land on the east side of Old Cutler Road more particularly described in Resolution No. 7626 [below] passed and adopted on December 16, 1958, by the Commission of the City of Coral Gables, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 59-20. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted June 30, 1959)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described lands situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>Lot Three (3) of Block Eleven (11) of JULIA B. TUTTLE SUBDIVISION, consisting of approximately 13½ acres.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 59-33. HIALEAH</section><section>(Adopted August 25, 1959)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>Tracts Six (6) to Eleven (11), inclusive, and Tracts Forty-Nine (49) to Sixty-Four (64), inclusive, of FLORIDA FRUIT LAND COMPANY'S SUBDIVISION, in Section 35, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, according to the plat thereof, recorded in Plat Book 2, at Page 17 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 60-3. HIALEAH</section><section>(Adopted January 19, 1960)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>Tract Six (6) of the Florida Fruit Land Company's Subdivision in the Northeast Quarter (NE¼) of Section 1, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, as recorded in Plat Book 2, at Page 17, of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 60-43. HIALEAH</section><section>(Adopted November 29, 1960)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following described lands situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>That portion of Section 2, Township 53S, Range 40E which lies NORTH of N.W. 103rd Street and Sections 25, 26, 35 and 36 of Township 52S, Range 40E, except for those areas which are presently in the corporate limits of the City of Hialeah; and, except for that area of Section 36, Township 52S, Range 40E, more specifically described as:</section><section>Block 28 and Blocks 30 through 34 of the Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section A, Plat Book 57, page 17;</section><section>Blocks 35 through 40 of the Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section B, Plat Book 57, page 31;</section><section>Blocks 41 through 46 of the Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section C, Plat Book 57, page 38;</section><section>Blocks 47 through 53 of the Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section D, Plat Book 57, page 46;</section><section>Blocks 66 and 67 of the Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section F, Plat Book 62, page 72;</section><section>Replat of Tracts A and B, Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section A; and Tract A, Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section B, Plat Book 57, page 49;</section><section>That portion of an unplatted tract of land which lies between Lots 4 and 5, Block 34 of the Fourth Addition to Palm Springs Subdivision, Section A, Plat Book 57, page 17;</section><section>Together with that portion of Section 2, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, lying South of the North right-of-way of Northwest 103rd Street.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the following express conditions and reservations, namely:<section prefix='(a)'>That this ordinance shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power & Light Company, and Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said County Franchise in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That a proposed land use map shall be prepared jointly by the City of Hialeah and the Dade County Planning Department to determine the appropriate use of the lands hereinabove described and feasible means of access to the Palmetto Expressway, which shall govern and control said annexed lands.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 60-37. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted November 22, 1960)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>The East 235 feet of the North 275 feet of the NE¼ of the NE¼,, Township 52 South, Range 41 East, consisting of 1.48 acres, more or less, lying and being in Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 727 passed and adopted on September 13, 1960, by the Council of the City of North Miami, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 61-3. FLORIDA CITY</section><section>(Adopted January 24, 1961)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Florida City are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Florida City of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>The NE¼ of the SW¼; E½ of the NW¼ of the SW¼; all in, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Dade County, Florida,</section><section>The SE¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 57 South, and<section>Range 38 East.</section></section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the following express conditions and reservations, namely:<section prefix='(a)'>That this ordinance shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power & Light Company, and Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said County Franchise in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That the City Commission of the City of Florida City shall adopt and effectuate a land use plan governing the lands annexed, to be prepared in conjunction and cooperation with the County Planning Department, which shall conform to the comprehensive land use plan and provide for (1) a buffer of single family homes north and west of the canal as shown on the tentative plot of the area, titled "Terra Mia Estates", (2) a park buffer strip of approximately 100 feet along the east side of said plot and (3) a centralized shopping area within the area to be annexed instead of a business strip along Roberts Road as shown on said plat.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 61-35. SOUTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted July 25, 1961)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of South Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of South Miami, Florida, of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>The West½ of the NE¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, less the East 66 feet thereof.</section></section><section>(Ord. No. 61-35, § 1, 7-25-61)</section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said County Franchise in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County.</section><section>This ordinance enacted under and pursuant to the provisions of(B) of the Home Rule Charter and Ordinance No. 60-42, and in compliance with the procedures therein provided, shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its adoption.</section><section>ORD. NO. 61-42. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted Oct. 3, 1961)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described lands situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>That portion of the S½ of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, lying East of the Florida East Coast Railway right-of-way, consisting of approximately 4.3 acres.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said county franchise in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the county.</section><section>ORD. NO. 61-43. NORTH MIAMI BEACH</section><section>(Adopted Oct. 3, 1961)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami Beach are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami Beach, of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>That portion of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of Section 6, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, lying Easterly of State Road No. 9, Dade County, Florida, consisting of approximately 10 acres.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said county franchise in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County.</section><section>ORD. NO. 62-16. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted March 27, 1962)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>All that part of the South Half (S½) of the North Half ( N½) of the Southeast Quarter (SE¼) of the Southwest Quarter (SW¼) of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, lying Westerly of the East Right-of-Way line of the Florida East Coast Railway Company.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said county franchise in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County. (Ord. No. 62-27, § 1, 6-19-62)</section><section>ORD. NO. 62-29. NORTH BAY VILLAGE</section><section>(Adopted July 3, 1962)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of North Bay Village are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to North Bay Village of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>A parcel of submerged land (now filled) in Biscayne Bay situated in Section 9, Township 53 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida,</section><section>Commencing at the ½ mile post on the West line of Section 9, Township 53 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida, run North 88°41′24″ East along the center line of the 79th Street Causeway highway right-of-way (100 feet wide) a distance of 1,560 feet to a point;</section><section>Thence North 1°37′08″ West 55.0 feet to a point of beginning of the parcel of land herein described:<section>Thence North 1°37′08″ West 600.0 feet</section><section>Thence North 88°41′24″ East 400.0 feet</section><section>Thence South 1°37′08″ East 600.0 feet</section><section>Thence South 88°41′24″ West 400.0 feet</section></section><section>to the point of beginning;</section><section>Containing 5.5 acres more or less; plus a five foot (5′) strip bordering the South boundaries of the above described 5.5 acres tract which is described as follows:</section><section>Commence at the intersection of the West line of Section 9, Township 53 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida, with the center line of the N.E. 79th Street Causeway as shown on plat recorded in Plat Book 25, at page 70 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence North 88°41′25″ East along the center line of the aforesaid Northeast 79th Street Causeway for a distance of 1,560 feet to a point, thence North 1°37′8″ West for a distance of 50.0 feet to a point on the North right-of-way line of the said Northeast 79th Street Causeway and the point of beginning of the parcel of land herein described; thence North 88°41′24″ East along the North right-of-way line of the said Northeast 79th Street Causeway for a distance of 400.0 feet to a point, thence North 1°37′8″ West for a distance of 5.0 feet to a point; thence South 88°41′24″ West along a line 5.0 feet North of and parallel with the North right-of-way line of said Northeast 79th Street Causeway for a distance of 4000 feet to a point thence South 1°37′8″ East for a distance of 5.0 feet to the point of beginning of the parcel of land herein described.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said County franchise, and any extensions thereof, in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County.</section><section>ORD. NO. 63-6. MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted March 5, 1963)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, to provide for the annexation to the City of Miami and the inclusion within the official boundaries of such municipality of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>Those certain lands known as "Primrose Park" consisting of approximately 13.2 acres, and more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Commencing at the southeast corner of the Northeast Quarter (NE¼) of Section 2, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, run South 89°59′55″ West along the South line of the Northeast Quarter (NE¼) of Section 2 for a distance of 1360.10 feet more or less to a point of intersection with the Westerly right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railway; thence run North 1°31′38″ East along the said Westerly boundary of the Florida East Coast Railway right-of-way for a distance of 647.27 feet to a point on the Northerly bank of the Tamiami Canal, said point being the Point of Beginning of the hereinafter described parcel of land; thence continue North 1°31′38″ East along said Westerly boundary of the Florida East Coast Railway right-of-way for a distance of 1889.61 feet to a point of intersection with the North line of the Northeast Quarter (NE¼) of said Section 2; thence run North 89°22′35″ West along the said line of the Northeast Quarter (NE¼) of said Section 2 for a distance of 2.86 feet to a point; thence run South 21°31′25″ West along the Easterly boundary of the Seaboard Airline Railroad right-of-way for a distance of 836.46 feet to a point of curvature; thence run Southerly along the arc of a curve to the left having a radius of 1860.08 feet and a central angle of 20°03′30″ for a distance of 651.18 feet to a point of tangency; thence run South 1°27′55″ West along said Easterly boundary of the Seaboard Airline Railroad for a distance of 651.27 feet to a point on the Northerly bank of the Tamiami Canal; thence run North 66°35′44″ East along said Northerly bank of the Tamiami Canal for a distance of 441.44 feet to the Point of Beginning. (Ord. No. 63-6, § 1, 3-5-63)</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said county franchise, and any extensions thereof, in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County. (Ord. No. 63-6, § 2, 3-5-63)</section><section>ORD. NO. 63-17. SOUTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted May 14, 1963)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of South Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of said municipality is hereby amended, to provide for the annexation to the City of South Miami and the inclusion within the official boundaries of said municipality of all the lands described in the schedule attached to and made a part hereof by reference.</section><section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 1<section>Beginning at a point in the centerline of SW 57th Avenue (Red Road), said point being the SE corner of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence run Westerly along the South line of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36 to the SW corner of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36; thence run Northerly along the West line of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36 to the intersection with the North line of the South 528 feet of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36, and centerline of SW 84th Terrace, thence run Easterly along the North line of the South 528 feet of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36, and centerline of SW 84th Terrace; to the intersection with the East line of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36, and the centerline of SW 57th Avenue (Red Road), thence run Southerly along the East line of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36, and the centerline of SW 57th Avenue (Red Road), to the SE corner of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36, and the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 2<section>Beginning at a point at the intersection of the centerline of SW 62 Avenue at the centerline of SW 82 Street, said point being the NW corner of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence running Easterly along the centerline of SW 82 Street, to the centerline of SW 60 Avenue, said point being the NE corner of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, a distance of 660 feet, more or less; thence running Southerly along the centerline of SW 60 Avenue to the SE corner of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36, a distance of 660 feet, more or less; thence running Westerly along the South line of the NW¼ of the SE¼ to the centerline of SW 62 Avenue, said point being the NW corner of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 36, a distance of 660 feet, more or less; thence running Northerly along the centerline of SW 62 Avenue a distance of 660 feet, more or less, to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 3<section>Beginning at the NW corner of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence in a Northerly direction along the centerline of SW 67 Avenue (Ludlam Road) 165 feet, more or less, to the NW corner of the S½ of the S½ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence in an Easterly direction along the North line of the S½ of the S½ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of said Section 36, a distance of 660 feet, more or less, to the NE corner of the S½ of the S½ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of said Section 36, said point also being the Northwest Corner of Lot No. 1, Block 2, of DAVIS MANOR; thence in a Southerly direction along the rear lot line of Lots One and Two, Block Two, of said DAVIS MANOR, 165 feet, more or less, to the NE corner of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence in a Westerly direction along the North line of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of Section 36, a distance of 660 feet, more or less, to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 4<section>Beginning at the intersection of the centerline of the SW 80 Street (Davis Drive) and the centerline of SW 67 Avenue (Ludlam Road); thence in a Northerly direction along the centerline of said SW 67 Avenue to the intersection with the centerline of SW 79 Street, a distance of 250.70 feet, more or less; thence running Easterly along the centerline of Southwest 79 Street to its intersection with the centerline of SW 66 Avenue, a distance of 400 feet, more or less; thence Southerly along the centerline of SW 66 Avenue to the centerline of SW 80 Street (Davis Drive), being also the South line of the NW¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, a distance of 251.65 feet, more or less; thence in a Westerly direction along the centerline of SW 80 Street (Davis Drive) also the South line of the NW¼ of Section 36, to the centerline of SW 67 Avenue (Ludlam) to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 5<section>Beginning at the NW Corner of the S½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of the NE¼ of Section 35, Twp. 54S, Rge. 40 E Dade County, Florida; thence run easterly along the north line of said S½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of the NE¼ to the NW Corner of "Ludlam Groves" according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 51 at Page 48 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run southerly along the west line of Ludlam Groves to a point on the south line of the NE¼ of said Section 35 and the center line of S.W. 80 St. (Davis Drive); thence run westerly along the south line of said NE¼, being the center line of S.W. 80 St. (Davis Drive) to the SW corner of the SE¼ of the NE¼ of said Section 35; thence run northerly along the west line of the SE¼ of the NE¼ of said Section 35 to the NW Corner of the S½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of the NE¼ of said Section 35 and the point of beginning.</section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 7<section>Beginning at the SW corner of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, Dade County, Florida, also being the intersection of the center line of SW 68th Street and the westerly boundary line of Nelson Homesites recorded in Plat Book 39 at Page 57 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run northerly along the Westerly boundary of Nelson Homesites, also being the west line of the aforementioned NE¼ of the SE¼ to the NW corner of said NE¼ of SE¼, being the point of intersection of the center line of SW 69th Avenue and SW 64th Street (Hardee Drive); thence run westerly along the north line of the SE¼ of said, also being the center line of SW 64th Street, (Hardee Drive) to a point on the easterly R/W line of the Florida East Coast Railway Co., Miami Belt Line; thence run northerly along the east boundary line of said Miami Belt Line to a point of intersection with the north line of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said, also being a point on the center line of SW 60th Street; thence run easterly along the north line of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said and the center line of SW 60th Street to the intersection of the center lines of SW 60th Street and SW 69th Avenue, also being the NW corner of the SE¼ of the NE¼ of said; thence run southerly along the west line of said SE¼ of the NE¼ to the SW corner of the N½ of the SE¼ of the NE¼ of said; thence run easterly along the south line of the North½ of the SE¼ of NE¼ of said to the SE corner of the N½ of SE¼ of NE¼ of said, said point being on the center line of SW 67th Avenue (Ludlam Road); thence run southerly along the center line of SW 67th Avenue, (Ludlam Road) also being the east line of the NE¼ and the east line of the SE¼ of said, to the SE corner of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of said; thence run westerly along the south line of the NE¼ of the SE¼ of said to the SW corner thereof and the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 8<section>Beginning at the SW corner of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence in a Northerly direction along the centerline of SW 67 Avenue (Ludlam Road) to the NW corner of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence in an Easterly direction to the NE corner of the W½ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence in a Southerly direction to the SE corner of the W½ of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; thence in a Westerly direction 330 feet, more or less, to the centerline of SW 67 Avenue (Ludlam Road) also the SW corner of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East; to the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section>PARCEL NO. 9<section>Beginning at the NW Corner of the SW¼ of, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, Dade County, Florida, being the intersection of the center line of S.W. 67 Avenue (Ludlam Road) and S.W. 48 Street (Blue Road); thence run Easterly, along the North line of the SW¼ of said, and the center line of S.W. 48 Street (Blue Road) to the NE Corner of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of said; thence run Southerly, along the East line of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of said, to the SE Corner of the N½ of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of said; thence run Westerly along the South line of the N½ of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of said to the SW Corner of the N½ of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of said being a point on the center line of S.W. 67 Avenue (Ludlam Road); thence run Northerly, along the West line of the SW¼ of said and the center line of S.W. 67 Avenue to the NW Corner of the SW¼ of said and the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power and Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said county franchise, and any extensions thereof, in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County.</section><section>ORD. NO. 63-43. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted October 8, 1963)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, to provide for the annexation to the City of Homestead and the inclusion within the official boundaries of such municipality of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>Begin at the NE corner of the S½ of the S½ of the NE¼ of the NW¼,, Township 57 South, Range 38 East; thence run Westerly to the NW corner of the S½ of the S½ of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of said Section 12-57-38; thence run Southerly to the West¼ corner of Section 12-57-38; thence continue Southerly to the SW corner of Section 12-57-38; thence continue Southerly to the West¼ corner of Section 13-57-38; thence continue Southerly to the SW corner of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East; thence run Easterly to the SE corner of the W½ of the West½ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Northerly to the NE corner of the W½ of the W½ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Easterly to the NE corner of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Southerly to the SW corner of the NE¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Easterly to the SE corner of the W½ of the NE¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Northerly to the NE corner of the W½ of the NE½ of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Easterly to the SE corner of the W½ of the NW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence Northerly to the NE corner of the W½ of the NW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence continue Northerly to the SW corner of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of Section 12-57-38; thence run Easterly to the SE corner of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of Section 12-57-38; thence run Northerly to the center of Section 12-57-38; thence run Westerly to the SE corner of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of Section 12-57-38; thence run Northerly to the NE corner of the SW¼ of the NW¼ of Section 12-57-38; thence run Easterly to the SE corner of the NE¼ of the NW¼ of Section 12-57-38; thence run Northerly to the NE corner of the S½ of the S½ of the NE¼ of the NW¼ of Section 12-57-38 to the Point of Beginning.</section><section>Begin at the SW corner of Section 13-57-38; thence run Easterly to the SE corner of the W½ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Northerly to the NE corner of the W½ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Westerly to the NW corner of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Southerly to the Point of Beginning.</section><section>Begin at the SW corner of the E½ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Easterly to the SE corner of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Northerly to the NE corner of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Westerly to the NW corner of the E½ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 13-57-38; thence run Southerly to the Point of Beginning.</section><section>Begin at the NE corner of Lot 4 of WAREHOUSE SUBDIVISION, recorded in Plat Book 32, Page 49, Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run Westerly to the NW corner of said Lot 4; thence Southerly to the SW corner of Lot 9 of said WAREHOUSE SUBDIVISION; thence Easterly to the SE corner of said Lot 9, thence Northerly to the Point of Beginning.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said County franchise, and any extensions thereof, in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County.</section><section>ORD. NO. 63-56. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted December 3, 1963)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended, to provide for the annexation to the City of North Miami and the inclusion within the official boundaries of such municipality of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>That certain real property now in the area which is bounded on the South by the center line of N.W. 119th Street, on the North and West by the present city limit's line of the City of North Miami and on the East by the Westerly boundary of U. S. Interstate Highway No. 95, also known as the North-South Expressway, and more particularly described as containing Tract 1 and Tract 23 and Block 22, less Tract A of NORTH SHORE HEIGHTS, according to the plat thereof, recorded in Plat Book 40, Page 62 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, and Lots 1—10, inclusive, and Lots 27—40, inclusive, Block 4, and Lots 1—15, inclusive, and Lots 28—32, inclusive, Block 9, ALHAMBRA HEIGHTS, according to the plat thereof, recorded in Plat Book 17, Page 54 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, together with the area from the center line of N.W. 119th Street adjacent to said property above described and all streets, alleyways and easements included within the limits of the above described property.</section></section><section>This ordinance is enacted and the annexation of the lands herein described is accomplished upon the express condition and reservation that the same shall be subject to the provisions of County Ordinance No. 60-16 granting an electric franchise to the Florida Power &amp; Light Company, and that Dade County shall continue to receive and collect all franchise revenues derived from the lands hereinabove described during the full term of said County franchise, and any extensions thereof, in the same manner as though such annexed lands remained a part of the unincorporated area of the County.</section><section>ORD. NO. 64-48. SOUTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted October 6, 1964)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of South Miami are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of South Miami of the following described lands situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to-wit:<section>The East 80 feet of Tract 4, BILTMORE HEIGHTS REVISED, recorded in Plat Book 39 at Page 65 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; also formerly known as Lots 23, 24, 25, and the East 5 feet of Lot 22 in Block 4 of BILTMORE HEIGHTS, recorded in Plat Book 21 at Page 34 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>ORD. NO. 65-5. HIALEAH</section><section>(Adopted January 11, 1965)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following described property:<section>The West½ of the West½ of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East, LESS the following described parcel of land: COMMENCE at the Northwest corner of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East; thence run North 86 degrees 59 minutes 59 seconds East along the North line of the Northwest¼ of said for a distance of 100.01 feet to the Point of Intersection with a line that is 100.00 feet East of and parallel to the West line of the Northwest¼ of said, said point also being the Point of Beginning of the following described parcel; thence continue North 86 degrees 59 minutes 59 seconds East along the North line of the Northwest¼ of said for a distance of 603.22 feet; thence run South 49 degrees 26 minutes 41 seconds West for a distance of 703.48 feet to a point that is 140.00 feet East of, as measured at right angles to, the West line of the Northwest¼ of said; thence run South 13 degrees 21 minutes 53 seconds West for a distance of 136.01 feet to the Point of Intersection with a line that is 100.00 feet East of and parallel to the West line of the Northwest¼ of said; thence run North 3 degrees 44 minutes 17 seconds West along the line that is 100.00 feet East of and parallel to the West line of the Northwest¼ of said for a distance of 559.34 feet to the Point of Beginning; ALSO LESS the North 559.34 feet of the West 100 feet of the Northwest¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East, ALSO, subject to the West 100 feet of said described tract for public road purposes, according to the Plat thereof, as recorded in Plat Book 70 at Page 5 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 2487 passed and adopted on September 15, 1964, by the Council of the City of Hialeah, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 65-14. NORTH MIAMI BEACH</section><section>(Adopted March 16, 1965)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami Beach, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami Beach of the following described property:<section>The South 75′ of the East 175′ of the North 157′ of the East½ of the Southeast¼ of the Southeast¼ of the Southeast¼ less the East 25′ Section 7, Township 52 South, Range 42 East; known and designated as 16750 N.E. 10th Avenue, Miami, Florida, said property lying and being in Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 116 passed and adopted on November 17, 1964, by the Council of the City of North Miami Beach, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 63-35. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted May 4, 1965)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The North¾ of the West½ of the NW¼ of the NE¼,, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, containing 15 acres, more or less.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 64-10-1, passed and adopted on October 4, 1964, by the council of the City of Homestead, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 65-36. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted May 4, 1965)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>LOT 2, BLOCK 1, Subdivision of the South½ of the North½ of the Southwest¼ of the Southeast¼ and the North½ of the South½ of the Southwest¼ of the Southeast¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, according to the Plat thereof as recorded in Plat Book 1, Page 93 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 1078, passed and adopted on December 22, 1964, by the council of the City of North Miami, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 66-54. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted October 18, 1966)</section><section>as amended by</section><section>ORD. NO. 67-36. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted May 16, 1967)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:</section><section>   PARCEL A<section>SLS Shopping Center, Plat Book 80, Page 25, a subdivision of Dade County, Florida, as per plat thereof recorded in the Public Records of Dade County, Florida,</section><section>AND</section></section><section>   PARCEL B<section>The E½ of the S½ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East, lying and being situated in Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 1168, passed and adopted March 25, 1966, by the Council of the City of North Miami, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 66-55. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted October 18, 1966)</section><section>as amended by</section><section>ORD. NO. 67-37. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted May 16, 1967)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>The West one-half of the South one-half of the Southeast¼ of the Southeast¼ of the Southeast¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East lying and being situated in Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 1169, passed and adopted on March 25, 1966, by the Council of the City of North Miami, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 67-68. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted September 19, 1967)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>Begin at the SW corner of the North½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida; thence run East along the South line of the North½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said for 169.53 feet; thence run N 29-21-15 E for 381.19 feet to the South line of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of said; thence run East along the South line of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of said to the center line of Little Arch Creek; thence run Southwesterly along the center line of Little Arch Creek to the South line of the North½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said; thence run East along the South line of the North½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said to the Northwest corner of Tract 1 of the Amended Plat of a Portion of Subdivision of a Portion of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, according to the Plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 41 at Page 86 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run Southerly along the West line of said Tract 1, to the Southwest corner of said Tract 1 being on the South line of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said; thence run Westerly along the South line of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said to the Southwest corner of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said; thence run Northerly along the West line of the NW¼ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said to the Point of Beginning.</section><section>AND</section><section>Beginning at the SW corner of the N½ of the N½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, thence run due East along the South line of the North½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of the said for a distance of 169.53 feet, thence run North 29°21′15″ East for a distance 381.19 feet to the South line of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, thence run West 354.53 feet to the NW corner of the N½ of the N½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, thence South 332.25 feet to the place of beginning.</section><section>The above described real estate being also referred to as Parcel No. 2, adjacent to and East of NE 14th Avenue, and North of NE 122nd Street.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 1176, passed and adopted on April 26, 1966, and Resolution No. 1210, passed and adopted on October 11, 1966, by the Council of the City of North Miami, which Resolutions are made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 67-86. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted November 21, 1967)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>The West½ of the SE¼ of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, LESS the North 25 feet and less all of the East 25 feet except the South 330 feet, all lying and being in Dade County, Florida;</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 1177 passed and adopted on April 26, 1966, by the Council of the City of North Miami, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 67-90. VIRGINIA GARDENS</section><section>(Adopted November 21, 1967 as Amended by Ord. No. 68-26, Adopted May 7, 1968)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the Village of Virginia Gardens, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the Village of Virginia Gardens of the following described property:<section>That part of Tract 21 in, Township 53 South, Range 40 East of FLORIDA FRUIT LANDS COMPANY'S SUBDIVISION NO. 1, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 2 at Page 17 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, that lies South of the North line of the South 25 feet of the North½ of said Tract 21 and lies North of the North Right-of-Way line of N.W. 36th Street as said Right-of-Way line is shown on the Right-of-Way Map for the N.W. 36th Street Extension recorded in Plat Book 75 at Page 80 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 168 passed and adopted on February 9, 1966, by the Council of the Village of Virginia Gardens, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 69-4. HIALEAH</section><section>(Adopted January 7, 1969)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following described lands, situate, lying and being in Dade County, Florida, to wit:<section>Sections 27, 28 and 34, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>As set forth in Resolution No. 2633, passed and adopted on March 14, 1966, by the Council of the City of Hialeah, Florida, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 69-23. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted April 1, 1969)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>That part of Tract 1 of the plat recorded in Plat Book 41 at Page 86 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, described as follows:<section>Commence at the Southeast corner of said Tract 1; thence run North along the East line of said Tract 1 for 30 feet; thence run West 300 feet; thence run North 250 feet to the Point of Beginning; thence run East 300 feet; thence run North to the South line of the North½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East; thence run West along the South line of the North½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said for 300 feet; thence run South to the Point of Beginning;</section></section></section><section>in accordance with the terms of Resolution 1274 passed and adopted on September 26, 1967, by the City Council of the City of North Miami, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference, except for that portion of Resolution 1274 containing the legal description of the land to be annexed, which legal description has been modified by the legal description as hereinabove set out in order for the legal description herein to conform with the standard form of legal descriptions used in Dade County, and, further, the modified legal description hereinabove set out changes only the form of the legal description contained in Resolution 1274 and does not in any way describe a different portion of land intended to be described by the City Council of the City of North Miami in Resolution 1274.</section><section>ORD. NO. 69-45. NORTH MIAMI BEACH</section><section>(Adopted July 23, 1969)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami Beach, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of North Miami Beach of the following described property:<section>The North 120 feet of the South 290 feet of the West 110 feet of the West½ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of Section 7, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, lying and being in Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>   AND<section>The North of the West½ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of the SE¼ of Section 7, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida;</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution Nos. R-69-24 and R-69-25, passed and adopted on February 18, 1969, by the Council of the City of North Miami Beach, which Resolutions are made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 69-85. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted November 26, 1969)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The S½ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of Section 7, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, containing 4.72 acres, more or less;</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 69-2-4, passed and adopted on February 17, 1969, by the Council of the City of Homestead, which Resolution is made a part hereof.</section><section>ORD. NO. 70-1. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted January 7, 1970)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>The West 440 feet and the South 30 feet less the West 440 feet of Tract 1 of a portion of a subdivision of the South½ of the North½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ and the North½ of the South½ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 41 at Page 86 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, which contains approximately 3.563 acres,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 1345 passed and adopted on June 24, 1969, by the Council of the City of North Miami, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 70-56. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted July 14, 1970)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>SE¼ of NE¼ of SE¼,, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 1345 passed and adopted on March 16, 1970, by the Council of the City of Homestead, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 70-61. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted July 24, 1970)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the property described on Exhibit A attached hereto and made a part hereof, as set forth in Resolution No. 1412 passed and adopted on June 23, 1970, by the City Council of the City of North Miami, which resolution is made a part hereof as Exhibit B, and Dade County relies upon and accepts all the commitments made therein to it by the City of North Miami.</section><section>The City of North Miami, in requesting the annexation of the above described lands, has expressly agreed that the city will, within 90 days, proceed to sell its entire $12,000,000 General Obligation Bond Issue and pay to the Inter-American Center Authority the net proceeds thereof, after deduction of discount and expenses of sale, said proceeds to be immediately utilized toward the satisfaction of the existing bonded indebtedness of the Inter-American Center Authority.</section><section>The Board of County Commissioners of Dade County, Florida, in approving this annexation by passing and adopting this ordinance, has specifically relief upon the above representations and agreement for payment of the net proceeds of North Miami's $12,000,000 General Obligation Bond Issue to the Inter-American Center Authority to be utilized for the payment of said bonded indebtedness of the Inter-American Center Authority. This ordinance shall be deemed to be invalid, null and void if said net proceeds are not so paid over to the Inter-American Center Authority within 90 days from the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section>It is the legislative intention of the Board of County Commissioners of Dade County, Florida, in adopting this ordinance, that the lands which are the subject matter of this annexation ordinance which are now in public ownership shall be used for public purposes only. If any portion of the said lands shall cease to be owned and controlled by the Inter-American Center Authority or cease to be used for other public purposes as defined by law, said portion of land shall revert to an unincorporated status, and this ordinance shall be null and void, insofar as it pertains to that portion of land, from the date said portion of land ceases to be used for public purposes. This section shall not apply to any portion of publicly owned land which is the subject matter of this annexation ordinance, in the event it is exchanged for any privately owned land included in this annexation ordinance.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance, including but not limited to Sections 2, 3 and 4, are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. This Board hereby declares that it would not have passed this ordinance without enactment of Sections 2, 3 and 4 hereof. If any of the provisions are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null, void and of no force or effect.</section><section>EXHIBIT A. INTERAMA PROPERTY ANNEXATION BY THE CITY OF NORTH MIAMI, LEGAL DESCRIPTION:</section><section>A parcel of land situated in Dade County, Florida, being a portion of Sections 14, 15, 16, 21, 22 and 23, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Begin at a point where the Northerly Right-of-Way line of State Road No. 826 (Sunny Isles Boulevard), extended East, intersects the centerline of the Intracoastal Waterway (PB 37 Pg. 6); thence run Southerly, along the centerline of said Intracoastal Waterway to the intersection with the Easterly extension of the South line of said; thence run Westerly, along the said South line of, to the Southwest corner of said; thence run Westerly, along the South line of said, to the Southwest corner of East½ of the SE¼ of; thence run Northerly, along the West line of said East½ of the SE¼ of, to the Southeast corner of Tract 25 of "Amended Plat of R. E. McDonald's Subdivision," as recorded in Plat Book 2 at Page 22 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run Westerly, along the South line of Tracts 25, 26 and 27 of the last described plat, to the Southwest corner of Tract 27; thence run Northeasterly, along the Westerly line of said Tract 27, to the Southwest corner of Tract 22 of the last described plat; thence run Northerly, along the West line of Tract 22, of last described plat, to the Northwest corner of the South½ of said Tract 22; thence run Easterly along the North line of the South½ of said Tract 22, to the Southwest corner of the East½ of the North½ of said Tract 22; thence run Northerly, along the West line of the East½ of the North½ of said Tract 22, to the Northwest corner of the East½ of the North½ of Tract 22; thence run Easterly, along the North line of said Tract 22, for a distance of 27.12 feet; thence run Northeasterly, along a line parallel to the centerline of Federal Highway State Road No. 4 (PB 34 Pg. 50), presently known as U. S. Highway No. 1, for a distance of 482.26 feet to a point; thence run Westerly, along a line parallel to the South lines of Tracts 11 and 12 of said "Amended Plat of R. E. McDonald's Subdivision" (PB 2 Pg. 22), for a distance of 891.2 feet, more or less, to the intersection with the Easterly Right-of-Way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1; thence run Northeasterly along the Easterly Right-of-Way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1, to the South line of the NW¼ of said; thence run Easterly, along the South line of the NW¼ of, to the enter of said; thence run Northerly, along the East line of the NW¼ of said, and along the West line of Tracts 7, 6 and 3 of said "Amended Plat of R. E. McDonald's Subdivision" (PB 2 Pg. 22) to the Southwest corner of Tract 2, of same plat; thence run Westerly along the South line of the North½ of the North½ of the NW¼ of said, to a point of intersection with the Westerly Right-of-Way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1; thence run Northeasterly, along the Westerly Right-of-Way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1, to the Southeast corner of Lot 3, Block 2 of "Biscayne Boulevard Subdivision One," as recorded in Plat Book 40 at Page 4 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run Westerly, along the South line of said Lot 3, to the intersection with the Easterly Right-of-Way line of Florida East Coast Railway; thence run Northeasterly, along the Easterly Right-of-Way line of said Florida East Coast Railway, to the point of intersection with the Westerly extension of the North line of Lot 2, Block 2 of last described plat; thence run Easterly, along the Westerly extension of the North line of said Lot 2 and along the North line of said Lot 2, to the Southeast corner of Lot 1, Block 2, of same plat; thence run Northeasterly, along the Westerly Right-of-Way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1, to the Southeast corner of Lot 2, Block 1 of said "Biscayne Boulevard Subdivision One" (PB 40 Pg. 4); thence run Westerly, along the South line of said Lot 2 and the Westerly extension thereof, to a point of intersection with the Easterly Right-of-Way line of said Florida East Coast Railway; thence run Northeasterly, along said Easterly Right-of-Way line, to the point of intersection with the Westerly extension of the North line of Lot 3, Block 1 of said "Biscayne Boulevard Subdivision One" (PB 40 Pg. 4); thence run Easterly, along the Westerly extension of the North line of said Lot 3 and along the North line of said Lot 3, to the Northeast corner of said Lot 3; thence run Northeasterly, along the Westerly Right-of-Way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1, to the Southeast corner of Lot 6, Block 1 of same plat; thence run Westerly, along the South line of said Lot 6 and the Westerly extension thereof, to the point of intersection with Easterly Right-of-Way line of the Florida East Coast Railway; thence run Northeasterly, along the said Easterly Right-of-Way line of the Florida East Coast Railway to the point of intersection with the West line of the SE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East; thence run Southerly, along the West line of the SE¼ of said to the Southwest corner of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of said; thence run Easterly, along the South line of the NW¼ of the NW¼ of the SE¼ of said to the Southeast corner of same; thence run Northerly, along the East line of the NW¼, of the NW¼, of the SE¼ of said, and along the East line of the South½ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said, to the Northeast corner of the South½ of the SW¼ of the SW¼, of the NE¼ of said; thence run Westerly along the North line of the South½, of the SW¼, of the SW¼, of the NE¼ of said and the Westerly extension thereof, to the point of intersection with the Westerly Right-of-Way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1; thence run Northeasterly, along said Westerly Right-of-Way line of U. S. Highway No. 1, to a point of intersection with the North line of the South½ of the West½ of the NE¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East; thence run Easterly, along said North line of the South½ of the West½ of the NE¼ of, to the point of intersection with the Northerly Right-of-Way line of State Road No. 826 (Sunny Isles Boulevard); thence run Easterly along the Northerly Right-of-Way line of State Road No. 826 (Sunny Isles Boulevard), to the intersection with the centerline of the Intracoastal Waterway, being the point of beginning.</section><section>LESS the following described parcels of land:</section><section>PARCEL A</section><section>Commence at the NE corner of the SW¼ of said, Township 52 South of Range 42 East; thence run West along the North line of said SW¼, a distance of 400 feet for a point of beginning; thence from said point of beginning run South parallel with the East boundary line of said SW¼ to the Oleta River; thence Southeasterly, easterly and northeasterly meandering on the northerly side of said river to a point on the northwesterly bank of said river 600 feet north of the south boundary line of the NE¼ of said; thence west parallel with the south boundary lines of the NE¼ and the NW¼ of the said section and a distance of 600 feet therefrom for a distance of 1281 feet more or less to a point 600 feet north of point of beginning; thence south parallel with the East boundary line of the NW¼ of said Section a distance of 600 feet to the point of beginning.</section><section>PARCEL B</section><section>For a point of beginning commence at a point 600 feet north of the south boundary line of the NW¼ of said, and a distance of 400 feet West of the east boundary line of said NW¼; thence north parallel with the east boundary line of the said NW¼ to the right-of-way of the public highway running east and west through said; thence run east along said right-of-way a distance of 100 feet more or less to a point on the south line of said highway right-of-way 300 feet west of the east boundary line of said NW¼; thence south to a point 600 feet north of the south boundary line of the NW¼ of said, and 300 feet from the east boundary line of said NW¼; thence 100 feet west to a place of beginning, the same being a strip of land extending from the west 100 feet of Parcel A to the public highway as is now located.</section><section>PARCEL C</section><section>Commence at the Southwest corner of the N½ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said, said corner being 666.59 feet East and 330.385 feet South of the Northwest corner of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said, thence Northerly along the West line of the N½ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said, a distance of 40 feet, thence East parallel with the South line of the N½ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said, a distance of 40 feet to the point of beginning, said point of beginning being marked by an iron pipe, thence westerly a distance of 19.8 feet, more or less to the Easterly line "of right-of-way to be acquired" of State Road No. 4 as shown on the plat of "State Road Department Right-of-way Plans, Road No. 4, Dade County, Florida" recorded in Plat Book 34 at Page 51 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, thence southwesterly along the Easterly line of said "Right-of-way" to a point of intersection with a line drawn parallel to and 160 feet Southerly at right angles to the South line of the N½ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said; thence Easterly 375 feet along said line to a point, thence Northerly at right angles to the last mentioned line 200 feet to a point; thence Westerly along a line parallel to and 40 feet Northerly at right angles from the South line of said N½ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of said, to the point of beginning.</section><section>PARCEL D</section><section>For a point of beginning commence at a point on the easterly line of said State Road No. 4 as shown on the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 34, Page 51 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, where the Southerly line of State Road No. 270 intersects said State Road No. 4, which southerly line is the southerly line of that certain parcel of land conveyed by Sunny Isles Holding Company et al. to the State Road Department, of the State of Florida, by warranty deed dated July 1941, and recorded in Deed Book 2182, page 508 et seq. of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, which parcel of land is shown on a photostatic copy of Right-of-way map of Project 5155, State Road No. 270 revised April 11, 1941, attached to and by reference made a part of said deed; from said point of beginning, which point is marked by an iron pipe set in concrete, run South 83° 21′ 40″ East along the southerly Right-of-way line of said State Road No. 270 according to said revised Right-of-way map, a distance of 27.01 feet to the point of curve of a circular curve to the left as shown on said revised Right-of-way map, which curve has a radius of 6466.26 feet; run thence along said curve to the left and said southerly Right-of-way line through a central angle of 00° 39′ 43″ an arc distance of 74.71 feet to a point, which point is marked by an iron pipe set in concrete; run thence South 4° 09′ East a distance of 100 feet to a point, which point is marked by an iron pipe set in concrete; run thence north 83° 36′ 15.1″ West a distance of 101.72 feet to a point 100 feet South 4° 09′ East of the point of beginning; continue along the last mentioned course a distance of 33.31 feet, more or less, to a point on the easterly right-of-way line of said State Road No. 4, which point is marked by an iron pipe set in concrete; run thence northeasterly along the easterly right-of-way of said State Road No. 4 to the point or place of beginning.</section><section>ORD. NO. 70-81. NORTH MIAMI BEACH</section><section>(Adopted October 27, 1970)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami Beach, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami Beach of the following described property:<section>Commence at the SE corner of the NE¼ of Section 9, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida; thence run Westerly along the South line of the NE¼ of said Section 9 for a distance of 284.98 feet to a point of intersection thereof with the Southwesterly right-of-way line of the Oleta River, said point being the point of beginning of the parcel of land herein described; thence continue in a Westerly direction along the South line of the NE¼ of said Section 9 for a distance of 231.91 feet to a point on the most easterly right-of-way line of U. S. Highway No. 1, the same being State Road No. 5, formerly known as State Road No. 4, as the same is recorded in Plat Book 34 at Pages 49 through 54 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run Northeasterly along the most Easterly right-of-way line of said U. S. Highway No. 1, the same being State Road No. 5 for a distance of 161.80 feet to a point of intersection thereof with the Southwesterly right-of-way line of the Oleta River; thence run Southeasterly along the Southwesterly right-of-way line of the Oleta River for a distance of 234.01 feet to the point of beginning,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. R70-3, as amended, passed and adopted on January 6, 1970, by the Council of the City of North Miami Beach, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORD. NO. 71-7. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted January 6, 1971)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:<section>The South½ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of Section 8, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, Dade County, Florida; AND the South½ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of the SW¼ of said Section 8; AND the West½ of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 70-05-16, passed and adopted on May 4, 1970 by the Council of the City of Homestead, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>The City of Homestead, in requesting the annexation of the above described land, has expressly agreed that said city will not directly or indirectly or by any means whatsoever, authorize, permit or cause to be effected any zoning change to the below described portion of the above described property for a period of one year from the effective date of this ordinance:<section>That portion of the West½ of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, Dade County, Florida, that lies South and East of the South and East right-of-way lines of Central and Southern Florida Flood Control District Canal C-103S in said.</section></section><section>The Board of County Commissioners, in approving this annexation by passing and adopting this ordinance, has specifically relied on the above representation that no zoning changes to any of the above described property would be effected [affected] for a period of one year from the effective date of this ordinance. This ordinance shall be deemed to be invalid, null and void if any zoning changes to the aforesaid property shall be made by said city, without the express consent of this Board within the said time period.</section><section>Pursuant to of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, and Ordinance Nos. 70-84, as amended, and 70-85 as amended, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing with in the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>ORD. NO. 71-26. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted March 16, 1971)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:<section>N½ of the SW¼ of the NE¼ of the SW¼, Section 7, Township 57 South, Range 39 East,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 70-05-15, passed and adopted on May 4, 1970, by the Council of the City of Homestead, which Resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, and Ordinance Nos. 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>ORD. NO. 71-27. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted March 16, 1971)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>SW¼ of the NW¼ of NE¼ of SW¼, Sec. 7, Township 57S, Range 39E, Dade County, Florida, consisting of 2.5 acres more or less, including all improvements thereon,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 70-08-28, passed and adopted on August 17, 1970, by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, and Ordinance Nos. 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>ORD. NO. 73-48. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted September 6, 1972)</section><section>Subject to the remaining provisions of this ordinance, the municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>That part of the SW¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East, Dade County, Florida, lying south of the south right-of-way line of Opa Locka Boulevard,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 1243, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of North Miami, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>It is expressly made a condition precedent to the effectiveness of this ordinance that the County shall receive a resolution of the City of North Miami certifying that the city intends to proceed with the site improvements, namely, those relating to the filling and contouring as specified in the plan originally submitted by the city.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County, (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended) this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 73-74. HIALEAH GARDENS</section><section>(Adopted September 4, 1973)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Hialeah Gardens, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the Town of Hialeah Gardens of the following described property:<section>The west ½ of Tract 17, and all of Tracts 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 27, 28, 29, 30 and 31, in, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, according to the Plat of Florida Fruitlands Company recorded in Plat Book 2, Page 17 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 314, passed and adopted by the Council of the Town of Hialeah Gardens on October 5, 1972, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>ORD. NO. 74-74. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted September 16, 1974)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The west 449 feet of Tract 13, Block 1, Section 17-57-39, Miami Land and Development Company Subdivision, Plat Book 5, page 10, Public Records of Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 73-10-42, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 74-75. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted September 16, 1974)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The SW¼ of the NW¼ of the SW¼, Section 8, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, Public Records of Dade County, Florida, 10 acres, more or less,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 74-02-8, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 74-76. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted September 16, 1974)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:<section>All of the following blocks, lying within the plat of Miami Land and Development Company Subdivision as recorded in Plat Book 5, page 10 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida:<section>Block 1, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 1, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 2, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 4, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 3, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 4, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 1, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section></section></section><section> AND<section>The SW¼ of, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>The NW¼ of, Township 57 South Range 30 East</section></section><section> AND<section>All of Tracts 1 thru 8 and 13 thru 16 both inclusive according to the revised plat of Florida City Park as recorded in Plat Book 33, at page 48 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section> AND<section>Lots 6 and 7 Block 1 and Lots 29 and 30 Block 5 according to the plat of Florida City Park as recorded in Plat Book 16, at page 53 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section> AND<section>A portion of the following blocks, lying within the plat of Miami Land and Development Company Subdivision as recorded in Plat Book 5, at page 10 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida:<section>Block 3, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 4, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 4, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 2, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 3, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 4, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 4, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 1, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 2, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 1, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 3, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 1, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 2, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section><section>Block 2, Township 57 South Range 39 East</section></section><section>the same being more particularly described as follows:<section>Begin at the northwest corner of the northeast one-quarter of said, thence N 88°35′47″ E (all bearings and distances contained herein are derived from Dade County Public Works Department Survey of Township 57 South, Range 39 East) a distance of 2715.84 feet along the north line of said northeast one-quarter to the northwest corner of the northwest one-quarter of said, thence N 88°26′31″ E a distance of 2720.39 feet along the north line of said northwest one-quarter to the southeast corner of the southwest one-quarter of said; thence N 0°22′40″ W a distance of 998.09 feet along the east line of said southwest one-quarter to an intersection with the westerly prolongation of the north line of Lots 15 thru 20 inclusive Block 4 of said; thence N 89°41′41″ E a distance of 1357.31 feet along the north line of said Lots 15 thru 20 inclusive to the northeast corner of said Lot 20; thence N 0°27′45″ W a distance of 333.11 feet along the west line of Lot 27, Block 4 to the northwest corner thereof; thence N 89°40′39″ E a distance of 1356.82 feet along the north line of said Lot 27 and a prolongation thereof, to the east line of the southeast one-quarter of said; thence N 89°37′30″ E along the prolongation of the north line of Lot 14 and Lot 27, Block 4 of said subdivision of said, a distance of 2667.38 feet to an intersection with the east line of the southwest one-quarter of said; thence N 89°34′01″ E along the westerly prolongation of and the north line thereof of Lot 14, Block 4 of said subdivision of said a distance of 1334.32 feet to the northeast corner thereof; thence S 0°22′26″ E along the east line of said Lot 14 and Lot 20, Block 4 and a prolongation thereof a distance of 1332.75 feet to a point on the north line of the northeast one-quarter of said; thence N 89°31′46″ E along the north line of said northeast one-quarter of said a distance of 444.41 feet to the northerly prolongation of the east line of Lot 5 Block 1 of said subdivision of said; thence S 0°29′02″ E along the east line of said Lot 5 a distance of 1002.10 feet to the southeast corner thereof; thence N 89°31′56″ E along the north line and the easterly prolongation thereof of Lot 28 of said Block 1 a distance of 889.00 feet to an intersection with the east line of the northeast one-quarter of said; thence S 0°29′41″ E along the east line of said northeast one-quarter of a distance of 668.10 feet to an intersection with the westerly prolongation of the north line of Lots 15 thru 26 inclusive Block 2, of said subdivision of said; thence N 89°34′52″ E along the prolongation of, and the north lines thereof of said Lots 15 thru 26 inclusive to the east line of the northwest one-quarter of said a distance of 2677.61 feet; thence S 0°26′40″ E along the east line of said northwest one-quarter of, a distance of 1002.48 feet to the northwest corner of the southeast one-quarter of said; thence N 89°35′18″ E along the north line of said southeast one-quarter a distance of 2671.84 feet to the northwest corner of the southwest one-quarter of said; thence N 89°31′05″ E along the north line of said southwest one-quarter a distance of 2680.99 feet to the northeast corner thereof; thence S 0°19′00″ E along the east line of said southwest one-quarter a distance of 2707.95 feet to the northeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of said; thence S 0°02′02″ W along the east line of said northwest one-quarter a distance of 2668.83 feet to the southeast corner thereof; thence S 89°23′22″ W along the south line of said northwest one-quarter a distance of 2678.31 feet to the southeast corner of the northeast one-quarter of said; thence S 89°39′39″ W along the south line of said northwest one-quarter a distance of 2657.91 feet to the southeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of said; thence S 89°39′39″ W along the south line of said northwest one-quarter a distance of 2657.90 feet to the southeast corner of the northeast one-quarter of said; thence S 89°34′48″ W along the south line of said northeast one-quarter a distance of 2668.60 feet to the southeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of said; thence S 89°34′47″ W along the south line of said northwest one-quarter a distance of 2668.47 feet to the southeast corner of the northeast one-quarter of said; thence S 89°26′49″ W along the south line of said northeast one-quarter a distance of 2709.41 feet to the southeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of said; thence S 89°26′50″ W along the south line of said northwest one-quarter a distance of 2712.36 feet to the southwest corner thereof; thence N 0°29′00″ W along the west line of said northwest one-quarter a distance of 2672.79 feet to the southeast corner of the southeast one-quarter of said; thence S 89°30′38″ W along the south line of said southeast one-quarter a distance of 2041.95 feet to the southwest corner of the east one-half of the west one-half of the southeast one-quarter of said; thence N 0°31′33″ W along the west line of the east one-half of the west one-half of said southeast one-quarter of said a distance of 2684.41 feet to the north line of said southeast one-quarter of said; thence S 89°12′03″ W along the south line of the northeast one-quarter of said a distance of 679.17 feet to the southwest corner thereof; thence N 0°36′48″ W along the west line of said northeast quarter a distance of 2617.55 feet to the point of beginning,</section></section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 74-04-25, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 74-77. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted September 16, 1974)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>Lots 7 through 12 inclusive, Lot 13 less the west 449 feet thereof, Lot 14 less the south 115 feet thereof, all in Block 1, Miami Land and Development Company Subdivision of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East as recorded in Plat Book 5, at page 10 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, and the unnumbered tract in the amended plat of Cocoapalm Village as recorded in Plat Book 35, at page 4 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, less the area lying to the southeast of the SE line of the right-of-way of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike as recorded in Plat Book 88 at page 13 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:<section>Begin at the northeast corner of the northeast one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, thence S 2°24′21″ E a distance of 1664.32 feet along the east line of said northeast one-quarter to the southeast corner of said amended plat of Cocoapalm Village; thence S 89°27′31″ W a distance of 1349.27 feet along the south line of said plat to the southwest corner thereof; thence N 2°05′31″ W a distance of 115.04 feet along the west line of said plat to a point on a line 115 feet north of and parallel to the south line of Lot 14, Block 1 of said plat of Miami Land and Development Company Subdivision of said, thence S 89°27′31″ W a distance of 1348.64 feet along said parallel line to a point of intersection with the west line of the northeast one-quarter of said; thence N 1°46′32″ W along said west line a distance of 215.38 feet to an intersection with an extension of the north line of said Lot 14; thence N 89°24′31″ E along the north line of said Lot 14 a distance of 449.10 feet to an intersection with a line that is 449 feet east of and parallel to the west line of said Lot 14; thence N 1°46′32″ W along said parallel line a distance of 330.80 feet to the north line of Lot 13 of said Miami Land and Development Company Subdivision of said; thence S 89°21′30″ W a distance of 449.09 feet along the north line and a prolongation of said north line of said Lot 13 to an intersection with the west line of the northeast one-quarter of said; thence N 01°46′32″ W along the west line of said northeast one-quarter a distance of 991.23 feet to the northwest corner of said northeast one-quarter; thence N 89°12′25″ E along the north line of said northeast one-quarter a distance of 2680.00 feet to the point of beginning, less the area lying to the southeast of the SE line of the right-of-way of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike as recorded in Plat Book 88 at page 13 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section></section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 74-78. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted September 16, 1974)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The southeast one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the northeast one-quarter of the northeast one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 74-04-25, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 74-79. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted September 16, 1974)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The northwest one-quarter of the northeast one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 74-04-25, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 74-80. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted September 16, 1974)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The northeast one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, less the north 329 feet of the west 265 feet and less the north 430.5 feet of the east 1,037.5 feet, Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 74-04-25, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 75-93. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted November 4, 1975)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>All of Block 4, Oleander Park, Plat Book 21, page 74, Public Records of Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 73-12-55, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 80-131. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted November 18, 1980)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The east 220 feet of the north one-half of the northwest one-fourth of the northeast one-fourth of the northeast one-fourth,, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, lying and being in Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 78-09-31, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORD. NO. 80-134. NORTH MIAMI</section><section>(Adopted December 2, 1980)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following described property:<section>Replat of Block 12 and a portion of Block 1, Sans Souci Estates, Plat Book 65-20, part of Lots 2 and 3, Block 12-A, Beg. 24.65 feet northwest of southeast corner, Lot 2 north 66.92 feet, west 50 feet, south 33.95 feet, southeasterly 59.88 feet to POB</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. R-79-64, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of North Miami, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 81-28. HOMESTEAD</section><section>(Adopted March 17, 1981)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following described property:<section>The west 491 feet of the south one-half of the south one-half of the northwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of Section 7, Township 57, Range 39, of Dade County, Florida,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 80-12-37, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference. (Ord. No. 81-51, § 1, 5-5-81)</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 82-117. MIAMI SPRINGS</section><section>(Adopted December 21, 1982)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Miami Springs, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Miami Springs of the following described property:<section>A portion of the northeast quarter of, Township 53 South, Range 41 East, Dade County, Florida, more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Begin at the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of said; thence run south 1 degree 43 minutes 05 seconds east along the west line of the northeast quarter of said for a distance of 1307.89 feet to a point; thence run north 88 degrees 16 minutes 55 seconds east for a distance of 478.00 feet to a point; thence run north 1 degree 43 minutes 05 seconds west for a distance of 1.37 feet to a point on curve, said point bears south 5 degrees 24 minutes 35 seconds east from the center of said curve; thence run easterly and northerly along said curve having a radius of 670.00 feet through a central [angle] of 46 degrees 48 minutes 30 seconds for an arc distance of 547.36 feet to a point of tangency; thence run tangent to the aforementioned curve north 37 degrees 46 minutes 55 seconds east for a distance of 114.00 feet to a point; thence north 61 degrees 17 minutes 29 seconds west for a distance of 748.37 feet to a point on a circular curve concave to the southeast, said point bears north 50 degrees 30 minutes 43 seconds west from the center of said curve; thence run northerly and easterly along said curve having a radius of 869.93 feet through a central angle of 29 degrees 21 minutes 04 seconds for an arc distance of 445.64 feet to the point of tangency; thence run north 68 degrees 50 minutes 21 seconds east tangent to the aforementioned curve for a distance or 102.07 feet to the point of intersection with the center line of N.W. South River Drive; thence northwesterly along the center line of N.W. South River Drive to a point of intersection with north line of northeast quarter of said; thence westerly along the north line of the northeast quarter of said to the point of beginning as set forth in Resolution No. 82-2667, passed and adopted by the Council of City of Miami Springs, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section></section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 84-16. MIAMI SPRINGS</section><section>(Adopted February 7, 1984)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Miami Springs, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Miami Springs of the following described property:<section>A portion of the northeast quarter of, Township 53 South, Range 41 East, Dade County, Florida, described as follows: Tract A, commence at the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of, Township 53 South, Range 41 East, Dade County, Florida; thence run north 87 degrees 59 minutes 26 seconds east along the north line of said for a distance of 50 feet to a point; thence run south 1 degree 43 minutes 05 seconds east along a line parallel to and 50 feet east of the west line of the said northeast one-half [quarter] for a distance of 1,307.89 feet to a point; thence run north 88 degrees 16 minutes 55 seconds east for a distance of 69.86 feet to a point being the beginning of a curve concave to the southeast and having a tangent bearing of north 7 degrees 18 minutes 06 seconds east through said point; thence run northeasterly along said curve having a central angle of 2 degrees 19 minutes 15 seconds and a radius of 2,817.93 feet for an arc distance of 114.14 feet to the end of said curve; thence run north 9 degrees 37 minutes 21 seconds east for a distance of 210.35 feet to the beginning of a curve to the right; thence run northeasterly along said curve to the right having a radius of 919.93 feet through a central angle of 29 degrees 16 minutes 22 seconds for an arc distance of 470 feet to a point; thence run south 61 degrees 17 minutes 29 seconds east for a distance of 50.83 feet to a point on a circular curve concave to the southeast and the point of beginning of the parcel of land herein described; thence continue south 61 degrees 17 minutes 29 seconds east for a distance of 748.37 feet to a point; thence run south 37 degrees 46 minutes 55 seconds west for a distance of 114.0 feet to the beginning of a tangential circular curve; thence run in a southwesterly direction along said circular curve having a radius of 670 feet through a central angle of 46 degrees 48 minutes 30 seconds for an arc distance of 547.36 feet to a point, the center of the aforesaid circular curve bears north 5 degrees 24 minutes 35 seconds west from said point; thence run south 1 degree 43 minutes 05 seconds east along a line parallel to and 528 feet east of the west line of the northeast quarter of said for a distance of 503.37 feet to a point; thence run south 88 degrees 16 minutes 55 seconds west for a distance of 478.0 feet to a point 50 feet east of the west line of the northeast quarter of the said; thence run south 1 degree 43 minutes 05 seconds east along a line parallel to and 50 feet east of the west line of the northeast one-half [quarter] of the said for a distance of 200 feet to a point of intersection thereof with the northerly right-of-way line of the Seaboard Airline Railroad; thence run north 83 degrees 38 minutes 43 seconds east along the northerly right-of-way line of the Seaboard Airline Railroad for a distance of 1,065.53 feet to the beginning of a tangential circular curve; thence run in a northeasterly direction along the northwesterly right-of-way line of the Seaboard Airline Railroad and along said circular curve having a radius of 855.336 feet through a central angle of 75 degrees 31 minutes 15 seconds for an arc distance of 1,127.41 feet to a point of intersection thereof with the southwesterly right-of-way line of NW South River Drive; thence run north 50 degrees 51 minutes 06 seconds west along the southwesterly right-of-way line of NW South River Drive for a distance of 1,360.11 feet to a point; thence run south 68 degrees 50 minutes 21 seconds west for a distance of 67.07 feet to the beginning of a tangential circular curve; thence continue in a southwesterly direction along said circular curve being concave to the southeast having a radius of 869.93 feet through a central angle of 29 degrees 21 minutes 04 seconds for an arc distance of 445.64 feet to the point of beginning of the parcel of land herein described as set forth in Resolution No. 83-2699, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Miami Springs, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section></section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 85-92. NORTH MIAMIBEACH</section><section>(Adopted October 15, 1985)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami Beach, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami Beach of the property attached hereto as Exhibit A. The City Council of the City of North Miami Beach passed and adopted on June 18, 1985, Resolution No. R85-45, a copy of which is attached hereto as Exhibit B.<section>A portion of the southwest quarter of Section 5, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, together with a portion of the southeast quarter of Section 6, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida, more particularly described as follows: Begin at the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said Section 5, also being the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of said Section 6; thence run westerly along the north line of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of said Section 6, to the intersection with the southwesterly right-of-way line of Snake Creek Canal (C-9); thence run northwesterly along the southwesterly right-of-way line of Snake Creek Canal (C-9) to its intersection with the southeasterly right-of-way line of State Road 9; thence southwesterly along the southeasterly right-of-way line of State Road 9 to the intersection with the west line of the east half of the southeast quarter of said Section 6; thence run southerly along the west line of the east half of the southeast quarter of said Section 6, to the intersection with the south line of said Section 6; thence easterly along the south line of said Section 6, to the intersection of the base line of Miami Gardens Drive, as recorded in plat book 80 at page 94 of the public records of Dade County, Florida; said point also known as the southwest corner of said Section 5; thence easterly along the south line of said Section 5, to the intersection with the southwesterly right-of-way line of Snake Creek Canal (C-9); thence run northwesterly along the southwesterly right-of-way line of Snake Creek Canal (C-9) to the intersection with said base line of Miami Gardens Drive; thence run northeasterly along said baseline of Miami Gardens Drive to the intersection of the north line of the south half of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said Section 5; thence run westerly along the north line of the south half of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said Section 5 to the northeast corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said Section 5; thence run south 87 degrees 39 minutes 37 seconds west, along the north line of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said Section 5, for 116 feet; thence run south 67 degrees 53 minutes 49 seconds west for 98.98 feet; thence run south 83 degrees 38 minutes 24 seconds west for 120.6 feet; thence run northerly along the west line of the east half of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said Section 5, to the intersection with the north line of the southwest quarter of the southwest of the southwest quarter of said Section 5; thence run westerly along the north line of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said Section 5 to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 86-96MEDLEY(Adopted December 16, 1986)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Medley, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the Town of Medley of the following property:<section>Tract, Sunny Glade Farms, according to the plat thereof, as recorded in Plat Book 8 at Page 73 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, as set forth in Resolution No. C-459, passed and adopted by the Council of the Town of Medley, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section></section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85, as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 88-99HOMESTEAD(Adopted October 18, 1988)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the property legally described on the attached Exhibit "A" and Resolution No. R-87-12-48, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to Sections, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended and 70-85, as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that (1) the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County and (2) the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department will retain the water and [sewer authority.]</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 90-80MEDLEY(Adopted July 24, 1990)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Medley, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the Town of Medley of the following property:<section>Tract 50; Tract 51 and 52, less the east 35 feet; Tracts 54 through 56 inclusive; Tract 57 less the west 35 feet and less the south 35 feet; Tract 58, less the west 35 feet; Tract 59; Tracts 60, 61, 62 and 63, less the west 35 feet; and Tract 64, less the west 35 feet and less the north 35 feet, of FLORIDA FRUIT LAND COMPANY'S SUBDIVISION, in Section 5, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, according to the plat thereof, as recorded in Plat Book 2 at Page 17 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; Together with existing excavations, permits and bonds; and with all roads and streets within said area extending to the centerline of the right-of-way of all bordering and adjacent roads and streets, as set forth in Resolution No. C-521, passed and adopted by the Town Council of the Town of Medley, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section></section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 90-112NORTH MIAMI BEACH(Adopted September 25, 1990)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami Beach, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of North Miami Beach of the following property:<section>A portion of the NW ¼ of the SE ¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East, Dade County, Florida more particularly described as follows;</section><section>Commence at the SE Corner of NW ¼ of the SE ¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 41 East, said point being at the intersection of the centerline of North Miami Avenue and the centerline of NW 171st Street as shown on the Plat of PARKWAY ESTATES as recorded in Plat Book 64 at Page 37 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run S 89°39′42″ W along the centerline of said NW 171st Street a distance of 511.00 feet, more or less, to a point of intersection with the southerly extension of the east line of Lot 12 in Block 2 of said plat of PARKWAY ESTATES said point being the Point of Beginning of the herein described tract of land; thence N 00°23′08″ W along the southerly extension of the east line of said Lot 12 and along the east line of said Lot 12 a distance of 125.00 feet more or less to the NE corner of said Lot 12; thence N 89°39′42″E along the south line of Lot 6 of said Block 2 a distance of 75.00 feet more or less to the SE corner of said Lot 6; thence N 00°23′08″ W along the east line of said Lot 6 and its northerly extension, a distance of 125.00 feet more or less to its intersection with the centerline of NW 171st Terrace, as shown on said plat of PARKWAY ESTATES; thence S 89°39′42″W along the centerline of said NW 171st Terrace a distance of 163.39 feet more or less to a point of curvature of a circular curve to the right, having as its elements a Radius of 50 feet and a central angle of 49°43′40″; thence westerly and northwesterly along the arc of said curve a distance of 43.40 feet to a point of tangency; thence run N 40°35′38″W a distance of 75.00 feet more or less, along the centerline of said NW 171st Terrace and its northwesterly extension, to a point of the easterly right-of-way line of State Road #9 as shown on said plat; thence run S 49°23′22″W along said easterly right-of-way line a distance of 194.77 feet more or less to a point; thence run S 42°47′35″W along said easterly right-of-way line a distance of 271.40 feet to a point of intersection with the centerline of said NW 171st Street; thence run N 89°39′42″ E along the centerline of NW 171st Street a distance of 510.49 feet more or less to the Point of Beginning.</section><section>Includes Subdivision PB 64-37, Block 2, Lots 1—6 and 12—14 and intervening right-of-way, of NW 171st Street,</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. R90-15, passed and adopted by the City Council of the City of North Miami Beach, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 90-148</section><section>CITY OF MEDLEY</section><section>(Adopted December 18, 1990)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Medley, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such munici-pality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the Town of Medley of the following property:<section></section><section>Tracts 41 and 42 of Florida Fruit Land Company's Subdivision No. 1, of Section 3, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 2, Page 17, of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, Less that portion beginning at the northeast corner of said tract 42; thence westerly along the north line of said tract 42, a distance of 31.11 feet to a point on the southwesterly right-of-way line of Florida East Coast Railroad; thence southeasterly along said Florida East Coast Railroad right-of-way line, a distance of 40.79 feet to a point on the east line of Tract 42; thence northerly along the east line of Tract 42, a distance of 25.60 feet to the Point of Beginning; and with all roads and streets within said area extending to the centerline of the right-of-way of all bordering and adjacent roads and streets;</section><section></section><section>The north 230.80 feet of Section 9 of Florida Fruit Land Company's Subdivision No. 1 of Section 9, Township 53 South, Range 40 East according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 2, at Page 17, of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; and with all roads and streets within said area extending to the centerline of the right-of-way of all bordering and adjacent roads and streets;</section><section></section><section>The North 251.46 feet of the West ¾, N.W. ¼ of Section 10, Township 53 South, Range 40 East Dade County, Florida; and with all roads and streets within said area extending to the centerline of the right-of-way of all bordering and adjacent roads and streets;</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. C-528, passed and adopted by the Town Council of the Town of Medley, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remain a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 90-149</section><section>CITY OF MEDLEY</section><section>(Adopted December 18, 1990)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Medley, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the Town of Medley of the following property:<section>A tract of land lying in the northeast ¼ of the northeast ¼ of the northeast ¼ of Section 10, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, Dade County, Florida, and being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>That portion of the northeast ¼ of the northeast ¼ of the northwest ¼ that lies northeasterly of the northeasterly right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railway.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. C-537, passed and adopted by the Town Council of the Town of Medley, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 91-72</section><section>CITY OF MIAMI BEACH</section><section>(Adopted July 9, 1991)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Miami Beach, Florida are hereby changed, contracted and reduced, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the separation from the City of Miami Beach of the following property:<section>A portion of Section 10, Township 54, South Range 42 East, Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Commence at the north-northwest corner of "Lindisfarne on Fisher Island Section 3" according to the plat thereof as recorded in Plat Book 135, Page 15 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence south 65°13′00″ east along the north line of the aforementioned "Lindisfarne of Fisher Island Section 3″ a distance of 786.41 feet to the point of beginning of the herein described property; thence continue south 65°13′00″ east along said north line a distance of 233.35 feet; thence north 27°39′54″ west a distance of 124.28 feet; thence south 55°23′23″ west a distance of 44.69 feet of the Point of Beginning.</section><section>Said lands situate, lying and being on Fisher Island, Dade County, Florida and containing 0.231 acres or less.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution 90-20033, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Miami Beach, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>The County shall collect and reserve all applicable electric franchise revenues, utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the subject area in the same manner as other parts of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 91-135CITIES OF NORTH MIAMIAND NORTH MIAMI BEACH(Adopted November 5, 1991)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of (a) the City of North Miami, Florida, are hereby changed, contracted, and reduced, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the separation from the City of North Miami and (b) the City of North Miami Beach, Florida are hereby changed, expanded and increased, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the addition to the City of North Miami Beach of the following, approximately 1.22 acre property:<section>Lots 2 and 3 of Block 2 of Biscayne Boulevard Subdivision One Sunny Isles according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 40 at Page 4 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>as set forth in City of North Miami Beach Resolution RS 91-22 and City of North Miami Resolution R-91-22 which resolutions are made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>The municipal boundaries of (a) the City of North Miami Beach, Florida, are hereby changed, contracted and reduced, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the separation from the City of North Miami Beach and (b) the City of North Miami, Florida are hereby changed, expanded and increased, and the Charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the addition to the City of North Miami of the following approximately 6.26 acre property:<section>Begin at the Southeast corner of the Northwest ¼ of said, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, also known as the center of said, thence run S 87°, 38′ 52″ W, along the South line of said northwest ¼, 983.86 feet (983.96′ deed) to the point of intersection with the easterly right-of-way line of Biscayne Boulevard (SR5-US1), as shown on right-of-way map recorded in Plat Book 34 at page 50 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, thence run N 15°, 22′ 28″ E, along said easterly right-of-way line, for 300.02 feet (299.37′ deed), to the southwest corner of a tract of land platted as "L G Smith Tract", according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 67 at page 1 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, thence run N 86°, 52′ 53″ E, along the southerly boundary of the last described plat and easterly extension thereof for 891.64 feet to the point of intersection with east line of the northwest ¼, of said, thence run S 2°, 32′ 03″ E, along said East line of the northwest ¼, for 297.70 feet to the southeast corner of said Northwest ¼, being the point of beginning.</section></section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami Beach, Florida, are hereby changed, expanded, and increased, and the charter of such municipality hereby amended by the addition to the City of North Miami Beach of the following, approximately .15 acre property:<section>That portion of a 30-foot right-of-way known as EARL LANE as shown on the plat of BISCAYNE BOULEVARD SUBDIVISION ONE SUNNY ISLES according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 40 at Page 4 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, lying south of the westerly prolongation of the South line of Lot 3 in Block 2 and lying north of the westerly prolongation of the south line of Lot 6 in Block 2 and lying easterly of the easterly right-of-way line of Florida East Coast Railway.</section></section><section>as set forth in City of North Miami Beach Resolution R 91-21 passed and adopted by the City Council of the City of North Miami Beach, which resolution is made a part hereby by reference.</section><section>The County shall collect and reserve all applicable electric franchise revenues, utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the area described in Section 3 in the same manner as other parts of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 91-136TOWN OF MEDLEY(Adopted November 5, 1991)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Medley, Florida, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the Town of Medley of an approximately 20 acre area described as follows:<section>A tract of land lying in the southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ and the East ¼ of the northwest ¼ of Section 10, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Commence at the northeast corner of the southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ of said Section 10; thence run south 01°46′17″ east along the east line of the said southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ for a distance of 261.16 feet to a point of intersection with the southwesterly right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railway said point being the Point of Beginning of the tract of land hereinafter described; thence continue south 01°46′17″ east for a distance of 289.01 feet to a point of intersection with a line 550 feet south of and parallel with the north line of the southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ of said Section 10; thence run south 89°39′15″ west along a line parallel with the north line of the southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ of said Section 10 for a distance of 358.96 feet to a point; thence run north 69°14′30″ west for a distance of 232.72 feet to a point; thence run north 01°14′17″ east for a distance of 231.59 feet to a point; thence run north 87°23′26″ west for a distance of 823.88 feet to a point; thence run north 54°42′31″ west for a distance of 229.55 feet to a point; thence run north 01°15′19″ west for a distance of 697.83 feet to a point; thence run north 45°11′14″ west for a distance of 616.34 feet to a point on the west line of the east ¼ of the northwest ¼ of said Section 10; thence run north 01°47′16″ west along the said west line for a distance of 244.44 feet to a point of intersection with the north line of the northwest ¼ of said Section 10; thence run north 89°39′13″ east along the north line of the northwest ¼ of said Section 10 for a distance of 96.43 feet to a point on the southwesterly right-of-way line of Florida East Coast Railway; thence run south 50°58′09″ east along the said southwesterly right-of-way line for a distance of 744.38 feet to a point on the east line of the northwest ¼ said Section 10; thence run south 01°48′11″ east along the said east line for a distance of 848.66 feet to the northwest corner of the southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ of said Section 10; thence run north 89°39′15″ east along the north line of the southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ of said Section 10 for a distance of 1012.12 feet to a point on the southwesterly right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railway; thence run south 50°58′09″ east for a distance of 411.54 feet to the Point of Beginning.</section><section>AND …</section><section>That portion of the southwest ¼ of the northeast ¼ of said Section 10 which lies northeasterly of the northeasterly right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railway as set forth in Resolution No. C-554, passed and adopted by the Town Council of the Town of Medley, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section></section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void, or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 95-43CITY OF HOMESTEAD(Adopted March 7, 1995)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:<section></section><section>The southeast one-quarter of the southeast one-quarter of the northeast one-quarter of, Township 57 south, Range 38 east, Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:<section>Commence at the northwest corner of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence N89°21'04"E along the north line of said southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned, a distance of 1993.62 feet to the point of beginning, said point also being the southwest corner of the southeast one-quarter of the southeast one-quarter of the northeast one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence N00°56'16"W a distance of 667.03 feet; thence N89°22'29"E a distance of 664.42 feet to the east line of the aforementioned; thence S00°56'52"E along said east line, a distance of 666.76 feet to the east one-quarter corner of the aforementioned; thence N89°21'04"E a distance of 664.54 feet to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>Said parcel contains 10.126 acres, more or less.</section><section></section><section>A parcel of land lying in Sections 7 and 8, Township 57 south, Range 39 east, Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:<section>Commence at the northwest corner of the northeast one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 8; thence N00°58'41"W a distance of 663.88 feet to the point of beginning, said point also being the southeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 8; thence S89°14'14"W a distance of 667.99 feet to the southwest corner of the northwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 8; thence S00°54'50"E a distance of 664.05 feet to the southeast corner of the north one-half of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 7; thence S89°10'34"W, along the south line of the north one-half of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 7, a distance of 1692.20 feet, to an intersection with the northwesterly right-of-way line as depicted on the plat of oleander park as recorded in Plat Book 21 at page 74 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence N41°16'56"E, along said right-of-way of Dixie Highway, a distance of 526.38 feet to an intersection with the west line of the northeast one-quarter of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 7; thence N00°55'48"W a distance of 937.31 feet to the northwest corner of the northeast one-quarter of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 7; thence N89°09'55"E a distance of 1338.91 feet to the northeast corner of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 7; thence N89°15'05"E a distance of 667.25 feet to the northeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 8; thence S00°58'41"E a distance of 663.38 feet to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>Said parcel contains 52.573 acres, more or less.</section></section><section>As set forth with respect to Parcels 1 and 2 in Resolution No. R93-04-23, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 96-11CITY OF HOMESTEAD(Adopted January 16, 1996)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:<section></section><section>A parcel of land lying in Sections 10, 11, 14, 15, 22 and 23 Township 57 South, Range 39 East, Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Commence at the northeast corner of the southeast one-quarter of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 9; thence north 89°22′13″ east a distance of 2677.80 feet to the northeast corner of the south one-half of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 10; thence north 89°22′13″ east a distance of 2677.80 feet to the northeast corner of the south one-half of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 10; thence south 01°47′20″ east, along the east line of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 10, a distance of 412.16 feet to an intersection with a line parallel with and 907.66 feet north of the south line of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned, thence north 89°10′26″ east, along said parallel line, a distance of 2361.98 feet; thence south 01°47′20″ east, along a line parallel with the east line of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 10, a distance of 907.66 feet to an intersection with the south line of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence north 89°10′26″ east a distance of 295.57 feet to the northeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence south 00°51′04″ east a distance of 2784.68 feet to the northeast corner of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence south 00°33′46″ east a distance of 2658.04 feet to the northeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence south 00°23′20″ east a distance of 2676.52 feet to the northeast corner of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence south 89°31′05″ west a distance of 2680.99 feet to the southeast corner of the northeast one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence south 89°35′18″ west a distance of 2671.84 feet to the southeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence north 00°26′40″ west, along the east line of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned, a distance of 1002.48 feet; thence south 89°34′52″ west, along the south line of Lots 14 and 27, Block 2, according to the "Plat of Lands Belonging to the Miami Land Development Company" as recorded in Plat Book 5, page 10, of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida, a distance of 2677.61 feet to an intersection with the west line of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence north 00°29′41″ west a distance of 1670.25 feet to the northwest corner of the aforementioned; thence north 00°19′37″ west a distance of 2663.75 feet to the northwest corner of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence north 00°16′00″ west a distance of 2735.67 feet to the northwest corner of the aforementioned; thence north 02°32′30″ west a distance of 1331.37 feet to the point of beginning.</section><section>Said parcel contains 1,641.358 acres, more or less.</section></section><section>as set forth with respect to Parcel 3 in Resolution No. R93-04-23, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 96-27CITY OF CORAL GABLES(Adopted February 16, 1996)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Coral Gables are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Coral Gables of the following property:<section>Annexation of Pine Bay Estates Subdivision</section><section>Begin at the southeast corner of, Township 55 South, Range 40 East, Dade County, Florida, (being the intersection of S.W. 120 street and S.W. 57 Avenue); thence northerly along the east line of said and along S.W. 57 Avenue to its intersection with the easterly extension of the north line of Block 1 of Pine Bay Estates Section No. 1, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 82 at page 24 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run westerly along said north line of said Block 1 and its easterly and westerly extensions, to its intersection with the centerline of S.W. 60 Avenue; thence southerly along the centerline of said S.W. 60 Street to its intersection with the westerly extension of the south line of Block 4 of said Pine Bay Estates Section No. 1; thence easterly along said extended line and the south line of said Block 4 to the northwest corner of Lot 3, in Block 4 of Pine Bay Estates Section No. 2, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 87 at page 83 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence south along the west line of said Lot 3 to the southwest corner thereof; thence east along the south line of said Lot 3 to the northwest corner of Lot 4 in said Block 4; thence southerly along the west line of said Lot 4 and its southerly extension to its intersection with the south line of aforementioned, thence easterly along said south line of and along S.W. 120 Street to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 28845, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Coral Gables, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference. The boundaries of the proposed Village of Pinecrest are hereby changed, in accordance with the proposed Village charter, by the annexation of the Pine Bay Estates Subdivision, as described herein, to the City of Coral Gables.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of its enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 96-57CITY OF FLORIDA CITY(Adopted May 7, 1996)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Florida City, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Florida City of the following property:<section></section><section>The Northeast ¼ of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, and the West ½ of the West ½ of the Southeast ¼ of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, Dade County, Florida.</section><section></section><section>The East ½ of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Less the Northwest ¼ of the Northeast ¼ of said section, Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 94-48, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Florida City, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Pursuant to Ordinance No. 96-30, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall take effect only upon the written approval by property owners of more than fifty percent of the land in each parcel sought to be annexed.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 96-58CITY OF CORAL GABLES(Adopted May 7, 1996)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Coral Gables, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Coral Gables of the following property:</section><section>SNAPPER CREEK LAKES<section>COMMENCE at the intersection of the North line of Section 6, Township 55 South, Range 41 East, (being the centerline of N. Kendal Drive), with a line 35.00 feet Westerly of and parallel to the centerline of Old Cutler Road (Ingraham Highway), thence meander Southerly to Southwesterly, along the line that is 35.00 feet Westerly of and parallel to the centerline of said Old Cutler Road (being also the city limit line of the City of Coral Gables) to the point of intersection with the South line of the SW ¼ of the NW ¼ of the SE ¼ of said Section 6 and the Point of Beginning of the parcel of land hereinafter described; thence run West, along said South line, to the point of intersection with the East line of Block 6 of SNAPPER CREEK LAKES SUBDIVISION, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 57 at Page 86 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run North, along the East line of said Block 6, to the Northeast corner thereof, thence run West, along the North line of said Block 6, to the Northwest corner thereof; thence run South, along the West line of said Block 6, to the Northeast corner of Block 9 of the aforesaid SNAPPER CREEK LAKES SUBDIVISION; thence run West, along the North line of said Block 9, and its Westerly extension, to the point of intersection with the East right-of-way line of Red Road, being also the West right-of-way line of Snapper Creek Canal (Canal No. C-2); thence run South, along said East right-of-way line of Red Road, to the point of intersection with the South line of the NW ¼ of the SW ¼ of the NW ¼ of Section 7, Township 55 South, Range 41 East; thence run East, along said South line, to the point of intersection with the centerline of said Snapper Creek Canal; thence run Southeasterly, along said centerline, to the point of intersection with a line lying 35.00 feet Westerly of and parallel to the centerline of said Old Cutler Road (Ingraham Highway); thence run Northerly to Northeasterly, along said line, to the POINT OF BEGINNING; all lying and being in Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 28947, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Coral Gables, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area n the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Pursuant to Ordinance No. 96-30, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall take effect only if approved by a majority vote of the electors voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 96-100CITY OF CORAL GABLES(Adopted June 18, 1996)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Coral Gables are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Coral Gables of the following property:</section><section>HAMMOCK LAKES<section>BEGIN at the intersection of the North line of Section 6, Township 55 South, Range 41 East, (being the centerline of N. Kendall Drive), with a line 35.00 feet Westerly of and parallel to the centerline of Old Cutler Road (Ingraham Highway); thence meander Southerly to Southwesterly, along the line that is 35.00 feet Westerly of and parallel to the centerline of said Old Cutler Road (being also the city limit line of the City of Coral Gables) to the point of intersection with the South line of the NW ¼ of the SE ¼ of said Section 6; thence run West, along said South line, to the point of intersection with the East line of Block 6 of SNAPPER CREEK LAKES SUBDIVISION, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 57 at Page 86 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run North, along the East line of said Block 6, to the Northeast corner thereof; thence run West, along the North line of said Block 6, to the Northwest corner thereof; thence run South, along the West line of said Block 6, to the Northeast corner of Block 9 of the aforesaid SNAPPER CREEK LAKES SUBDIVISION; thence run West, along the North line of said Block 9, and its Westerly extension, to the point of intersection with the East right-of-way line of Red Road, being also the West right-of-way line of Snapper Creek Canal (Canal No. C-2); thence run North, along said East right-of-way line of Red Road, to the point of intersection with the North line of said Section 6; thence run Easterly, along the North line of said Section 6, to the POINT OF BEGINNING;</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution 28967, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Coral Gables, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 79-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Pursuant to Ordinance No. 96-30, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty-year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty-year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall take effect only if approved by a majority vote of the electors voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 96-117CITY OF CORAL GABLES(Adopted July 18, 1996)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Coral Gables are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Coral Gables of the following property:</section><section>DEERING BAY<section>Begin at the Northeast corner of, Township 55 South, Range 40 East, Dade County, Florida, said point being the intersection of Red Road (SW 57 Avenue) and SW 136 Street (Howard Drive); thence South along the East line of said to the Southeast corner of said; thence West along the South line of said to the Southeast corner of the SW ¼ of said; thence North along the East line of the SW ¼ of said to the Southeast corner of the North ½ of the SW ¼ of said; thence continue North along said East line of the SW ¼ of said a distance of 100 feet to its intersection with the boundary line of the Turning Basin as shown on the Plat of KING'S BAY SUBDIVISION as recorded in Plat Book 57, Page 45 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run the next five (5) courses along the boundary line of said Turning Basin, thence Northwesterly a distance of 464 feet, thence Westerly a distance of 294.7 feet; thence Northwesterly a distance of 52.6 feet; thence Northerly a distance of 485.4 feet; thence Easterly along the North boundary of said Turning Basin and its Easterly extension a distance of 665.6 feet to its intersection with aforementioned East line of the SW ¼ of, this line also being the centerline of SW 62 Avenue; thence North along said East line of the SW ¼ of said to the Northeast corner of the SW ¼ of said, said point being the intersection SW 62 Avenue and Mitchell Drive (SW 144 Street); thence West along the North line of SW ¼ of said to its intersection with a point 15 feet South of, the Southwest corner of Tract D-6, as shown on the Plat of DEERING BAY as recorded in Plat Book 139, Page 60 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence North at right angles to the South line of the NW ¼ of said a distance of 15 feet to said Southwest corner of Tract D-6; thence Northeasterly, along the westerly boundary of said Tract D-6 and its Northeasterly extension, a distance of 422.4 feet to its intersection with the boundary of Chapman Field Park as described in Deed Book 3221 at Page 377 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence run the following four (4) courses along said boundary of Chapman Field Park; thence Easterly a distance of 1454.7 feet; thence Northeasterly a distance of 1754.2 feet; thence Northwesterly a distance of 553.0 feet; thence North a distance of 576.4 feet to its intersection with the North line of said; thence East along the North line of said a distance of 2336.5 feet to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution 28871, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Coral Gables, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 79-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Pursuant to Ordinance No. 96-30, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty-year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty-year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 96-128CITY OF SOUTH MIAMI(Adopted September 10, 1996)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of South Miami, are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of South Miami of the following property:</section><section>SECTION D (LESS PROPERTYWEST OF PALMETTO)<section>Begin at the intersection of the North line of Section 35, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, Dade County, Florida, also being the centerline of SW 72 Street (Sunset Drive) with the East line of the West ½ of the NE ¼ of said Section 35; thence South along the East line of the West ½ of the NE ¼ of said Section 35, also being the city limit line of the City of South Miami, to its intersection with the South line of the N ½ of said Section 35; thence West along the South line of the N ½ of said Section 35, being the centerline of S.W. 80 Street (Davis Drive), to its intersection with the East limited access right-of-way line of State Road 826 (Palmetto Expressway), as shown on sheet 5 of 16 of the State of Florida Department of Transportation Right-of-way Map recorded in Road Map Book 73 at page 7 of the Public Records of Dade County, Florida; thence Northerly, Northeasterly, Easterly, Northerly and Northeasterly along said limited access right-of-way line to the end of said limited access right-of-way line at S.W. 72nd Street, thence continue on its Northeasterly extension to its intersection with the aforementioned North line of Section 35, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, thence East along the North line of said Section 35, being he centerline of S.W. 72 Street (Sunset Drive), to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. 62-95-9610, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of South Miami, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Metropolitan Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Pursuant to Ordinance No. 96-30, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty-year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance shall take effect only if approved by a majority vote of the electors voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 01-124CITY OF HOMESTEAD(Adopted July 24, 2001)</section><section>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended, by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:</section><section>A portion of Sections 3, 9 and 10, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, being more particularly as follows:<section>Begin at the Northeast corner of said Section 10; thence run S0°58'15"E along the East line of the NE¼ of said Section 10 for 2636.86 feet to the N.E. corner of the S.E.¼ of said Section 10, thence run S01°47'20"E along the East line of the SE¼ of said Section 10 for 1319.79 feet to the Southeast corner of the North½ of the South½ of said Section 10; thence run S89°22'14"W along the South line of the North½ of the South½ of said Section 10 for 5355.59 feet to the Southwest corner of the North½ of the South½ of said Section 10; thence run S88°40'26"W along the South line of the North½ of the SE¼ of said Section 9 for 1442.25 feet to the Southeasterly right-of-way line of the HOMESTEAD EXTENSION OF FLORIDA'S TURNPIKE, Section No. 87005-2303, S.R. No. 821 right-of-way map last revised 7-25-85; thence run N55°35'29"E along the said Southeasterly right-of-way line for 1043.01 feet to a point of curvature; thence continue Northeasterly along the said Southeasterly right of line, being a circular curve to the left, having for its elements a radius of 7789.44 feet and a central angle of 9°03'54" for 1232.40 feet to a point of tangency; thence run N46°31'35"E along the said Southeasterly right-of-way line for 3052.19 feet to a point of curvature; thence run Northeasterly along the said Southeasterly right-of-way line, being the arc of a circular curve to the left, having for its elements a radius of 3424.04, and a central angle of 22°09'18" for 1324.00 feet to a non-tangent point of intersection with the Southwesterly right-of-way line of the South Florida Water Management District Canal C—103N; thence run N33°14'27"E across the said Canal C—103N right-of-way for 130.02 feet to the point of intersection of the Northeasterly right-of-way said Canal C—103N right-of-way with the said Southeasterly right-of-way line of the HOMESTEAD EXTENSION OF FLORIDA'S TURNPIKE; thence run N18°59'20"E along the said Southeasterly right-of-way line of the HOMESTEAD EXTENSION OF FLORIDA'S TURNPIKE for 129.38 feet; thence run N19°10'54"E for 615.00 feet to a point of curvature; thence run Northeasterly along the arc of a circular curve to the right, having for its elements a radius of 1055.92 feet and a central angle of 26°00'00" for 479.16 feet to a point of tangency; thence run N45°10'54"E for 332.00 feet to point of curvature; thence run Northeasterly, Northerly and Northwesterly along the arc of a circular curve to the left, having for its elements a radius of 588.22 feet and a central angle of 46°00'00" for 472.25 feet to a point of tangency; thence run N0°49'06"W for 135.50 feet to a point on the Southerly Limited Access right-of-way line of S.W. 288 Street the last 5 courses being along the said Southeasterly right-of-way line of the HOMESTEAD EXTENSION OF FLORIDA'S TURNPIKE; thence run N85°22'38"E along the said Southerly Limited Access right-of-way line S.W. 288 Street for 303.31 feet to the terminus point of the said Limited Access right-of-way line; thence run N0°49'06"W for 125.00 feet the North line of the SE¼ of said Section 3; thence run N89°10'54"E along the last described line for 612.77 feet to the Northeast corner of the SE¼ of said Section 3; thence run S0°34'05"E along the East line of the SE¼ of said Section 3 for 2654.65 feet to the Point of Beginning. Less the South 218.02 feet of the West 200 feet of the East½ of the NE¼ of the SW¼ of the SE¼ of said Section 3.</section></section><section>as set forth in Resolution No. R2000-06-24, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Homestead, which resolution is made attached hereto as Exhibit 1 and made a part hereof by reference.</section><section>Pursuant to, and of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Pursuant to of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>If any section, subsection, sentence, clause or provision of this ordinance is held invalid, the remainder of this ordinance shall not be affected by such invalidity.</section><section>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section><section>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 02-69</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF CORAL GABLES, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING SEVERABILITY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE.</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Coral Gables are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Coral Gables of the following property:</section></section><section>City of Coral Gables</section><section>Proposed Annexation</section><section>Legal Description<section>The East One Half (E ½) of the Southeast Quarter (SE ¼) of the Southwest Quarter (SW ¼) of, Township 54 South, Range 41 East, LESS the South 250.00 feet thereof, in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 28843, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Coral Gables, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.<section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this ordinance shall take effect only if approved by a majority vote of the electors voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: May 7, 2002</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 02-79</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE TOWN OF MEDLEY, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING SEVERABILITY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE.</section><section>WHEREAS, the Town of Medley requested annexation of an area pursuant to Resolution No. C-750 which resolution is attached hereto and made a part hereof by reference (Attachment I); and</section><section>WHEREAS, the Town of Medley, at this time, requests annexation of only a portion of its original proposal as generally depicted on the attached map (Attachment II),</section><section>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Medley are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the Town of Medley of the following property:</section></section><section>Annexation by the Town of Medley</section><section>Legal Description<section>All that portion of, Township 52 South, Range 39 East, lying Easterly of the Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike (State Road 821) and excluding therefrom the right-of-way for said Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike</section></section><section>AND<section>All that portion of, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, lying and being Southwesterly of the centerline of the Miami Canal (Canal C-6) and lying Southeasterly of said Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike (State Road 821) and excluding therefrom the right-of-way for said Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike</section></section><section>AND<section>All of that portion of, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, lying and being Southwesterly of said centerline of the Miami Canal (Canal C-6) and lying Southeasterly of said Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike (State Road 821) and excluding therefrom the right-of-way for said Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike,</section><section>All lying and being in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: May 21, 2002</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 02-146</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF FLORIDA CITY, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING SEVERABILITY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>WHEREAS, the City of Florida City has requested annexation of an area pursuant to Resolution No. 01-06 which resolution is attached hereto and made a part hereof by reference (Attachment I),</section><section>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Florida City are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Florida City of the following property:</section></section><section>Florida City Annexation Area "E"</section><section>Legal Description<section>A portion of the West half (W ½) of the Southwest quarter (SW ¼) of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, in Miami-Dade County, Florida, more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Commence at the Northwest corner of the Southwest quarter (SW ¼) of said; thence East along the North line of said Southwest quarter (SW ¼) for 26.14 feet to the centerline of Krome Avenue (State Road 997) and the POINT OF BEGINNING; thence Southerly and Southeasterly, along said centerline of Krome Avenue as it is described in that certain deed between Dade County and the State of Florida recorded in Deed Book 1483 at Page 403, of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, to the intersection of said centerline of Krome Avenue with the centerline of U.S. Highway No. 1 (State Road 5) as shown on Florida State Road Department Right-of-way Map, Section No. 8702-109, recorded in Plat Book 60 at Page 65 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence Northerly along said centerline of U.S. Highway No. 1 to the Northeast corner of the Northwest quarter (NW ¼) of the Northwest quarter (NW ¼) of the Southwest quarter (SW ¼) of said; thence Westerly, along the North line of the Southwest ¼ of said (centerline of SW 352nd Street), to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: September 12, 2002</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 03-156</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE TOWN OF MEDLEY, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING SEVERABILITY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>WHEREAS, the Town of Medley requested annexation of an area pursuant to Resolution No. C-750 which resolution is attached hereto and made a part hereof by reference (Exhibit I); and</section><section>WHEREAS, the Town of Medley, at this time, requests annexation of only a portion of its original proposal as generally depicted on the attached map (Attachment II),</section><section>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the Town of Medley are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the Town of Medley of the following property:</section></section><section>Annexation by the Town of Medley</section><section>Legal Description</section><section>TOWN OF MEDLEY ANNEXATION<section>All of Section 10, Township 53 South, Range 40 East in Miami-Dade County, Florida, lying Southwesterly of the Centerline of the Miami Canal as shown on the Florida State Department of Transportation Right-of-Way Map Section 87090-2518 dated June 26, 1970 and recorded in Road Plat Book 88 at Page 12 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida,</section><section>LESS all those portions of said Section 10 previously incorporated into the Town of Medley, Florida.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: July 8, 2003</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 03-157</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF NORTH MIAMI, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; RESTRICTING MODIFICATION OF APPLICABLE LAND DEVELOPMENT REGULATIONS; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THIS ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following property:</section></section><section>Annexation by the City of North Miami</section><section>Legal Description<section>Tract "A" of "OAKLAWN PARK", according to the plat thereof as recorded in Plat Book 159 at Page 27 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 2002-38 of the Mayor and City Council of the City of North Miami which resolution is attached hereto (Attachment I) and made a part hereof by reference.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This ordinance shall be effective only if the City of North Miami executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement wherein it agrees to (a) make an annual mitigation payment to the County's Municipal Services Trust Fund and (b) pay Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $26 per year for approximately 22 years.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>This ordinance shall be effective only upon the following additional conditions: (a) the annexed area shall be annexed with Miami-Dade County's current BU-2 zoning district boundary regulations remaining in full force and effect; (b) should the City of North Miami adopt new land development regulations that rezone the annexed area, Miami-Dade County's BU-2 zoning district boundary regulations shall nevertheless remain in full force and effect if the City's new zoning restricts Home Depot's rights to operate or continue to operate the store on the annexed area; and (c) in the event of a casualty on the annexed area, the City of North Miami agrees that the annexed area may be redeveloped in accordance with plans substantially complying with the site plan used for construction of the store.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: July 8, 2003</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 03-158</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF SOUTH MIAMI, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING FOR RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THIS ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of South Miami are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of South Miami of the following property:</section></section><section>Annexation by the City of South Miami-Dade County Attorney's Office</section><section>Legal Description</section><section>CITY OF SOUTH MIAMI</section><section>SNAPPER CREEK ANNEXATION<section>All that part of the Southwest ¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida, lying North of the existing Northerly municipal boundary of the Village of Pinecrest which is the centerline of the Snapper Creek (C-2) Canal according to Miami-Dade County Ordinance 95-207;</section><section>LESS and excepting that portion thereof previously included within boundaries of the City of South Miami more particularly described as: the North ½ of the Northeast ¼ of the Northwest ¼ of said Southwest ¼ of Section 36, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, also known and described as "Fuchs Park".</section></section><section>-AND-<section>A portion of the Southeast ¼ of Section 35, Township 54 South, Range 40 East in Miami-Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:<section>BEGIN at the Northeast corner of said Southeast ¼ of said Section 35; thence run Westerly along the North line of the Southeast ¼ of said Section 35 to it's point of intersection with the Northerly extension of the West line of Tract "F" of DADELAND NORTH METRORAIL STATION according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 147 at Page 55 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County Florida; thence Southerly along said Northerly extension of said West line of said Tract "F", and along said West line of said Tract "F", and along the Southerly extension of said West line of said Tract "F" to the Southerly limited access right-of-way line of State Road 878 according to the Right-of-way Map thereof recorded in Plat Book 88 at Page 74 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County; thence Southeasterly, following said Southerly limited access right-of-way line of State Road 878 to it's point of intersection with the Northwesterly right-of-way line of State Road 5 ; thence Southwesterly along said Northwesterly right-of-way line of State Road 5 to it's intersection with the centerline of the Snapper Creek (C-2) Canal; thence Southeasterly along said centerline of the Snapper Creek Canal and the Northerly municipal boundary of the Village of Pinecrest according to Miami-Dade County Ordinance 95-207, to the East line of said Southeast ¼ of said Section 35; thence Northerly along said East line of said Southeast ¼ of Section 35 to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section></section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 68-02-11417, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of South Miami, which resolution is made a part hereof by reference.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County. It is provided, however, that if the Board of County Commissioners after the effective date of this ordinance, amends or repeals Sections 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and grants to any municipality having an above average per capita taxable value as compared to all other municipalities within Miami-Dade County, including the Unincorporated Municipal Service Area, the right to be paid electrical franchise revenues, utility tax revenues and cigarette tax revenues accruing within an area that the municipality annexes, this ordinance and any other applicable provisions of the Code of Miami-Dade County shall be deemed modified and amended to require that as of the effective date of that amendment or repeal and grant to another municipality, the City of South Miami shall be entitled to be paid the electric franchise revenues, utility tax revenues and cigarette tax revenues which accrue from the area annexed pursuant to this Ordinance.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of South Miami executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement wherein it agrees to (a) make an annual mitigation to the County's Municipal Services Trust Fund (b) pay Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $6,700 per year for approximately 22 years and (c) abide by the Downtown Kendall Urban Center District, pursuant to Sec. 33-284.55, et seq. of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The interlocal agreement shall be approved by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>This ordinance does not contain a sunset provision.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>The provisions of this ordinance shall take effect only if approved by a majority vote of the electors voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: July 8, 2003</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 03-216</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF HIALEAH, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THIS ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Hialeah of the following property:</section></section><section>CITY OF HIALEAH ANNEXATIONLEGAL DESCRIPTION<section>All of and 20, Township 52 South, Range 40 East in Miami-Dade County, Florida, and those portions of Sections 16 and 21, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, lying Westerly of the City of Miami Lakes, Florida, the West boundary of said City of Miami Lakes being the East Limited Access right-of-way line of State Road No. 93 (I-75) as shown on the Florida State Department of Transportation Right-of-Way Map Section No. 87075-2402 dated December 1, 1978.</section><section>encompassing an area described by Ordinance No. 02-71 of the Mayor and City Council of the City of Hialeah which resolution is attached hereto (Attachment I) and made a part hereof by reference.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95. An existing agreement dated December 4, 1996 entitled "First Amended and Restated Interlocal Agreement between Metropolitan Dade County and Contract Cities for City Use of the County Solid Waste Management System" meets the requirement for a 20 year interlocal agreement for disposal.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Hialeah: (1) executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement wherein it agrees, among other things, to: (a) pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $786 per year for approximately 22 years or as provided in the interlocal agreement, (b) pay to Miami-Dade County the Fire debt service at the appropriate millage rate (currently .079 mills or approximately $4000 per year) through the year 2022 or as provided in the interlocal agreement and (c) require approval of land uses and land development regulations outside Miami-Dade County's Urban Development Boundary to be consistent with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan (Master Plan) and that Miami-Dade County retains jurisdiction regarding applications to amend the Master Plan in that portion of the annexed area lying outside Urban Development Boundary, (2) adopts an ordinance which requires sellers or lessors to disclose in conspicuous type to prospective purchasers or lessees in conjunction of the sale or lease of real property within two miles of the Miami-Dade Lake Belt Area that mining activities involving the use of explosives occur within this area and, (3) adopts by ordinance appropriate building and construction standards for the area affected by blasting.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: Oct. 21, 2003</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 04-76</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF HIALEAH GARDENS, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THIS ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Hialeah Gardens are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Hialeah Gardens of the following property:</section></section><section>CITY OF HIALEAH GARDENS ANNEXATION LEGAL DESCRIPTION<section>See Attachment 1 which is incorporated herein by reference.</section><section>encompassing an area described by Ordinance No. 2003-41 of the Mayor and City Council of the City of Hialeah Gardens which resolution is attached hereto (Attachment 2) and made a part hereof by reference.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste, if any, within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95. An existing agreement dated December 4, 1996 entitled "First Amended and Restated Interlocal Agreement between Metropolitan Dade County and Contract Cities for City Use of the County Solid Waste Management System" meets the requirement for a 20 year interlocal agreement for disposal.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Hialeah Gardens executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement wherein it agrees, among other things, to: (a) make an annual mitigation payment to the County's Municipal Services Trust Fund in an amount equivalent to .506 mills of the assessed value of the portion of the Northwest Commercial Business Industrial Area contained within the annexed area (b) pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $15.00 per year for approximately 20 years or as provided in the interlocal agreement and (c) require approval of land uses and land development regulations outside Miami-Dade County's Urban Development Boundary to be consistent with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan (Master Plan) and that Miami-Dade County retains jurisdiction regarding applications to amend the Master Plan or Developments of Regional Impact in connection with Master Plan Amendments in that portion of the annexed area lying outside the Urban Development Boundary.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: APR 13, 2004</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 05-111</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF FLORIDA CITY, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING FOR PAYMENT OF DEBT SERVICE ON CERTAIN COUNTY BONDS; PROVIDING THAT THIS ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; SUPERSEDING CONFLICTING PROVISIONS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>WHEREAS, the City of Florida City originally applied to annex certain lands in unincorporated Miami-Dade County, as more specifically described in Resolution No. 03-29 of the Mayor and City Council of the City of Florida City, which resolution is attached hereto as Attachment 1; and</section><section>WHEREAS, the Mayor and the City Council of the City of Florida City agree to a reduction of the area sought to be annexed by Florida City, pursuant to Resolution No. 05-21 of the Mayor and City Council of the City of Florida City adopted on May 10, 2005, which is attached hereto as Attachment 2,</section><section>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The foregoing recitations are hereby incorporated herein as a portion of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Florida City are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Florida City of the following property:</section></section><section>CITY OF FLORIDA CITYANNEXATIONLEGAL DESCRIPTION<section>See Attachment 3 which is incorporated herein by reference encompassing an area generally depicted in Attachment 4.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance Nos. 61-8 as amended, 70-84 as amended, and 70-85 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County (Ordinance No. 96-30 as amended), this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste, if any, within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>This ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Florida City executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement wherein it agrees, among other things, to:<section prefix='(a)'>pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's (i) prorated share of any County debt outstanding at the time the area is annexed for which revenues from the annexed area have been pledged for repayment of or security for such debt and (ii) its prorated share of any refunding of such debt; this obligation shall include, but not be limited to the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>obtain County pre-approval of land uses and land development regulations outside Miami-Dade County's Urban Development Boundary which shall be consistent with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan ("CDMP"), and agree that Miami-Dade County retains jurisdiction regarding applications to amend the CDMP or Developments of Regional Impact in connection with CDMP Amendments in that portion of the annexed area lying outside the Urban Development Boundary.</section></section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>All special laws applying only to Miami-Dade County, Florida, or to any municipality in Miami-Dade County, or any general law which the Board of County Commissioners is authorized by the Constitution or the Home Rule Charter to supersede, nullify, modify or amend, or any part of any such law, or any prior ordinances or resolutions of Miami-Dade County in conflict with the procedures for the annexation of the annexed land by Florida City, are hereby superseded.</section><section prefix='Section 8.'>This ordinance shall be subject to the adoption of an interlocal agreement between Florida City and Miami-Dade County which requires land uses and land development regulations in the annexed area outside Miami-Dade County's Urban Development Boundary to be consistent with the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan (Master Plan) and which provides further that Miami-Dade County retains jurisdiction regarding applications to amend the Master Plan or Developments of Regional Impact in connection with Master Plan Amendments in that portion of the annexed area lying outside the Urban Development Boundary.</section><section prefix='Section 9.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: June 21, 2005</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 05-213</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF SWEETWATER, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 5.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THE ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Sweetwater are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Sweetwater of the following property:</section></section><section>Annexation by the City of Sweetwater</section><section>Legal Description<section>All of, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, and all of Excess Government Lot 6 between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 40 East, and the North ½ of Section 6 Township 54 South, Range 40 East, in Miami-Dade County, Florida, LESS the West ½ of Tracts 1 through 8 inclusive in Block 24, and LESS the East ½ of Tracts 7 and 8 in Block 25 of SWEETWATER GROVES according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 8 at Page 50 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as previously incorporated and approved on March 11, 1986 encompassing an area described by Resolutions No. 3114 and 3120, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Sweetwater, which resolutions are attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Sweetwater executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County wherein it agrees, among other things, to: (a) an annual mitigation payment to the County's Municipal Services Trust Fund based on the future growth of a portion of the annexed area as shown in Attachment B, which is contained within the areas identified by County Commission as Commercial, Business, Industrial (CBI) areas, pursuant to Miami-Dade County Ordinance No. 05-73, and (b) pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $88,800 per year for approximately 25 years until FY 28-29 or as provided in the interlocal agreement. The County Manager shall prepare and present directly to the County Commission an Interlocal Agreement in accordance with this Section within 30 days of the effective date of this Ordinance.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>This ordinance shall become effective: (a) ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board and (b) only if approved by a majority vote of the electors voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: December 6, 2005</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 08-25</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF FLORIDA CITY, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THE ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Florida City are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Florida City of the following property:</section></section><section>Annexation by the City of Florida City</section><section>Legal Description<section>A portion of Miami-Dade County generally bounded on the North by the centerline of theoretical SW 352 Street, bounded on the East by Krome Avenue (SW 177 Avenue), State Road 5 (US-1) and Card Sound Road, bounded on the South by theoretical SW 360 Street and bounded on the West by the former East right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railroad, said parcel of land being more particularly described as follows;</section><section>BEGIN at the intersection of the North line of the Southeast one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida (centerline of theoretical SW 352nd Street) with the former East right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railroad as shown on the Florida Department of Transportation FEC RAILROAD ACQUISITION MAP recorded in Plat Book 124, Page 77 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence run East along the said North line of the Southeast one-quarter of said and along the North line of the Southwest one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida (centerline of theoretical SW 352nd Street) to the intersection with the centerline of Krome Avenue (SW 177 Avenue) as shown on the Dade County Public Works Department Right-of-Way Map recorded in Plat Book 112, Page 90 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence run Southerly and Southeasterly along said centerline of Krome Avenue (SW 177 Avenue), the centerline of State Road 5 (US-1) as shown on the Florida Department of Transportation Right-of-Way Map recorded in Plat Book 60, Page 36 of the Public Records of said Miami-Dade County and the centerline of Card Sound Road to the intersection with the South line of the Southwest 1/4 of said (theoretical centerline of SW 360 Street); thence Westerly along the South line of the Southwest 1/4 of said (theoretical centerline of SW 360 Street) to the intersection with the above mentioned former East right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railroad; thence Northwesterly along said former East right-of-way line of the Florida East Coast Railroad to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 04-47, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Florida City, which resolution is attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Florida City executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County wherein it agrees, among other things, to: (a) pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $1,000 per year for approximately 25 years until FY 2028-29 or as provided in the interlocal agreement and (b) the City agrees that the County will retail all zoning and permitting authority over rockmining, lake excavations and related requests within the annexation area in perpetuity.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: March 4, 2008</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 08-54</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF HOMESTEAD, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THE ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:</section></section><section>CITY OF HOMESTEADCOMBINED LEGAL DESCRIPTIONANNEXATION AREAS NW-1 &amp; NW-2<section>A parcel of land lying in Sections 2 and 11, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>Begin at the southeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned, also being the intersection of the centerlines of S.W. 304 Street (Kings Highway) and S.W. 192 Avenue (Tower Road); thence northerly along the east line of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned, also being the centerline of S.W. 192 Avenue (Tower Road), to the intersection with the south line of north 329 feet of the west 265 feet of the northeast one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence easterly to the intersection with the east line of the west 265 feet of the northeast one-quarter of the aforementioned; thence northerly along the east line of the west 265 feet of the northeast one-quarter of the aforementioned to the intersection with the south line of the Southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 296 Street (Avocado Drive); thence easterly along the south line of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 296 Street (Avocado Drive), to the intersection with the east line of the west one-half of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 189 Avenue; thence northerly along the east line of the west one-half of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 189 Avenue, to the north line of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of the S.W. 288 Street (Biscayne Drive); thence westerly along the north line of the southeast one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 288 Street (Biscayne Drive), and along the north line of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 288 Street (Biscayne Drive), to the west line of the east one-half of the east one-half of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 193 Avenue; thence southerly along the west line of the east one-half of the east one-half of the southwest one-quarter of the aforementioned Section 2, also being the centerline of S.W. 193 Avenue, to the intersection with the north line of the northwest one-quarter of aforementioned, also being the centerline of S.W. 296 Street (Avocado Drive); thence westerly along the north line of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned, also being the centerline of S.W. 296 Street (Avocado Drive), to the intersection with the west line of the east one-half of the northwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned, thence southerly along the west line of the east one-half of the northwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter and the west line of the northeast one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter to the intersection with the south line of the northeast one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the aforementioned, also being the centerline of S.W. 302 Street; thence easterly along the south line of the northeast one-quarter of the southwest one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the aforesaid, also being the centerline of S.W. 302 Street, to the intersection with the west line of the southeast one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the aforesaid, also being the centerline of S.W. 194 Avenue; thence southerly along the west line of the southeast one-quarter of the northwest one-quarter of the aforesaid, also being the centerline of S.W. 194 Avenue, to the intersection with the south line of northwest one-quarter of the aforesaid, also being the centerline of S.W. 304 Street (Kings Highway); thence easterly along the south line of the northwest one-quarter of the aforesaid, also being the centerline of S.W. 304 Street (Kings Highway), to the Point of Beginning, containing 222.29 acres more or less.</section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolutions No. R2004-04-36 and R2005-09-128, passed and adopted by the City Council of the City of Homestead, which resolutions are attached hereto as Attachment A and Attachment B respectively and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment C and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment C, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Homestead executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County wherein it agrees, among other things, to: pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service as provided in the interlocal agreement.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>This ordinance shall become effective: (a) ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board and (b) only if approved by a majority vote of the electors voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: May 6, 2008</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 08-69</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF NORTH MIAMI, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE, UTILITY TAX AND CIGARETTE TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THE ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following property:</section></section><section>Annexation by the City of North Miami</section><section>Legal Description<section>That portion of the S ½ of the NW ¼ of the SW ¼ of the SW ¼ of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, lying East of the centerline of NE 2 Ave. (known as NE 2 Ct.) as shown and delineated upon Deed Book 1952, Page 509, of record, in Miami-Dade County, Public Records, Florida.</section><section>And</section><section>That portion of the S ½ of the N ½ of the NW ¼ of the SW ¼ of the SW ¼, Township 52 South, Range 42 East, lying East of the centerline of NE 2 Ave. (known NE as 2 Ct.) as shown and delineated upon Deed Book 1952, Page 509, of record, in Miami-Dade County, Public Records, Florida.</section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolutions No. R-2005-21, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of North Miami, which resolution is attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section prefix='Section'>2. Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues and all cigarette tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section'>3. Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of North Miami executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County wherein it agrees that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: June 3, 2008</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 08-118</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF FLORIDA CITY, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE AND UTILITY TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of the City of Florida City are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Florida City of the following property:</section></section><section>CITY OF FLORIDA CITYCOMBINED LEGAL DESCRIPTIONANNEXATION AREAS G-1, G-2 AND G-3<section>The East one-half of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>BEGIN at the Northeast corner of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of said, also being the intersection of the centerline of S.W. 356th Street (S.W. 11th Street) and the East line of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of said; thence Southerly along said East line of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of to the intersection with the South line of the Southwest one-quarter of said, also being the centerline of S.W. 360th Street (Lucille Drive); thence Westerly along said South line of the Southwest one-quarter of, also being the centerline of S.W. 360th Street (Lucille Drive), to the intersection with the West line of the East one-half of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of said; thence Northerly along said West line of the East one-half of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of to the North line of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of said, also being the centerline of S.W. 356th Street (S.W. 11th Street); thence Easterly along the said North line of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of, also being the centerline of S.W. 356th Street (S.W. 11th Street), to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section><section>TOGETHER WITH THE FOLLOWING:</section><section>A portion of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East, also being all of Blocks 8 and 9, CITY OF FLORIDA CITY REALTY COMPANY'S SUBDIVISION, according to the Plat thereof, recorded in Plat Book 14, Page 50 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; together with the right-of-way of 24th Street lying between said Blocks 8 and 9, and that portion of the right-of-way of S.W. 180th Avenue (S.W. 5th Avenue) lying adjacent to said Blocks 8 and 9 in Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter said; being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>BEGIN at the Southwest corner of the Southeast one-quarter of said, also being the intersection of the centerlines of S.W. 360th Street (Lucille Drive) and the Westerly line of the said Southeast one-quarter of, thence Northerly along said West line of the Southeast one-quarter of to the intersection with the centerline of S.W. 359th Street (23rd Street); thence Easterly along the centerline of S.W. 359th Street (23rd Street) to the intersection with the East line of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of said; thence Southerly along said East line of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southwest one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of (S.W. 280th Avenue/S.W. 5 Avenue) to the intersection with the South line of the Southeast one-quarter of said; thence Westerly along said South line of the Southeast one-quarter of, also being the centerline of S.W. 360th Street (Lucille Drive), to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section><section>TOGETHER WITH THE FOLLOWING:</section><section>The East one-half of the Northwest one-quarter of the Northeast 1/4 of the Southeast one-quarter of, Township 57, Range 38 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida; being more particularly described as follows:</section><section>BEGIN at the intersection of the Northerly line of the Southeast one-quarter of said, also being the centerline of S.W. 352nd Street (S.W. 7th Street) and the East line of the Northwest one-quarter of the Northeast one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of said; thence Southerly along said East line of the Northwest one-quarter of the Northeast one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of to the Southeast corner of the Northwest one-quarter of the Northeast one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of said; thence Westerly along the South line of the Northwest one-quarter of the Northeast one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of said to the Southwest corner of the East one-half of the Northwest one-quarter of the Northeast one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of said; thence Northerly along the West line of the East one-half of the Northwest one-quarter of the Northeast one-quarter of the Southeast one-quarter of said to the intersection with the North line of the Southeast one-quarter of said, also being the centerline of S.W. 352nd Street (S.W. 7th Street); thence Easterly along said North line of the Southeast one-quarter of, also being the centerline of S.W. 352nd Street (S.W. 7th Street), to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 05-40, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Florida City, which resolution is attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Sections 20-8.1 and 20-8.2 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: October 7, 2008</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 08-138</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF MIAMI SHORES VILLAGE, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE AND UTILITY TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THE ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:<section prefix='Section 1.'>The municipal boundaries of Miami Shores Village are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to Miami Shores Village of the following property:</section></section><section>MIAMI SHORES VILLAGELEGAL DESCRIPTION<section>THAT PORTION OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA IN SECTION 36, TOWNSHIP 52 SOUTH, RANGE 41 EAST, BOUNDED ON THE NORTH BY THE CENTERLINE OF N.W. 115TH STREET, BOUNDED ON THE SOUTH BY CENTERLINE OF N.W. 111TH STREET, BOUNDED ON THE WEST BY THE EASTERLY LIMITED ACCESS RIGHT-OF-WAY LINE OF INTERSTATE 95, BOUNDED ON THE EAST BY THE EXISTING BOUNDARY OF THE VILLAGE OF MIAMI SHORES ALONG THE CENTERLINE OF N.W. 5TH AVENUE</section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 1077-04, passed and adopted by the Council of Miami Shores Village, which resolutions are attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section prefix='Section 2.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.1, 20-8.2 and 20-8.3 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section prefix='Section 3.'>Pursuant to Section 20-8.4, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section prefix='Section 4.'>This Ordinance shall be effective only if Miami Shores Village executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County wherein it agrees, among other things, to: pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at approximately $2,537 per year for approximately 25 years until FY 2028-29 or as provided in the interlocal agreement.</section><section prefix='Section 5.'>It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section prefix='Section 6.'>The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section prefix='Section 7.'>This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section></section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: December 2, 2008</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 09-32</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF HOMESTEAD, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE AND UTILITY TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING THAT THE ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:</section><section>Section 1. The municipal boundaries of the City of Homestead are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Homestead of the following property:</section><section>HOMESTEAD ANNEXATIONLEGAL DESCRIPTION</section><section>The Southeast 1/4 of the Southwest 1/4 of, Township 57 South, Range 38 East in Miami-Dade County, Florida; bounded on the South by SW 328th Street (also known as Lucy Street or SW 8th Street); bounded on the West by SW 194th Avenue; bounded on the North by SW 324th Street; bounded on the East by SW 192nd Avenue (also known as Tower Road or Longview Road or SW 18th Avenue);</section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 2007-04-46, passed and adopted by the City of Homestead Council, which resolution is attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section>Section 2. Pursuant to, and of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Section 3. Pursuant to, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>Section 4. This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Homestead executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County.</section><section>Section 5. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section>Section 6. The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>Section 7. This ordinance shall become effective ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: May 5, 2009</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 10-70</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF SWEETWATER, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE AND UTILITY TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; EXEMPTING THE ANNEXATION FROM OF THE CODE OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY REQUIRING MUNICIPALITIES TO MAKE CERTAIN PAYMENTS TO THE COUNTY WHEN ANNEXING COMMERCIAL, BUSINESS AND INDUSTRIAL ("CBI") AREAS; PROVIDING THAT THE ORDINANCE WILL ONLY BECOME EFFECTIVE UPON THE OCCURRENCE OF CERTAIN EVENTS; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY, INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:</section><section>Section 1. The municipal boundaries of the City of Sweetwater are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of Sweetwater of the following property:</section><section>Annexation by the City of Sweetwater</section><section>Legal Description</section><section>Portions of, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, Section 6, Township 54 South, Range 40 East and Government Lot 6, between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 40 East, lying in Miami-Dade County, Florida, being more particularly described as follows:<section>BEGIN at the intersection of the south line of the Northwest 1/4 of Section 6, Township 54 South, Range 40 East, also being the centerline of West Flagler Street, with the southerly projection of the west line of the East 1/2 of said Lots 7 and 8, Block 25 of SWEETWATER GROVES, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 8, Page 50 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence northerly along said southerly projection and said west line of the East 1/2 of Lots 7 and 8, Block 25 to the Northwest corner of the East 1/2 of said Lot 7, Block 25; thence easterly along the north line of said Lot 7, Block 25 and its easterly projection to the southwest corner of Lot 6, Block 24 of said SWEETWATER GROVES; thence northerly along the west line of said Block 24 and its extension, being 15 feet east of and parallel to both the west line of the Northeast 1/4 of said Section 6 and the centerline of NW 112 Avenue, to the intersection with the north line of said Northeast 1/4 of Section 6; thence easterly along said north line of the Northeast 1/4 of Section 6, also being the centerline of NW 7 Street, to the intersection with the southerly projection of the east line of Tract "A", EURO SUBDIVISION, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 134, Page 43 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence northerly along said southerly projection and the east line of Tract "A" to the northeast corner of said Tract "A" and the southerly limited access right-of-way line of State Road 836 as shown on State of Florida State Road Department Right-of-way Map Section 87200-2521; thence easterly along said southerly limited access right-of-way line to the intersection with the east line of said Government Lot 6; thence northerly along said east line of Government Lot 6 and the east line of said, also being the centerline of NW 107 Avenue, to the intersection with the north right-of-way line of NW 25 Street; thence westerly along said north right-of-way line of NW 25 Street, also being 60 feet south of and parallel with the north line of said, to the intersection with the west line of said; thence southerly along the west line of said to the intersection with the north line of said Government Lot 6; thence easterly along said north line of Government Lot 6 to the intersection with the east line of a 130 foot wide canal reservation as shown on State of Florida State Road Department Right-of-way Map Section 87200-2521; thence southerly along said east line of said canal reservation, also being 130 feet east of and parallel to the west line of said Government Lot 6, to the intersection with the north line of said Section 6; thence easterly along the north line of said Section 6 to the southwest corner of Tract "A" of TORREMOLINOS WEST - PHASE ONE, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 126, Page 25 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence continue easterly along the north line of said Section 6, also being the south line of said Tract "A", for 115.00 feet to the intersection with the easterly limited access right-of-way line of State Road 836 as shown on State of Florida State Road Department Right-of-way Map Section 87200-2521; thence southerly along said easterly limited access right-of-way line to the intersection with the north line of Tract "A" of ORSA SUBDIVISION, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 140, Page 61 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida; thence westerly along the north line of said Tract "A" to the intersection with the east line of a 40 foot wide canal right-of-way as shown on said plat of ORSA SUBDIVISION; thence southerly along said east line of 40 foot wide canal right-of-way to the intersection with the south line of the NW 1/4 of said Section 6; thence easterly along said south line of the NW 1/4, also being the centerline of West Flagler Street, to the POINT OF BEGINNING;</section></section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. 3377, passed and adopted by the Commission of the City of Sweetwater, which resolution is attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section>Section 2. Pursuant to, and of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Section 3. Pursuant to, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>Section 4. The provisions of of the Code of Miami-Dade County, requiring an annexing municipality to pay to the County 100% of the net excess of revenues minus expenses attributable to an annexed area designated as a CBI, shall not apply to this annexation.</section><section>Section 5. This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of Sweetwater executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County wherein it agrees, among other things, to pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $39,200 per year for approximately 19 years until FY 28-29 or as provided in the interlocal agreement.</section><section>Section 6. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section>Section 7. The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>Section 8. This ordinance shall become effective: (a) ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board; and (b) filing with the Clerk of this Board, within 30 days after enactment of this ordinance, of a resolution of the City of Doral consenting to the subject City of Sweetwater annexation; and (c) approval by a majority of the electors in the area to be annexed, voting in an election to be called by this Board.</section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: October 19, 2010</section><section>ORDINANCE NO. 13-31</section><section>ORDINANCE CHANGING THE BOUNDARIES OF THE CITY OF NORTH MIAMI, FLORIDA, AND AMENDING THE CHARTER OF SUCH MUNICIPALITY BY PROVIDING FOR THE ANNEXATION OF CERTAIN LANDS, UNDER AND PURSUANT TO PROCEEDINGS PRESCRIBED BY SECTION 6.04(B) OF THE HOME RULE CHARTER; PROVIDING FOR RESERVATION TO THE COUNTY OF ELECTRIC FRANCHISE AND UTILITY TAX REVENUES; PROVIDING RETENTION OF GARBAGE AND REFUSE COLLECTION AND DISPOSAL; PROVIDING INTERDEPENDENCY INCLUSION IN THE CODE, AND AN EFFECTIVE DATE.</section><section>BE IT ORDAINED BY THE BOARD OF COUNTY COMMISSIONERS OF MIAMI-DADE COUNTY, FLORIDA:</section><section>Section 1. The municipal boundaries of the City of North Miami are hereby changed, extended and enlarged, and the charter of such municipality is hereby amended by the annexation to the City of North Miami of the following property:</section><section>Annexation by the City of North Miami</section><section>Legal Description</section><section>A portion of Miami-Dade County, Florida, lying South of NE 135 Street, North of NE 131 Street, East of the Biscayne Canal and West of NE 4 Avenue more particularly described as the NW 1/4, of the NW 1/4, of, Township 52 South, Range 42 East</section><section>encompassing an area described by Resolution No. R-2011-150, passed and adopted by the Council of the City of North Miami, which resolution is attached hereto as Attachment A and made a part hereof by reference. A map depicting the annexed area is attached hereto as Attachment B and made a part hereof by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description and the map identified as Attachment B, the boundaries of the annexation area as described by the legal description shall prevail.</section><section>Section 2. Pursuant to, and of the Code of Miami-Dade County, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall continue to collect and reserve all electric franchise revenues accruing within the annexed area during the full term of the County franchise, and the County shall forever continue to collect and receive all utility tax revenues accruing within the annexed area in the same manner as though the annexed area remained a part of the unincorporated areas of the County.</section><section>Section 3. Pursuant to, Code of Miami-Dade County, this Ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition and with the reservation that the County shall forever continue to collect and dispose of all residential waste within the annexed area in the same manner as though such annexed areas remained part of the unincorporated areas of the County, unless the authority to collect such waste is delegated by the County to the governing body of the municipality through a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for collection services, and a twenty (20) year interlocal agreement which provides for disposal services in substantially the form approved by Resolution No. R-1198-95.</section><section>Section 4. Pursuant to of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, this ordinance shall be effective only upon the condition that the Board retains jurisdiction over the modification or deletion of declarations of restrictive covenants accepted by either the Board or a Community Zoning Appeals Board in connection with a Comprehensive Development Master Plan application or zoning application, regardless of whether such declaration provides for modification or deletion by a successor governmental body. It is provided, however, that the Board of County Commissioners may not exercise such jurisdiction unless the applicable municipality has first approved the modification or deletion.</section><section>Section 5. This Ordinance shall be effective only if the City of North Miami executes a duly authorized interlocal agreement acceptable to the County wherein it agrees, among other things, to pay to Miami-Dade County the annexed area's prorated share of the Stormwater Utility Revenue Bonds debt service estimated at $39,200 per year for approximately 19 years until fiscal year 2028-2029 or as provided in the interlocal agreement.</section><section>Section 6. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners, and it is hereby ordained that the provisions of this ordinance, including any sunset provision, shall become and be made a part of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. The sections of this ordinance may be renumbered or relettered to accomplish such intention, and the word "ordinance" may be changed to "section," "article," or other appropriate word.</section><section>Section 7. The provisions of this Ordinance are interdependent upon one another, and the entire ordinance shall be deemed invalid if any of its provisions are declared invalid or unconstitutional. If any of the sections of this ordinance are found or adjudged to be illegal, void or of no effect, the entire ordinance shall be null and void and of no force or effect.</section><section>Section 8. This ordinance shall become effective: (a) ten (10) days after the date of enactment unless vetoed by the Mayor, and if vetoed, shall become effective only upon an override by this Board.</section><section>PASSED AND ADOPTED: April 2, 2013</section></section></text></law>